<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/categories/ideas-and-rants.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2016-08-26T15:10:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>The Psychological Side of Remote Work</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2016/08/the-psychological-side-of-remote-work/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-08-26T15:10:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Jason Antman</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2016-08-26:2016/08/the-psychological-side-of-remote-work/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For most of my professional career, I&amp;#8217;ve worked from home a few days a week - and a few times, for
stretches of a few weeks - and that&amp;#8217;s been the norm on most of my teams, not counting full-time
remote workers. But for all the talk about remote work, much of it seems to focus on tools,
collaboration and productivity - and relatively little on the human side, and tips to help
balance work and life when the work happens in your home (or wherever else you&amp;nbsp;are).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These certainly aren&amp;#8217;t for everyone, but here are some of the tricks I&amp;#8217;ve accumulated so
far that help me be happier, more productive and more sane when working from home, whether
it&amp;#8217;s a day or few a week or a few weeks straight. I know these aren&amp;#8217;t applicable to everyone,
and they also assume a culture that already values work-life balance, but might not spend
a lot of time talking about the little hacks to make remote work better. Not all of these
will work for every person, and there are plenty I&amp;#8217;m surely forgetting or not aware&amp;nbsp;of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-dress-for-the-job"&gt;1. Dress for the&amp;nbsp;Job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve made the &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m working from home so I&amp;#8217;m not wearing pants&amp;#8221; joke plenty of times
myself. But it&amp;#8217;s never true. When I&amp;#8217;m working from home, the first thing I do is
go through the same morning routine I do when going in to the office - most importantly,
making coffee and getting dressed. Lately I&amp;#8217;ve taken to wearing &amp;#8220;nicer&amp;#8221; (read: having
buttons somewhere on them) shirts to the office, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt;, I&amp;#8217;ll wear a t-shirt when I&amp;#8217;m
home. But I still put on long pants and&amp;nbsp;shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this is a big part of the psychological side of work/life separation. I have
&amp;#8220;work clothes&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;hanging around the house&amp;#8221; clothes. When I&amp;#8217;m going to be working,
I wear work clothes. When I&amp;#8217;m done for the day, a (psychologically) big part of my
end-of-the-work-day routine is changing from work clothes to &amp;#8220;hanging around&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;clothes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoever I heard this from - and I&amp;#8217;m sad to say I don&amp;#8217;t even remember who it was - probably
sounded crazy to me. But it really goes a long way to psychologically separate work time
from personal time - especially on the days when I finish up work and get right back to
the keyboard working on personal projects or&amp;nbsp;gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2-separate-profiles"&gt;2. Separate&amp;nbsp;Profiles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep separate profiles in your browser, one for work and one for personal.
&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/2364824?hl=en"&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="https://www.chromium.org/user-experience/multi-profiles"&gt;Chromium&lt;/a&gt; have support
for separate users; Firefox recently added built-in
&lt;a href="https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/profile-manager-create-and-remove-firefox-profiles"&gt;support for switching profiles&lt;/a&gt;,
which is quite nice for those of us who had been using &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Mozilla/Profile_Manager"&gt;Profile Manager&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;#8217;m sure there are some people who do this simply to keep history/bookmarks/etc. separate,
I do it as an incentive to focus on work when I&amp;#8217;m at work and focus on not work when I&amp;#8217;m not.
At the end of my work day I close my &amp;#8220;work&amp;#8221; browser session and open my &amp;#8220;personal&amp;#8221; one back
up. Thanks to session restore, all of my tabs are right where I left them&amp;#8230; and I don&amp;#8217;t have
a reason to leave distracting personal tabs open during the work day, or work tabs open
when I&amp;#8217;m on my own&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I know this doesn&amp;#8217;t work for everyone, especially if you&amp;#8217;re on-call and it&amp;#8217;s busy. In those
cases, I usually keep tabs in separate windows, one for work and one for personal; it&amp;#8217;s all
there when I need it, but out of the way when I&amp;nbsp;don&amp;#8217;t).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3-take-breaks"&gt;3. Take&amp;nbsp;Breaks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#8217;m physically in the office, my day is usually broken up by moments away from my computer
work with colleagues - whether it&amp;#8217;s walking to a meeting or lunch, whatever conversations pop up
in the room, or even just whiteboarding a problem. Sure, there&amp;#8217;s plenty of conversation on HipChat
when we&amp;#8217;re remote, but I&amp;#8217;m not &lt;em&gt;getting away from the keyboard&lt;/em&gt; like I do in the&amp;nbsp;office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take breaks. Take the dogs out, take five minutes to play with your kids or pets, go make coffee
or lunch, whatever. Just be sure to break up your day and not fall into the trap of sitting in
the same spot for however many hours staring at a monitor. Our bodies need &amp;#8220;get up and walk around&amp;#8221;
time, but our minds need a change of scenery too. Five minutes away from the same monitor is helpful.
Sure, if I&amp;#8217;m deep in the middle of something, I&amp;#8217;ll keep at it. But I usually find that stepping
away for a few minutes now and then at logical context switch points helps a lot. And if it&amp;#8217;s
a day of mostly writing code, it also provides a good time to think about what I&amp;#8217;m working on
without the burning urge to immediately start&amp;nbsp;implementing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t fall into the trap of feeling that work from home time demands that
you&amp;#8217;re glued to the keyboard every second without pause - nobody in the office is doing that.
And don&amp;#8217;t fall into the trap of feeling like you have to prove you&amp;#8217;re being productive while
remote by never taking a break - if you&amp;#8217;re like many people I know, you&amp;#8217;re probably already
more productive when you&amp;#8217;re in an environment that feels more comfortable (you can always
point people to Psychology Today&amp;#8217;s
&lt;a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/mind-the-manager/201605/remote-workers-are-happier-and-more-productive"&gt;Remote Workers Are Happier and More Productive&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, don&amp;#8217;t give up opportunities to change your surroundings. If you have a webinar or
online meeting, grab the laptop and take it from the couch (assuming the setting is acceptable
for the attendees). Need to read a lengthy article or documentation? Bring the laptop
outside. Anything to get a mental and visual change of&amp;nbsp;pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="4-lunch-is-holy"&gt;4. Lunch is&amp;nbsp;Holy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#8217;m in the office, if my team doesn&amp;#8217;t have lunch plans (which is the rule rather
than the exception), I tend to eat at my desk, and only take as much time as I need
to eat. Sometimes I&amp;#8217;m good to myself and read something, other times I just work while
I&amp;nbsp;eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#8217;m at home, I take the 45 minutes we&amp;#8217;re given for lunch, every day. If my wife is
home, we watch something on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; and eat together. If she isn&amp;#8217;t, I catch up on an episode
of something on Netflix. But no matter what I do, I set aside the full &amp;#8220;official&amp;#8221;
45 minutes to decompress, step away from the keyboard, and breathe a bit. Sure, sometimes
my mind is still churning away on whatever I&amp;#8217;m working on, and I usually only break
for food at a logical stopping point. But it&amp;#8217;s still an important part of staying
focused through the day, and not hitting the end of the day feeling exhausted and&amp;nbsp;glassy-eyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5-disconnect"&gt;5.&amp;nbsp;Disconnect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On-call or similar exceptions aside, when they day&amp;#8217;s over, the day&amp;#8217;s over. Disconnect.
I have HipChat and various other communication tools on my phone if I absolutely have
to be reached after hours. But aside from that, when my work day is over, I close my
work browser session and switch to personal, close any editors/windows/etc. I have open,
and ensure all of my changes are committed and pushed. As much as I occasionally rue
the fact that my current job has almost everything on our private network, it means
I can disconnect my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VPN&lt;/span&gt; client and be unable to access anything work-related. I&amp;#8217;ll
admit that I usually leave my work-related &lt;code&gt;screen&lt;/code&gt; windows open overnight, just
for ease of picking back up, but I always close them over a weekend or&amp;nbsp;vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you&amp;#8217;re being paid for a 168-hour work week, you deserve to have some time
away from work. I&amp;#8217;ll admit I&amp;#8217;ve had some jobs where on-call was&amp;#8230; quite busy&amp;#8230;
but it doesn&amp;#8217;t take that long to connect and start up what you need, when needed.
You owe it to yourself: when you&amp;#8217;re done, make the work stuff disappear from your
field of view. If you spend much time at your computer outside of work, you need
to keep the two separate&amp;#8230; or else &amp;#8220;work time&amp;#8221; becomes &amp;#8220;awake&amp;nbsp;time.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6-end-of-day-routine"&gt;6. End-of-day&amp;nbsp;Routine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Develop a daily end-of-work routine or ritual. Do something to psychologically say
to yourself &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m done with work for today, I&amp;#8217;m switching gears to my personal life.&amp;#8221;
If your office is also your home, you miss out on the decompression and context switch
provided by a commute (even a short one). Put something in its place. This is
especially important if your after-work time, even occasionally, involves going back
to the same chair, keyboard and monitor(s) - whatever the&amp;nbsp;reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change your clothes, catch up with family, spend some time with your pets, watch a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;
show or read a book, cook dinner, go for a walk - whatever. Just do something to signal
to yourself that the work day is over, and you can leave all of those thoughts, anxieties,
problems, ideas and tasks until tomorrow. As much as you may intellectually know that
you&amp;#8217;re &amp;#8220;done&amp;#8221; for the day (even if your pager might go off), do something to &lt;em&gt;show&lt;/em&gt;
yourself, and tell your subconscious, that you&amp;#8217;re &amp;#8220;going&amp;nbsp;home.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7-get-outside"&gt;7. Get&amp;nbsp;Outside&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m an introvert, and have occasionally suffered from mild depression. Neither of those
is unusual in our industry; the former is just much more accepted and discussed
than the latter&amp;nbsp;(unfortunately).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can, &lt;strong&gt;get outside&lt;/strong&gt;. Even if it&amp;#8217;s just to run an errand, take a short walk,
or drive around the block, get out of the house. This is especially important if
you usually don&amp;#8217;t (but can), or if you&amp;#8217;re working long hours. At a previous job
we had an &amp;#8220;incident&amp;#8221; that resulted in the engineering team working round-the-clock
for the better part of two weeks; we ended up scheduling a 24x7 rotation, but until
that two-week-ish mark, we were all more-or-less working whenever we were awake.
It was awful for all of us - both our personal well-being and our productivity
and focus. Even just running to the store or to pick up dinner was an immense
relief from the wake-work-sleep-repeat&amp;nbsp;cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you&amp;#8217;re not working insane hours (and I certainly hope you&amp;#8217;re not), be aware
of how much time you&amp;#8217;re spending at home indoors. If you&amp;#8217;re not terribly social by
nature, make sure you get outside, and do it on a regular basis. Even if you don&amp;#8217;t
&lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to go somewhere, do it anyway for a change of scenery and a chance to clear
your&amp;nbsp;mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8-talk-about-burnout-and-frustrations"&gt;8. Talk About Burnout and&amp;nbsp;Frustrations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This goes for everyone, but more so for people who are remote full-time or for
long stretches, on a team that&amp;#8217;s at least partially in-office. It&amp;#8217;s really easy
to feel disconnected from what&amp;#8217;s happening, and it&amp;#8217;s also really difficult -
especially if you do most of your communication via text - for your manager and
co-workers to know when you&amp;#8217;re feeling stressed or overworked. Talk about&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burnout - even to the point of suicide - in technology has been talked about
more recently, including John Willis&amp;#8217;
&lt;a href="http://itrevolution.com/karojisatsu/"&gt;Karōjisatsu&lt;/a&gt;, Gene Kim&amp;#8217;s recent work,
and &lt;a href="https://victorops.com/blog/burnout-in-tech/"&gt;Jason Hand&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s certainly
something that our industry needs to be &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; more aware of, and something we
all need to work to fix, both personally and with our colleagues. If you&amp;#8217;re a
manager of remotes, make sure you check in with them often - not just on how
their work is going, but on how they&amp;#8217;re doing emotionally, especially related
to work. Find out what&amp;#8217;s frustrating them, what&amp;#8217;s draining their energy and
how their work-life balance is. If you&amp;#8217;re not a manager, check in with your
coworkers about the same things, and make sure someone knows how you&amp;#8217;re doing.
It might feel awkward when you&amp;#8217;re having a great time or starting a new job,
but it&amp;#8217;s a habit that&amp;#8217;s much easier to get into when things are going well
than when you really need&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="wfh"></category><category term="remote"></category><category term="work"></category><category term="balance"></category><category term="work from home"></category><category term="culture"></category></entry><entry><title>Terraform Shortcomings - No Interpolated Default Values, No Functions, No Conditionals, Local State Storage</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2016/04/terraform-shortcomings-no-interpolated-default-values-no-functions/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-04-19T07:40:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Jason Antman</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2016-04-19:2016/04/terraform-shortcomings-no-interpolated-default-values-no-functions/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;#8217;ve been using HashiCorp&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="https://www.terraform.io/"&gt;Terraform&lt;/a&gt; a lot to manage infrastructure. It certainly has some big things going for it; it supports a whole bunch of providers (including on-prem, non-cloud stuff like VMWare and Docker) as well as some database engines and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; providers and can even manage GitHub teams, it can plan changes before committing them (which CloudFormation only &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/new-change-sets-for-aws-cloudformation/"&gt;very recently&lt;/a&gt; learned), and it can store the current state of your infrastructure in &lt;a href="https://www.consul.io/"&gt;Consul&lt;/a&gt;. Also a big step past CloudFormation, it has &lt;a href="https://www.terraform.io/docs/provisioners/index.html"&gt;provisioners&lt;/a&gt; including local execution, remote execution, file copying and Chef (strangely no built-in support for Puppet, but the remote-exec can do that) that can reach out to your newly-created instances and take actions on&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terraform also has a &lt;a href="https://www.terraform.io/docs/providers/template/index.html"&gt;template provider&lt;/a&gt; that&amp;#8217;s used any time you need a templated file, such as &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EC2&lt;/span&gt; instance user-data or dynamically generated scripts to place on hosts. Terraform uses a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DSL&lt;/span&gt; for its &lt;a href="https://www.terraform.io/docs/configuration/index.html"&gt;configuration&lt;/a&gt;, either the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;-like but slightly-more-human-readable &lt;a href="https://github.com/hashicorp/hcl"&gt;Hashicorp Configuration Language (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HCL&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/a&gt; or the same information conveyed in pure &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;. The configuration language supports variables (passed in at the command line or in a file) and is based on &lt;a href="https://www.terraform.io/docs/configuration/interpolation.html"&gt;string interpolation&lt;/a&gt; with a handful of functions defined. It&amp;#8217;s also worth noting that Terraform is written in Go; it has a &lt;a href="https://www.terraform.io/docs/plugins/index.html"&gt;plugin system&lt;/a&gt; but only for Providers and Provisioners; there&amp;#8217;s no way to add core functionality (I suppose I&amp;#8217;ve been spolied by Puppet having such good support for adding core functionality via Ruby, or HashiCorp&amp;#8217;s Vagrant having a config file that itself is&amp;nbsp;Ruby).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;#8217;ve been nice and said some great things about Terraform (and it really is; at least for the way my current job is managing infrastructure, I&amp;#8217;ve fallen in love with it, and it certainly does fix some shortcomings that I found in CloudFormation, specifically with pre-execution plans and ability to interact with resources), on to my complaints of the&amp;nbsp;day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="local-state-storage"&gt;Local State&amp;nbsp;Storage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first complaint is that by default, Terraform stores the state of your infrastrucutre in a file in your current working directory. It uses this to attempt to figure out the already-existing resources you&amp;#8217;ve created, and only make the required changes. The first time I used terraform, I completely destroyed one of our (luckily non-production) services; coworkers of mine have brought down production services because of&amp;nbsp;this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s say that we have a Terraform configuration which takes one variable, &lt;code&gt;environment&lt;/code&gt;. That variable determines the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VPC&lt;/span&gt; and subnets we deploy into, our &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; names, and also gets passed to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EC2&lt;/span&gt; instances via user-data. We build our infrastructure with &lt;code&gt;environment = "prod"&lt;/code&gt;, and everything works right - we now have a production cluster of our service. Then we want to test some changes, so we run again with &lt;code&gt;environment = "dev"&lt;/code&gt;. The naive - and logical - assumption would be that we get a second &amp;#8220;dev&amp;#8221; cluster of our service. Nope. Terraform finds the &lt;code&gt;terraform.tfstate&lt;/code&gt; file in our current directory, reads it, and takes it to be the current state of our infrastructure. It sees that we &lt;strong&gt;changed&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;environment&lt;/code&gt; from &amp;#8220;prod&amp;#8221; to &amp;#8220;dev&amp;#8221;&amp;#8230; so it destroys our &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EC2&lt;/span&gt; instances and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; record, and creates new ones for &amp;#8220;dev&amp;#8221; (applying the requested&amp;nbsp;changes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This teaches us two important&amp;nbsp;points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always&lt;/strong&gt; run &lt;code&gt;terraform plan&lt;/code&gt;. Even if you think your changes are trivial, examine what Terraform will do before running &lt;code&gt;apply&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always&lt;/strong&gt; run &lt;code&gt;terraform&lt;/code&gt; through a wrapper. We have a simple Rake task in an internal rubygem that ensures that Terraform will always store state in Consul, so it won&amp;#8217;t be locked to one person&amp;#8217;s local machine, and also removes any local state files before running so they won&amp;#8217;t pollute the run or result in changes intended for one isolated instance of our Terraform configuration from being applied to&amp;nbsp;another.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id="functions"&gt;Functions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terraform&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="https://www.terraform.io/docs/configuration/interpolation.html"&gt;configuration interpolation&lt;/a&gt; has a bunch of built-in functions for working with variables. They&amp;#8217;re a subset of what you&amp;#8217;d expect in a language that is mainly based around strings, arrays and maps/hashes: split, join, concat, lookup (get a hash item by key), index (find the index of an item in a list), element (return the n&amp;#8217;th element of a list), format (sprintf-like), etc. However, there&amp;#8217;s no function to retrieve only unique elements from a list. This becomes a problem especially when dealing with multi-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AZ&lt;/span&gt;/multi-subnet &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AWS&lt;/span&gt; resources, as some of them (e.g. managing a set number individual &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EC2&lt;/span&gt; instances outside of an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ASG&lt;/span&gt;, such as when assigning static IPs) require a list of subnets matching the number of resources, and others (cross-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AZ&lt;/span&gt; ELBs) require a list of unique&amp;nbsp;subnets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terraform and its language have no way to add this functionality (&lt;em&gt;see note below&lt;/em&gt;); the only option that I&amp;#8217;ve found is to wrap Terraform in some sort of runner (I use &lt;a href="https://github.com/ruby/rake"&gt;Rake&lt;/a&gt; but you could use any scripting or Make-like language) that does whatever manipulation and calculation is needed, and passes in the necessary values distinct variable values (i.e. the full subnet list, and the unique subnet list, as separate variables). To make this even more difficult, though Terraform supports loading built-time variables from a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HCL&lt;/span&gt; file instead of the command line, it only supports taking in variables as strings (even in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;). So in our subnet example, our wrapper script needs to join the list of subnets into a string (i.e. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSV&lt;/span&gt;) and then whenever we use the variable in Terraform, we need to &lt;code&gt;split()&lt;/code&gt; it on our separator character (because Terraform doesn&amp;#8217;t support variable setting or&amp;nbsp;manipulation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;Terraform [has] no way to add this functionality&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt; - I&amp;#8217;m aware that I could fork Terraform, learn Go, and submit pull requests for all of the features I think would be useful; and if I had maybe half a dozen less unfinished projects, I&amp;#8217;d probably do that. However, this still means that HashiCorp would need to accept and merge my PRs and release a new version, or else I&amp;#8217;d need to build and distribute my forked version. Terraform supports &lt;a href="https://www.terraform.io/docs/plugins/index.html"&gt;plugins&lt;/a&gt;, but only for Providers and Provisioners, not language internals. What I&amp;#8217;d really like is a way to define plugin functions that could be distributed without having to rebuild all of&amp;nbsp;Terraform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="no-interpolated-default-variable-values"&gt;No Interpolated Default Variable&amp;nbsp;Values&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terraform variables can have default values defined for them. However, these default values have no way of using other variables. This means that even for relatively common use cases - like a service that has a name and a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; record, both of which can be overridden but with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; record defaulting to &amp;#8220;SERVICE_NAME.example.com&amp;#8221;, you can&amp;#8217;t do that. The only options that I&amp;#8217;ve been able to figure out are to either do it in your wrapper script (which means the Terraform configs can&amp;#8217;t be run without the wrapper) or use the &lt;code&gt;coalesce&lt;/code&gt; function to give your variable an empty default value, and then choose a second interpolated string if the variable is&amp;nbsp;empty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="no-conditionals"&gt;No&amp;nbsp;Conditionals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terraform&amp;#8217;s configuration language also lacks conditional statements such as &lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt;. This poses a problem with all but the simplest applications, and is certainly likely to be an issue for anyone who wants to do the right thing and use the same tooling to deploy multiple environments. It seems that the only options are to either pass in the necessary information as variables from a wrapper script, or generate Terraform configurations with other tooling. The former works only if the desired result is a variable in your configuration; there&amp;#8217;s simply no way that I&amp;#8217;ve found to have a conditional around resource(s). The only obvious option for that is to take advantage of Terraform&amp;#8217;s ability to read configurations as &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;, and simply generate your entire terraform configuration with another&amp;nbsp;tool.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="terraform"></category><category term="hashicorp"></category><category term="AWS"></category><category term="go"></category></entry><entry><title>A Rant on Post-Secondary Tech Education</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2015/10/a-rant-on-post-secondary-tech-education/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-10-05T16:46:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Jason Antman</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2015-10-05:2015/10/a-rant-on-post-secondary-tech-education/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Disclaimer: First, I know there&amp;#8217;s a wide range of curricula in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CS&lt;/span&gt;/tech education world,
and some schools are better than others; there are certainly programs that prepare students
much better than what I experienced. Second, these views are somewhat biased to my own
experience in the web, agile and DevOps worlds; for people who want to write Java for banks
their whole career, I&amp;#8217;m sure most schools prepare them&amp;nbsp;well.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been a decade since I&amp;#8217;ve been in the University system, but I&amp;#8217;ve seen precious little to
indicate that much has changed since then. I graduated with a degree in &lt;a href="https://comminfo.rutgers.edu/component/cur,547/option,com_courses/sch,04/task,listing/"&gt;Information Technology
and Informatics (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ITI&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;;
I switched majors partly because of my deep hatred for calculus, and partly
because I was already working for Rutgers University as a student systems programmer, and it
was painfully obvious how little the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CS&lt;/span&gt; program would do to prepare me for a career. My time
in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CS&lt;/span&gt; was spent writing pitifully small Java applications in teams as large as &lt;strong&gt;three&lt;/strong&gt; (any
team work was highly unusual) and playing with linked lists. I switched to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ITI&lt;/span&gt; so I could take
classes on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; management and policy, information security and &amp;#8220;web application development&amp;#8221; (with
databases and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;!) Since then, I&amp;#8217;ve had two family members enter &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CS&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ECE&lt;/span&gt; programs, and I
tried to give them the best advice I could. I happened to be thinking about it, and figured
I&amp;#8217;d write down some of my&amp;nbsp;thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, I understand that technology changes very quickly - a lot quicker than
college syllabi. However, my alma mater&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="https://www.cs.rutgers.edu/undergraduate/courses/"&gt;undergrad course list&lt;/a&gt;
does not appear to have changed &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt; since I took some of those classes a decade ago.
Don&amp;#8217;t get me wrong, it&amp;#8217;s very good that we&amp;#8217;re teaching classes in Operating Systems Design
and Compilers. But current curricula seem to focus almost exclusively on fundamentals
and low-level details. When I was in college, almost all the classes were taught in Java,
and that already seemed dated and ignoring the &amp;#8220;Web 2.0&amp;#8221; world; these days, it relegates
most graduates to jobs that I&amp;#8217;d consider boring, in the Enterprise sector. Rutgers&amp;#8217; undergrad
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CS&lt;/span&gt; catalog doesn&amp;#8217;t list &amp;#8220;Internet Technology&amp;#8221; until &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CS&lt;/span&gt; 352, and I&amp;#8217;d be surprised if any
networking (aside from maybe &amp;#8220;use raw sockets to do something&amp;#8221;) is covered before that class,
which is tentatively designed for third-year students. Very few of the courses that I see
listed (and many that I looked at haven&amp;#8217;t changed their description, or even their instructor,
in ten years) do much to prepare students for the actual tech industry. Even worse, most
of them are the same classes that I found boring, and caused me to switch&amp;nbsp;majors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, I can understand the argument that tech moves too fast for class materials
to keep pace. But introducing the Internet as a third-year topic, and Distributed
Systems as a senior-level class? Writing &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; in Java? This seemed silly
to me a decade ago; now, it seems downright wrong for a department that claims to
prepare students for careers in technology. Once again, I agree that a strong grasp
of fundamentals is overwhelmingly important. However, a balance needs to be struck
between this and (1) providing students with useful, current skills, and (2) keeping
students interested. In a world where more and more (and in many areas, such as my own
subculture, almost all) software runs in the browser, how can education ignore&amp;nbsp;this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll take a small moment to dovetail this to a heated topic in tech at the moment:
hiring practices and diversity. The tech education at most universities does little
to prepare students for actual jobs outside of, quite literally, &amp;#8220;entry-level Java
programmer&amp;#8221;. The people who will get good, interesting jobs in tech (yes, that&amp;#8217;s quite
opinionated; I&amp;#8217;m defining that as jobs with web or DevOps shops) are the ones who
either have ample free time and pre-existing interest to hack on their own projects,
and/or are insomniacs and can handle going to class, working, and still writing
a lot of code and experimenting on their own. I suppose this ends up being biased
towards stereotypical white males, even if only because it seems socially acceptable
for us to ignore having a social life in favor of finishing those last lines of&amp;nbsp;code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I digress. There are few other industries that I can think of - and certainly
no professions - where someone leaves the University system with the highest
degree commonly attained in their field, yet has virtually zero real world
hands-on experience. I&amp;#8217;ll leave out the doctor or lawyer analogies, but some
of our closest parallels - engineers, architects, etc. - graduate and are able
to start practicing their profession. Sure, there&amp;#8217;s organization- or domain-specific
on the job training, but for the most part, they can do what they were hired to do.
On the other hand, tech-focused programs are turning out graduates many of whom
have never seen the tools (or even languages) that we use. They don&amp;#8217;t have
any real experience working in teams larger than three or four (at the best),
and have no concept of what goes into developing real software, working in
a large (or distributed) team, or what happens to software after someone
grades it (which in my experience, was usually as simple as &amp;#8220;does this program
produce the right output when it&amp;#8217;s run at the command&amp;nbsp;line).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, that&amp;#8217;s my rant. What do I think should be covered in tech/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CS&lt;/span&gt; curricula that isn&amp;#8217;t?
Here are a&amp;nbsp;few:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testing&lt;/strong&gt; - I have painful memories of being marked as failing assignments because
I used a tab when the instructors expected some number of spaces in the output of my
program. In most cases, my instructors used a test harness that exec&amp;#8217;ed our Java applications
and inspected the string output. I still have no idea why they didn&amp;#8217;t use JUnit. But that&amp;#8217;s
beyond the point; we&amp;#8217;re turning out programmers who don&amp;#8217;t know what unit or integration tests
are. I still don&amp;#8217;t understand how I got through a four-year degree, partially in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CS&lt;/span&gt; and
partially in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt;, without writing a single test for any program I wrote (aside from a few
courses where we wrote &amp;#8220;test harnesses&amp;#8221;, but never used a proper testing&amp;nbsp;framework).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software Distribution&lt;/strong&gt; - Here&amp;#8217;s another no-brainer. Why - especially when working in
Java - would students email completed assignments to professors, or upload them to online
courseware, when so many artifact repositories exist? If people can&amp;#8217;t use your software it&amp;#8217;s
pretty pointless. Distribution should be a part of at least some assignments, whether it&amp;#8217;s
an open source model or just uploading an artifact to an internal maven&amp;nbsp;repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintenance&lt;/strong&gt; - Ok, sure, this is the part that none of us really like. But it&amp;#8217;s also
an inherent part of what we do, and the odds are most entry-level programmers will first
find themselves fixing bugs or adding features to someone else&amp;#8217;s application. Being able
to read and understand existing code is perhaps the most important thing we do, whether it&amp;#8217;s
to fix it or just to learn from it. Nobody I&amp;#8217;ve talked to about education as a programmer
has ever encountered an assignment of &amp;#8220;here&amp;#8217;s an application, here&amp;#8217;s a bug report, find and
fix it&amp;#8221; beyond the most trivial contrived examples. The process of fixing a bug in or adding
a feature to an existing codebase is probably one of the most important lessons in learning
to write code - even if it&amp;#8217;s partially a lesson in what not to&amp;nbsp;do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distributed Projects&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#8220;big&amp;#8221; project in my time as a student was pairing on a Java
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt;/backend program. Perhaps I didn&amp;#8217;t have the best experience, as my partner neglected to write
any code. However, few people are going to enter the workforce and be the sole person touching
a given codebase. I think there should be much more emphasis on working as part of a realistically-sized
team. Sure, the tooling might not be the same, but at least graduates should have some experience
in collaborating with others, and more importantly, in working on code where they don&amp;#8217;t necessarily
understand all of it. If we&amp;#8217;re going to teach Java, we should at least be teaching it realistically
and throwing in some black-box classes or having students code to each others&amp;#8217; (not-yet-complete)&amp;nbsp;APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web-First&lt;/strong&gt; - With the plummeting cost of cloud computing and containers, and the massive
compute farms available at most universities, there&amp;#8217;s really no excuse for completely ignoring
the Internet. Sure, it doesn&amp;#8217;t play much of a role in the low-level basics, but for the classic
&amp;#8220;hello world&amp;#8221;, calculator app, tic-tack-toe, etc. it&amp;#8217;s not really that much overhead to do
them in &lt;a href="http://spring.io/guides/gs/rest-service/"&gt;Spring&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://flask.pocoo.org/"&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href="http://guides.rubyonrails.org/getting_started.html"&gt;Rails&lt;/a&gt; and also give students exposure
to a modern, web-centric framework that someone might actually use to write a simple application.
Most programmers are probably going to touch the web at some point. I&amp;#8217;d argue that it&amp;#8217;s also a
lot more applicable for people who aren&amp;#8217;t going into a distinctly programming&amp;nbsp;role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operable Software&lt;/strong&gt; - Going with the web-first paradigm, we have the virtualization or
container technology to give students a shell and a running web server. Why not show them
how to use it? I once failed a major assignment because the graders used a script that combined
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;STDOUT&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;STDERR&lt;/span&gt; and evaluated it. They asked me what all these weird lines in my output
were; I told them it was log4j. They asked what that was. Even the classes I took that
included working in teams or something else somewhat realistic, completely ignored the
operations side of software, as far as never discussing logging. If we want the quality
of software that we (as an industry) turn out to increase, one of the best things we can
do is introduce programmers to logging, testing, debugging and the operations side as early
as possible, even if in a quick, superficial way. If students had to actually &lt;em&gt;run&lt;/em&gt; their
app, and let it serve actual requests, they&amp;#8217;d have a lot clearer picture of what software
actually does after the build a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JAR&lt;/span&gt;. Related to this, an introduction to the concepts
of security and stability would be quite&amp;nbsp;useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re currently going to school for something programming-related, here are a few
things that I&amp;#8217;d recommend doing to get ahead of the&amp;nbsp;pack:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn some languages. Look through job ads for the type of entry-level/graduate work you
hope to get when you graduate, and see what they&amp;#8217;re asking for. If your school is still the
way mine appears to be, in a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CS&lt;/span&gt; program you&amp;#8217;ll probably be exposed to Java and C. Learn some
Ruby or Python, or something else that&amp;#8217;s in use on the web. It certainly won&amp;#8217;t hurt you, and
it&amp;#8217;ll also be less intimidating to learn a new language once you already know a few, preferably
that are rather&amp;nbsp;different.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to work in the web world and are a Windows person, learn Linux. Despite what
some people tell you, it&amp;#8217;s the rule not the&amp;nbsp;exception.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read. I understand that not everyone has extensive time to experiment on their own, and I know
a lot of people who didn&amp;#8217;t, especially in college. Read. A lot. It seems that most tech programs
require a lot less work than other engineering disciplines; I remember how envious my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ECE&lt;/span&gt; and Mech-E
friends were at the &amp;#8220;low&amp;#8221; amount of work we &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CS&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; majors had to do. Read everything you can, especially
about the industry you want to work in (if you have an idea of what it is). Find out what tools they&amp;#8217;re
using from job ads or company tech blogs, and find out about them. Even if you can&amp;#8217;t use them
yourself, at least knowing a bit about them will help a&amp;nbsp;lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you can, find an open source project or two to work on. This one comes with a bit of a warning;
the open source world can be quite abrasive, and sometimes downright hurtful. Unfortunately, technology
as a whole seems to attract a lot of very loud, angry, bad people. So do some research; try to find
a project that you&amp;#8217;re interested in and that you have some relevant experience for. But most importantly,
find a project that&amp;#8217;s clearly open to mentoring new contributors; they&amp;#8217;re unfortunately few and
far between, but it will really pay&amp;nbsp;off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="college"></category><category term="computer science"></category><category term="CS"></category><category term="technology"></category><category term="education"></category></entry><entry><title>NSA Targeting SysAdmins</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2014/03/nsa-targeting-sysadmins/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-22T09:38:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Jason Antman</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2014-03-22:2014/03/nsa-targeting-sysadmins/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I try not to rant too much, but I feel that this one was needed. If you&amp;#8217;re looking for
objective, technical information, skip this&amp;nbsp;one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was younger and more naive, I had near complete trust in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; government. There&amp;#8217;s a Constitution,
and they abide by it, and so do I. Since 2001, that feeling has eroded a bit. Since 2008, it&amp;#8217;s eroded even
more. But the documents leaked by &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Snowden"&gt;Edward Snowden&lt;/a&gt; have been
the &amp;#8216;icing on the cake&amp;#8217;. I know there&amp;#8217;s disagreement about whether what he did was right or not - I&amp;#8217;m pretty
decided on how I feel, but I know many others who feel that he should be taken out and shot - but one thing
that&amp;#8217;s no longer deniable is, since he released those documents, it&amp;#8217;s come to light that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; government
is routinely performing unconstitutional acts in the furtherance of &amp;#8220;national&amp;nbsp;security.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like many people, who said over and over again that it could never get to this point, that the
Government might cut some corners but they&amp;#8217;d never blatantly do things like &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/agencies-collected-data-on-americans-cellphone-use-in-thousands-of-tower-dumps/2013/12/08/20549190-5e80-11e3-be07-006c776266ed_story.html"&gt;mass collection of cellular data&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/nsa-tracking-cellphone-locations-worldwide-snowden-documents-show/2013/12/04/5492873a-5cf2-11e3-bc56-c6ca94801fac_story.html"&gt;tracking the physical location of cell phones worldwide&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/nsa-infiltrates-links-to-yahoo-google-data-centers-worldwide-snowden-documents-say/2013/10/30/e51d661e-4166-11e3-8b74-d89d714ca4dd_story.html"&gt;tapping into the networks of private companies like Google and Yahoo&lt;/a&gt;. It seems that
every new document leaked is worse than the last. I refuse to accept the arguments that this is all &amp;#8220;legal&amp;#8221;,
they simply don&amp;#8217;t keep up with the times. I couldn&amp;#8217;t care less if the government reads my postal mail (which
they still need an actual warrant for, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AFAIK&lt;/span&gt;) - they probably get the same credit card and siding offers anyway.
I do, however, care that the government - out of their own self-interest and excitement at near-effortless surveillance -
refuses to extend the same protections that wireline phone calls and postal mail get to their electronic and
wireless&amp;nbsp;equivalents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came to light that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/12/20/us-usa-security-rsa-idUSBRE9BJ1C220131220"&gt;paid $10M to put a backdoor in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSA&lt;/span&gt; encryption&lt;/a&gt;
I was astonished. Late last year a number of other deals came to light, where the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt; paid or extorted software
and hardware manufacturers to intentionally introduce flaws in security to make it easier for the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt;
to gain access. The worst part is these weren&amp;#8217;t &amp;#8220;master passwords&amp;#8221; available only to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt;; for the most
part, they appear to be mathematical flaws known to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt;, but just as easily discovered by our enemies.
This part seems to have been glossed over by the media&amp;#8230; the consequences of some mathematician
or security researcher discovering those flaws and selling them to a national enemy or terrorist
would be flat-out devastating to the country and economy. Our government deliberately put a flaw in
an encryption standard, and then used its&amp;#8217; influence via &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NIST&lt;/span&gt;, the National Institute of Standards
and Technology, to &lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/security/2013/09/the-nsas-work-to-make-crypto-worse-and-better/"&gt;recommend that standard for use&lt;/a&gt;
including by banks, e-commerce sites and financial&amp;nbsp;institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What has me even more upset, though, is the recent revelation that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt; is &lt;a href="https://firstlook.org/theintercept/article/2014/03/20/inside-nsa-secret-efforts-hunt-hack-system-administrators/"&gt;systematically targeting
the private, personal accounts of system administrators to gain access to their employers&amp;#8217; networks&lt;/a&gt;. The bulk of the information came from an internal classified blog entry of an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt; employee,
&lt;a href="https://s3.amazonaws.com/s3.documentcloud.org/documents/1094387/i-hunt-sys-admins.pdf"&gt;available as a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
(or &lt;a href="/GFX/i-hunt-sys-admins.pdf"&gt;local copy&lt;/a&gt;). It&amp;#8217;s pretty technical, but it&amp;#8217;s also a startling view into
both the mindsets of &lt;em&gt;individuals&lt;/em&gt; within the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt;, and the organization&amp;#8217;s overall goals. Just two of the many
worthy&amp;nbsp;excerpts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(S/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SI&lt;/span&gt;//&lt;span class="caps"&gt;REL&lt;/span&gt;) One of the coolest things about it is &lt;strong&gt;how much&lt;/strong&gt; data we have at our fingertips. If we
&lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; collected the data we knew we wanted&amp;#8230; yeah, we&amp;#8217;d fill some of our requirements, but it is
a whole world of possibilities we&amp;#8217;d be missing! It would be like going on a road-trip, but wearing a
blindfold the entire time, and only removing it when you&amp;#8217;re at one of your destinations&amp;#8230; yeah,
you&amp;#8217;ll still see stuff, but you&amp;#8217;ll be missing out on the entire&amp;nbsp;journey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So&amp;#8230; ok, they&amp;#8217;re admitting that they collect more data than they want (or legally can?). This person&amp;#8217;s
blog series is about &amp;#8220;using passive collect to identify/enable &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNE&lt;/span&gt; efforts&amp;#8221; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNE&lt;/span&gt; being Computer Network
Exploitation), which is also implying that they have access to massive amounts of data from non-target
persons, including American&amp;nbsp;citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the document, multiple references are made to the &lt;a href="https://firstlook.org/theintercept/article/2014/03/12/nsa-plans-infect-millions-computers-malware/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;QUANTUM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
program which seems to be viewed as, in short, a tool that lets the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt; input someone&amp;#8217;s Facebook,
webmail, or other online service account, and take control of the computers they use to access&amp;nbsp;it&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, for people in my line of work, the more troubling&amp;nbsp;part:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, fade off with me into dream-land. Pretend that we had some master list. This master list
contained tons of networks around the world, and the personal accounts of admins of each of
those networks. And any time you wanted to target a new network, you could just find the admin
associated with it, queue his accounts up for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;QUANTUM&lt;/span&gt;, get access to his box and proceed to pwn
the network. Wouldn&amp;#8217;t that be&amp;nbsp;swell?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(S/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SI&lt;/span&gt;//&lt;span class="caps"&gt;REL&lt;/span&gt;) Well, you can stop dreaming my friends, I think it&amp;#8217;s possible (at least kinda&amp;nbsp;partially).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So&amp;#8230; we&amp;#8217;re talking about deliberately targeting the personal accounts of innocent third parties,
in order to compromise their credentials to also innocent networks, in order to eventually
gain access to the information of a target. This seems so horribly illegal I can barely
explain. It&amp;#8217;s also a direct affront to the people in my industry who have an ethical obligation
to protect the data of their employers, customers and users against illegal disclosure. And,
maybe even more troubling, it&amp;#8217;s being perpetrated by other people &amp;#8220;in our industry&amp;#8221;, other
technical people, who obviously have a very clear picture of exactly what they&amp;#8217;re&amp;nbsp;doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first thought was to make an analogy between our resposibility as those &amp;#8220;with the keys to
the kingdom&amp;#8221; to a more legally entrenched privacy, like that between a doctor and their patient,
or between a lawyer and their client, that would be much more obviously illegal for the government
to breach. But, apparently that&amp;#8217;s an all-too-correct analogy, since it came to light last month
that the &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/16/us/eavesdropping-ensnared-american-law-firm.html"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt; was intercepting privileged lawyer-client communications through the use of a
foreign intermediary, namely Australia&lt;/a&gt;.
Given the intelligence allicances between the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt; and Australia, and the scope of what
has been already disclosed, I find it entirely probable that in all of these leaked documents
that discuss doing this to &amp;#8220;foreign&amp;#8221; entities only, the reality is that to do the same to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;
citizens, it&amp;#8217;s as simple as logging in to the Australian or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt; equivalent&amp;nbsp;system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is truly disturbing to me. I continue to feel that (1) if the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt; had provable cause to
collect this information, they&amp;#8217;d obtain a warrant like the Constitution says they have to,
and (2) their electronic data collection is the equivalent of wiretapping every phone in the
country and hoping for something useful - which has been continually held to be unconstitutional,
but because of the nature (already digital) of electronic communications, it&amp;#8217;s actually feasible
to&amp;nbsp;do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a related note, a while ago I enabled &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time-based_One-time_Password_Algorithm"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;TOTP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;-based
two factor authentication on a number of my accounts (Google, GitHub, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AWS&lt;/span&gt;, etc.) to try
and keep them more secure against the possibility of a password compromise. Yes, that still works
to keep an unscrupulous person out of them. However, if &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-switch/wp/2013/08/24/loveint-when-nsa-officers-use-their-spying-power-on-love-interests/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt; officials use classified systems to
spy on love interests&lt;/a&gt;,
it&amp;#8217;s entirely possible that an unscrupulous &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt; employee (or even worse, someone who manages to
compromise the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s systems? Though I imagine they only use in-house-developed security for now-obvious reasons)
could decide to compromise an individual&amp;#8217;s accounts for personal gain. Given all this news, I
find it highly unlikely that such an event would ever be reported to the proper oversight authorities,
let alone become public knowledge or known to the&amp;nbsp;victim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if we look at some of the information about what the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt; is doing, like their
&lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/threatlevel/2012/03/ff_nsadatacenter/all/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s Utah Data Center&lt;/a&gt;
and their plans for an &lt;a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2014/01/03/snowden_docs_show_nsa_building_encryptioncracking_quantum_system/"&gt;encryption-cracking quantum computer&lt;/a&gt;,
and assume that they probably have a datacenter full of FPGAs, it&amp;#8217;s entirely conceivable
that they can calculate this faster than most people think possible. On the other hand,
if they have passive taps on backbone providers, it&amp;#8217;s also possible they can just hijack
a session with the click of a&amp;nbsp;mouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t want to sound like too much of a nut. I&amp;#8217;ve never been terribly concerned about the
government snooping on my data because, well, I&amp;#8217;m not doing anything illegal. And aside from
my stance in favor of tighter controls and more electronic freedom, I&amp;#8217;m not in many groups
that I think would be targeted. However, I do feel very strongly about what&amp;#8217;s going on in general
(we already &lt;a href="http://www.marquette.edu/library/archives/Mss/JRM/JRM-main.shtml"&gt;learned&lt;/a&gt; that
government records on individuals&amp;#8217; activities can be horribly misused). Even more so, I&amp;#8217;m
deeply disturbed that &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; personal data and accounts could be compromised simply as a way
for a government employee to gain access to my employer&amp;#8217;s computer systems, and then to
those of our employees and&amp;nbsp;customers.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="nsa"></category><category term="government"></category><category term="privacy"></category><category term="security"></category></entry><entry><title>SOPA Blackouts</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/01/sopa-blackouts/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-01-24T20:29:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-01-24:2012/01/sopa-blackouts/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, good news about &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SOPA&lt;/span&gt;. All of my sites participated in the &lt;a href="http://sopastrike.com/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SOPA&lt;/span&gt;
Strike&lt;/a&gt;. While I didn&amp;#8217;t fully black everything
out (I guess I wasn&amp;#8217;t keeping up enough on what others were doing&amp;#8230;), I
displayed a full-screen popover with a message (I have a version of my
homepage with the popover enabled
&lt;a href="http://www.jasonantman.com/sopa.php"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). I actually spent a few
hours trying to come up with a safe, effective, cross-browser way to do
it with one line of javascript put in all of my pages (everything from
static &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; to &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/"&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://www.redmine.org/"&gt;redmine&lt;/a&gt;), but ended up giving up and
including a few javascript files and a stylesheet too. At some point,
I&amp;#8217;ll try and post the info on how I did&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I just wanted to share a &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; cool &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SOPA&lt;/span&gt; protest blackout
page that I saw:
&lt;a href="http://www.zachstronaut.com/lab/text-shadow-box/stop-sopa.html"&gt;http://www.zachstronaut.com/lab/text-shadow-box/stop-sopa.html&lt;/a&gt;,
by Zachary Johnson. Of course, apparently, I&amp;#8217;m not the only person who
saw&amp;nbsp;it&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="blackout"></category><category term="censorship"></category><category term="SOPA"></category></entry><entry><title>How to make software distribution secure</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/09/how-to-make-software-distribution-secure/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-09-17T12:42:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-09-17:2010/09/how-to-make-software-distribution-secure/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We were seeing some strange behavior with Mac client machines on the
network lately, specifically with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; queries (I&amp;#8217;d guess that a lot of
it has to do with
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bonjour_(software)"&gt;Bonjour&lt;/a&gt;), but the
discussion touched on the &lt;a href="http://isc.sans.edu/diary.html?storyid=3595"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt;
Changer&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.dnschanger.com/"&gt;trojan&lt;/a&gt; for Mac. I&amp;#8217;d really never heard
about it before, and after some basic reading, it really got me thinking
about the state of software packaging, updates, and distribution.
Granted, some of my observations would require sweeping changes to how
packaging is handled (even on the *nixes), and would require buy-in
from more than just the vendor and distributor (well, I guess &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt; can
probably pressure ISVs to do whatever they want), but seems to be the
only way to keep appliancization from becoming the solution to security
issues. I&amp;#8217;ve written about this
&lt;a href="/2009/12/book-comments-the-future-of-the-internet-and-how-to-stop-it-by-jonathan-zittrain/"&gt;before&lt;/a&gt;,
and a while ago in respect to
&lt;a href="/2008/10/my-biggest-problem-with-linux/"&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt;, but here&amp;#8217;s my current
take on what needs to be done to software packaging to allow our
machines to stay secure, no matter what &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; they&amp;nbsp;run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allow packages to be installed as a user.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a mammoth task
    under Windows or Mac, but still an issue under Linux. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt;
    Changer trojan is a case in point - there&amp;#8217;s no reason a &amp;#8220;video
    codec&amp;#8221; would need to be installed system-wide, and if that were
    simply installed user-specific, the malicious installer would never
    have the privileges to change system-wide &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; settings. This is also
    a big issue under Linux. Yum, apt, rpm, etc. should (if run as a
    non-root user) install packages in a user-local path under &lt;code&gt;/home&lt;/code&gt;
    by default. Of course, this would mean many things would need to
    change in order to cope - perhaps even a change to the
    &lt;a href="http://www.linuxfoundation.org/collaborate/workgroups/lsb"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LSB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;spec.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warn about inconsistencies on package installation.&lt;/strong&gt; The package
    installation program should warn a user (whether installing packages
    system-wide or local to a user) if the package is going to modify
    system-wide files, i.e. files not specifically placed by that
    package and that package&amp;nbsp;only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real package management for Windows and Mac&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;#8217;s about time that
    Apple and Microsoft admit that people without billions in funding
    can come up with good ideas. Get rid of these Installer programs
    (the many many different ones). Each &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; should pick a package
    format, develop a yum-like (or, even better, zypper-like) package
    management program that understands repositories. I don&amp;#8217;t know how
    they&amp;#8217;d cope with the pervasive license keys and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DRM&lt;/span&gt; in the non-nix
    world, but I&amp;#8217;m sure they could figure out a way that still allowed
    sane package management. The idea here is that vendors run
    repositories and are responsible for their &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPG&lt;/span&gt; keys, so trojans
    claiming to be an update to a given vendor&amp;#8217;s software would be
    rejected. Also, isn&amp;#8217;t it about time that you can update all your
    software on Windows or Mac through one&amp;nbsp;tool?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filesystem-based &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IDS&lt;/span&gt; for Windows and Mac&lt;/strong&gt; Assuming it will take a
    while to get everyone onboard with the packaging idea, and noting
    that users of these OSes like installing applications from arbitrary
    sources, there should be an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;-level feature to audit all filesystem
    changes made by untrusted/unsigned applications, and a way to alert
    the user to these changes if they appear suspisious (essentially
    what &lt;a href="http://www.safer-networking.org"&gt;Spybot Search &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Destroy /
    TeaTimer&lt;/a&gt; do, but builtin to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vendor support of packaging/repositories&lt;/strong&gt; - Along with the idea
    of repositories, vendors should have a trust or signing system for
    ISVs signing keys. If users are installing arbitrary software,
    making them trust an arbitrary key won&amp;#8217;t do anything to improve
    security. Microsoft and Apple need to run a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt; that signs the
    package signing keys of their ISVs. The also - and here&amp;#8217;s the big
    one - need to have a parallel framework for &amp;#8220;independent
    developers&amp;#8221;. I.e. something that doesn&amp;#8217;t cost any money for the
    packagers, and allows them to at least give a &amp;#8220;this person is who
    they say they are&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;Make package management pervasive&lt;/strong&gt; - Have a real push to
    apply the packaging and signing keys standard to all software for
    the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a final note, applicable to both the current state of Linux packaging
and my ideas about Mac and Windows&amp;#8230; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; is the ideal method of key
distribution (granted, yes, this just means that the security of the
packager&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; records, and their servers and signing key, is just more
of an issue). But even with Yum and Zypper, it seems to me to be logical
that the packager&amp;#8217;s public key should be stored in a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; record (or at a
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; stored in a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TXT&lt;/span&gt; record). That way, it wouldn&amp;#8217;t be up to an end
user to import and trust a key, they&amp;#8217;d just have to trust the repository
(i.e. software.adobe.com) and the package manager would pull down the
key and verify that package X in software.adobe.com is, in fact, signed
by the software.adobe.com&amp;nbsp;key.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="linux"></category><category term="mac"></category><category term="packaging"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="software"></category><category term="windows"></category></entry><entry><title>PC vs Mac</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/08/pc-vs-mac/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-08-15T16:25:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-08-15:2010/08/pc-vs-mac/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Begin shameless&amp;nbsp;rant&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I read the &amp;#8220;system requirements&amp;#8221; for hardware these days, and see
&amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt; or Mac&amp;#8221;, I cringe. Surely someone who&amp;#8217;s developing the hardware
should understand the horrible inaccuracy of&amp;nbsp;this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221;, or Personal Computer, is used to refer to any hardware
that is (at this point, a derivative of) an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IBM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt; architecture clone.
This generally means Intel x86 (compatible)&amp;nbsp;systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2005, Apple discontinued their PowerPC systems and made the move to
Intel-based computers. Since 2005, all Apple (Mac, iMac, MacBook, etc.)
computers have been&amp;nbsp;PCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt; refers just to the hardware, not the operating system. An
Intel-based computer running Linux is a&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you mean &amp;#8220;Requires Microsoft Windows or Mac&amp;#8221;, say that. I don&amp;#8217;t know
whether it&amp;#8217;s more disturbing to see this on the box of a piece of (I
assume, engineered) hardware or in a tutorial or how-to supposedly
written by someone who knows something about&amp;nbsp;technology.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="mac"></category><category term="pc"></category><category term="windows"></category></entry><entry><title>Hiring Technical People</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/03/hiring-technical-people/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-07T10:48:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-03-07:2010/03/hiring-technical-people/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After seeing a link to it on the &lt;a href="http://www.sage.org"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SAGE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; mailing
list, I happened to read Mark Dennehy&amp;#8217;sblog post on &lt;a href="http://www.stochasticgeometry.ie/2008/04/25/tips-for-hiring-new-engineers/"&gt;Tips for hiring new
engineers&lt;/a&gt;.
I felt the need to make a few comments on some of his findings. Perhaps
someone in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt;, or a recruiter, will actually read this and learn a thing
or&amp;nbsp;two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basics of professional work – getting along with others, being
able to manage your time, being able to communicate clearly and well,
being able to work to deadlines – it is a waste of your time and mine
to put these in the job advert. You aren’t taking random people off
the street here – you’re hiring trained professionals who’ve working
in this field for some time. It’s nearly insulting to tell them not to
apply unless they play well with&amp;nbsp;others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there are some places where this is required. In the
public sector, at least, the job ad and description set up fixed
guidelines. If you have a job description that doesn&amp;#8217;t include &amp;#8220;plays
well with others&amp;#8221;, and the hire doesn&amp;#8217;t play well with others, it&amp;#8217;s
immensely difficult to fire them - the hire&amp;#8217;s failing wasn&amp;#8217;t listed in
the job&amp;nbsp;description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t have the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt; people write the technical requirements. You have
engineers, use&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to whole-heartedly agree with what Mark said about writing
technical requirements. I don&amp;#8217;t know why &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt; seems to think that they can
write &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; job descriptions - they wouldn&amp;#8217;t attempt it for most other
professionals. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; job descriptions should be left to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; people to write
- and, more importantly, people who actually understand what the person
will be&amp;nbsp;doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don’t class all those requirements as being absolutely necessary.
Have two lists – critical, mandatory skills; and skills which would be
advantageous to have. Because many professional engineers will look at
the mandatory skills listed and if we see some we don’t have, we won’t&amp;nbsp;apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also a very good point. Even when I&amp;#8217;m not actively looking for work, I
usually get a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of phone calls and emails from recruiters.
Especially if I update my resume on one of the big job sites or post a
consulting ad on CraigsList, I get inundated with emails and phone calls
(which I usually refer to email, unless they&amp;#8217;re from a big player). I
can&amp;#8217;t possibly spend the hours to read and apply to all of them. The
first ones that get deleted are from people who obvously didn&amp;#8217;t even
look at my resume - entry-level (operator) positions, Windows admins,
anything with a primary duty that isn&amp;#8217;t even near my skill set (i.e.
they just used keyword matching and never read&amp;nbsp;anything).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, I start looking through the descriptions and building two
lists - the ones that will likely get thrown out unless there&amp;#8217;s some
amazing thing that redeems them (i.e. a company that I really want to
work for) and the ones that I know I&amp;#8217;ll follow up on. Here are some of
the criteria I&amp;nbsp;use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Likely to&amp;nbsp;ignore:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read the job description and still can&amp;#8217;t figure out what I&amp;#8217;d be&amp;nbsp;doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The buzzword-to-content ratio is&amp;nbsp;horrible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The skills/requirements section lists every hot technology - a list
    that no human being can&amp;nbsp;master.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The skills/requirements section has far too disparate of a list -
    something that only an engineer, administrator, programmer, and
    hardware designer could&amp;nbsp;master.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow-up:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use of the &lt;a href="http://www.sage.org/field/jobs-descriptions.html"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SAGE&lt;/span&gt; Job
    Descriptions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An actual salary range, not &amp;#8220;varies with experience&amp;#8221; or&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;competitive&amp;#8221;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some description of &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;#8217;ll work - size of the team,
    responsibility, work environment,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examples of current things the team is working on, or examples of
    what I&amp;#8217;d be working&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skills/requirements broken down into mandatory and&amp;nbsp;optional/preferred.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A description that was obviously written by someone who understands
    the&amp;nbsp;technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In closing, I have a theory for companies (especially those in the
public sector that have stringent &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt;/hiring policies) listing jobs in
the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; sector: have both &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; write portions of the job
description. Have &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt; write a paragraph or two with all of their
non-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt;-specific stuff, and then have the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; hiring people (preferably
the manager the new hire will report to) write the rest. Put the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt;
stuff at the bottom. Break the skills/requirements lists down into
&amp;#8220;Technical Skills&amp;#8221; (further divided into Required and
Preferred/Optional/Bonus) and a &amp;#8220;Soft Skills&amp;#8221; section for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt; (with the
usual crap like &amp;#8220;works with a team&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;eligible for employment&amp;#8221;,&amp;nbsp;etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone&amp;#8217;s up in arms about the recession, high unemployment, and low
job openings. Logic would dictate that it&amp;#8217;s an employer&amp;#8217;s market - and,
to a large extent, it is. However, that doesn&amp;#8217;t mean that employers
don&amp;#8217;t need to worry about making the advertisement attractive and
descriptive. Actually, I&amp;#8217;d say it&amp;#8217;s the opposite - since I know that
there will likely be hundreds of other applicants, I only send a resume
in for jobs that I think I have a very good chance of getting. I&amp;#8217;m sure
I&amp;#8217;ve skipped over good positions just because the description didn&amp;#8217;t
communicate that to me - and I&amp;#8217;m sure I&amp;#8217;m not&amp;nbsp;alone.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="hiring"></category><category term="hr"></category><category term="jobs"></category></entry><entry><title>Slashdot - A Public Funded “Microsoft Shop?”</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/03/slashdot-a-public-funded-microsoft-shop/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-04T21:27:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-03-04:2010/03/slashdot-a-public-funded-microsoft-shop/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just came by an interesting post on Slashdot, &lt;a href="http://science.slashdot.org/story/10/03/04/1416226/A-Public-Funded-Microsoft-Shop"&gt;A Public Funded
&amp;#8220;Microsoft
Shop?&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;.
The author works at a publicly-funded hospital and comments that he
received an email from management&amp;nbsp;stating:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information Services is strategically a Microsoft shop and when
talking to staff / customers we are to support this strategy. I no
longer want to see comments promoting other Operating&amp;nbsp;Systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, my anti-Microsoft buzzer went off. But the post also stated
that they were ordered to remove Firefox from any computers not
specifically authorized by management. As usual, the Slashdot
conversation degenerated into a proprietary vs open&amp;nbsp;debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I have to comment on the Microsoft issue, I have two remarks. First,
software (an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;, a browser, a text editor, whatever) is a tool. A tool
should be chosen base on whether it&amp;#8217;s the right one for the job, not
just because of who makes it. I&amp;#8217;d like to see a major construction
company state decree that they&amp;#8217;ll only buy Stanley and DeWalt tools.
What will their answer be when the plumbers realize that neither of
those companies make a simple pipe wrench? &amp;#8220;Use a hammer&amp;#8221;? Secondly, as
is evidenced by history, popularity is a relatively poor indicator of
quality, and always ephemeral. Wigs were popular for wealthy men. The
telegraph was popular, and many thought the telephone would never catch
on. The &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fluoroscope"&gt;fluoroscope&lt;/a&gt; was
popular for shoe fitting. Racism was popular. Smoking was popular. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BASIC&lt;/span&gt;
was the greatest programming language ever. Decisions based solely on
popularity are rarely good in the long&amp;nbsp;term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, alas, enough of the Microsoft-bashing. What struck me more was the
prohibition against Firefox, and what it means for technically-apt
employees. Times are changing, and many of the people now entering the
workforce are well-versed with technology. The days when employers could
expect to give their new hires initial computer training are long gone.
And, while many may not see it, the days when every new employee could
be expected to know only a common &amp;#8220;popular&amp;#8221; system (Windows, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt; Office,
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MSIE&lt;/span&gt;) are gone, too. Many people who work at universities, such as
myself, are seeing browser stats that report less than 40% Windows, with
an explosion of Mac-based users and (perhaps thanks to Android,
Netbooks, and Ubuntu) a strong growth in the Linux user&amp;nbsp;base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rutgers University student computing labs have both &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IE&lt;/span&gt; and Firefox
installed on the Windows machines (and we also have a *very* large
number of Mac or dual-boot Windows/Mac clients) and a walk through a
busy lab will reveal a strong majority of users on Firefox. Many
cash-strapped students, even the ones I knew a few years ago, were using
OpenOffice rather than pay for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A similar trend can be seen in the new hires and young professionals who
simply won&amp;#8217;t settle for a corporate cell phone - Windows Mobile, iPhone
or Android, they already have a phone and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; that they like, and
consider a part of their&amp;nbsp;lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a very simple point here - for an increasing number of people,
especially those now entering the workforce, technology is an
inextricable part of their lives. It&amp;#8217;s part of their sense of self, of
expression, of free choice. Telling many people what browser they can
and can&amp;#8217;t use is like telling a new hire a decade or two ago how their
handwriting had to look or what size note pad they could use. Asking
many of my (even non-techie) friends to switch cell phone &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; would be
like telling them what color clothes or tie they have to wear to work.
Telling the average 20-year-old that they can&amp;#8217;t use instant messenger or
facebook at work is like telling the average 40-year-old they can&amp;#8217;t
receive a phone call from their spouse or child. Most especially, with
the pervasiveness of Internet access, connected devices and choice in
browsers and other software, these choices are being seen as a part of
life, a part of&amp;nbsp;technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, and perhaps most importantly to many businesses, the role of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt;
as seen by the end-user is changing, and the role of technology in
productivity is changing. For many young college-educated workers, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; is
more of a procurement avenue than a support system. Many would happily
install the software application of their choice (whether it is Firefox,
OpenOffice, or something else) on their own, without the worry of a
formal help desk. There&amp;#8217;s also the issue of productivity -
technologically proficient new hires are already used to a software
environment. They&amp;#8217;ve been able to choose their own applications, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;,
browser, etc. Forcing them to switch - especially if they have been
using an application for years and still do at home - will only result
in lower productivity and some amount of frustration. I know that I, for
one, have almost laughed when people advertising for Linux admin jobs
said I&amp;#8217;d be using the same Windows desktop environment as all of the&amp;nbsp;users.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="microsoft"></category></entry><entry><title>On FIle Sharing, DRM, and customer choice</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/02/on-file-sharing-drm-and-customer-choice/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-27T13:04:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-02-27:2010/02/on-file-sharing-drm-and-customer-choice/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s been a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of buzz over the past few years about &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DRM&lt;/span&gt;, file
sharing, &amp;#8220;intellectual property theft&amp;#8221;, etc. A lot of that has been the
two extreme sides - the media industry and their &amp;#8220;have it our way&amp;#8221;
attitude, and the extremists who feel that everything digital should be
freely shareable by everyone. I don&amp;#8217;t fall into either of those
categories, and I don&amp;#8217;t think the majority of people do&amp;nbsp;either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let&amp;#8217;s look at a bit of history. In my early childhood (1990&amp;#8217;s),
cassettes were giving way to CDs, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHS&lt;/span&gt; tapes were the norm for
videos. You could go to any corner store and buy a blank cassette tape
or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHS&lt;/span&gt; tape, and it was widely known that people recorded &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; shows or
copied audio or video tapes. To cope with this, a portion of the
purchase price of every blank tape was distributed among media companies
and artists, to compensate them for the copies being made. It seemed
that everyone was happy about this - nobody was trying to ban the sale
of blank tapes, and my neighborhood video rental store never made me
sign a contract promising not to copy a rented tape. There seemed to be
a balance between the need for profit and what consumers wanted to&amp;nbsp;do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That all changed when the world went digital - first audio CDs, then
movies on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt;. It requires mention that almost all of the problems faced
by the media industry (namely &amp;#8220;piracy&amp;#8221; and file sharing) were brought by
the industry itself. I vividly remember, over a period of a mere two
years or so, the transition from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHS&lt;/span&gt; to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt;. I remember going to the
video rental store (we were late adopters, nobody in my family had a
standalone &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt; player) and being told that new releases were no longer
coming out on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHS&lt;/span&gt;. We &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to buy a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt; player. This was a format that
was pushed on consumers by the movie industry, and was pushed hard and
fast. While everyone talked of the quality benefits, it was obvious that
distributors were in love with the format&amp;#8217;s cheap and quick
reproduction. I simply do not believe that the movie industry was
unaware (especially given the proliferation of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt; drives in computers)
that this cheap reproduction was as easily available to consumers as it
was to them. If they were unaware, we must ask how their
million-dollar-a-year technical teams never mentioned it. You can&amp;#8217;t have
your cake and eat it too. The movie industry &lt;em&gt;chose&lt;/em&gt; to convert to a
format that&amp;#8217;s easily copied. The movie industry &lt;em&gt;chose&lt;/em&gt; to convert to a
format that could be easily read - and copied - on any home computer.
They should be forced to accept that choice, and the effect that anyone
with a computer can duplicate or share their products. If they didn&amp;#8217;t
want people to do this, they should have stuck with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHS&lt;/span&gt;, or gone to a
higher-quality tape&amp;nbsp;format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I digress. The main point that I want to make is about consumer
choice, and how that effects purchasing (and sharing)&amp;nbsp;habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my parent&amp;#8217;s generation, and those before it, customers voiced their
choice through making a purchase or not making a purchase. If they
didn&amp;#8217;t like a car salesman&amp;#8217;s attitude, they&amp;#8217;d buy the car from someone
else. If they didn&amp;#8217;t like the terms of a warranty, they&amp;#8217;d buy their
washing machine from Sears instead of the local store. If they didn&amp;#8217;t
like their phone company, they&amp;#8217;d&amp;nbsp;switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My generation, in the digital age, was faced with a different choice -
buy or share. The recording and movie industries more or less made this
choice for us. They wouldn&amp;#8217;t let us buy how we wanted to, so we made the
other&amp;nbsp;choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This choice required a bit of a tangent to explain. The industry wants
us to think of file sharing as stealing. When sharing digital files,
they want us to think of the fact that the file is duplicated (i.e. my
friend now has it, but I still have it too). This is simply a
side-effect of how digital systems work. Whether right or wrong, whether
antiquated or not, in most human minds the concept of stealing is
inextricably linked to physical property. Walking into a library and
walking out with a book that you didn&amp;#8217;t check out is clearly stealing.
However, most people wouldn&amp;#8217;t think the same thing of photocopying some
pages from the book. Most people wouldn&amp;#8217;t think of photocopying a
newspaper article and mailing it to their friend as stealing. How many
people, in the day of audio cassettes, thought of it as &amp;#8220;stealing&amp;#8221; when
they copied a tape for their friend? I&amp;#8217;d guess that, for the vast
majority of people, file sharing is much more closely associated with
these actions than walking out of a record store with a&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal theory is that a large amount of file sharing (of
copyrighted material) would stop if the movie industry would let people
buy the way they&amp;nbsp;want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a time, a few years ago, when I got almost all of my music
through peer-to-peer file sharing (though, unlike many, I didn&amp;#8217;t allow
uploads). I never thought much of it - I shared lots of things with my
friends, why not music? Then &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIAA&lt;/span&gt; started their &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PR&lt;/span&gt; and lawsuit
campaigns. They started suing college kids for sharing music - and suing
them for a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; more than even the cost of the CDs they&amp;#8217;d &amp;#8220;stolen&amp;#8221; (and
that&amp;#8217;s ignoring the fact that they just &amp;#8220;stole&amp;#8221; the information on the
CDs, so the actual cost should have been lower, less the physical media
and distribution costs). So, I heard what the recording industry was
telling me: we don&amp;#8217;t like you. I stopped downloading music, and I also
stopped buying it. For about 3 1/2 years, I listened to what I already
had on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt;, or the radio, but nothing&amp;nbsp;new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there was iTunes. You could buy whatever music you wanted, usually
for less than $1. But you had to use their software, which didn&amp;#8217;t run on
Linux. And if you wanted to listen to it away from your computer, you
had to use an iPod. And you couldn&amp;#8217;t burn it to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt;, so it wouldn&amp;#8217;t work
with the older stereo in my&amp;nbsp;car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the industry woke up. Amazon came out with their &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MP3&lt;/span&gt; store,
where I could buy individual songs or complete albums, as standard
(non-DRMed) &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MP3&lt;/span&gt; files, that I could listen to on my cell phone, any of
my computers, or burn to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt; and play in my car. And I&amp;#8217;ve been hooked
ever since - I get all of my music for a low price, in a standard
unrestricted format. I can burn it to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt; for my car, put it on my
computers at home and at work, put it on my laptop, put it on my phone.
Thanks to 1-click ordering and instant downloads, I probably spend more
on music now than I did when I had to go to a store to buy CDs. And why?
Because I have choice. Because, finally, they&amp;#8217;ll sell music to me the
way I want it - and I buy&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know of any source of unbiased statistics, but I&amp;#8217;d venture a
guess that since various stores have begun selling &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DRM&lt;/span&gt;-free music
online, the volume of peer-to-peer sharing of copyrighted music files
has gone&amp;nbsp;down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it seems that the movie industry hasn&amp;#8217;t woken up to this, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MPAA&lt;/span&gt;
hasn&amp;#8217;t taken a lesson from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIAA&lt;/span&gt;. While options are starting to appear -
NetFlix streaming and others - they still haven&amp;#8217;t made the realization
that customers will continue to choose &amp;#8220;other&amp;#8221; until offered the choice
they want. I still can&amp;#8217;t buy and download movies on Linux, and since I
use &lt;a href="http://www.mythtv.org"&gt;MythTV&lt;/a&gt; for my home theater, it&amp;#8217;s no use to
get a NetFlix box. Until offered what they want - a download of an
unencumbered, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DRM&lt;/span&gt;-free movie file, or full &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt; image, people will keep
sharing movies, and will keep renting them and ripping full-resolution&amp;nbsp;copies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it&amp;#8217;s worth mention that the secret Anti-Counterfitting Trade
Agreement
(&lt;a href="http://www.boingboing.net/2010/02/21/acta-internet-enforc.html"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACTA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)
is obviously tilted in the favor of content producers, and has a number
of &lt;a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/4808/125/"&gt;chilling&lt;/a&gt;
provisions for the Internet. Most importantly, it seeks to reverse
previous law and hold ISPs liable for infringement by their customers.
Firstly, and I say this with all my heart, this is wrong. &lt;em&gt;Until
publishers start successfully suing Xerox for every copy of a page of a
book ever made, don&amp;#8217;t try and hold ISPs responsible for what their
customers do.&lt;/em&gt; But more importantly, this is braindead - we should know
by now that copyright holders can&amp;#8217;t win the cat-and-mouse game. We saw
it with p2p and random ports, etc. Trying to detect transmission of
infringing material is impossible. Once a new method is invented, it
will be bypassed. No matter how many millions the media industry spends
on trying to detect violations, there&amp;#8217;s simply more people working on
the other side, and they&amp;#8217;re probably smarter and better motivated as
well. If the media industry pushes for ISPs to use deep packet
inspection (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DPI&lt;/span&gt;) technology, the users will just turn to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PKI&lt;/span&gt; and
encryption to hide their data. If ISPs just look at traffic patterns,
the users will accept slower download times and shape their traffic to
look like web&amp;nbsp;browsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the media industry really wants to stop file sharing of their content
(instead of just benefiting from lawsuits) the solution is simple - let
consumers buy it the way they&amp;nbsp;want.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="drm"></category><category term="file sharing"></category><category term="intellectual property"></category><category term="IP"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="p2p"></category><category term="peer to peer"></category><category term="shopping"></category></entry><entry><title>Microsoft submits driver code for Linux kernel</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/07/microsoft-submits-driver-code-for-linux-kernel/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-07-23T09:32:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-07-23:2009/07/microsoft-submits-driver-code-for-linux-kernel/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I read a very interesting &lt;a href="http://www.linux-mag.com/cache/7439/1.html"&gt;article on
Linux-Mag.com&lt;/a&gt; today. The
gist of it is that Microsoft (as happily announced in a &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/presspass/features/2009/Jul09/07-20LinuxQA.mspx"&gt;press
release&lt;/a&gt;)
has submitted 20,000 lines of code for inclusion into the kernel.
Specifically, the code is comprised of a number of drivers that will
enable Linux to run better under Microsoft&amp;nbsp;Hyper-V.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, that&amp;#8217;s right, Microsoft released code under GPLv2 and is asking for
it to be put in Linux. They released it under the license that they call
&amp;#8220;cancer&amp;#8221;. And the entire purpose is, essentially, saying &amp;#8220;we want your
project to run well as a guest under our&amp;nbsp;hypervisor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Linux Mag article did touch on some recent news, such as Microsoft&amp;#8217;s
&lt;a href="http://www.linux-mag.com/id/7325"&gt;lawsuit against TomTom&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/microsoft/news/2009/03/microsoft-and-tomtom-settle-patent-dispute.ars"&gt;settled in
late
March&lt;/a&gt;)
claiming that the Linux kernel infringes their &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VFAT&lt;/span&gt; patents and the 2004
&lt;a href="http://ec.europa.eu/comm/competition/antitrust/cases/decisions/37792/en.pdf"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EU&lt;/span&gt; antitrust case
(&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of things are immediately apparent to&amp;nbsp;me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only reason for this is so Linux will virtualize well under&amp;nbsp;Windows/Hyper-V.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to be making any similar effort to allow
    Windows to virtualize well under Xen (and it seems to me that many
    more people would want Windows on a reliable Linux host than the
    other way&amp;nbsp;around).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft reached a settlement with TomTom, but never did anything
    to indemnify the Linux community at&amp;nbsp;large.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; a Microsoft endorsement (or even recognition) of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft &lt;a href="http://www.linux-watch.com/news/NS6670466370.html"&gt;made
    threats&lt;/a&gt; about
    Linux violating &amp;#8220;over 228&amp;#8221; of its patents in&amp;nbsp;2007.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a
&lt;a href="http://www.kroah.com/log/linux/microsoft-linux-hyper-v-drivers.html"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;
on &lt;a href="http://www.kroah.com/log/"&gt;Greg Kroah-Hartman&amp;#8217;s blog&lt;/a&gt; (he&amp;#8217;s the
kernel maintainer who will - or will not - eventually be in charge of
the inclusion of the code). It should be noted that &lt;strong&gt;this all started&lt;/strong&gt;
due to a guy who I really admire, &lt;a href="http://linux-network-plumber.blogspot.com/"&gt;Stephen
Hemminger&lt;/a&gt;, the principal
engineer at Vyatta (whose router product I absolutely love, and their
mock advertisements are just as wonderful). Steve has a &lt;a href="http://linux-network-plumber.blogspot.com/2009/07/congratulations-microsoft.html"&gt;post on his
blog&lt;/a&gt;
giving the&amp;nbsp;background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what do &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; think should be done? Include the code. But first&amp;#8230; (I
know Microsoft doing all of this at once would be a dream, but maybe one
or two of them would be&amp;nbsp;nice)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If they haven&amp;#8217;t already done so, Microsoft should publicly recognize
    the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt; and all of its terms as being a legally binding&amp;nbsp;license.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior to having any Microsoft code included in the Linux kernel,
    Microsoft publicly states that the Linux kernel, as of the time they
    submitted their code, does not infringe on any Microsoft
    intellectual&amp;nbsp;property.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would be nice of Microsoft would agree to some level of
    cooperation with the Linux&amp;nbsp;community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft pledges to allow, support, and actively develop for
    Windows as a guest under Xen and&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;KVM&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><category term="gpl"></category><category term="kernel"></category><category term="linux"></category><category term="microsoft"></category></entry><entry><title>Please Don’t resize my browser</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/06/please-dont-resize-my-browser/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-06-22T23:48:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-06-22:2009/06/please-dont-resize-my-browser/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It always amazes me to see how much &amp;#8220;old school&amp;#8221; web design practice is
still out there. I&amp;#8217;m talking about commercial sites (not MySpace pages)
that blatantly ignore web standards about both content and user
experience. This isn&amp;#8217;t just a Linux thing, though some aspect of it
certainly is. The web site of my home town,
&lt;a href="http://www.mpnj.com"&gt;mpnj.com&lt;/a&gt; uses a Flash-based navigation menu that
even the official, proprietary Flash player for Linux won&amp;#8217;t support -
the transparency renders as white, obscuring the text beneath the fully
extended size of the menu. I emailed the developer about this on the
launch day, and was told in no uncertain terms that - despite the fact
that he had a fully-functional alternate version - Linux wasn&amp;#8217;t
important enough to fix the site. Ironically for a town government web
page, it also doesn&amp;#8217;t incorporate any accessibility features, which
seems to be standard for most of these poor&amp;nbsp;designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still countless large news sites whose Flash-based video
players won&amp;#8217;t run under Linux, and even CitiBank&amp;#8217;s credit card site has
a flash ad that plays incorrectly under&amp;nbsp;Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real pain that I happened to see today was a company who uses
coupons.com to allow customers to print out retail coupons. My first
surprise was that to print the coupons, you have to download Windows or
Mac software. I&amp;#8217;m not quite sure how many people will do this, but it&amp;#8217;s
probably how viruses spread so quickly (people who will download
anything that claims to get them half a dollar off of a roll of toilet
paper, or whatever the coupons are for). So, that&amp;#8217;s not cool - most
coupons I&amp;#8217;ve gotten were just &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; emails or PDFs. If their thinking is
to control the distribution (they make some comment about a &amp;#8220;paper-based
printer, not a fax or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt; creator&amp;#8221;), they&amp;#8217;ve obviously forgotten about
photocopy machines and scanners, let alone capturing the spool file on&amp;nbsp;Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More striking, however, was the shock of opening their help page. My
primary monitor is a 24&amp;#8221; widescreen, and I generally keep a browser
window occupying half the screen width and a terminal next to it. Once I
opened their &amp;#8220;help&amp;#8221; site, it promptly resized my browser window to a
tiny&amp;nbsp;640x480!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This problem, unfortunately, isn&amp;#8217;t as rare as it should be. There are
still sites that force browser size, disable right clicks (I hadn&amp;#8217;t seen
that since about 2004 until a few weeks ago&amp;#8230; obviously someone who&amp;#8217;s
never used `wget`) or have a page that doesn&amp;#8217;t fully work in FireFox
on any platform. Even worse, my personal pet peeve (as at the time of
writing this I have about 50+ tabs open in Firefox, and it&amp;#8217;s only using
a small sliver of my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;2GB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt;) is sites that don&amp;#8217;t play well with tabbed
browsing - either using only JavaScript for &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; navigation links, or
opening all links (site-wide) in the same tab/window. I don&amp;#8217;t know how
many web sites have lost my business because of this. Or the one I know
of that starts a new shopping cart for every tab opened (so if I open
each product I want to buy in a new tab, when I add them all to the
cart, it ends up with only&amp;nbsp;one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know how there can be anyone out there who&amp;#8217;s still not using
valid &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XHTML&lt;/span&gt; with all of the accessibility features for anything new,
especially a commercial site. But even more so, how can there still be
people designing web sites who disregard the golden rule of web design:
&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t mess with someone&amp;#8217;s browser.&lt;/strong&gt; Leave things like where to open
the link and how big to make the browser to the user. If they&amp;#8217;re not
technically literate, changing what &amp;#8220;usually happens&amp;#8221; will just confuse
them. If they&amp;#8217;re well-versed in how to use a web browser, like me,
they&amp;#8217;ll just get aggravated by having someone else change their workflow
(I doubt the guys who designed those sites would like it if I told them
they had to design the whole thing in Emacs). If they&amp;#8217;re somewhere in
the middle (just found Ctrl+click in Firefox), you&amp;#8217;ll confuse them. And
God forbid they&amp;#8217;re blind and using a page reader&amp;#8230; good luck with
JavaScript or Flash&amp;nbsp;navigation.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="design"></category><category term="standards"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>My Take on the MS TomTom Suit</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/03/my-take-on-the-ms-tomtom-suit/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-03-05T10:05:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-03-05:2009/03/my-take-on-the-ms-tomtom-suit/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;To keep it short, I&amp;#8217;m sure anyone who winds up here has already heard
about the recent Microsoft lawsuit against TomTom, alleging patent
infringement. Coverage has been extensive, including
&lt;a href="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20090226070041454"&gt;GrokLaw&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href="http://www.linux-mag.com/id/7258"&gt;Linux Magazine&lt;/a&gt;. While the
mentioned patents include car navigation technology (at least the names
of the patents seem amazingly vague) and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FAT&lt;/span&gt; . Most of the news stories
I&amp;#8217;ve read say that it&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;good for Linux&amp;#8221; and will never see the inside
of a&amp;nbsp;courtroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I&amp;#8217;m just a pessimist, but I see the idea behind this as much worse
than &amp;#8220;good for Linux&amp;#8221;. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt; chose one company to sue. TomTom just happens
to be not only a household name, but also posted a $1.2 Billion loss
last year. It seems to me this is more of a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FUD&lt;/span&gt; campaign than anything
else&amp;#8230; the best case for Microsoft is that they could strangle TomTom
in a legal battle, perhaps force them to go under, and then ensure a
media spin along the lines of &amp;#8220;Know that company that made the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; in
every car? They used Linux in it, they got sued by Microsoft, and
they&amp;#8217;re no&amp;nbsp;more.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I haven&amp;#8217;t always been a fan of TomTom - and am still bothered by
the fact that my (stolen, no longer in my possession) TomTom One ran
Linux but wouldn&amp;#8217;t give me a console or even let me see the filesystem -
I&amp;#8217;ll be watching this closely, and hoping that the powers that be will
not let the angry dinosaur crush a company over a series of patents that
are either horribly obvious (anyone other than Garmin having a claim to
any &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;-related idea is beyond me) or just horrible&amp;nbsp;(&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FAT&lt;/span&gt;?!?!?!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a final note - isn&amp;#8217;t it about time that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; finally dealt with
this damn software patent thing? Not only does it horribly stifle
innovation (not good to do in a bad economy), and I have a hard time
grasping the claim that Microsoft&amp;#8217;s developers are so all-powerful that
they&amp;#8217;re the only people that thought of technology X, but it&amp;#8217;s about
time that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; government got the balls to look Microsoft in the eyes
and say, &amp;#8220;you&amp;#8217;re not the only game in town anymore. Get used to&amp;nbsp;it.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="lawsuit"></category><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="patents"></category><category term="tomtom"></category></entry><entry><title>ROUThost DNS problems; GoDaddy and Security through Obscurity</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/02/routhost-dns-problems-godaddy-and-security-through-obscurity/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-02-25T11:07:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-02-25:2009/02/routhost-dns-problems-godaddy-and-security-through-obscurity/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The external-facing web site and (internal use) mailing list for the
&lt;a href="http://www.midlandparkambulance.com"&gt;ambulance corps&lt;/a&gt; is hosted by
&lt;a href="http://www.routhost.com"&gt;ROUThost&lt;/a&gt;. Not my choice, it was inherited.
ROUThost, first off, appears to be a fly-by-night hosting provider that
just buys a few boxes in a colo facility. I should have known to raise a
stink when they say you need to fax a copy of your driver&amp;#8217;s license to
get &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; turned on, and that you have to agree - in legalese - not to
mess with anyone else&amp;#8217;s configs. Well, last night, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; for the site went
down. As in nothing, wouldn&amp;#8217;t resolve at all. I submitted a ticket
online for ROUThost&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;24x7&amp;#8221; support - by the way, they don&amp;#8217;t have a
phone number, only an online ticket form. After 2h 34m 40s of downtime,
the issue resolved itself and I downgraded the ticket from &amp;#8220;critical&amp;#8221; to
medium. Now, 11 hours later, it still hasn&amp;#8217;t been replied to. And my
emails to support and management - 2 hours ago - are&amp;nbsp;unanswered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the problem started, I knew the yearly contract with ROUThost was a
bad idea - even at $35/year &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USD&lt;/span&gt;. So, given the great experience I&amp;#8217;ve had
with them as registrar for my myriad domains, I took a look at
&lt;a href="http://www.godaddy.com"&gt;GoDaddy&amp;#8217;s Site&lt;/a&gt;. They offer shared
hosting at around $4/month (for shared on a Linux box) and are currently
offering some deals, so I figured it would be a good idea. I know and
trust GoDaddy&amp;#8217;s support, and have had an account with them for &lt;em&gt;quite
some time&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ambulance corp&amp;#8217;s web site, hosted through ROUThost, does essentially
three things; provide a minimal web presence (the whole web root is
probably &amp;lt; 1Mb minus the photo albums), five e-mail forwarders for the
officers and a &lt;a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/mailman/index.html"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GNU&lt;/span&gt;
MailMan&lt;/a&gt; mailing list
for internal business. Unfortunately, I couldn&amp;#8217;t find anything in their
&amp;#8220;features&amp;#8221; list mentioning MialMan or any other listserv, or even what
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MTA&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDA&lt;/span&gt; they&amp;nbsp;run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put a call in to GoDaddy &amp;#8220;Sales/Support&amp;#8221;. The poor guy had never heard
of MailMan, but asked &amp;#8220;one of the hosting guys&amp;#8221; and was told it would
only be supported on dedicate hosting accounts. Not exactly financially
feasible for a mailing list with 30 subscribers, maybe 2 messages a day,
and a monthly &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt; transfer of under 20Mb. I was told their shared
hosting packages don&amp;#8217;t include any mailing list/listserv software,
though they include every &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CMS&lt;/span&gt; and language known to man. Hell-bent to
get away from ROUThost, I then asked if they ran an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDA&lt;/span&gt; that supported
piping mail to a command, as can be done with .procmailrc. After a brief
hold (not to sound cynical, but I&amp;#8217;m sure the gentleman was looking up
&amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDA&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221;) he came back on the line and told me they didn&amp;#8217;t. I then switched
to problem-solving mode and asked what &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MTA&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDA&lt;/span&gt; they were running.
Another brief hold, and I was told &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;I can&amp;#8217;t tell you that&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;. Speechless
for a moment, I asked what that meant; &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;we don&amp;#8217;t give out that
information&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;. Just about ready to begin explaining &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMTP&lt;/span&gt; headers, I gave
up and thanked him for his&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, so Sales probably doesn&amp;#8217;t understand &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMTP&lt;/span&gt; headers. I&amp;#8217;d considered
trying to find mail from a GoDaddy Linux hosted box and check the
headers, but I figured I couldn&amp;#8217;t do that before the call ended. So, now
I&amp;#8217;m left with a dilemma. ROUThost is not, in my opinion, reliable, and
their support is flat-out nonexistent. 11 hours is far too long to wait
for a reply to a &amp;#8220;critical&amp;#8221; ticket when someone claims 24x7 support.
However, by previous experience, GoDaddy would be my next choice - but
not only do they ot support mailing lists - arguably the most used
feature of our current hosted account - but they won&amp;#8217;t even tell a
customer what &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MTA&lt;/span&gt; they&amp;#8217;re running. I&amp;#8217;m too let down by this to telnet 25
on one of their boxes and see what&amp;nbsp;happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;#8217;s left? I guess waiting until (hopefully some time within the
next few weeks) I upgrade to Optimum static &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; at home, and consider
running it all there (and hope mains power never goes out for more than
30&amp;nbsp;minutes?)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="dns"></category><category term="godaddy"></category><category term="hosting"></category><category term="routhost"></category><category term="security through obscurity"></category><category term="support"></category></entry><entry><title>My Dream Network</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/02/my-dream-network/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-02-07T01:15:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-02-07:2009/02/my-dream-network/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the same thread as the &lt;a href="/2009/02/community-datacenter/"&gt;last
post&lt;/a&gt;, some
thoughts on my ideal network, or the hosts on that&amp;nbsp;network:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One &amp;#8220;gold master&amp;#8221; installation/kickstart file of a single chosen
    distro, with a base set of packages, including site-specific
    packages. (or something like this implemented in a configuration
    management&amp;nbsp;system)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All new installations performed over the network in an automated
    fashion, and from a local&amp;nbsp;repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software updates are automated (either through a configuration
    management tool or something like the behemoth I talked about
    &lt;a href="/2008/10/my-biggest-problem-with-linux/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)
    and pulled from a local repository (perhaps one which mirrors the
    mainline repos, but only downloads a package the first time it&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;requested?).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://reductivelabs.com/trac/puppet"&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt; or
    &lt;a href="http://www.cfengine.org/"&gt;CFengine&lt;/a&gt; on each machine. Better than
    just having them is having each machine automatically added when
    it&amp;#8217;s created. Even better yet would be to have Puppet or CFengine
    combined with something like
    &lt;a href="https://fedorahosted.org/cobbler/"&gt;Cobbler&lt;/a&gt;, so I can define a new
    machine in {puppet|cfengine}, list its&amp;#8217; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MAC&lt;/span&gt; address, then netboot
    the box and come back in a few hours to have an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; installed,
    packages installed and the machine configured, monitored in Nagios,
    monitored for security and backed&amp;nbsp;up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tripwire.com/"&gt;Tripwire&lt;/a&gt; or some other sort of security
    software, as well as centralized logging and auditing, on every&amp;nbsp;box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small number of additional &amp;#8220;package groups&amp;#8221; to add to the &amp;#8220;gold
    master&amp;#8221; via config management - something like &amp;#8220;web server&amp;#8221;
    (Apache2, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;, MySQL, log analysis for them, etc.), &amp;#8220;development
    server&amp;#8221; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt;, debuggers, etc.). These would also update the backup
    system to include appropriate directories, update Nagios configs,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good way - if even a human making notes in a per-machine text file&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;of tracking the &amp;#8220;little stuff&amp;#8221; like that one cron script that
makes everything work right, the location of that hacked-together
Python script, etc. A way to easily remember the things needed to
recreate a box which aren&amp;#8217;t found in &lt;code&gt;rpm -qa&lt;/code&gt; or any obvious&amp;nbsp;overviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bacula.org"&gt;Bacula&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://www.amanda.org/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AMANDA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    setup to backup every box, perhaps with some sort of template system
    for server types - every machine gets &lt;code&gt;/root&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/etc&lt;/code&gt; backed up,
    but web servers get &lt;code&gt;/srv/www&lt;/code&gt; and mail servers get &lt;code&gt;/var/mail&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nagios setup to monitor everything logical on every box. Perhaps
    this would use a configuration management engine to handle Nagios
    configs, so that for example if any Proliant hardware is used,
    {config management program} will figure this out, install the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HPASM&lt;/span&gt;
    packages, put the appropriate check scripts on the box, and update
    the Nagios configs. Likewise, adding Apache to a machine should
    cause it to be monitored in the Nagios&amp;nbsp;configs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, as I&amp;#8217;m not independently wealthy, I don&amp;#8217;t have the time
to quit my job, wipe every machine I own, and start from scratch. But it
sure would be nice to be able to, one day, start a server farm from
scratch and be able to implement some of these cool&amp;nbsp;things&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="configuration"></category><category term="dream network"></category><category term="ideal network"></category><category term="management"></category></entry><entry><title>Community Datacenter</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/02/community-datacenter/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-02-07T00:50:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-02-07:2009/02/community-datacenter/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been planning a lot of administrative work lately&amp;#8230; I have a few
machines that need &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; upgrades, my backup system is barely functional
(it needs both a new, large disk and a configuration overhaul), and I&amp;#8217;m
planning a switch to static &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; service - which means not only a new
&lt;a href="http://www.vyatta.com/"&gt;router/firewall&lt;/a&gt; to design, configure and
monitor, as well as moving some services previously run by
&lt;a href="http://www.ipcop.org/"&gt;IPcop&lt;/a&gt; over to a dedicated box, but also finally
adding three IPsec VPNs, monitoring them and tunneling all sorts of
stuff over them, and reconfiguring all of my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt;, finding any hard-coded
URLs, and a slew of other&amp;nbsp;projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this got me thinking. While there are a number of reasons why I run
such a complex network at home (mainly including maintaining my presence
on the web and my email, providing temporary hosting for freelance work,
the convenience of file access from anywhere, the breadth of
administrative experience it gives me, and a way to test new
technologies) there are some parts of it that I just don&amp;#8217;t like dealing
with. I&amp;#8217;ve never been a really network-centric guy, and the idea of
having to setup a router/firewall (I&amp;#8217;m going with
&lt;a href="http://www.vyatta.com"&gt;Vyatta&lt;/a&gt; as it seems to be the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; thing that
will deal with the complex configuration I want) for all this just to
get 5 static IPs seems a bit much. Not to mention there&amp;#8217;s just too much
running on all those boxen (8 at home, 2 at school, plus 3 others at 2
other locations) for me to keep a handle on all of it and still be a
full-time student, work 30 hours/week, and do freelance work.
Something&amp;#8217;s always bound to get ignored - sometimes backups stop for a
week, sometimes Nagios goes haywire, and sometimes Cacti stops graphing
for a month before I notice&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest thing I learned from running all of these systems for
personal use is to start everything consistently and with a plan. My
oldest box in semi-production is running SuSE 9.3, installed somewhere
between April and October of 2005. It was ignored for so long (a period
when it wasn&amp;#8217;t being used for much) that I now can&amp;#8217;t even perform
updates, as the update sequence is virtually impossible to accomplish.
Then again, re-purposed desktops shouldn&amp;#8217;t be in &amp;#8220;production&amp;#8221; for 4
years. Anyway, perhaps the biggest lesson in trying to deal with all of
this is the importance of consistency. Not just attempting to
standardize on one distribution, but also making a local image that
includes the standard packages, configurations, and other important
stuff - like the Nagios user account and local plugins and maybe even
the public &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; key of the Nagios box. Even better would be a
configuration management system like
&lt;a href="http://reductivelabs.com/trac/puppet"&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href="http://www.cfengine.org/"&gt;CFengine&lt;/a&gt;, or even manually keeping all of
the distros updated to a common&amp;nbsp;version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I digress. The real point of this post was supposed to be a simple
idea: I have all of this running at home, and I know quite a few &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt;
people who have a similar setup at home or at work, or have considerable
resources at a hosting/colo facility. So, why not start a &amp;#8220;community
datacenter&amp;#8221; project? At home I have to do everything from backups to
firewall and router administration to security. I&amp;#8217;d be much happier just
handling network/service monitoring, log analysis, and some tool and web
scripting. I know a few Cisco-heads who run their &amp;#8220;home&amp;#8221; LANs on chassis
switches, but find it such a pain to reconfigure Apache or run a
monitoring app. I&amp;#8217;m sure someone&amp;#8217;s thought of this in the past, and
probably tried it, but why don&amp;#8217;t some guys (who can be trusted) get
together, find some colo space (or anywhere with power and connectivity)
and start, essentially, a co-op data center? Assuming you could find a
large enough circle of trusted friends, I&amp;#8217;m sure you could find someone
willing to volunteer every service needed - from network engineering to
backups, monitoring, and security - in exchange for some rack space and
connectivity, or even a virtual host. I know I&amp;#8217;d opt in any second - or
even let someone throw a box in my basement in exchange for someone to
help read through logs or setup a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTPS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VPN&lt;/span&gt;, if it weren&amp;#8217;t for the
archaic equipment I&amp;#8217;m&amp;nbsp;running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a&amp;nbsp;thought&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="community"></category><category term="datacenter"></category></entry><entry><title>My biggest problem with Linux</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/10/my-biggest-problem-with-linux/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-10-27T15:27:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-10-27:2008/10/my-biggest-problem-with-linux/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update / Notice:&lt;/strong&gt; This post was written in 2008. The world has
changed since then. A lot. We have good, easy configuration management
like Puppet, Chef, etc. (which, in fact, I
&lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/workstation-bootstrap"&gt;use to manage my desktop and laptop&lt;/a&gt;)
and, more importantly, creating and destroying servers can be done in
&lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/"&gt;seconds&lt;/a&gt; rather than hours.
In short, in my opinion, this post is a rant about a problem that no longer
exists. If you&amp;#8217;re still thinking of things the way this post does, you&amp;#8217;re
doing it&amp;nbsp;wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For one of my wonderful classes, Internet Security, I&amp;#8217;m doing a
presentation on &amp;#8220;patch management&amp;#8221;. While I&amp;#8217;m obligated to cover Windows
- and, of course, will talk about MacOS - I&amp;#8217;ll obviously be spending a
good deal of time on the Unix/Linux side of things. This has gotten me
thinking about one of my biggest problems with Linux (and specifically
&lt;a href="http://www.opensuse.org"&gt;OpenSuSE&lt;/a&gt;, my usual default distro. Patch
management is utterly&amp;nbsp;awful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s the problem: I have about a dozen machines under my control. I
need to keep them all up-to-date. Currently, I manually do patches and
upgrades via YaST or zypper. I thought about scripting this through
zypper, but that doesn&amp;#8217;t make any sense - the packages on the machines
are far from homogenous, so there&amp;#8217;s no clear way to make one script that
updates them all. I considered using Puppet or CFengine or something of
that sort, but that&amp;#8217;s too heavy-weight for me - for only a dozen
machines, many of which are personal or development only, that&amp;#8217;s a lot
to keep track of by hand, and a lot of work defining which patches
should be applied, and which machines shouldn&amp;#8217;t be&amp;nbsp;changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My other peeve is distribution upgrades. About three of my machines are
still running OpenSuSE 10.0 or 10.1, both of which are unsupported, and
no longer even have downloads available. Why? Becuase I&amp;#8217;ve done major
OpenSuSE upgrades before, broken a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LOT&lt;/span&gt; of stuff, and I simply can&amp;#8217;t risk
that on machines that can&amp;#8217;t stand extended downtime. This process
*needs* to be made easier. Bottom line - it should be made no more
difficult or unreliable than a kernel upgrade. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IMHO&lt;/span&gt;, the biggest selling
point for Solaris is its&amp;#8217; ability to do a total upgrade to a second
partition, and switch-over at runtime. Why doesn&amp;#8217;t Linux (or SuSE) have
this&amp;nbsp;yet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What&amp;#8217;s my ideal solution?&lt;/em&gt; A curses application that uses text-file
backends (curses so I can run it over &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; even if I have a slow link or
high latency, like from a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; session on my cell phone, if need be). The
app would allow me to list all of the machines I want managed. It would
connect to the machines over standard &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt;, and would leave an extensive
audit trail of what&amp;#8217;s done, both on the management console and on the
machines (as well as running as a dedicated user). The application would
maintain an inventory of all of the packages on every machine. It would
check daily for new patches/updates to any of those packages, and e-mail
me a daily summary of what&amp;#8217;s new, including all dependency changes, and
which machines need the update. It would also allow me to define, on a
per-machine (or per-group-of-machines) basis, rules for packages that
must stay at their current version - i.e. I have a bunch of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP4&lt;/span&gt; apps,
so machine X needs to stay at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP4&lt;/span&gt;. The e-mail summary would include any
packages that aren&amp;#8217;t going to be updated for a specific machine because
of dependency/version rules, as well as warnings about any new packages
that have a dependency that has a rule set. I could then run the main
curses app on my admin machine and, starting from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NO&lt;/span&gt; selections, select
which updates I want to apply and whether I want to ignore or create new
rules to keep something at its current version, on a per-machine or
per-group basis. This curses app would generate a file (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt;?) of what to
do (which would also be generated or edited by hand, easily). The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt;
file would then be fed into a script that downloads all of the needed
packages to a central (local) mirror (or, optionally, for remote
machines, has them download locally on the machine), checksums them, and
then installs them (running commands over &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt;) on all applicable
machines. It would then keep a log of all changes, both on each machine
changed (in a master changelog file) and on the central administrative
machine. &lt;strong&gt;Most importantly&lt;/strong&gt;, the curses interface would have a simple,
quick way to back out any specific update or group of updates for all
machines, a group of machines, or one machine. All data needed to back
out a change would be kept on each machine (say, cleaned up at the next
update of that package and all of its&amp;#8217; dependencies) with
machine-readable instructions kept in a central file, allowing local
rollbacks - i.e. a machine goes down, I realize that it was because of
an update to package X, and on the local machine I can check the
changelog, see an entry like &amp;#8220;Package X updated 1.0.0 to 1.0.1 on
yyyy-mm-dd, Change &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ID&lt;/span&gt; 1234&amp;#8221; and then, to rollback, simply issue a
command like &amp;#8220;patchmgt rollback 1234&amp;#8221; on the effected&amp;nbsp;machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just some ideas, and a little&amp;nbsp;rant.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="linux"></category><category term="patch management"></category><category term="solaris"></category><category term="updates"></category><category term="upgrades"></category></entry><entry><title>T-Mobile G1 (Googlephone) and VoIP?</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/10/t-mobile-g1-googlephone-and-voip/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-10-27T08:12:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-10-27:2008/10/t-mobile-g1-googlephone-and-voip/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So&amp;#8230; what&amp;#8217;s the deal? Will anyone come out and definitively say what
the fate of VoIP&amp;nbsp;is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what I&amp;#8217;ve read, there are two distinct&amp;nbsp;issues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ease of developing VoIP applications on Android, given the lack
    of a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;stack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T-Mobile&amp;#8217;s shunning of VoIP over their 3G&amp;nbsp;network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Android&lt;/strong&gt; - obviously, if we want to see VoIP apps on the G1, Android
needs to support &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIP&lt;/span&gt;. And the best way to do this is with real, native
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; support. Even if VoIP possibilities are limited to WiFi, still, it
would be nice to have &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIP&lt;/span&gt; support and let my cell double as a WiFi VoIP
phone&amp;#8230; even if handoffs between APs are still nearly impossible. The
next question that begs to be asked is how well such a third-party app
can integrate with the phone. Will the user experience of receiving a
VoIP call be substantially similar to that of receiving a normal phone&amp;nbsp;call?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T-Mobile 3G&lt;/strong&gt; - I&amp;#8217;ve read, so far, that T-Mobile &amp;#8220;does not support&amp;#8221;
VoIP over their 3G network. What&amp;#8217;s this whole &amp;#8220;does not support&amp;#8221; thing?
I&amp;#8217;m still a bit confused about how their 3G network works&amp;#8230; do they
actively block 3G, or just not enable it? If the latter, doe this mean
that other &amp;#8220;non-standard&amp;#8221; things, such as SSHing to a non-standard port,
won&amp;#8217;t work? Does this mean that there will be other heavy restrictions
on what types of data are sent over the&amp;nbsp;network?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about tunneling &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIP&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IAX&lt;/span&gt;/whatever else over &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt;? Will the G1 be
capable of handling that at a relatively good&amp;nbsp;speed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve read that the G1 &amp;#8220;can&amp;#8217;t&amp;#8221; be tethered. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WTF&lt;/span&gt;? Firstly, what is this
&amp;#8220;can&amp;#8217;t&amp;#8221; thing? Couldn&amp;#8217;t a developer just write an app that&amp;#8217;s essentially
a proxy server, that proxies from some sort of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt;-based wired
connection to&amp;nbsp;3G?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, as has been written many times already, less than a week
from the G1&amp;#8217;s release, it seems that the &lt;strong&gt;openness&lt;/strong&gt; touted by Google
and T-Mobile is much less than that. With all their claims of openness,
I&amp;#8217;d expect a phone that will do anything - especially not be locked to
one carrier, given Google&amp;#8217;s history of opposing that (their bid for
700Mhz) - and a data plan that would allow anything over the air that my
home &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; will allow over the&amp;nbsp;wire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google: Have you forsaken all of your stated ideals at the prospect of
making some cash off of a&amp;nbsp;phone?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="cell"></category><category term="g1"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="phone"></category><category term="t-mobile"></category><category term="voip"></category></entry><entry><title>Internet Security, Microsoft Lies</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/09/internet-security-microsoft-lies/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-09-16T23:24:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-09-16:2008/09/internet-security-microsoft-lies/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet&amp;nbsp;Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this semester I&amp;#8217;m taking a class on Internet Security. Our textbook
is &lt;a href="http://search.barnesandnoble.com/booksearch/isbninquiry.asp?ean=1423901304"&gt;Management of Internet Security, 2nd
Edition&lt;/a&gt;
by Michael E. Whitman and Herbert J. Mattord. It seems pretty basic, and
very much focused on the management side of things (as opposed to
technical). The table of contents is as&amp;nbsp;follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to the Management of Information&amp;nbsp;Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning for&amp;nbsp;Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning for&amp;nbsp;Contingencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Security&amp;nbsp;Policy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing the Security&amp;nbsp;Program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security Management Models and&amp;nbsp;Practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk Management: Identifying and Assessing&amp;nbsp;Risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk Management: Assessing and Controlling&amp;nbsp;Risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protection&amp;nbsp;Mechanisms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personnel and&amp;nbsp;Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Law and&amp;nbsp;Ethics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Security Project&amp;nbsp;Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, given that it&amp;#8217;s really a &amp;#8220;management&amp;#8221; book, I can&amp;#8217;t say I&amp;#8217;m
surprised that it reads like an essay that was graded on a scale of
buzzwords-per-sentence. However, it seems to be missing the one chapter
that&amp;#8217;s the most important - actually, the only chapter that would be in
the book if I wrote it - &amp;#8220;How to get management to allocate the money
you need for proper security.&amp;#8221; In fact, skimming over the book, I found
a lot of content on general management planning, job descriptions,
sample policies, and a lot of other pie-in-the-sky stuff, but not one
concrete section dedicated to the most difficult part of security -
getting the &amp;#8220;resources&amp;#8221; to do it&amp;nbsp;right!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft&amp;nbsp;Lies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why we would spend time analyzing corporate mission statements in an
Internet Security class, I have no idea. That seems, to me, too much
like what we covered in &amp;#8220;Management of Technological Organizations.&amp;#8221;
But, we do, and one of the examples used is &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/About/default.mspx"&gt;Microsoft&amp;#8217;s Mission and
Values statement&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps,
being the F/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt; advocate that I am, my reading of it was a bit cynical.
Let&amp;#8217;s take a look at&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;At Microsoft, our mission and values are to help people and business
throughout the world realize their full potential.&amp;#8221; Well, we&amp;#8217;re off to a
good start. Aside from the fact that they want you to realize that
potential using &lt;strong&gt;only their software&lt;/strong&gt;, and use their power and money
to actively monopolize (or attempt to) most industries that they enter,
this seems pretty&amp;nbsp;run-of-the-mill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corporate Citizenship:&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8220;Every successful corporation has &lt;em&gt;a
responsibility to use its resources and influence to make a positive
impact on the world and its people&lt;/em&gt;. Microsoft’s Global Citizenship
Initiative is focused on mobilizing our resources across the company and
around the world, to create opportunities in the communities where we do
business, and to &lt;em&gt;fulfill our commitment to serving the public good
through innovative technologies and partnerships&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#8221; Well. Now we&amp;#8217;re
getting somewhere. Apparently &amp;#8220;a positive impact on the world and its
people&amp;#8221; is defined as trying to monopolize every sector that Microsoft
touches, whether attempting to crush and then buy-out the competition,
or through flat-out
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fear,_uncertainty_and_doubt"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FUD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and
billion-dollar marketing campaigns. Hmm&amp;#8230; innovative partnerships&amp;#8230; as
in&amp;nbsp;Novell?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Legal and Corporate Affairs:&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8220;Microsoft’s Legal and Corporate Affairs
Group works on the cutting edge of business and regulatory issues around
the world.&amp;#8221; Well, I can&amp;#8217;t argue with that, they sure are on the cutting
edge. What started with Bill Gates mailing out whiny letters about
pirated Altair &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BASIC&lt;/span&gt; has now turned into a global juggernaut, capable of
forcing the creation of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; standards at their whim, and successfully
quashing any dissent about obviously flawed and under-reviewed
&amp;#8220;standards&amp;#8221; (which, in fact, simply describe current software, rather
than setting any real&amp;nbsp;standard).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Values:&lt;/em&gt;As a company, and as individuals, we value &lt;strong&gt;integrity&lt;/strong&gt;,
&lt;strong&gt;honesty&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;openness&lt;/strong&gt;, personal excellence, &lt;strong&gt;constructive
self-criticism&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;continual self-improvement&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;mutual
respect&lt;/strong&gt;. We are committed to our customers and partners and have a
passion for technology. We take on big challenges, and pride ourselves
on seeing them through. &lt;strong&gt;We hold ourselves accountable to our
customers&lt;/strong&gt;, shareholders, partners, and employees by honoring our
commitments, providing results, and &lt;strong&gt;striving for the highest
quality&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;integrity&lt;/strong&gt; - i.e. not creating a draft &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; standard and then
    &lt;a href="http://www.networkworld.com/news/2007/083007-microsoft-employee-offered-incentives-for.html"&gt;offering monetary incentives for
    acceptance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;honesty&lt;/strong&gt; - when it works. Intentionally making Vista-Capable
    labeling so ambiguous that it even &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/09/business/09digi.html?_r=1&amp;amp;oref=slogin"&gt;confuses Microsoft
    executives&lt;/a&gt;?&amp;nbsp;Fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;openness&lt;/strong&gt; um&amp;#8230; did they seriously say that? Openness like&amp;#8230;
    protocol interoperability? Standards that can be implemented without
    patent violations? An &amp;#8220;Open Specification Promise&amp;#8221; that doesn&amp;#8217;t come
    with a &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/interop/osp/default.mspx"&gt;three page
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FAQ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;? Nope. Not&amp;nbsp;Microsoft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;constructive self-criticism&lt;/strong&gt; - Ok, I&amp;#8217;ll give them this one. They
    do, rarely, criticize themselves. Though &amp;#8220;constructive&amp;#8221; usually
    means making comments about the poor design of a previous product,
    and suggesting that everyone upgrade to the new&amp;nbsp;version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;continual self-improvement&lt;/strong&gt; - I&amp;#8217;ll give them this one too. In
    fact, they&amp;#8217;re so crazy about it that they&amp;#8217;ve been improving the same
    codebase for&amp;nbsp;decades!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mutual respect&lt;/strong&gt; - See&amp;nbsp;above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We hold ourselves accountable to our customers&lt;/strong&gt; - Ok. They &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt;
    offering to allow users to &lt;a href="http://download.microsoft.com/download/5/f/4/5f4c83d3-833e-4f11-8cbd-699b0c164182/royaltyoemreferencesheet.pdf"&gt;downgrade from Vista to
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;striving for the highest quality&lt;/strong&gt; - I don&amp;#8217;t think so. They&amp;#8217;re
    striving for products that have the highest &lt;em&gt;market share&lt;/em&gt;. As long
    as the quality is acceptable to the majority of users, and the
    products do what the majority of users need, that&amp;#8217;s fine. But
    wait&amp;#8230; apparently they even missed &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; goal with&amp;nbsp;Vista.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just the opinion of one person. My motivations may be diverse,
and surely there&amp;#8217;s a bit of zealotry in there. After all, if Ford told
me I couldn&amp;#8217;t put fog lights on my car myself, I had to bring it to the
dealer and pay $400, I&amp;#8217;d stop buying their cars - and make sure everyone
else knew what they did. But there&amp;#8217;s also my ever-present desire to make
sure people know both sides of the story, and all the facts. The
mainstream media (specifically dumbed-down television) rarely reports on
the less cheerful side of Microsoft, like the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#8220;standard&amp;#8221;
&lt;a href="http://www.networkworld.com/news/2007/083007-microsoft-employee-offered-incentives-for.html"&gt;scandal&lt;/a&gt;,
or the &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/09/business/09digi.html?_r=1&amp;amp;oref=slogin"&gt;Vista
letters&lt;/a&gt;,
or the
&lt;a href="http://yro.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=08/04/22/2032232&amp;amp;from=rss"&gt;Vista-Capable&lt;/a&gt;
fiasco. And I find this to be horribly disturbing. Many people don&amp;#8217;t
realize that there &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; alternatives to Microsoft products, even ones
that are provided by such big names as &lt;a href="http://www.sun.com"&gt;Sun
Microsystems&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.ibm.com"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IBM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But,
most striking, is Microsoft&amp;#8217;s overwhelming monopoly. Windows&amp;#8217; market
share is currently
&lt;a href="http://marketshare.hitslink.com/report.aspx?qprid=8"&gt;90.66%&lt;/a&gt; or higher.
I ask you, what other industries which affect not only consumers, but
nearly every aspect of our daily lives (as computing does) would be
allowed to have such a monopoly? It has happened in many other American
industries - oil, steel, the railroads, telephone service. Where is the
government&amp;nbsp;now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened to the America that made massive monopolies illegal? Have
we forgotten a supremely part of our history that began in 1980 with the
Sherman Act? Or even the recent events with Bell? In order to truly
stimulate competition in the software industry, and provide for not only
choice but the improved quality, reliability, and security that comes
with true software competition, something needs to be done. For
starters, how about breaking Microsoft into separate entities - browser,
Office, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;, server, etc. And - the important part - preventing any
package sales, discounts, or bundling between the separate types of
software (and separate&amp;nbsp;companies).&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="rutgers"></category><category term="school"></category><category term="security"></category></entry><entry><title>Microsoft and Novell Deliver Joint Virtualization Solution - or do they?</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/09/microsoft-and-novell-deliver-joint-virtualization-solution-or-do-they/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-09-11T11:40:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-09-11:2008/09/microsoft-and-novell-deliver-joint-virtualization-solution-or-do-they/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;From PRNewsWire: &lt;a href="http://www.prnewswire.com/cgi-bin/stories.pl?ACCT=104&amp;amp;STORY=/www/story/09-11-2008/0004883058&amp;amp;EDATE="&gt;Microsoft and Novell Deliver Joint Virtualization
Solution Through
Partners&lt;/a&gt;.
The headline of the press release: &amp;#8220;Supported by Dell and other channel
partners, solution includes &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SUSE&lt;/span&gt; Linux Enterprise Server running as
optimized guest on Windows Server 2008&amp;nbsp;Hyper-V.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, maybe I&amp;#8217;m not up on the news regarding my favorite distribution,
but it seems to me that a deal allowing SuSE to be virtualized as a
&lt;strong&gt;guest&lt;/strong&gt; under Windows is not only &amp;#8220;joint&amp;#8221;, but plain moronic. Despite
the marketing efforts of Microsoft, Unix-based systems (including Linux)
have always had the upper hand in availability, reliability, and&amp;nbsp;performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must say, from what I&amp;#8217;ve heard, Windows Server is getting *much*
better in these areas - and I&amp;#8217;ve even heard that the latest version
includes an option to install without a graphical environment, and even
includes a command-line that&amp;#8217;s useful. It&amp;#8217;s about&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it seems to me, that any virtualization deal between Microsoft
and a Linux distributor can provide only one logical solution: Windows
Server virtualized as a guest in a high-availability Linux host. More
importantly, without the insane per-processor licensing - a per-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;VM&lt;/span&gt;
instance license that&amp;#8217;s hardware-agnostic and allows VMs to be migrated
across hardware as the admin sees&amp;nbsp;fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and one more insight. If Microsoft wants to be a serious player in
the virtualization arena, here&amp;#8217;s a few &amp;#8220;simple&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get Windows Server to work correctly under Xen, VirtualBox, etc.
    Certify it. Provide the correct guest &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; tool&amp;nbsp;packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide simple management of Windows in a virtualized environment -
    minimally, a standard &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; server that&amp;#8217;s compatible with OpenSSH, a
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt;-less environment, and a serial&amp;nbsp;console.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get rid of per-processor licenses. Provide a basic license that
    allows for, say, 10 VMs to be running at once, and allows as many
    installs as needed - the only licensing is based on the amount of
    VMs actually running. i.e., if you have 10 VMs and one gets
    corrupted, you can bring that one down and online a back-up image,
    without violating the&amp;nbsp;license.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make licensing processor-agnostic. Want to migrate a Xen &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VM&lt;/span&gt; (Windows
    guest) from a dual-core Pentium to an 8-core Xeon, or even a 16
    processor &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SPARC&lt;/span&gt;? Sure, no&amp;nbsp;problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="novell"></category><category term="suse"></category><category term="virtualization"></category></entry><entry><title>Where are we going and what’s with the handbasket?</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/04/where-are-we-going-and-whats-with-the-handbasket/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-04-02T12:13:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-04-02:2008/04/where-are-we-going-and-whats-with-the-handbasket/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;#8217;s it. Not only did Verizon and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AT&lt;/span&gt;&amp;amp;T come out on top in the
&lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2008/03/20/fcc-releases-700mhz-auction-details-verizon-atandt-big-winners/"&gt;700MHz spectrum
auction&lt;/a&gt;
- promising an end to hopes of Google&amp;#8217;s utopian ideals of a truly open
network - but I just heard that &amp;#8220;Office Open &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221; &lt;a href="http://www.iso.org/iso/pressrelease.htm?refid=Ref1123"&gt;was approved as an
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; standard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think it even merits comment on my part. The world is run by
corporations. Corporations with more money than brains, hopes, or balls.
The 700MHz spectrum will become another copy of what American has now -
a resource (frequencies) that are &amp;#8220;owned by the people&amp;#8221;, yet controlled
by major corporations, and horribly biased
&lt;em&gt;against&lt;/em&gt; the interests of the&amp;nbsp;consumer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt; is now a standard. Is it any less flawed? No. Is it any
safer for me to implement? No. Does it even contain enough information
for me to implement? No. But it&amp;#8217;s a specification, and it&amp;#8217;s here. While
Jason Matusow may have stated that &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/jasonmatusow/archive/2008/02/26/open-xml-brm-day-2-thoughts.aspx"&gt;the patents related to the
technology are not a barrier to use - for anyone, in any country, for
all
time&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;,
I&amp;#8217;m still a bit worried about the issues that will crop up with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt; -
not to mention the fact that it&amp;#8217;s a standard squarely aimed at
eliminating choice (we all know Microsoft will push hard for
organizations not to use &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ODF&lt;/span&gt;) and preventing competition in a sector
already overwhelmingly dominated by &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, what happened in the past few weeks? A confirmation that the
governments and organizations of the world care little about the
individual, and fear change. They&amp;#8217;re owned by big business, and the
700MHz spectrum will end up being, at best, a marginal improvement over
the current restrictive cellular system. And big business doesn&amp;#8217;t even
have the balls to fight for itself. Or, even worse, doesn&amp;#8217;t worry about
vendor lock-in or proprietary software because, as long as they keep
bending over backwards to follow Microsoft&amp;#8217;s every whim, Microsoft will
always be there to help&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m surprised that even multinational corporations, who have a data
center filled with redundant systems, and fiber running in every
direction in case this or that &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CO&lt;/span&gt; goes up in flames, doesn&amp;#8217;t consider
closed standards, proprietary (possibly patent-encumbered) software, or
closed-source software to be as obvious a single point of failure as a
critical service running on a single desktop computer. Sure, your vendor
might tell you their software will achieve five-nines. But if they
discontinue support, or have a few bad quarters, and they won&amp;#8217;t fix it
for you, what&amp;nbsp;then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m just thankful that there are &lt;a href="http://blogs.sun.com/jonathan/"&gt;some
people&lt;/a&gt;, few and far between, that don&amp;#8217;t
fall into the&amp;nbsp;trap.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="700mhz"></category><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="ooxml"></category><category term="spectrum"></category></entry><entry><title>Flash - Why do you have to be the way you are?</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/03/flash-why-do-you-have-to-be-the-way-you-are/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-03-13T09:02:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-03-13:2008/03/flash-why-do-you-have-to-be-the-way-you-are/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just a little comment. I&amp;#8217;m usually not one to click on ads, but when I
saw a banner ad for a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEC&lt;/span&gt; projector with 3000 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ANSI&lt;/span&gt; lumens for under
$1000 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USD&lt;/span&gt;, I just had to take a&amp;nbsp;look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.necdisplay.com/Products/Product/?product=71957542-7825-400f-997e-c7a2b8a01d06"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEC&lt;/span&gt; product
page&lt;/a&gt;
has a nice little sidebar to &amp;#8220;Check out how &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEC&lt;/span&gt; displays are being used
by businesses&amp;#8221;. Hoping that they might say something about displaying
the output of an
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_management_system"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NMS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I decided
to go for a look. Now, a little note about my browsing habits. I use
&lt;a href="http://www.mozilla.com/en-US/firefox/?from=getfirefox"&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;, and
have since it came out. I can&amp;#8217;t use anything else - after all, I need my
two dozen &lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/"&gt;add-ons&lt;/a&gt;. Like any
good Firefox user, I use tabs. At the moment, I have about a dozen open.
Sometimes I have three times that (and I&amp;#8217;ve never found problems with
that. Try it in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IE&lt;/span&gt;, I dare you). (Side note - I don&amp;#8217;t understand how &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IE&lt;/span&gt;
can still have market share, but not have an add-on facility like
Firefox. Then again, they&amp;#8217;re 3 years behind in almost all&amp;nbsp;features&amp;#8230;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I unsuspectingly right-click on the link to &amp;#8220;Learn More&amp;#8221;, hoping for
a nice right-click context menu. What do I get? A Flash menu. I
Ctrl-click, and get the page I wanted - in the same&amp;nbsp;window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, it&amp;#8217;s not animated, there&amp;#8217;s no reason why they need Flash
to do what can be done with a simple image. Just another thing I hate
about wed design - the use of &amp;#8220;advanced&amp;#8221; technologies (read:
non-interoperable) when they&amp;#8217;re not needed. But more importantly,
respect your users&amp;#8217; browsing habits. The right-click menu has a purpose.
And if your users want to open a link in a new tab/window, let&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the converse side of things, why doesn&amp;#8217;t Macromedia get their act
together and make flash into a technology that follows the functionality
of the rest of the web? Surely right-clicking on a link wouldn&amp;#8217;t be that
hard to&amp;nbsp;implement&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="webdesign flash"></category></entry><entry><title>Microsoft $1.35B poorer</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/02/microsoft-135b-poorer/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-02-27T14:42:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-02-27:2008/02/microsoft-135b-poorer/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I almost forgot to link right to the&lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/mergersNews/idUSBRU00634320080227"&gt;article from Reuters about
the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EU&lt;/span&gt; fining
Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;
$1.35 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BILLION&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USD&lt;/span&gt; (899 million&amp;nbsp;euros).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft&amp;#8217;s monopolistic business practices are costing it billions of&amp;nbsp;dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IDEA&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
Actually be open. Open up all of your protocols, specifications, APIs.
Even start opening up some of your source code, under GPLv3, and
assigning patents to the &lt;a href="http://www.patent-commons.org/"&gt;Patent
Common&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.patent-commons.org/"&gt;s&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, your sales will go up. Maybe then Bill can donate the
next $1B in fines to some starving kids who need&amp;nbsp;laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously though, if I could get Windows Server under GPLv3, and do
whatever I want - fork it, whatever, I might buy a copy. I&amp;#8217;m sure a lot
of people would if they realized that they could change it, wouldn&amp;#8217;t get
locked in,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="patents"></category></entry><entry><title>Microsoft… again</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/02/microsoft-again/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-02-27T14:05:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-02-27:2008/02/microsoft-again/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20080227031234460"&gt;another Groklaw article on recent Microsoft
tribulations&lt;/a&gt;.
This really is starting to get disgusting. It&amp;#8217;s not that I hate
Microsoft, I don&amp;#8217;t. What I hate is their attitude, and their business
practices. Everyone else - I mean &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; - makes software that
interoperates with other vendors. Microsoft, even after a &lt;em&gt;billion&lt;/em&gt;
dollar fine, won&amp;#8217;t. Everyone else uses open, industry-accepted
standards. Microsoft doesn&amp;#8217;t. Many other vendors open up their code.
Microsoft tried to make some vague gesture to, but makes it incompatible
with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;d code (okay, okay, I know about &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ZFS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8230;) and says developers
can only use it in non-commercial projects. So they open a few things up
to hobbyists, and want a pat on the back. It boils down to how they
treat customers and developers. Not very well. I don&amp;#8217;t like that. I&amp;#8217;m
not going to start on the technical aspects of Windows, though it seems
to be getting better, a baby step at a time. But the bottom line is that
Microsoft actively tries to turn the software industry into a facist
dictatorship, where you do it Microsoft&amp;#8217;s way, or you&amp;#8217;re taken out back
and shot (ok, bought up and then shut&amp;nbsp;down).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, from the blog of Zeheda Bhorat, Open Source Programs Manager at&amp;nbsp;Google,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google believes &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt; would be an insufficient and unnecessary
standard, designed purely around the needs of Microsoft&amp;nbsp;Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can it be that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; - the International
Organization for &lt;em&gt;Standardization&lt;/em&gt; - would
actually consider a &lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt;,
competing standard for document formats. And one that&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.noooxml.org/argu-brief"&gt;as flawed as
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;? These guys are the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt;. They
practically run the world, at least technically. Why don&amp;#8217;t they have the
balls to look Microsoft in the eye and say, &amp;#8220;Hey, moron. We already
&lt;strong&gt;have&lt;/strong&gt; a document format
standard. It&amp;#8217;s called &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; 26300. If you want to have anything to do with
the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt;, which sets &lt;em&gt;standards&lt;/em&gt;,
you can take your 6,000 page specification, put it through a crosscut
paper-burning radiation-producing shredder, pay the $320 for a copy of
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO26300&lt;/span&gt;, and implement&amp;nbsp;it!&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="iso"></category><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="ooxml"></category></entry><entry><title>Making Available finally recognized for the sham it is</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/02/making-available-finally-recognized-for-the-sham-it-is/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-02-26T13:38:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-02-26:2008/02/making-available-finally-recognized-for-the-sham-it-is/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;From A &lt;a href="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20080226005921833"&gt;Groklaw article
today&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Atlantic v. Brennan&lt;/em&gt;, the courts have finally recognized &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIAA&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s
&amp;#8220;making available&amp;#8221; argument for the sham it is. Groklaw has a link to
the full ruling, which&amp;nbsp;includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least one aspect of Plaintiffs&amp;#8217; distribution claim is problematic,
however, namely the allegation of infringement based on &amp;#8220;mak[ing] the
Copyrighted Recordings available for distribution to others.&amp;#8221;&amp;#8230; This
amounts to a valid ground on which to mount a defense, for
&amp;#8220;without actual distribution of copies &amp;#8230;
there is no violation [of] the distribution right.&amp;#8221; 4 William
F. Patry, &lt;em&gt;Patry on Copyright&lt;/em&gt; § 13:9 (2007); &lt;em&gt;see also id.&lt;/em&gt; n.10
(collecting cases); &lt;em&gt;Perfect 10, Inc. v. Amazon.com, Inc&lt;/em&gt;., 508 F.3d
1146, 1162 (9th Cir. 2007) (affirming the district court&amp;#8217;s finding
&amp;#8220;that distribution requires an &amp;#8216;actual dissemination&amp;#8217; of a&amp;nbsp;copy&amp;#8221;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, finally, the judge
rejected the claims as being speculative, as they all rested on the
&amp;#8220;upon information and belief&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;statements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe things will start going in the right&amp;nbsp;direction&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a side note, if you still haven&amp;#8217;t read it, check out the &lt;a href="http://labs.google.com/papers/disk_failures.html"&gt;Google Labs
paper &amp;#8220;Failure Trends in a Large Disk Drive
Population&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;USENIX&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FAST&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8216;07).&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="copyright"></category><category term="IP"></category><category term="riaa"></category></entry><entry><title>I’m sorry, but I don’t like this contract anymore.</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/01/im-sorry-but-i-dont-like-this-contract-anymore/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-01-28T13:43:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-01-28:2008/01/im-sorry-but-i-dont-like-this-contract-anymore/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The other big news in tech today - as posted on
&lt;a href="http://yro.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=08/01/26/0341210&amp;amp;from=rss"&gt;slashdot&lt;/a&gt;,
the author of the pchdtvr/atscap package previously on SourceForge has
&lt;a href="http://sourceforge.net/developer/diary.php?diary_id=26407&amp;amp;diary_user=147583"&gt;announced his attempt to
&lt;em&gt;retroactively&lt;/em&gt; remove his package
from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;
coverage&lt;/a&gt;.
His post states, in&amp;nbsp;part,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have revoked the licensing under the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GNU&lt;/span&gt; General Public&lt;br /&gt;
License (herein after referred to as &amp;#8220;the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221;) for the&lt;br /&gt;
atscap version 1.1 codebase, all prior versions of the&lt;br /&gt;
atscap codebase and all the various release candidates of&lt;br /&gt;
the atscap codebase.&lt;br /&gt;
[&amp;#8230;]&lt;br /&gt;
As sole author of both the atscap and the pchdtvr codebases,&lt;br /&gt;
the licenses under the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt; were granted at my sole&lt;br /&gt;
discretion and the licenses under the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt; are now hereby&lt;br /&gt;
revoked at my sole discretion.&lt;br /&gt;
[&amp;#8230;]&lt;br /&gt;
If you are currently using the atscap or pchdtvr packages,&lt;br /&gt;
or any part thereof, it is in your best interest to remove&lt;br /&gt;
the software from your system(s) and destroy all copies in&lt;br /&gt;
your possession.&lt;br /&gt;
[&amp;#8230;]&lt;br /&gt;
If you have incorporated the atscap or pchdtvr codebase, or&lt;br /&gt;
any part thereof, into any of your projects, it is in your&lt;br /&gt;
best interest to remove any and all of my code from your&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;project(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So not only is this guy trying to retroactively unassign rights that he
has previously irrecovably assigned, but he&amp;#8217;s
&lt;strong&gt;asking developers to pull his code from
their codebase&lt;/strong&gt;???? I mean, that&amp;#8217;s not just an inconvenience. Does
he comprehend what he&amp;#8217;s asking? To pull a few excerpts from
&lt;a href="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/old-licenses/gpl-2.0.html"&gt;GPLv2&lt;/a&gt;:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may copy and distribute verbatim copies of the Program&amp;#8217;s source
code as you receive it, in any medium, provided that you conspicuously
and appropriately publish on each copy an appropriate copyright notice
and disclaimer of warranty; keep intact all the notices that refer to
this License and to the absence of any warranty; and give any other
recipients of the Program a copy of this License along with the&amp;nbsp;Program.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each time you redistribute the Program (or any work based on the
Program), the recipient automatically receives a license from the
original licensor to copy, distribute or modify the Program subject to
these terms and conditions. You may not impose any further
restrictions on the recipients&amp;#8217; exercise of the rights granted&amp;nbsp;herein.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently this is being &lt;a href="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=2006062204552163"&gt;discussed at length over at
GrokLaw,&lt;/a&gt;
including the analysis, &amp;#8220;If you change your mind and don&amp;#8217;t want to use
the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt; any more, you can stop and use something else on new code going
forward, and you can dual license your own code, but you can&amp;#8217;t redo the
past and pull back &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;d code&amp;#8221;. The developer is telling people to
delete their copies, and to cease distribution. Now, I&amp;#8217;m not a lawyer,
and I&amp;#8217;m not an expert on copyright law. But I didn&amp;#8217;t think that one
party to a contract could unilaterally alter it if there weren&amp;#8217;t any
terms allowing such an action, and the &lt;a href="http://www.fsf.org/licensing/licenses/gpl-faq.html#CanDeveloperThirdParty"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FAQ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;seems
to support&amp;nbsp;this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take an example: Your car breaks down. You have planned a family
vacation tomorrow. The car dealer, out of the kindness of their hearts
(ha ha) gives you a free loaner car. You sign the agreement to keep the
loaner until your car is fixed, pack up the car with all of your
luggage, and head off on the trip, stopping at a hotel along the way. In
the morning, you wake up, walk out to the hotel parking lot, and find
all of your luggage in a pile in a parking space - no car! On top of the
pile is a letter reading, &amp;#8220;we&amp;#8217;re sorry, but we decided that we don&amp;#8217;t
want you to have this free loaner car anymore. We&amp;#8217;ve taken it back. Have
a nice&amp;nbsp;trip.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My biggest curiosity, though, is what happened to the developer. He was
using the SourceForge account &amp;#8220;inkling&amp;#8221;, but it seems like both of his
previous projects are now gone, along with any other relevant
information. I&amp;#8217;d sure like to see his response to the community
regarding this&amp;nbsp;incident.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>700MHz - Salvation or more of the same?</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/01/700mhz-salvation-or-more-of-the-same/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-01-28T12:12:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-01-28:2008/01/700mhz-salvation-or-more-of-the-same/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest pieces of news in the tech world today is the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s
auction of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;700MHZ&lt;/span&gt; spectrum. I won&amp;#8217;t go into background - you can get
that from the wonderful TechRepublic article I just read, &lt;a href="http://blogs.techrepublic.com.com/hiner/?p=592"&gt;&amp;#8220;Sanity
Check: The 700 MHz auction will tip the wireless balance, but in which
direction?&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;. The author
makes some very good points. The bottom line is that 700MHz has the
capability to flat-out revolutionize mobile communications in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;.
Not only does it hold the possibility for a truly open network, where
devices and applications are carrier-neutral, but it had bandwidth and
geographical coverage possibilities that are revolutionary here in the
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;. With the right driving force, 700 MHz could begin replacing cellular
service altogether, with people simply buying mobile bandwidth and
handsets that are natively&amp;nbsp;VoIP-capable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 700 MHz spectrum has endless possibilities. It has the possibility
of revolutionizing mobile communications in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; and, most
importantly, letting us catch up with the rest of the&amp;nbsp;world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the topic of broadband, I also read another interesting article from
ComputerWorld - &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://www.computerworld.com/action/article.do?command=viewArticleBasic&amp;amp;articleId=310785&amp;amp;source=rss_news50"&gt;Keeping a lid on
broadband&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;.
Thanks to my involvement with &lt;a href="http://www.sun.com/"&gt;Sun&lt;/a&gt; as a Campus
Ambassador for Rutgers, I&amp;#8217;ve been in contact with other &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s across the
world, not to mention many people involved in the
&lt;a href="http://opensolaris.org/os/"&gt;OpenSolaris&lt;/a&gt; project. Here in New Jersey, I
have about 5Mb broadband to my home and apartment (5 Mb down / 2 Mb up).
Download rates rarely peak over 700 Kb. I was flat-out amazed, when
speaking with CAs from Japan, to learn that they have connections well
over 50Mb, and even 100Mb (!!!) to their homes, and they pay &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LESS&lt;/span&gt; than I&amp;nbsp;do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the broadband revolution has swept into urban and suburban
American homes, for the most part consumers are ignorant of the state of
broadband outside of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;. People remember 56k, and know that what
they have now is a lot better. How did the American public allow the
telephone/cable comapanies to force us into a position where we pay more
than citizens of almost any other developed nation for service that is
orders of magnitude slower, and markedly less reliable, than anyone&amp;nbsp;else?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;#8217;t touch on the topic of &lt;a href="http://www.savetheinternet.com/"&gt;Net
Neutrality&lt;/a&gt; - for me, one of the most
important current issues - aside from my anger at the thought that one
day, this blog (and the rest of my web presence) may disappear simply
because I don&amp;#8217;t want to pay money to an unknown third party. But I must
raise the question, &amp;#8220;what has happened to the rights of communications
customers in America, and how have we let our rights be ignored for so&amp;nbsp;long?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PS&lt;/span&gt; - If you&amp;#8217;re interested, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RCR&lt;/span&gt; Wireless has &lt;a href="http://www.rcrnews.com/apps/pbcs.dll/section?category=700MHzmain"&gt;ongoing coverage of the 700
MHz
auction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Piracy and options</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/01/piracy-and-options/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-01-25T13:44:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-01-25:2008/01/piracy-and-options/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, the semester is starting to heat up, and I have a bunch of
personal stuff I haven&amp;#8217;t posted yet. But I&amp;#8217;ll get to it this&amp;nbsp;weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the mean time, I feel the need to comment on an article I read
online, in Conde Nast Portfolio. It&amp;#8217;s a &lt;a href="http://www.portfolio.com/news-markets/national-news/portfolio/2008/01/14/Media-Defenders-Profile#page1"&gt;lengthy piece about
&amp;#8220;Ethan&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;,
the malicious user (I take great offense to the article using the term
&amp;#8220;hacker&amp;#8221; in the media-popularized sense) who broke into MediaDefender&amp;#8217;s
network and publicly released internal emails and even phone calls (I
guess there&amp;#8217;s a downside to&amp;nbsp;VoIP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let me say that while I utterly hate what MediaDefender does, I
don&amp;#8217;t view Ethan&amp;#8217;s highly illegal actions as being any different from
physically picking the lock on their office door and photocopying stuff
from file cabinets. It&amp;#8217;s theft of information. It&amp;#8217;s burglary. No matter
what the motive, it&amp;#8217;s illegal. And even worse, this wasn&amp;#8217;t a
socially-minded attack on one specific &amp;#8220;evil&amp;#8221; company, but some script
kiddie randomly compromising corporate networks. He happened to find
something interesting, of social value, and let the rest of the world
know about it. He deserves to rot in&amp;nbsp;jail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, I have two main comments on the article. First, one of
the entertainment industry execs flat-out says that &lt;span class="caps"&gt;P2P&lt;/span&gt; file sharing,
and BitTorrent specifically, have no positive qualities. Obviously, he&amp;#8217;s
not a Linux user. But the very idea that there are companies out there
trying to unilaterally crush the medium (BitTorrent) which lets me
download an &lt;a href="http://www.opensuse.org"&gt;OpenSuSE&lt;/a&gt; image in record time is
disturbing. But I guess nobody takes the time to tell these people that
there&amp;#8217;s lots of software on BitTorrent and, believe it or not, much
contrary to the Microsoft and entertainment industry view, there are
actually people out there who produce software and *want* people to be
able to get it for&amp;nbsp;free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, and most importantly, is the flat-out ignorance of the
entertainment industry. Traditionally, it&amp;#8217;s an industry that&amp;#8217;s been full
of what I call &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BS&lt;/span&gt;; focus groups, surveys, and customer feedback. Did any
one of these guys take the time to have a focus group agency sit down
with a hundred *anonymous* &lt;span class="caps"&gt;P2P&lt;/span&gt; users, and ask them why they use the
technology? Obviously, either they haven&amp;#8217;t, or they don&amp;#8217;t want to listen
to the&amp;nbsp;answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can only speak for myself and a few friends who I&amp;#8217;ve discussed this
with, but for us, it&amp;#8217;s not about getting something *free*. It&amp;#8217;s about
getting it how we want it - which most importantly means &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NOW&lt;/span&gt;. If I want
to watch a movie, I really don&amp;#8217;t want to drive to a video rental store.
I have a 5Mb internet connection, so I want to use that. I want to have
the movie *here*, now. Or not here. Maybe on my laptop, or on my Nokia
tablet. Or on my cell phone. Would I pay $5 for that? Sure. And there&amp;#8217;s
no reason why that&amp;#8217;s not a realistic price. If I can buy a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt;, in a
nice printed box, in shrink wrap, that had to be shipped to my local
Best Buy, for $10 or $15, then surely it would be reasonable to buy the
*content* of that &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt; for $5. The same goes with songs. I can&amp;#8217;t count
how many times I&amp;#8217;ve looked at a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt;, realized that I only want to hear
one song on it, and not purchased&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, perhaps more important, is the idea of options. People are used to
being able to use what they buy however they buy it. I&amp;#8217;ve heard many
times that the recording industry tries to push the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FALSE&lt;/span&gt; notion that
simply ripping an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MP3&lt;/span&gt; from a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt; - for your own use, or for backup
purposes - is illegal. More to the point, I use Linux. I can&amp;#8217;t buy music
from iTunes, or any other source that includes
&lt;a href="http://defectivebydesign.org/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DRM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. By including &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DRM&lt;/span&gt;, I&amp;#8217;m being told
that whoever sells that music doesn&amp;#8217;t want my business. It&amp;#8217;s that
simple. But this isn&amp;#8217;t an issue that&amp;#8217;s just limited to Linux users. What
if you own (gasp) &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MP3&lt;/span&gt; player that&amp;#8217;s not an iPod, and just shows up on
your computer as a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; mass storage device? What if your car stereo
plays &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MP3&lt;/span&gt; CDs? &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DRM&lt;/span&gt; is designed to tell these people that their money
isn&amp;#8217;t&amp;nbsp;wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I could pay $5, or even a bit more, for a movie or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; episode that I
could download, copy to my laptop or cell phone (I have a Treo 700p) or
tablet computer - or whatever else - I would. In an instant. It becomes
the retail industry&amp;#8217;s most powerful sales too - an impulse buy; instant
gratification. If I could pay $1 or $3 for a single song, of my
choosing, and play it on my Sansa &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MP3&lt;/span&gt; player, on my laptop, on my
desktop at work, and on an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MP3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt; in my car (truck), I would in an
instant (one viewer at one time = fair use). When will the entertainment
industry wake up and realize that a new distribution medium - the
Internet - will *help* them&amp;#8230; if they realize what people want, and
provide&amp;nbsp;it?&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Sun and MySQL</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/01/sun-and-mysql/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-01-20T02:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-01-20:2008/01/sun-and-mysql/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve got a lot to update about in the next few days. I&amp;#8217;m back in my
apartment for the new semester of school, I&amp;#8217;ve got a lot of
infrastructure work to do here (most importantly getting net-to-net &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VPN&lt;/span&gt;
with &lt;a href="http://www.dyndns.org"&gt;DynDNS&lt;/a&gt; at both ends working from here to
home, even if it means bypassing &lt;a href="http://www.ipcop.org/"&gt;IPcop&lt;/a&gt;
totally), and I also did some freelance administration over winter
break, including some work with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCO&lt;/span&gt; OpenServer and some work with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DF&lt;/span&gt;
generation - I also set up my own &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt; form filling system, which I&amp;#8217;ll be
posting in &lt;a href="http://cvs.jasonantman.com"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; once it&amp;#8217;s done. Most
importantly, the new mailserver has been up and running for 22 days
without any problems. And, by far the most exciting, I&amp;#8217;m typing this up
on my beautiful new &lt;a href="http://eeepc.asus.com/us/product.htm"&gt;Asus eeePC
4G&lt;/a&gt; (which I upgraded to 1 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt;)
running &lt;a href="http://www.opensuse.org"&gt;OpenSuSE&lt;/a&gt; 10.3 from a 4 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SDHC&lt;/span&gt; card -
A &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HOWTO&lt;/span&gt; will be coming soon. I&amp;#8217;m also going to be doing some work with
sitemaps on this site - specifically Google sitemaps - and building one
map for the blog, Mediawiki, and static content. I&amp;#8217;m also testing
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/"&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt; on my
&lt;a href="http://www.jasonantman.com"&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt; to augment
&lt;a href="http://www.mrunix.net/webalizer/"&gt;Webalizer&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;ll be updating the blog
in the next few days with a lot of&amp;nbsp;content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m also catching up on all of my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; feeds in &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/reader/"&gt;Google
Reader&lt;/a&gt; (yes, I use Google everything -
but not mail or Docs) which I mostly ignored over break. I started
yesterday with 780 items, and I&amp;#8217;m down to 500. I&amp;#8217;m also going to attempt
to start quick little &amp;#8220;links of the day&amp;#8221; entries, as it seems that it&amp;#8217;s
taking me too much time to fully blog on the interesting news of the
day, and my&lt;a href="http://del.icio.us/jantman/1-toblog"&gt;list of things to blog
on&lt;/a&gt; is getting way too long. (Just
as a side note, the only reason I really use
&lt;a href="http://del.icio.us"&gt;del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt; is so I can have the &lt;a href="http://del.icio.us/help/firefox/extensionnew"&gt;firefox
plugin&lt;/a&gt; sync my bookmarks
between the many machines I&amp;nbsp;use.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, on to the hottest bit of news today - &lt;a href="http://www.sun.com"&gt;Sun
Microsystems&lt;/a&gt; has acqured &lt;a href="http://www.mysql.com/"&gt;MySQL
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Now, I must say that I&amp;#8217;m an intern at Sun -
the Campus Ambassador to Rutgers University. Essentially, my job is
talking to students, professors, and staff and telling them that &amp;#8220;Yes,
Sun does open source, and they have a few things that should interest
you&amp;#8221; - in addition to giving tech demos, handing out CDs, and raffling
off t-shirts - and even a &lt;a href="http://www.sunspotworld.com/"&gt;SunSPOT&lt;/a&gt;. I
must emphasize that what I say here is my own opinion and nothing more.
Heck, I&amp;#8217;m an intern, it&amp;#8217;s not like I know any more about what&amp;#8217;s going on
at Sun than anyone else who reads&amp;nbsp;Digg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, lots of people are talking about the MySQL acquisition. I&amp;#8217;ve
heard every possible opinion, but it seems like lots of them are
worrying about something along the lines of Sun pushing a
Solaris/Apache/MySQL/Java stack on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SPARC&lt;/span&gt; hardware. Now, I&amp;#8217;ve been
watching Sun *very* closely for the past year or so. And I&amp;#8217;ve been
following &lt;a href="http://www.sun.com/aboutsun/executives/schwartz/bio.jsp"&gt;Jonathan
Schwartz&lt;/a&gt;
pretty closely too, especially &lt;a href="http://blogs.sun.com/jonathan/entry/in_a_vortex"&gt;his blog post about the MySQL
acquisition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t say anything as a Sun employee (I don&amp;#8217;t have anything more to
say than anyone else who follows the news) but, personally, I think a
lot of people who are worried are just missing the point. Sun used to be
a closed, proprietary company pushing Solaris on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SPARC&lt;/span&gt;. But it seems to
me, lately, Sun is all about options. Java&amp;#8217;s Free software now. Solaris
&lt;a href="http://www.opensolaris.org"&gt;has been opened&lt;/a&gt; as well. I don&amp;#8217;t get the
feeling that acquiring MySQL is about pushing Solaris instead of Linux,
or that it will cause Sun to ignore
&lt;a href="http://www.postgresql.org/"&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/a&gt; or Oracle/Solaris products.
It&amp;#8217;s about options. Just look at Sun in the news lately - more and more
Intel-based commodity hardware, Solaris, Linux, or even Windows on Sun
Hardware, Java,&amp;nbsp;OpenSolaris&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I very much get the feeling that Sun/MySQL is not about Sun trying to
force &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAMP&lt;/span&gt; out of the marketplace or, as some have conjectured, to turn
MySQL into a mostly proprietary product with minimal free version. It
seems to be about options. About diversity. Whatever you want, Sun can
help. Everything from million-dollar Enterprise servers running &lt;a href="http://www.sun.com/software/solaris/trustedsolaris/"&gt;Trusted
Solaris&lt;/a&gt; and giant
Oracle databases to Intel-based 1U or 2U &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAMP&lt;/span&gt; servers - or even, now,
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAMP&lt;/span&gt; servers on non-Sun hardware. (Though why anyone with the money to
do so wouldn&amp;#8217;t buy Sun hardware, I have no&amp;nbsp;idea).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for&amp;nbsp;more.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="mysql"></category><category term="sun"></category></entry><entry><title>Stallman and Free Software</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/12/stallman-and-free-software/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-12-21T00:28:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-12-21:2007/12/stallman-and-free-software/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve long been a fan of Free Software - both the technical aspects and
the moral implications. As such, I&amp;#8217;ve long been
somewhat of a fan of
&lt;a href="http://www.stallman.org"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RMS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and have followed his public persona.
I&amp;#8217;ve had the experience of exchanging
short emails with him, and was lucky enough to attend a speech of his,
entitled &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://www.fsf.org/events/rmsspeechrutgers/view"&gt;Copyright vs. Community in the Age of Computer Networks&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;,
here at&amp;nbsp;Rutgers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m a big fan of most of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RMS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s thoughts. I do, however, think of him as
a religious zealot. While his teachings may be pure and closest to &amp;#8220;the
right way&amp;#8221;, I find them a bit to pure for the lay-people; perhaps
they&amp;#8217;re more suited to the priestly class. Reading an
&lt;a href="http://itmanagement.earthweb.com/cnews/article.php/3717476"&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt;
with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RMS&lt;/span&gt; today, I came by an interesting response (&lt;a href="http://itmanagement.earthweb.com/cnews/article.php/12035_3717476_2"&gt;the first answer on
the second
page&lt;/a&gt;)
dealing with the use of proprietary software and drivers. I&amp;#8217;ll be the
first to say that I&amp;#8217;m a big fan of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;, including GPLv3 - granted most
of the &amp;#8220;software&amp;#8221; I write is shorter than the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I have a bit of an issue with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RMS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s stance. In my view, freedom
is the right of the masses. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt; speaks at length as to the freedoms
granted to a user of software. However, what of the responsibilities of
the developers? Compromise is part of life. Very few of us have the
privilege of being able to live an idealistic life free of compromise.
So, in my opinion, one of the most important aspect of free software is
the &lt;strong&gt;right of users to be exposed to
Free software&lt;/strong&gt;. This entails not only producing truly (purely)
Free software, but also the responsibility of us, the developers,
administrators, consultants, and manufacturers, to raise the world&amp;#8217;s
awareness of Free software. Most importantly, this must be done with the
long-term, &amp;#8220;big picture&amp;#8221; view in&amp;nbsp;mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I hadn&amp;#8217;t acquiesced to using proprietary video drivers, I never would
have gotten Linux running on my laptop. Unfortunately, I routinely have
the need to view multimedia files which are encoded with proprietary
codecs. This isn&amp;#8217;t a choice of mine - if I had an option of getting
files which only use Free technology, I would. But unfortunately, the
only other logical option is to run a separate system, running Windows
or Mac &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;, and transcode everything. But I have an issue doing that. So,
I do the best that I&amp;nbsp;can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the world view, most people aren&amp;#8217;t programmers. They aren&amp;#8217;t going to
actively seek out Free software, since they don&amp;#8217;t receive most of the
important benefits of it. Therefore, we as developers must make a
concerted effort to raise the awareness level of run-of-the-mill
end-users when it comes to Free software. Most importantly, for us, this
means actively working to create fully functional replacements for
proprietary software. However, the inherent problem is that most
end-users don&amp;#8217;t care whether they can see the source code of a program,
whether they can modify it, or whether it&amp;#8217;s Free. What they care about
is whether it works or not. If the average person buys a computer with a
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt; player, and wants to watch DVDs on it, they&amp;#8217;ll use whatever software
they need to do that. If Linux doesn&amp;#8217;t do it, they&amp;#8217;ll most likely use
Windows or&amp;nbsp;Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that the average end-user doesn&amp;#8217;t care about morals
or Freedom or getting source code. Because they haven&amp;#8217;t been shown the
advantages of that. For the average user to care about software Freedom,
they must be introduced to it. Most importantly, they must be introduced
to the *power* of Free software, not its&amp;#8217; limitations. Ubuntu is a
prime example of this - it&amp;#8217;s easy, and does a *lot* out of the&amp;nbsp;box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main point is the compromise is a good thing, with long-term
objectives in sight. In order for Linux, or any other Free operating
system, to gain significant share of the desktop market, it must &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WORK&lt;/span&gt;.
It has to do everything that end-users expect from a new computer
system, and do it without pain - out of the box. Limiting the software
options of an end-user to those which are religiously pure will limit
acceptance of that software to those who already share the ideals of
Free software. Provide a *mostly* Free alternative (i.e. free where
ever it is at all possible) which is functionally identical (or
superior) to the common proprietary alternatives, and users will adopt.
The more users that adopt, the more they will become aware of the
concepts behind Free software. More importantly, each and every user
that adopts will increase support for Free software, increase
development capabilities, and decrease reliance on proprietary&amp;nbsp;components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an issue of critical mass, of momentum. At the moment, we are
forced to make compromises by installing proprietary drivers on our
otherwise Free &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GNU&lt;/span&gt;/Linux systems. As can already be seen through Dell,
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ATI&lt;/span&gt;, and other major vendors, when the installed user base grows, the
reliance on proprietary software &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WILL&lt;/span&gt; shrink. As more people adopt Free
operating systems, vendors will clearly see this trend, and will respond
with Free drivers and Free alternatives to other proprietary&amp;nbsp;software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My cry to the Free software world is, therefore, that trading some of
our religious purity for a larger installed user base, and greater
public awareness, is ultimately in the interest of the greater good of
Free&amp;nbsp;software.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="stallman RMS GPL software proprietary free GNU"></category></entry><entry><title>Facebook Beacon; Linux in the Real World; Blog Updates</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/12/facebook-beacon-linux-in-the-real-world-blog-updates/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-12-15T22:57:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-12-15:2007/12/facebook-beacon-linux-in-the-real-world-blog-updates/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, for one thing, I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking about making more changes to my
blog. For one, I was thinking about ditching Blogger and just doing
everything myself server-side. My only qualm about this is whether using
blogger (a Google product) raises my Google rankings - after all, Google
rankings are a good thing. Also, I&amp;#8217;ve been toying around with the idea
of creating multiple feeds. Specifically, categorizing my posts into
descriptive categories, such as tech how-tos, tech news, personal views,
etc. and then offering either a combined feed or feeds of only a certain
category. If anyone actually reads this thing (I think most of my
readers come from searching specific topics, and probably only read that
post - though I don&amp;#8217;t have anything to support that). Obviously, to do
this, it would be easiest to handle the blog with software on my server,
probably something slightly&amp;nbsp;custom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="facebook-beacon"&gt;Facebook&amp;nbsp;Beacon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an update on Facebook Beacon, I came by
&lt;a href="http://yro.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=07/12/14/1620258&amp;amp;from=rss"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;
post on Slashdot, referencing a &lt;a href="http://www.computerworld.com/action/article.do?command=viewArticleBasic&amp;amp;articleId=9053002&amp;amp;intsrc=hm_list"&gt;ComputerWorld
article&lt;/a&gt;
questioning whether Facebook Beacon could possibly be sued, as it
appears to violate the Video Privacy Protection Act of 1988, which
prevents video rental agencies from disclosing the rental history of
their customers without a written release. Interesting&amp;nbsp;stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="linux-in-the-real-world"&gt;Linux in the Real&amp;nbsp;World&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being an avid Linux user, and a fan of both the functionality (from the
point of view of a user as well as a programmer) and religion of F/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt;,
I always like to hear stories of Linux (and other F/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt;) usage in the
&amp;#8220;real world&amp;#8221;. Especially situations where Linux is displacing Windows,
but really anything Linux-based in general. I can&amp;#8217;t wait for a Linux
cellphone that will do everything I want - though being a Verizon
customer, I doubt that will happen until they move to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GSM&lt;/span&gt; in a few
years. Some people accuse me of being anti-Microsoft. Sure, I am. Why
would I pay $200 for Windows when it doesn&amp;#8217;t do half of what my free
Linux does? I&amp;#8217;m not even going to touch on the moral aspects. But just
look at the &lt;a href="http://www.noooxml.org/petition"&gt;arguments against the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt;
standard&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft sure does do some
stupid stuff, and seems to miss the whole idea of the workings of
standards. If it only exists in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONE&lt;/span&gt; proprietary product, I don&amp;#8217;t see how
you can call it a&amp;nbsp;standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I found
&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/idg/IDG_002570DE00740E18002573B100020F62.html?ex=1355288400&amp;amp;en=1a1c847788830aeb&amp;amp;ei=5088&amp;amp;partner=rssnyt&amp;amp;emc=rss/ru/"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;
article from the New York Times, talking about how the New York Stock
Exchange is &amp;#8220;investing heavily&amp;#8221; in Linux on commodity x86 hardware,
replacing Unix mainframes, nonetheless. And what hardware are they
using? My beloved &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Proliants.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="facebook beacon blog linux NYSE"></category></entry><entry><title>Commentary - Best Products, or most hype?</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/12/commentary-best-products-or-most-hype/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-12-11T15:36:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-12-11:2007/12/commentary-best-products-or-most-hype/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In my usual lunchtime &lt;a href="http://www.digg.com"&gt;Digg&lt;/a&gt; reading, I came by a
link to the &lt;a href="http://images.businessweek.com/ss/07/12/1210_bestworst_products/index_01.htm"&gt;BusinessWeek Most Important Products of
2007&lt;/a&gt;.
Given the number of cars, it&amp;#8217;s apparent that this is a very
consumer-oriented listing. But I was a bit surprised - the first four
products were all from Apple - the iPhone, MacBook Pro, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; X Leopard,
and Apple &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;. While some of these are definitely interesting, I really
don&amp;#8217;t think that any other than the iPhone could be considered truly
important or groundbreaking. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; X Leopard and the MacBook Pro may be
wonderful for Mac users, but they&amp;#8217;re not really anything &amp;#8220;new&amp;#8221; in the
sense of ideas - they&amp;#8217;re just updated versions with more/better
features. Given the amount of hype that surrounded it, it was clear that
the iPhone would be on this list. And I will admit that, despite my
moral objections to it (bricking phones that innocent users unlocked),
the iPhone is very nicely done. But it&amp;#8217;s not anything truly &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEW&lt;/span&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s a
step in progression. There were phones with cameras, phones that were
thin, phones with touchscreens, and phones that played MP3s. Apple just
pulled all - and some extra - into a very nice&amp;nbsp;package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what else was mentioned? The Dell &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XPS&lt;/span&gt; One, some Mac-ish all-in-one
Media Center &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt;. It puts everything my computer has in one &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OEM&lt;/span&gt; package,
and adds on Windows Media Center, just to make sure it won&amp;#8217;t do
everything you want. And it even puts the entire computer inside a
monitor-sized enclosure, so if you crack the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LCD&lt;/span&gt;, you have to send the
whole thing back to Dell. Don&amp;#8217;t even ask me how the Braun Pulsonic
electric razor made it onto this list. Or a 30&amp;#8221; Gateway &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LCD&lt;/span&gt; monitor.
Yes, it&amp;#8217;s a big monitor. And it has a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; tuner. That makes it one of the
most important products of the year? Of course, there&amp;#8217;s also a 60&amp;#8221;
Pioneer &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LCD&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;, the Tivo &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HD&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVR&lt;/span&gt;, and the Motorola Razr2. All jazzed-up
versions of old ideas. And I&amp;#8217;m not even going to mention Windows Vista,
arguably Microsoft&amp;#8217;s biggest flop (other than Windows &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ME&lt;/span&gt;), which appears
on the list - though they do mention, &amp;#8220;While many users hate it, there&amp;#8217;s
little question that the operating system is selling extremely well.&amp;#8221;.
They mention that Microsoft said, in October, that it
&lt;strong&gt;had shipped 88 million copies of Vista&lt;/strong&gt;. While I don&amp;#8217;t totally doubt that figure, it doesn&amp;#8217;t take
into account the users who bought a Dell with Vista and then dumped it
for Ubuntu. Or even the (I imagine rather large) number of users, like
many of my friends, who bought that new computer with Vista and
immediately loaded their old &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XP&lt;/span&gt; Pro&amp;nbsp;disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, after all of that nitpicking, what do I think is&amp;nbsp;missing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The desktop processor revolution, with 64-bit systems becoming quite&amp;nbsp;common.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Intel and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AMD&lt;/span&gt; dual- and quad-core CPUs being put in consumer&amp;nbsp;machines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intel &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VT&lt;/span&gt; hardware virtualization&amp;nbsp;technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OLPC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Asus eeePC (well, this is still to be&amp;nbsp;determined)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motorola cellphones moving to Linux (as well as other&amp;nbsp;companies)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The portion of the 700-MHz spectrum set for auction by the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt;. (well, not a consumer product, but it could revolutionize mobile communications if it falls into the right&amp;nbsp;hands).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><category term="important businessweek vista iphone products"></category></entry><entry><title>Windows advances, Cutting out the middle-man</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/12/windows-advances-cutting-out-the-middle-man/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-12-07T16:29:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-12-07:2007/12/windows-advances-cutting-out-the-middle-man/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I have a nice weekend of real-world non-technical activities ahead of
me. A welcome end to a week of insanely busy school work, and a welcome
break before the threat of exams 2 weeks away becomes real. I&amp;#8217;ve been
working on a few projects - centralized logging and analysis, some way
to easily tie Nagios, log analysis, traffic analysis, etc. into a
one-look heads-up display, and a few other things. I even got the power
adapter for my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LCD&lt;/span&gt; so that I can have a try at the &lt;a href="http://www.tomsguide.com/us/supersize-your-tv-for,review-342.html"&gt;giant wall-size &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LCD&lt;/span&gt;
projector&lt;/a&gt;.
However, reading through my usual &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; feeds today, I felt the urge to
comment on a few&amp;nbsp;things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, for those who haven&amp;#8217;t heard, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SFLC&lt;/span&gt; and the BusyBox developers
have filed &lt;a href="http://www.softwarefreedom.org/news/2007/dec/07/busybox/"&gt;another
lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;
alleging &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt; violations, this time against Verizon for distributing an
Actiontec router to FiOS customers, sans source code. I&amp;#8217;m a FiOS
customer (in fact, the very text you&amp;#8217;re looking at is coming to you
courtesy of residential fiber) but got in on the wagon before they were
giving away these &amp;#8220;fancy&amp;#8221; routers. It&amp;#8217;s good to see, though, that the
F/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt; world is standing up for its&amp;#8217; values, and perhaps the mainstream
proprietary world will start to understand that just because you can
give a copy of BusyBox to your friends doesn&amp;#8217;t mean they can disregard
the&amp;nbsp;license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Windows Advances?&lt;/strong&gt;
I came by &lt;a href="http://blogs.ittoolbox.com/linux/locutus/archives/if-the-gui-is-so-good-then-why-is-microsoft-dropping-it-20951?e=unrec#commentsForm"&gt;this blog
post&lt;/a&gt;
discussing the fact that, apparently, Windows 2008 is going to be able
to be installed in a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt;-only (yes, that&amp;#8217;s right, no &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt;)&amp;nbsp;mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not going to preach about Microsoft turning unix-y. Rather, I think
it just reiterates something that I&amp;#8217;ve said time and time
again:&lt;em&gt;I&amp;#8217;m setting up a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; server.
It&amp;#8217;s going to be administered in a web &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; or by scripts. Why should I
tie up &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt; and processor cycles to display a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; that, if the system
works right, will never be looked&amp;nbsp;at?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than seeing this
as some victory for Linux, Unix, etc., I take it a bit more
realistically (though still, perhaps, over-optimistically):
Maybe Microsoft is finally realizing that their one-size-fits-all
mentality doesn&amp;#8217;t work. That people want options. And, even more
mysteriously, that not everyone wants to have to buy the newest hardware
just to run an&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cutting out the Middle Man:&lt;/strong&gt;
I found and &lt;a href="http://www.internetnews.com/stats/article.php/3655796"&gt;article at
internetnews.com&lt;/a&gt;
entitled
&amp;#8220;The Young, Smart And Loaded Watch Online &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221;. Many parts of it
saddened me - like the thought of allowing providers to push
advertisement through my computer, or tracking my viewing habits in
great&amp;nbsp;detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this is something that&amp;#8217;s occurred to me many times. Firstly, I
already use &lt;a href="http://www.mythtv.org/"&gt;MythTV&lt;/a&gt; to watch tv. So,
realistically, I&amp;#8217;m already watching &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; on a computer. I have broadband
in both my home and apartment (and anywhere else I&amp;#8217;d want to be). I have
a coaxial cable coming from the wall, plugged into my computer. And I
have to hook a tuner up and capture the video. Why not cut out the
middle&amp;nbsp;man?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pay Cablevision somewhere around $30/month for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;. That covers not
only the content, but also the costs for them to maintain a vast network
of cable lines stretching from where-ever to my house. I already have
broadband, why not just get &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; over&amp;nbsp;that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, I doubt any provider would give me what I want. But let&amp;#8217;s
think about it for a moment. Their only cost is a datacenter somewhere.
I simply connect to a somehow-authenticated video stream over my
existing broadband connection, and watch &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;! All they need is a contract
to rebroadcast. They can even pay on a per-view basis, as they would be
able to tell who&amp;#8217;s connected to what at a given time. They just need a
data center with a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LOT&lt;/span&gt; of bandwidth, some sattelite or fiber video
lines, and a system to capture each channel they offer. It then just
gets&amp;nbsp;streamed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds wonderful to me. I&amp;#8217;m already paying for high-bandwidth, why not
pay a third-party to stream &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; to me instead of paying the cable
company? They don&amp;#8217;t need to maintain anywhere near the level of
infrastructure - no physical cabling, no satellites, and QoS would be
determined by each individuals&amp;#8217; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;. It would even allow me to have one
account and watch at home, at my apartment, or at&amp;nbsp;work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The catch, at least for me? Well, while this might be viable, the odds
are there would be a proprietary viewer application. That&amp;#8217;s bad.
Firstly, it&amp;#8217;s useless if you can&amp;#8217;t record it and watch it later, or
transfer it to another computer. But more importantly, the odds of such
a company embracing a standardized technology (like just streaming
everything over the web and depending on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSL&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt;-based
authentication) that will run on my Linux boxen is pretty&amp;nbsp;slim.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="lcd projector sflc busybox microsoft windows tv streaming"></category></entry><entry><title>Cutting out the middle man - Now Facebook stalks you!</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/12/cutting-out-the-middle-man-now-facebook-stalks-you/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-12-03T15:21:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-12-03:2007/12/cutting-out-the-middle-man-now-facebook-stalks-you/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those of you who aren&amp;#8217;t familiar, Facebook recently rolled out the
Beacon service which provides Facebook with &amp;#8220;advertising&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick overview is available at:
&lt;a href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/id,140182-c,onlineprivacy/article.html"&gt;http://www.pcworld.com/article/id,140182-c,onlinepriacy/article.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that whenever you visit a participating site (there
are over 40 so far, including Amazon, Ebay, and many others),
information in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;YOUR&lt;/span&gt; purchases, browsing habits, etc. is sent back to
Facebook. Most scarily, this continues to happen &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EVEN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AFTER&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;YOU&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LOG&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OUT&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OF&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FACEBOOK&lt;/span&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is all detailed in the blog of a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;.com security researcher:
&lt;a href="http://community.ca.com/blogs/securityadvisor/archive/2007/11/29/facebook-s-misrepresentation-of-beacon-s-threat-to-privacy-tracking-users-who-opt-out-or-are-not-logged-in.aspx"&gt;http://community.ca.com/blogs/securityadvisor/archive/2007/11/29/facebook-s-misrepresentation-of-beacon-s-threat-to-privacy-tracking-users-who-opt-out-or-are-not-logged-in.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2007, I&amp;#8217;ve become used to gross invasions of my privacy. I&amp;#8217;ve become
used to the fact that Facebook is becoming hopelessly commercialized,
putting ads in my MiniFeed, and turning into MySpace (albeit worth&amp;nbsp;billions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the Beacon technology is a gross outrage. Most users were never
informed of it - I know I wasn&amp;#8217;t. It acts surreptitiously, collecting
data on your purchasing and browsing habits, and sending that data back
to Facebook. Who knows what happens to it after&amp;nbsp;that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even worse, supposedly, some items purchased are published in your
MiniFeed on your profile - not only is this turning your profile into
even more advertising for Ebay, Amazon, etc. but it&amp;#8217;s not keeping things
exactly private. I guess this will make people think twice before buying
that blow-up doll on Ebay, but in all seriousness, I don&amp;#8217;t want to check
my profile one day and find a list of what I bought everyone for&amp;nbsp;Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few groups dedicated to this - One that I started:
&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=6061274374"&gt;http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=6061274374&lt;/a&gt;
and a few others:
&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=19940635616"&gt;http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=19940635616&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=14537275404"&gt;http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=14537275404&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most appalling, Facebook doesn&amp;#8217;t have any way to opt-out of the service,
and signing out of Facebook does &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NOT&lt;/span&gt; stop information from being&amp;nbsp;sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, if you use Mozilla Firefox (www.getfirefox.com) (you &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DO&lt;/span&gt; use
firefox, right???) you can use the BlockSite extension to (supposedly)
block all data from being sent to Beacon. (This isn&amp;#8217;t possible in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IE&lt;/span&gt;).
Details can be found at:
&lt;a href="http://www.wikihow.com/Block-Facebook-Beacon"&gt;http://www.wikihow.com/Blok-Facebook-Beacon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just another reason why it seems like Facebook is doing whatever they
want - more to the point, whatever will make them worth more. I
understand capitalism and their right to money, but given that Facebook
is valued at well over $1 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BILLION&lt;/span&gt;, and gaining every day, I&amp;#8217;d think that
at some point they can let the value even out a bit, and go back to
respecting their users. Specifically, at least warning users through a
mass message when they implement something like&amp;nbsp;this.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Short Commentary</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/11/short-commentary/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-11-30T14:09:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-11-30:2007/11/short-commentary/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just a short note today - it&amp;#8217;s an insanely busy week. I&amp;#8217;ve been
finishing up the web &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; for my print accounting system (previously
mentioned) and had to dive into &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CUPS&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IPP&lt;/span&gt; to pull out information on
whether or not a print job is printed in duplex. I&amp;#8217;ve also been going
crazy with raw &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PJL&lt;/span&gt; queries to get some information that doesn&amp;#8217;t appear
to be found in &lt;a href="http://www.faqs.org/rfcs/rfc1759.html"&gt;Printer-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MIB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. In
other news, I have an exam Monday moring in a class (Religions of the
Eastern World - my non-western requirement) that I&amp;#8217;m getting a D in.
Then I have an essay for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; History &lt;span class="caps"&gt;II&lt;/span&gt; due Thursday - I haven&amp;#8217;t even
read the books&amp;nbsp;yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Tuesday night, I have my first tech demo as a Sun Campus Ambassador,
a short OpenSolaris overview for &lt;a href="http://ruslug.rutgers.edu/w/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RUSLUG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
that should touch on the coll facets of DTrace, Zones, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ZFS&lt;/span&gt;, etc. as well
as the new installer. So it&amp;#8217;s going to be a pretty busy weekend. And I&amp;#8217;m
hard set on doing a kick-ass demo, despite some of the &lt;a href="http://directorymanager.wordpress.com/2007/11/28/an-open-letter-to-the-opends-community-and-to-sun-microsystems/"&gt;disturbing
things&lt;/a&gt;
I&amp;#8217;ve been hearing about Sun lately. If I can get OpenSolaris to boot on
my laptop by then, I&amp;#8217;ll use that. If not, I guess I&amp;#8217;ll be dragging the
PowerEdge 2550 over&amp;nbsp;there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, I was looking through Google Reader this morining (my
only source for news) and came by a LinuxInsider article on the
&lt;a href="http://www.linuxinsider.com/rsstory/60447.html"&gt;upcoming &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KDE&lt;/span&gt; release&lt;/a&gt;.
Being a user of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KDE&lt;/span&gt; since 2000, this interested me. However, what struck
me was a comment about the new&amp;nbsp;KOffice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was speaking with a supervisor at the Rutgers University student
computer labs the other day, and was pretty astonished to realize that
&lt;a href="http://www.openoffice.org/"&gt;OpenOffice&lt;/a&gt; isn&amp;#8217;t loaded on the lab
computers. Why? Because 99% of their &amp;#8220;patrons&amp;#8221; wouldn&amp;#8217;t know what it is,
and can&amp;#8217;t handle choices. &lt;strong&gt;Can&amp;#8217;t handle choices&lt;/strong&gt;. Or, at least, don&amp;#8217;t want them. It&amp;#8217;s attitudes like this
that lead to a world where you have &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONE&lt;/span&gt; cable company, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONE&lt;/span&gt; phone
company, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONE&lt;/span&gt; high-bandwidth &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;, and can only use &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONE&lt;/span&gt; cellular
provider&amp;#8217;s equipment on a network. I wonder how those same &amp;#8220;patrons&amp;#8221;
would feel if they went to a car dealer and were offered the option to
buy a Honda Accord, a Honda Accord, or maybe a Honda&amp;nbsp;Accord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I&amp;#8217;m concerned, the biggest issue is publicity. The users don&amp;#8217;t
want choices because they don&amp;#8217;t know about them. And I thought that a
University was supposed to educate people? How naive of&amp;nbsp;me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hanging out at the &lt;a href="http://www.midlandparkambulance.com/"&gt;ambulance
corps&lt;/a&gt; that I volunteer with (I
have nothing to do with the front-end web site) the other weekend, and
one of the women asked whether I had Microsoft Office, since she needed
Word for a project. She said she didn&amp;#8217;t want to pay $250. I asked her
why she couldn&amp;#8217;t use OpenOffice. She asked what it was. It&amp;#8217;s absolutely
wonderful to hear the astonishment in someone&amp;#8217;s voice when you tell them
that they can download something at no cost that does everything that
Word&amp;nbsp;does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, my question is how many of these &amp;#8220;patrons&amp;#8221;, mostly students, would
use OpenOffice if they knew about it? More importantly, how many of them
would use it if someone told them they don&amp;#8217;t *have* to pay $150 to put
Word and Excel on their computers? I know the functionality isn&amp;#8217;t
perfect, but I routinely open, edit, and then save back Word and Excel
files in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OO&lt;/span&gt; without a&amp;nbsp;problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, back to the point of this rant. Choices are good. Fragmentation is
not. We have OpenOffice, StarOffice, KOffice, and probably a bunch more.
I understand they&amp;#8217;re all separate projects with separate goals. But,
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IMHO&lt;/span&gt;, one of the biggest problems with open-source (and no-cost)
alternatives to proprietary software is getting the word out there. And
fragmentation makes that so much harder. If you ask a Windows or Mac
user what office package is most prominent, they&amp;#8217;ll probably say &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt;
Office. If you ask three Linux users, you&amp;#8217;ll likely get three different&amp;nbsp;answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;#8217;t about the moral battle of Free/Open Source vs. closed or
proprietary. This is about user experience. If there&amp;#8217;s a no-cost (and
even better, Free) package out there that does almost everything a
$150-300 package does, users should have the right to try it and see if
it works for them. And I can think of few places where that&amp;#8217;s more
important than cash-starved college&amp;nbsp;kids.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="open source"></category><category term="openoffice"></category></entry><entry><title>Open Letter to Facebook and Mark Zuckerberg</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/11/open-letter-to-facebook-and-mark-zuckerberg/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-11-22T20:59:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-11-22:2007/11/open-letter-to-facebook-and-mark-zuckerberg/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I sent the following as (appropriately enough) a Facebook message to
Mark&amp;nbsp;Zuckerberg:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dude, I know you&amp;#8217;re a big-shot, but I thought I&amp;#8217;d give this a try, just
giving you (and the Facebook team) some&amp;nbsp;feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m growing so frustrated with facebook that I&amp;#8217;m thinking of writing my
own alternative. If only I could get people to use&amp;nbsp;it&amp;#8230;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Facebook that I first signed up for (the first day I got my college
e-mail address in July &amp;#8216;05) was prefect. I could find pretty much anyone
in any of my classes. I could talk to pretty much anyone at my school,
or most other schools. Most importantly, it was a place to get things
done and connect. It was free of the pressure of overbearing commercial
influence. It was a place where college kids - and only college kids -
could&amp;nbsp;connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My suggestion, my plea, is to give us back the old Facebook, or at least
the option to use the old Facebook. The Facebook &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; was nice, but some
things don&amp;#8217;t work for it. You took away Courses. Now I can&amp;#8217;t find people
in my classes, because there are six different applications, each of
which needs to be added separately, and some of which work horribly or
not at all. I don&amp;#8217;t want all of that junk. I don&amp;#8217;t want to see a million
boxes with kid-looking drawings and zombies and pirates on someone&amp;#8217;s
profile. If I wanted to use MySpace, I&amp;#8217;d use&amp;nbsp;MySpace!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newsfeeds. I don&amp;#8217;t want to know who is trying to turn my friends into a
Zombie or a Warewolf, or something else moronic. Put an option on the
preferences page to get rid of everything through the Facebook &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt;. I
only want to know about stuff that was in the &amp;#8216;Classic&amp;nbsp;Facebook&amp;#8217;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the f*** is up with the advertisements in my homepage/news
display? You&amp;#8217;ve already got banners at the left, right, or bottom. Leave
the center panel for the content that I &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WANT&lt;/span&gt;. You can shoves ads
everywhere else on the page, but don&amp;#8217;t mix an ad for Differin Gel in
with news about my&amp;nbsp;friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make networks more opaque. I only want to know about people who are in
colleges or workplace-related networks. Maybe, and that&amp;#8217;s just a maybe,
high-school people. but in my opinion, opening Facebook to anyone with
an email address was the worst move you ever&amp;nbsp;made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, my suggestions?&lt;br /&gt;
1) The &amp;#8220;courses&amp;#8221; feature has fragmented way too much. Unify it on a
school-by-school or Facebook-wide basis. I don&amp;#8217;t want to search 10 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt;
apps to find someone in my class.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Let me choose whether or not to display Facebook &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; notices in my
minifeed page. I don&amp;#8217;t want to know about every time my friends use an
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; app.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Take Facebook &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; stuff off of profile pages. A standardized view is
easy, intuitive, and quick. Searching through a mile-long profile just
to find the Personal Info area is not good.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring back a college- or workplace-centric facebook.&lt;br /&gt;
5) Don&amp;#8217;t try to be MySpace. I stopped using them because of clutter and
annoying extensions. Now Facebook is doing the same thing.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Keep advertisements on the sides or bottom and, most importantly, out
of content&amp;nbsp;areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom line - Facebook used to care about users and communication.
Now you just care about profits and advertisers. If you don&amp;#8217;t want to
lose traffic when something better comes along, give Facebook back to
the&amp;nbsp;people!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Updates, SuSE Online Update Issues</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/11/updates-suse-online-update-issues/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-11-01T15:29:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-11-01:2007/11/updates-suse-online-update-issues/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been way too long since I&amp;#8217;ve posted an update. But I haven&amp;#8217;t been
doing nothing. In fact, I&amp;#8217;ve been quite busy - and not just with school
and Sun and the Rutgers job. So, I&amp;#8217;ll go through a few of the happenings
of the past few&amp;nbsp;weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="machine-online-update-problems"&gt;Machine &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Online Update&amp;nbsp;Problems.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I lost two machines. About a month ago, my main
storage machine (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;STOR1&lt;/span&gt;) running a 6-disk &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCSI&lt;/span&gt; array of 18.2-Gb disks in
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAID&lt;/span&gt; 0+1 lost two disks in an hour. Strange. Next time I was home, I
pulled the two bad disks (bringing it down to 4 disks total), put
OpenSuSE 10.1 back on it (10.2 won&amp;#8217;t play well with my old Compaq &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAID&lt;/span&gt;
controllers - the machine is a G1 Proliant &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ML370&lt;/span&gt;) and installed Bacula.
I&amp;#8217;m happy to say that after a weeks&amp;#8217; worth of work, I have Bacula
working and backing up 3 machines locally. Unfortunately, I have two
machines - my mail and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; server and my storage server with a 250Gb &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IDE&lt;/span&gt;
drive - that were running SuSE 9.3 (still!). They wouldn&amp;#8217;t take Bacula
from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt; or source, as the director (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;STOR1&lt;/span&gt;) was running Bacula 2.x and
the only RPMs available were 1.x. I attempted an Online Update through
YaST/YoU. Well, wouldn&amp;#8217;t you know, it ran, it updated, and the whole
system broke. I mean gone. I couldn&amp;#8217;t run *any* command in the shell,
at all, because - you guessed it - YoU updated glibc. To a much newer
version, and pretty much everything was linked to the old version. I
couldn&amp;#8217;t even &amp;#8220;exit&amp;#8221; to end my&amp;nbsp;session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, luckily, I had data on the 250-Gb disk and everything else on a
10Gb, so next time I was home, I put OpenSuSE 10.2 on the box, and I now
have a 250Gb Bacula storage target on the network. Maybe I&amp;#8217;ll even
upgrade to Gig-E sometime soon to speed up those slow weekly full&amp;nbsp;backups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="help-my-files-are-gone"&gt;Help, My files are&amp;nbsp;gone!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big
storage box with the 250-Gb disk has been called &amp;#8220;janus&amp;#8221; for years,
since I called my do-everything-box &amp;#8220;saturn&amp;#8221; and the rest were Saturn&amp;#8217;s
moons. Since then, things have become complicated enough that I adopted
a functional naming convention, and the box became &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;STOR2&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221; when I
re-installed the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;. Well, about a week later, I &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;d into saturn - a
10-year-old Gateway desktop,&amp;nbsp;40Gb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD&lt;/span&gt;, 192Mb &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt;, and a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PII&lt;/span&gt;-350MHz processor - that now runs my mail
server and is my externally-visible box to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; into. I ran &amp;#8220;ls&amp;#8221; in my
home directory, and got nothing. Nothing at all. It just hung there. I
exited and tried again. I tried as root. By then I had about a dozen &amp;#8220;D&amp;#8221;
state ls processes. I was stumped. I tried everything. My first thought
was a stale &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NFS&lt;/span&gt; mount, but I checked, and everything looked right. I
could ls portions, like &amp;#8220;ls a*&amp;#8221; and get good output. I could strace ls
and see all the right output. But I couldn&amp;#8217;t ls. Just the one directory
- not any subdirectories - but any user. I spent hours looking around,
to no avail. It wasn&amp;#8217;t until two nights ago - about a week into the
problem - that I finally gave up and rebooted to get rid of those
now-zombie processes. And, wouldn&amp;#8217;t you know, ls worked perfectly. Why?
Yeah, you probably guessed that, too. When I looked over fstab and
mount, everything looked normal - except that after two years, the
hostname &amp;#8220;janus&amp;#8221; looked perfectly correct to&amp;nbsp;me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rack"&gt;Rack.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some discussion with
my roommates, last Friday night I found a 42U Compaq rack enclosure -
complete with wheels, door, and a side panel, on Craigslist from a
seller a few towns over. We all drove over in the truck and, $65 later,
we now have a 42U rack in the living room of our apartment. It&amp;#8217;s a thing
of beauty. We got it setup around 10:30 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt;, and Joe and I were up until
6 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt; the next morning bringing down the network, moving hardware to the
rack, re-cabling, and bringing everything back up. We did hit a few
snags - mainly because I demanded an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; switch from 192.168.0.xxx to
192.168.2.xxx so that I could easily setup a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VPN&lt;/span&gt; from the IPcop firewall
at the apartment to its&amp;#8217; matching counterpart in my basement at home.
Well, things are still being added to the rack, but it&amp;#8217;s coming along
very&amp;nbsp;nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="/GFX/rack1sm.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rack&lt;/strong&gt; - (clockwise from top left) some ballast in the bottom (an
ancient Proliant 6000 with 12 or so &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCSI&lt;/span&gt; disks and 3 power supplies, 3x
220MHz pentium, not running), 3 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt; - Joe troubleshooting the IPcop box,
with the rack almost fully loaded, Soekris net4501 as a temporary
firewall/router (running m0n0wall), me in my new home&amp;#8230;err&amp;#8230;&amp;nbsp;rack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vpn"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;VPN&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main impetus behind the
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; switch was my desire to have an IPsec &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VPN&lt;/span&gt; between home and the
apartment. Beyond ease of use, a good intranet, and the hope of being
able to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; into my various&amp;nbsp;boxen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;without going through saturn, my one externally-visible &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; server, I
was also psyched about the idea of small backups with Bacula over the
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;VPN&lt;/span&gt;, and the hope of getting two Nagios boxes - one at each end - that
would work in concert. Well, of course, the subnet mask here is /22 and
everything at home is still /24, so it&amp;#8217;s going to take a bit of work
this weekend, but hopefully everything will come together well. Stay&amp;nbsp;tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="pbx"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PBX&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was working on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VPN&lt;/span&gt;
stuff, Joe took it upon himself to forcibly commandeer one of my spare
boxes and setup
&lt;a href="http://www.trixbox.org/"&gt;Trixbox&lt;/a&gt; (formerly Asterisk @ Home) on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;. At the moment, we&amp;#8217;re
waiting for an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FXO&lt;/span&gt; card to show up in the mail - and for the money to
get a few &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIP&lt;/span&gt; phones for testing - but it looks like it&amp;#8217;ll all be up and
running, and we may even move over to VoIP in the apartment. To make
things better, we have Festival working, and I&amp;#8217;m well on my way to a
Nagios interface that will be able to dial an extension (or dial out)
and speak an&amp;nbsp;alert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conserver"&gt;Conserver.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of stuff on the rack has serial console access - switches, IPcop, routers, development
stuff, and - hopefully soon - some Sun hardware. So, a terminal server
sounded great. After some research, I came up with two possibilities - a
&lt;a href="http://www.eng.auburn.edu/users/doug/console.html"&gt;page&lt;/a&gt; from 1998
giving an example of a kludge of a console server using &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GNU&lt;/span&gt; Screen, and
&lt;a href="http://www.conserver.com/"&gt;conserver&lt;/a&gt;, a purpose-built application that
can operate in a client-server model over the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;, and also includes
good handling of locking on a per-user basis and console locking. I
planned two incarnations of the console server - the first and current
development machine is an ancient &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PII&lt;/span&gt; laptop with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;192MB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt; drive,
10Gb &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD&lt;/span&gt;, networking, and serial and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; ports. I decided to give serial
to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; adapters a&amp;nbsp;shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first installation was &lt;a href="http://www.debian.org/"&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;-based, as
&lt;a href="http://www.opensuse.org/"&gt;OpenSuSE&lt;/a&gt; 10.2 won&amp;#8217;t load on such an old
machine. However, after grappling with learning a new distro, I opted to
reinstall with &lt;a href="http://www.centos.org/"&gt;CentOS&lt;/a&gt; 5.0, a much more natural
transition from SuSE. After installing CentOS, it only took me a few
hours to get everything humming away, and get conserver compiled,
installed, and running. Configuration is fairly simple though, on my
next box, I&amp;#8217;m going to have it install to the locations I&amp;#8217;m used to -
/bin instead of /usr/local/bin, etc. All in all, it seems to work well.
I didn&amp;#8217;t try networked mode, but it works beautifully by SSHing into the
box. It handles multiple users on the same console very well, shows the
status of the consoles, and allows stealing of locks. I&amp;#8217;m working on
writing a Nagios check script for it in Python, but be warned - a
console&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;up&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;down&amp;#8221; status is simply whether the port is open. You
can, obviously, pull the cable from the device and still see&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;up&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one issue with this kludgey test setup is that my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; serial
adapters seem to change device names on reboot. I currently have two,
and at the last reboot, /dev/ttyUSB0 and /dev/ttyUSB1 switched names
which created some confusion. When I get around to it, I plan on getting
a small, quiet, older (and cheap) 1U server with a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PCI&lt;/span&gt; slot to serve as
the console server. I have a few spare Equinox breakout cables for
multiport serial cards, and I might be able to find and use a card that
they&amp;nbsp;fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="netra"&gt;Netra.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while, I&amp;#8217;ve been
wanting to try Solaris, and I can&amp;#8217;t think of a better way to do it than
buying some Sparc hardware, for the fun of it. Well, I found a Sun Netra
T1 on Ebay, 500MHz Sparc-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;II&lt;/span&gt;, 512Mb &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt;, 40Gb &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCSI&lt;/span&gt;) for $47 on Ebay,
and couldn&amp;#8217;t resist it. I ordered it Sunday night. Sure enough, Tuesday
afternoon, I get the following&amp;nbsp;E-Mail:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello,
This is Bcd-parts. we contact you because we make a mistake in this
item: 230185304870. we put it online but we sell it before, so we do not
have any of this item. I&amp;#8217;m apologize about this mistake, we will refund
the money as soon you respond back the email.
Thank&amp;nbsp;you!&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazingly, I was able to resolve the issue that day, and the refund is
being processed. However, I don&amp;#8217;t have my&amp;nbsp;server!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="nagios"&gt;Nagios.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m a big fan of
&lt;a href="http://www.nagios.org/"&gt;Nagios&lt;/a&gt;. I use it at home to monitor all of my
hosts, as well as some remote systems that I&amp;#8217;m responsible for. I make
heavy use of the check_by_ssh plugin, so that it doesn&amp;#8217;t require any
infrastructure past pubkey authentication for the Nagios user. Now that
I have a few systems running in the apartment also, once I get the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VPN&lt;/span&gt;
setup, I&amp;#8217;ll be installing Nagios down here as well, and probably trying
to tackle the task of setting up the two servers to jive by passing
passive check results of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt; hosts to each&amp;nbsp;other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="print-quota"&gt;Print&amp;nbsp;Quota.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a shared
laser printer in the apartment, used by all five people living there.
It&amp;#8217;s a low-end Brother model. After a discussion one evening, I got very
interested in finding out how many pages each user is printing. The
built-in print server doesn&amp;#8217;t provide this functionality, nor does it
support &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JCL&lt;/span&gt;. So, I googled for a solution&amp;#8230; and, amazingly, didn&amp;#8217;t find
one. The most that I could find is that there are two big Unix-based
print quota packages, but both of them require a print server between
the network and the printer - an option that I may consider, but don&amp;#8217;t
really want to implement. I don&amp;#8217;t need the ability to deny printing, or
figure out how much toner is used, or anything fancy like that - I just
want to find out how many pages each user on a defined list&amp;nbsp;prints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some brainstorming, I came up with an awful kludge that might
work. I wrote a Python script that screen-scrapes the print server&amp;#8217;s web
interface for the current lifetime page count and status. The concept is
essentially that I put a server on the network, and configure the switch
so that it is a monitor port for the printer. I then have access to the
printer&amp;#8217;s page count and all traffic to/from the printer. I&amp;#8217;ve
thought of two ways to get the page count of a&amp;nbsp;job:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dump all of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TCP&lt;/span&gt; traffic to the printer. When a job starts, find
    the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; (and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MAC&lt;/span&gt;?) that started it. Wait for it to finish. Wait a few
    seconds, check the printer status, if it&amp;#8217;s back to &amp;#8220;ready&amp;#8221;, get the
    page&amp;nbsp;count.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dump the traffic to the printer. Analyze all traffic to extract the
    print job information, and get the page count there. Then check
    against the printer&amp;#8217;s web interface (so we don&amp;#8217;t count pages when it
    ran out of paper or&amp;nbsp;jammed).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, #2 is much more complex. However, #1 already is wrought
with edge cases - two users printing simultaneously, a paper jam that
causes the printer to wait (and the script times out and returns a page
count of 0), etc. We&amp;#8217;ll see where I get in designing a&amp;nbsp;solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once each job is complete, and we have a page count, we can put that
into a database with the date and time, page count, printer name (the
advantage to this is that it would theoretically support multiple
printers as long as it could see their traffic), client &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MAC&lt;/span&gt;, and
client username (looked up from a table mapping &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MAC&lt;/span&gt; to&amp;nbsp;username).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="surplus"&gt;Surplus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the wonderful
things about working for Rutgers is that they own millions of dollars of
computer equipment. Usually, it seems like when they&amp;#8217;re done with it, it
falls into a black hole of buybacks, trade-ins, and disposal. However,
it just so happened that my department has a lot of stuff they&amp;#8217;re
getting rid of, and I was able to work out an employee purchase before
it disappears. So, coming to a rack in my living room (or my basement at
home) is a Dell PowerEdge 2550, PowerEdge 650, two rackmount
monitor/keyboard/mouse units, a BackUPS Pro 1400 (no monitoring, but
better than nothing), a BayStack 350T-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HD&lt;/span&gt; switch, a Xerox DocuPritn
N4525, and a few other goodies. I&amp;#8217;m already working on putting OpenSuSE
10.3 as Xen dom0 on the 650 and Solaris &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SXCE&lt;/span&gt; 11 (built 75) on the 2550.
We&amp;#8217;ll see what happens with it all&amp;nbsp;soon&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Why Doesn’t it Just Work</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/10/why-doesnt-it-just-work/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-10-02T13:21:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-10-02:2007/10/why-doesnt-it-just-work/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well I just finished a healthy 2-hour session with &lt;a href="http://reader.google.com"&gt;Google
Reader&lt;/a&gt; and have a few things to comment on,
but at the moment, I just wanted to make a quick&amp;nbsp;post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been using Linux for five years. I&amp;#8217;m in the process of planning to
move a lot of my servers and development systems to the openSolaris
operating system. Overall, I&amp;#8217;m a pretty technical person. While I admit
to occasionally using &lt;a href="http://www.webmin.com"&gt;Webmin&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;#8217;m perfectly
comfortable editing the Apache config files by hand. That being said,
with all of the recent emphasis on Linux as a desktop machine (for end
users!) there are some things that I expect to &amp;#8220;just work&amp;#8221;. When I
upgraded for openSuSE 10.2, and now 10.&lt;span class="caps"&gt;3RC1&lt;/span&gt;, I expected some good
desktop technology - granted, openSuSE isn&amp;#8217;t the choice for a &amp;#8220;just
works&amp;#8221; end-user&amp;nbsp;desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One word. &lt;strong&gt;Printing.&lt;/strong&gt; Despite how I&amp;#8217;ve tried, I still can&amp;#8217;t get my
Linux boxen to print well. Printing a webpage from Firefox requires
endless tweaking of borders, margins, and other nasty stuff. If I happen
to be in a new location and print something, I grab a pen, as I know
that the headers and footer/last few lines of text on my web page will
be cut off, unless I&amp;#8217;ve tweaked the margins for the specific&amp;nbsp;printer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this the case? Of all the things that people want Linux to do,
this seems like a simple one. The printable area of an 8 1/2x11&amp;#8221; piece
of paper is relatively standard. The actual printable margins for a
given printer are well known. So why is it the my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HP&lt;/span&gt; LaserJet or my
roommate&amp;#8217;s Brother &lt;span class="caps"&gt;5500DN&lt;/span&gt; is such a mystery to&amp;nbsp;Linux?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="linux suse printing"></category></entry><entry><title>PCpro UK: Boycott ad-blocking Firefox, urges furious web designer</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/09/pcpro-uk-boycott-ad-blocking-firefox-urges-furious-web-designer/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-09-17T14:04:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-09-17:2007/09/pcpro-uk-boycott-ad-blocking-firefox-urges-furious-web-designer/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When browsing through &lt;a href="http://digg.com/"&gt;Digg&lt;/a&gt; this morning, I came by a
story at PCpro &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt; entitled &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://www.pcpro.co.uk/news/news/124719/"&gt;Boycott ad-blocking Firefox, urges furious
web designer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;. This gentleman
stated that, &amp;#8220;Software that
blocks all advertisement is an infringement of the rights of website
owners and&amp;nbsp;developers.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I don&amp;#8217;t like giving press to such a story, I found it alarming on
many&amp;nbsp;levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I&amp;#8217;ve never heard of rights of website owners and developers.
Being a &amp;#8220;website owner and developer&amp;#8221; myself, I understand that the web
is a dynamic medium. Moreover, I think of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; as what it is - a markup
language. It just tells a program (browser) how to display something in
a user-friendly style. I test my pages with Lynx, and expect them to
conform to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;/1.1. In other words, I believe that the Internet is an
information distribution tool. I expect, I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt;, my content to be
viewable by as many people as possible. I try to use simple markup and
make use of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ALT&lt;/span&gt; tags so that as many people as possible will be able to
view the content. I want it to make sense on as many platforms as
possible. I want people who need accessibility aids to be able to
understand it. In short, I want my content to reach as many people as&amp;nbsp;possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only is this developer trying to do something which is ignorant and
a case of being a flat-out bad citizen of the &amp;#8216;net, but he is trying to
fight against the progress which has so painstakingly been made in the
field of web standardization. I well remember when, not long ago at all,
I was handicapped by my choice of using Firefox. I still come by the odd
site which chose to use a component which is tied to Internet Explorer,
thereby alienating 35% of web&amp;nbsp;users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will admit that I am by no means the typical Internet user. The fact
that all of my some dozen or so machines (excepting one which I need to
use a legacy &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCSI&lt;/span&gt; flatbed scanner) run 100% Free/Open Source software. I
use Linux. OpenSolaris. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BSD&lt;/span&gt;. I believe that I have a right to examine
and modify the source code of the programs that I use. When choosing a
bug tracking system, I spent hours customizing an open-source
alternative because I was unwilling to use the closed-source option
which seemed to fit best. Therefore, I guess it is easy to understand
that I refuse to buy from, or even visit, a web site that doesn&amp;#8217;t
support&amp;nbsp;Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a browser war. This is not me simply deciding to flame
someone who isn&amp;#8217;t a F/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt; zealot. This boils down to a deeper issue that
can be seen all around us - including in the recent news surrounding the
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s auction of a portion of the 700MHz spectrum. The issue at hand
is the complacency of technology users, and the feeling by technology
providers that they can push anything they want on users. The concept
that providers are sending data to me, and that I can use that data
however I want (within the extent of the law) is getting&amp;nbsp;lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I watch &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;, I used to leave the room or pick up a book when a
commercial comes on. Now that I have a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PVR&lt;/span&gt; (specifically, MythTV), I can
record the shows I want, and then have commercials flagged for automatic
skipping before I watch them. When I decide to watch them, I have no
commercials. When I use the web, I select the content that I want. If I
don&amp;#8217;t want it, I don&amp;#8217;t get&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, another large issue at hand is the simple nature of digital
media. This applies to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; recording, music and movie sharing, software
piracy, etc. Digital media is not the same as analog media. An &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MP3&lt;/span&gt; (or,
for that matter, a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt;) is not the same as a tape. In product litigation,
there is a term known as &amp;#8220;perceived use&amp;#8221;. If you make a glass coffee
table that is exactly at knee height, it is perceived that eventually,
someone will try to sit on it. That&amp;#8217;s common sense. If it shatters and
kills them, it was your responsibility to foresee such an obvious
eventuality. It&amp;#8217;s only common sense that if something is flat and at
normal sitting level, someone will try to sit on&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, I would argue that when any content is distributed digitally,
you must foresee that it will be copied or altered. It is simply the
nature of the medium. If the recording industry didn&amp;#8217;t want people
ripping music from CDs, they should have kept releasing things on tape.
Even more so with DVDs - I&amp;#8217;m sure we all remember the push. Five years
ago, I was hard pressed to find a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt; in a local rental store. Today, I
haven&amp;#8217;t seen a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHS&lt;/span&gt; tape in years. The industry *pushed* the format on
us, and is now complaining when we use it in a brutally obvious way. If
I had to liken it to any legal phenomenon, I would pick entrapment. It&amp;#8217;s
not a far stretch to compare the recording industry&amp;#8217;s actions to those
of a police officer who leaves a car running, with the keys in the
ignition, and a sign on the windshield that says &amp;#8220;Take me for a spin
around the parking lot&amp;#8221; and then arrests someone for auto theft when
they leave the lot. If they industry is worried about piracy, it should
have been their obligation to look into exactly how easy piracy would
be, before they chose a distribution&amp;nbsp;medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In closing my rant, I will ask a few simple&amp;nbsp;questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it that the law, being as biased to corporate interests (and
against the individual) as it is, doesn&amp;#8217;t recognize the rights of the
individual to use what they legally purchased in a way that they see
fit? (i.e. if I buy a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt;, I should be able to make a backup copy on my
computer - even the &lt;em&gt;copyright law&lt;/em&gt; states&amp;nbsp;that).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long will it be before someone turns up an internal &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIAA&lt;/span&gt; memo
from ten years ago stating that the industry could increase its&amp;#8217; profits
by releasing music on a medium (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt;) that is prone to piracy, and then
fining the people who exploit that common&amp;nbsp;sense?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When they came out with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHS&lt;/span&gt; recorders, the industry was up in arms
about piracy. So, they got together and added a small amount on the
price of every blank tape, intended to reimburse the
labels/artists/networks for the copy that it would be used to make. Why
can&amp;#8217;t they just tack $3 onto every blank &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt;, $20 on every blank
hard drive, and stop suing college&amp;nbsp;kids?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><category term="ad blocker"></category><category term="firefox"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="standards"></category></entry><entry><title>Relational / Object-Oriented Asset Management</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/02/relational-object-oriented-asset-management/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-02-21T16:27:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-02-21:2007/02/relational-object-oriented-asset-management/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just purchased four new servers, and set out to find some good asset
management software. Specifically, I&amp;#8217;m looking for a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; package that
allows me to track the details of all of my hardware. While software and
configuration tracking would surely be good for some applications, I
already have a package to handle&amp;nbsp;that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I searched a few popular sites, including SourceForge, and came up with
a dozen or so possibilities that looked good. They varied in level of
detail and features, but all had one common failure - they lack an
object-oriented or relational approach. What do I mean by that? Most of
them are designed so that you enter data in a form, it goes into a
database, and exists just as a table of data. Devices, networks, etc.
exist&amp;nbsp;independently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I want? An object-oriented approach that can handle
relationships between objects, and hierarchies. Lets design a few
objects as examples: We&amp;#8217;ll have Networks, Servers, Interfaces, Switches,
Hard Drives, and UPSs. They each represent the real-world hardware. An
interface, for our purposes, will be a physical way of connecting two
devices - an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NIC&lt;/span&gt;, serial line,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re experienced in object-oriented programming, you can think of
relationships as inheritance, with an added capability of other&amp;nbsp;references.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Server object will represent a real-world server. It has components
(other objects) such as Interfaces, Hard Drives, and&amp;nbsp;others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does this all pull&amp;nbsp;together?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We define, in our asset management software, a Server which has one
Interface (Ethernet &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NIC&lt;/span&gt; called &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NIC1&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221;) and three Hard Drives (called
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD1&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD3&lt;/span&gt;). The Interface, in turn belongs to a Network (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;VLAN&lt;/span&gt;), and
has a field called &amp;#8220;connection&amp;#8221; which references a Interface of a Switch
object, specifically Interface &amp;#8220;Port1&amp;#8221; on Switch &amp;#8220;Switch1&amp;#8221;. We&amp;#8217;ll define
one Network called &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221; which is identified by the 192.168.0 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; range
(a field of the Network object). We create a Switch object, which
belongs to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;, has &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; 192.168.0.2, and has 24 Interfaces, called
&amp;#8220;Port1&amp;#8221; through &amp;#8220;Port24&amp;#8221;. This represents a BayStack 450-24T Ethernet
switch. We&amp;#8217;ll also define a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; called &amp;#8220;SmartUPS&amp;#8221;, which in turn has an
Interface which is part of &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221;, Connected to Switch1 on&amp;nbsp;Port21.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you see the concept beginning to emerge. We have, in essence, an
inter-related mesh of objects representing physical hardware and its&amp;#8217;
properties. This can all be thought of in a three-dimensional form,
which represents the connections and relationships in our&amp;nbsp;network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main two advantages of this approach&amp;nbsp;are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to quickly recognize relationships between objects. If,
for example, we looked at a summary page in Switch1, we would see a
number of static fields describing its properties (manufacturer, model,
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MAC&lt;/span&gt;, etc.) as well as a diagram of its&amp;#8217; relationships. Such a
diagram would look something&amp;nbsp;like:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Port1  -&amp;gt; NIC1 -&amp;gt; Server1
Port21 -&amp;gt; SmartSlotCard1 -&amp;gt; UPS1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It would also have a listing of Networks which this device is a member
of,&amp;nbsp;specifically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, on a web interface, each one of these entries would be a
link to that object&amp;#8217;s summary. Clicking on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS1&lt;/span&gt;, Server1, etc.
would show us the summary of that object, so that we can browse through
our physical network. Clicking on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;, for example, would show &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s
properties, as well as all devices that are members of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt; (related to&amp;nbsp;it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power of such an approach also relies on binding objects to specific
pieces of hardware. For example, the disk drives in Server1 (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD1&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD2&lt;/span&gt;,
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD3&lt;/span&gt;) would in turn be references to objects representing actual
physical assets. We can then move these assets around. For example,
let&amp;#8217;s say that we assign a unique serial number of 000306 at a physical
hard drive. We now create an object for it, and reference &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD3&lt;/span&gt; in
Server1 to this object. If we reconfigure Server1 (physically) by
removing &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD1&lt;/span&gt; (000306) and place it on a shelf, we could then edit
Server1&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD3&lt;/span&gt; object to be &amp;#8220;empty&amp;#8221;, and have 000306 reassigned to an
object &amp;#8220;Shelf02&amp;#8221; that represents a physical storage location. By viewing
the summary for Server1, we would see that &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD3&lt;/span&gt; is &amp;#8220;empty&amp;#8221;, but if we
viewed Shelf02, we would see that 000306 is there, waiting to be used.
When we add a server, Server2, we could assign 000306 to that server,
as, say,&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD2&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give another example, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS1&lt;/span&gt; is an uninterruptible power supply. We can
&amp;#8220;assign&amp;#8221; devices to it, such as Switch1 and Server1. Viewing a summary
for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS1&lt;/span&gt; would show us that Switch1 and Server1 are connected to it.
Similarly, viewing the summary for either Server1 or Switch1 would show
us that they are connected to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS1&lt;/span&gt;. If we add &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS2&lt;/span&gt;, we could simply edit
the Server1 object so that it is connected to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS2&lt;/span&gt;, and the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS1&lt;/span&gt; and
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS2&lt;/span&gt; objects would show this change&amp;nbsp;automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Historical tracking. Every change would be accompanied by a person
responsible, a date and time, a reason, and perhaps other information.
Exactly how this would be implemented is not decided (whether
relationships would be marked as &amp;#8216;deleted&amp;#8217; or whether changes would be
held in a separate table in the database), but the idea is that any
object would also contain a history of relationships. From our previous
examples, if we viewed a summary of Server1, we would see that the
connection to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS1&lt;/span&gt; was severed on a specific date due to a reason such
as &amp;#8220;overload&amp;#8221; and on that same date, the current connection to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS2&lt;/span&gt; was
established. Similarly, if we view the summary for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD2&lt;/span&gt; on Server2, we
would see that the object represents real-world hardware asset #000306.
Viewing the summary for 000306 would show us that it is a 18.2 Gb &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCSI&lt;/span&gt;
drive in a Compaq hot-swap tray, and that it was originally installed in
Server1, but moved on a certain date for a certain reason to Shelf02,
and then later moved to&amp;nbsp;Server2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The implementation of this concept would most likely come about as a
web-based &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; front-end with a MySQL database back-end. In order to
achieve good functionality, there would be a simple interface with quick
execution of common tasks. Most likely, the names I have used such as
Server1, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS1&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD3&lt;/span&gt; on Server1, etc. would just be reference names to a
real-world hardware object, and its&amp;#8217; data object representation,
identified by a unique &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ID&lt;/span&gt;. For example, the name &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD3&lt;/span&gt; on Server1 would
really just be a reference to 000306, a Hard Drive&amp;nbsp;object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we physically removed this drive from Server1 and placed it on
Shelf02, we would browse to the Server1 page in our web interface, and
click on &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD3&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221;, which would bring us to a page representing 000306. We
could then click on a &amp;#8220;Move&amp;#8221; link, bringing us to a form. This allows us
to enter our name, date and time, reason, etc. and a new location of
&amp;#8220;Shelf02&amp;#8221;. We click submit and the move information is entered into a
table, which references all associated objects - Server1, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD3&lt;/span&gt; on
Server1, 000306, Shelf02, etc. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD3&lt;/span&gt; on Server1 has the reference to
000306 removed, and a reference to a History object added. Shelf02 has a
reference to the History object, as well as a reference to 000306,&amp;nbsp;added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, viewing &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDD3&lt;/span&gt; on Server1 would show that there is no physical device
associated with it (empty), but would give a reference (link) to the
000306 drive, the History entry for the removal, and the current
location of 000306 on&amp;nbsp;Shelf02.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="asset management"></category><category term="asset tracking"></category><category term="IT"></category><category term="object-oriented"></category><category term="relational"></category></entry><entry><title>Why hasn’t Linux caught up to Windows?</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/02/why-hasnt-linux-caught-up-to-windows/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-02-19T17:20:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-02-19:2007/02/why-hasnt-linux-caught-up-to-windows/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Those of us who are involved in the Linux community are often frustrated
by the lack of widespread acceptance of Linux. Granted, I haven&amp;#8217;t used
all of the newest &amp;#8220;desktop&amp;#8221; distributions (&amp;#8216;distros&amp;#8217;), but I know that
my choice - openSuSE - is far from being ready to compete with Windows
for the novice user market. From the first few screens of the
installation, it&amp;#8217;s clear that this isn&amp;#8217;t something for the uninitiated.
However, to get off on a short tangent, openSuSE has also severely
hampered access to the command-line-only, text-mode installation, which
I need in order to install on many of my&amp;nbsp;servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted, it will take a lot of work to get Linux to retain its&amp;#8217; strong
points, and still be user-friendly for the non-technical user. However,
there are three main points that I see as being the biggest problems for
new users. All of which, coincidentally, are ones which some people
would bill as strong points of Linux. And they all have to do directly
with some of the founding principles of Linux - interoperability and&amp;nbsp;choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="packaging"&gt;Packaging.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Searching for a package for a linux system goes something like this:
figure out what package format your distro uses, figure out the distro
version and architecture, and then start checking the online
repositories. If it&amp;#8217;s something simple, you may be able to use a you
distro-specific maintenance program to automatically upgrade it. If not,
you can sift through the myriad online repositories for packages that
fit your package manager (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt;, Apt, etc.) and your distro/architecture.
If you have no luck there, find the package&amp;#8217;s homepage, and hope someone
has contributed packages for your distro and architecture - usually a
hit-or-miss situation. Last but not least, when all else has failed, you
choose either to compile from source yourself, or give up. Compiling
from source not only requires some knowledge of your system, Linux, and
the compilation sequence used by the software - hopefully the generic
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GNU&lt;/span&gt;-style ./configure, make, make install and not some more esoteric
scheme. Furthermore, compilation requires a whole slew of tools to be
installed on your system - make, gcc, autoconf, and may others,
depending on package. While it&amp;#8217;s not practical for people with limited
resources, homogenous environments, or novice users, I operate in a
largely heterogeneous environment - i586/compatible systems running SuSE
9.3-10.2 - and therefore maintain a dedicated system for compilation, if&amp;nbsp;merited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this complexity just enforces the novice&amp;#8217;s idea that there is not
much software available for Linux, as many novices are limited (due to
technical knowledge) to the packages that come with their&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are a few schemes to standardize all of this, the real
solution is quite complex, and would be based on a single package system
to be adopted by all distros (beginning with the main ones). Such a
system should have the following&amp;nbsp;features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to work easily with all&amp;nbsp;distros&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I main configuration file which can define which directories to use -
i.e. /etc, /bin,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for both simple, novice-oriented interfaces and expert-level&amp;nbsp;configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple interfaces, including command-line, text/ncurses, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GTK&lt;/span&gt;, and
other graphical&amp;nbsp;subsystems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A generalized package format that is&amp;nbsp;non-distro-specific&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration with an online master-list of&amp;nbsp;repositories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to search, download, and install packages from these&amp;nbsp;repositories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic update&amp;nbsp;ability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to mine the repositories for updates, and display a list on
screen or emailed to a user&amp;nbsp;account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very good tools for easy compilation from&amp;nbsp;source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these ideas would be incorporated in the tool itself, and some
as add-on&amp;nbsp;modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The features that I, as administrator of a largely heterogeneous network
of about 10 machines, would most like to see&amp;nbsp;are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Truly automatic updates via list - select which packages can be
automatically updated, and run a cron job nightly to check for any
updates for those packages and automatically get and install&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;-based updating - A single server on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt; maintains a list
(perhaps gathered via an automatic tool) of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ALL&lt;/span&gt; packages installed on
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ALL&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt; machines. Each night the configured clients will update this
list over the network, and then the master server will download all
available updates for all packages. Once this is complete, it will send
a message to all &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt; machines, which will then update their software
from the central repository on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;. This would, in effect,
automatically keep all &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt; machines on the same version of each
package and totally&amp;nbsp;up-to-date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kernel updates would be done manually, but should have an option for the
administrator to push the update to all&amp;nbsp;machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="distro-specific-tools-filesystem-layout-etc"&gt;Distro-specific tools, filesystem layout,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not only a barrier for novice users, but experienced users as
well. If you do a search online for Linux training, you will surely come
by a nubmer of certifications - &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NCLE&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RHCE&lt;/span&gt;, etc. The many distinct
certifications - offered by each Linux vendor and independent training
companies - underscore the inherent differences in Linux distributions.
While I&amp;#8217;m perfectly comfortable working with SuSE Linux (by Novell), if
I was to sit down in front of a Gentoo system, I would probably be
totally&amp;nbsp;lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LSB&lt;/span&gt; project (http://www.linux-foundation.org/en/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LSB&lt;/span&gt;) has aimed
to provide compatibility between distros, there are three main points
which must still be&amp;nbsp;addressed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The organization of filesystems on different distros, specifically
the directory tree and default locations for certain components, still
differs. In the interest of usability, the Linux directory tree should
be standardized, so that locations of programs, files, etc. will be
identical across&amp;nbsp;distributions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An effort needs to be made to make administration as similar as
possible across all distros. This means that program names,
functionality, location, etc. should be standardized as much as&amp;nbsp;possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It seems that each distro has its&amp;#8217; own administration tool - YaST for
SuSE, and others for other distros. An effort needs to be made to
develop a tool encompassing all of the features in one, distro-neutral
form. Webmin (www.webmin.com) has done this wonderfully in a web-based
interface, but attention should be focused on a text-mode console
version as&amp;nbsp;well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gui"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the biggest hurdle for novices using Linux, and the biggest
development challenge, is general ease of use. While the above two
points may fall into this category, I am specifically referring to the
general, day-to-day use of the operating&amp;nbsp;system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I will not begin to suggest solutions, the main problems that I
see are as&amp;nbsp;follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The stability and security of Linux must be kept intact, unlike
distros such as&amp;nbsp;Lindows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There must remain a way for advanced users to perform advanced&amp;nbsp;tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As much of the inner workings should be hidden from the end-user as
possible, unless specifically&amp;nbsp;requested.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I good system would have a field added to a users&amp;#8217; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GECOS&lt;/span&gt; data
specifying their level of &amp;#8220;novice-ness&amp;#8221; - i.e. allowing a dumbed-down
interface for users while retaining a full interface with Expert
features for those who want&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;Mysterious&amp;#8221; things such as file permissions should be hidden from
novice-level users when not absolutely&amp;nbsp;needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There must be a strong integration with &amp;#8220;anti-mistake&amp;#8221; tools and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DWIM&lt;/span&gt;
technology. The system itself should manage file permissions in a way
that grants only the minimum needed&amp;nbsp;access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There should be good, strong mistake detection, specifically in terms
of catching a user&amp;#8217;s inadvertent changing of file permissions, deleting
required files,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tools should be built so that the novice user is never required to
login as root or run a root&amp;nbsp;shell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perhaps, and I&amp;#8217;m sure this is controversial, the root account should
be given either &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt;-only access, or should not have X running by
default, so as to discourage novice users from running day-to-day tasks
as&amp;nbsp;root.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m sure I&amp;#8217;ve missed a lot, and have also probably mentioned a number of
things that are already in place. However, the bottom line is that Linux
has to be able to achieve the easy of use and interoperability (between
distros) that Windows currently has, while retaining the extensibility,
advanced features, security, and stability that make Linux what it&amp;nbsp;is.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="compatibility"></category><category term="development"></category><category term="distribution"></category><category term="linux"></category><category term="novice"></category><category term="windows"></category></entry><entry><title>Support Open Source</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/02/support-open-source/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-02-08T18:09:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-02-08:2007/02/support-open-source/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I get paid tomorrow, and it&amp;#8217;s time to spend some money. Sure, there are
some great toys out there. The stuff from
&lt;a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com"&gt;ThinkGeek&lt;/a&gt; is always great. What about that
monitoring server I want? Or upgrading my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt; to gigabit&amp;nbsp;copper?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are also many charitable causes. The homeless. Cancer.
Strippers without&amp;nbsp;implants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this week, I&amp;#8217;m going to do something different. I use Open Source
software. My computers run Linux, this site is hosted by Apache, I use
Firefox as a browser. I didn&amp;#8217;t pay for any of these. But maybe I should,
and the rest of us should too. What&amp;#8217;s your favorite Open Source project?
They probably accept donations. Projects like Mozilla and Apache even
sell merchandise where some of the profit goes to support development.
Organizations like the Free Software Foundation (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FSF&lt;/span&gt;) and the Open
Source Initiative (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSI&lt;/span&gt;) also accept donations, which they allocate to
legal defense funds and grants to open-source&amp;nbsp;projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this week, I&amp;#8217;m going to do some&amp;nbsp;good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for the rest of you, next time you notice a bug or miss a feature in
an open-source project, just think&amp;#8230; if everyone who used it donated
$10, would it still be&amp;nbsp;missing?&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>The Big Name consipracy - and SSL certs</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/02/the-big-name-consipracy-and-ssl-certs/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-02-06T02:28:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-02-06:2007/02/the-big-name-consipracy-and-ssl-certs/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I decided to setup &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSL&lt;/span&gt; on my Apache server. After looking around for
ages, it seems that the answer to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSL&lt;/span&gt; Certs is that I need to buy one.
There doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to be any &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt; out there who will provide free certs
that are accepted by most&amp;nbsp;browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this brings me into one of my favorite diatribes. The &amp;#8220;Big Name&amp;#8221;
Conspiracy, as I like to call&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many many years ago, leading computer researchers began to connect their
systems into a worldwide (or at least nationwide) network. The admin of
each machine was trusted. There was a hosts.txt file distributed. Then
computers came to the home, and with them, serial modems and
connectivity. In the brief time before the &amp;#8216;net turned into a wasteland,
it was free. Free as in if you had a phone line, the hardware, and the
knowledge, you could setup your own &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BBS&lt;/span&gt; or other&amp;nbsp;server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skip forward to 2007. I pay exorbitant rates (well, about $40/month) for
a residential fiber-optic connection. A few people I know can&amp;#8217;t view my
web site. Why? Because Verizon, my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;, blocks incoming traffic on port
80 so that I can&amp;#8217;t run a server. And they won&amp;#8217;t give me a static &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt;, so
I can&amp;#8217;t run a server. Thankfully, the folks at DynDNS.org are fighting
for us, and they give me free &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt;, which I can even forward my domain
name to. To get around Verizon, I forward &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt; traffic to a high-number
unused port. Well, what do you know, a number of corporate Internet
filters block all web traffic going to ports other than the&amp;nbsp;defaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to send mail from a Linux machine. So, I configured Postfix and
sent mail. Worked perfectly to a few addresses, but &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AOL&lt;/span&gt;, Verizon,
Hotmail, Gmail, big companies - forget it. Rejected. Why? Because I have
a dynamic &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt;, and my domain name doesn&amp;#8217;t reverse-validate, so I must not
be a legitimate user. There&amp;#8217;s no way around it. Try sending mail from
you@yourdomain.dyndns.org - I have yet to find a mailserver that will
accept&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened to the community environment of the &amp;#8216;net? Yes, I know,
it&amp;#8217;s all in the name of &amp;#8220;bettering&amp;#8221; the &amp;#8216;net, reducing spam, etc. But I
have yet to find anyone who will whitelist my dynamic&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I&amp;#8217;m just obtuse. Or angry. But it seems to me that there is a
&amp;#8220;conspiracy&amp;#8221;, perhaps unspoken, among the Big Names out there to
centralize the Internet, to prevent [I]people[/I] from&amp;nbsp;participating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I&amp;#8217;m not the only person who has noticed this. While there are
many people and companies out there valiantly fighting for freedom on
the Internet, it seems that the majority of big companies, ISPs, hosting
providers, etc. want the &amp;#8216;net to be a one-way medium: content is
provided by those who can pay for leased lines and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; blocks, and
everyone else looks at&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a group of servers - web, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMTP&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IMAP&lt;/span&gt;, etc. - on a dynamic &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt;, I
am acutely aware of exactly how much modern Internet technology relies
on the fact that anyone who&amp;#8217;s [I]providing[/I] the content has a static
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; - and can pay the cost associated with&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting back to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSL&lt;/span&gt; cert, why isn&amp;#8217;t there a reputable authority who
provides free certificates? I have unlimited free long distance calls, I
would be more than willing to call the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; contact number for every
applicant to&amp;nbsp;validate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And why hasn&amp;#8217;t anyone developed a method of making a dynamic &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#8220;look&amp;#8221;
static to the rest of the world - surely &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IANA&lt;/span&gt; should set aside a massive
block of IPv6 for this, if not&amp;nbsp;IPv4.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>The ultimate Geek alarm clock!</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/01/the-ultimate-geek-alarm-clock/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-01-16T22:55:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-01-16:2007/01/the-ultimate-geek-alarm-clock/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, here&amp;#8217;s an idea that I&amp;#8217;ve been toying around with for a&amp;nbsp;while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been dong some development on a pair of
&lt;a href="http://www.soekris.com"&gt;Soekris&lt;/a&gt; embedded Linix boards I bought to use
as a firewall/router and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WAP&lt;/span&gt;. So, naturally, my interest in embedded
systems is piqued. I know that there are some smaller embedded Linux
devices out there. So, the idea is as&amp;nbsp;follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get an embedded Linux box that is either PoE or uses a hardwired
connection with a wall-wart, or better yet, uses both, so it can be
designed to have PoE as the primary power, with a 9v battery backup (ok,
it won&amp;#8217;t run too long, but can handle minor power losses if the PoE
switch isn&amp;#8217;t on a&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attach to it a clock-style &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt; display, or a matrix &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt; display, and an
additional really bright red &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt;, both controlled by software (serial or&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPIO&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system has one &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RJ&lt;/span&gt;-45 connector for Ethernet (10-BaseT) and a serial
console. The console is a captive login to a setup program to define &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt;,
etc. but by default uses&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plug it in, and it queries your &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt; server for an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NTP&lt;/span&gt; server (or in the
absence of one, uses a default Stratum 2). We re-update the time every
day or so. Now, you have an accurate-to-the-second&amp;nbsp;clock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We add a speaker to the box, and have a few default built-in MP3s or
WAVs for alarm tones, and add a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPIO&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#8220;snooze&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;off&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The serial console allows setting a daily alarm or two, as well as
selecting one of the default&amp;nbsp;tones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Geekier Part:&lt;/strong&gt;
The alarm clock is controlled by a script called by a Cron job. Now, we
add the miniserv web server and a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; admin gateway. Login via a
password (user-selectable) and we can upload new audio files for alarms,
as well as adding alarms via the web as cron jobs - now I can program in
my class schedule, and automatically have an alarm at the right time
each day of the&amp;nbsp;week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Geekiest Part:&lt;/strong&gt;
Remember the matrix display and that additional really bright &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt;? We
setup simple communication between machines via &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SNMP&lt;/span&gt; or a script on the
clock (called with an Expect script on a remote machine) and we can
activate the super-bright &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt;, a custom sound, and even a scrolling
message on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt; display (alternates between message and time, of
course) for critical events. Now, when the servers go down, I have
another device (in addition to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt; alerts on my cell) to tell me to
wake up and deal with it. If we want to get even more fancy, we can
enable a feature through the serial console or web interface that emits
a loud tone for a few seconds and blinks the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt; if PoE is lost, or we
can&amp;#8217;t ping a user-selectable address for more than, say, one&amp;nbsp;minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I have too much free time on my&amp;nbsp;hands..&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="alarm clock"></category><category term="embedded"></category><category term="geek"></category><category term="PoE"></category></entry></feed>