<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/categories/miscellaneous.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 21:41:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Yesterday’s Widespread Internet Outage, for non-geeks</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2016/10/yesterdays-widespread-internet-outage-for-non-geeks/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, Friday October 21st, 2016, Internet users in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; (initially the East Coast) experienced issues accessing many popular websites, including Twitter, Etsy, Spotify, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNN&lt;/span&gt;, Amazon and others. This also affected numerous companies and services used heavily in the technology industry for everything from storing and sharing source code to monitoring the health of services and alerting on-call technical&amp;nbsp;staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cause of the problems was an outage of Dyn, one of the leading providers of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_Name_System"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; services, the system which translates human-readable domain names (like &amp;#8220;blog.jasonantman.com&amp;#8221;) to the numeric &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; addresses actually used by computers to communicate. Aside from the immediate take-away - that so many high-traffic websites are relying on a single &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; provider, and therefore a single point of failure - there are a number of important points about what&amp;nbsp;happened:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) This was not an accidental outage, it was an intentional attack by a malicious party; specifically a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denial-of-service_attack"&gt;distributed denial of service (DDoS)&lt;/a&gt; attack, where an attacker takes control of tens or hundreds of thousands of computers, and uses them to bombard the target with data. Assuming enough data is generated, as was the case yesterday, this will overwhelm the target, preventing it from fulfilling the requests of legitimate users. This was a very visible, intentional attack on critical Internet&amp;nbsp;infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) Some of the leading experts on computer security, people who consult for Fortune-500 companies and have substantial access to non-public information, &lt;a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2016/09/someone_is_lear.html"&gt;believe&lt;/a&gt; that this attack was one of a series carried out by an advanced, well-funded nation state attacker (likely either China or Russia, with evidence pointing to the former). Furthermore, evidence points to this attack not being the end-goal, but rather part of an escalating test to determine the point of failure of critical Internet infrastructure. The cyber equivalent of test-firing missiles and flying over enemy territory to map defenses, in preparation for an attack. Homeland Security and the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FBI&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-cyber-idUSKCN12L1ME"&gt;are investigating&lt;/a&gt;, but have not speculated publicly on the source of the&amp;nbsp;attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) The &lt;a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2016/10/hacked-cameras-dvrs-powered-todays-massive-internet-outage/"&gt;source&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://thehackernews.com/2016/10/iot-dyn-ddos-attack.html"&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; the flood of traffic that caused the outage was a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Botnet"&gt;botnet&lt;/a&gt;, a large network of hundreds of thousands of computers that were hijacked by the attacker and used to send massive amounts of data to Dyn&amp;#8217;s systems. More specifically, the computers in this instance were &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_of_things"&gt;&amp;#8220;Internet of Things&amp;#8221; (IoT)&lt;/a&gt; Internet-connected devices, mainly &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt;-based video/surveillance cameras and video recorders; everything from warehouse and corporate surveillance cameras to &amp;#8220;nanny cams&amp;#8221; and video baby monitors. These devices pose a significant risk to the Internet, and therefore to our economic and physical infrastructure; they&amp;#8217;re often manufactured by companies that provide little to no support (the most common manufacturer provides none, selling their goods &amp;#8220;white box&amp;#8221; to be relabeled by distributors) and sold to users with little to no technical expertise. Unfortunately, there&amp;#8217;s also no legal requirement in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; for them to be secure, generally no procedure for software updates, and usually no way for users to enhance the security of the&amp;nbsp;devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first two pieces of information should be deeply disturbing to all of us; in an age when &amp;#8220;cyber warfare&amp;#8221; is constantly in the media, yesterday&amp;#8217;s even is the modern equivalent of a foreign power sending fighter planes over Washington, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DC&lt;/span&gt;, to see how we react. There&amp;#8217;s no plausible explanation for this, short of testing our defenses for an imminent or possible attack. It&amp;#8217;s also important to note the implications of this beyond Twitter and Etsy; an attack of this magnitude launched against more than one - or all - of the leading &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; providers at once would cripple everything from banking, payments and credit card processing to healthcare and travel, and possibly large portions of our transportation, power and utility infrastructure. All areas of modern American life have become inextricably linked to the health of the Internet, whether we realize it or not (ever tried to eat at a restaurant when their &amp;#8220;computers were down,&amp;#8221; or fill your car with gas when there was a local Internet outage?) And while the original core of the network that became the Internet was designed to withstand a cold-war nuclear attack, the modern infrastructure relies increasingly on a small number of private companies. An attack of the scale possible from a nation-state has never happened before, and it&amp;#8217;s not likely that it would be handled&amp;nbsp;well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a separate note, the use of IoT &amp;#8220;smart&amp;#8221; devices in this attack is particularly unsettling. While most people expect that their desktop and laptop computers and smartphones will receive regular software updates from a company that cares about their continued functionality, and expect that their devices won&amp;#8217;t be hijacked to attack critical infrastructure, the same is not true of the exploding field of &amp;#8220;smart&amp;#8221; devices. Robotic vacuum cleaners, Internet-based baby monitors, light bulbs that can be dimmed from your phone and networked thermostats are often sold as appliances at face-value, with very little ongoing support. Most people who buy these devices expect them to just work as advertised, and to be secure - they expect their baby monitor to &lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/news/baby-monitors-connect-internet-vulnerable-hackers-cybersecurity/"&gt;not let hackers watch inside their homes&lt;/a&gt; and they expect their light bulbs to not attack critical Internet infrastructure on behalf of a third party. Perhaps the worst part is that, as many manufacturers of such devices are neither &amp;#8220;computer companies&amp;#8221; nor terribly interested in long-term customer relationships, every insecure device that&amp;#8217;s sold will likely be in operation for the next five to ten years, or more. We need both a legislative solution to this, as well as a consumer-focused solution; perhaps the modern equivalent of Underwriter&amp;#8217;s Laboratory for computerized devices. Without a solution, we may well end up in the world where, as &lt;a href="http://mjg59.dreamwidth.org/45098.html"&gt;suggested by some experts&lt;/a&gt;, it will be up to the Internet Service Provider of befuddled users to disconnect their service when a foreign power turns their toaster into a&amp;nbsp;weapon.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Antman</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 21:41:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2016-10-22:2016/10/yesterdays-widespread-internet-outage-for-non-geeks/</guid><category>Dyn</category><category>DNS</category><category>botnet</category><category>security</category><category>DDoS</category></item><item><title>A Short Comment on Gun Rights in America</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2016/06/a-short-comment-on-gun-rights-in-america/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This blog has, for many years, been unabashedly &amp;#8220;all tech.&amp;#8221; I&amp;#8217;ve often had second thoughts about that, wondering if I should give the rest of my self - my political, moral and ethical views - more of a voice. But I&amp;#8217;ve always put that aside - partially because this &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; comes up when I&amp;#8217;m looking for a new job and I don&amp;#8217;t really want to be remembered as that guy with the strongly disagreeing views, partially because I don&amp;#8217;t want people looking for technical content to be frustrated by my rants. And partially because it&amp;#8217;s just harder for me to convey political or social concepts in the way I intend than it is to convey technical ones. But after the events of the past 36 hours - and moreover, of the past decade-plus - I&amp;#8217;m going to deviate from that. &lt;strong&gt;Be advised&lt;/strong&gt; that if you have strong feelings on either side of the gun control debate, this probably isn&amp;#8217;t going to make you&amp;nbsp;happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m a gun owner. I have been since my eighteenth birthday, the day when I became legally able to exercise my second amendment rights in my then-home state of New Jersey. That was only a decade ago, but the impact of guns on America seems so shockingly different. I own a single .22-caliber target pistol; certainly dangerous as any firearm is, but essentially the bottom of the scale when it comes to lethality. It&amp;#8217;s designed to shoot paper, not much else. I&amp;#8217;ve been shooting off and on since I was in my early teens, mostly handguns and shotguns. Apparently unlike most people who are vocal gun owners, I&amp;#8217;ve never fired a shot at anything that is or was ever alive, unless you count paper. I&amp;#8217;ve never fired a shot outside of a shooting&amp;nbsp;range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve also never carried a gun in public, nor have I ever had a serious desire to. Despite what gun-rights activists claim about self-defense and defense of others, I think that the way police in this country are both trained and act in the field is a wonderful example of why firearm carry in public often doesn&amp;#8217;t work: we&amp;#8217;re talking about people whose &lt;em&gt;profession&lt;/em&gt; involves firearms, who must train and qualify with their guns annually (or more often), and still often can&amp;#8217;t hit a target in a real-life situation. As far as I&amp;#8217;m concerned, if someone wants to carry a firearm to defend themselves or others, they damn well better be shooting &lt;em&gt;every day&lt;/em&gt;, doing live-fire training, and completely confident that they could identify and hit a target in real life. To my knowledge, only the most elite units of the military do this. I grew up in New Jersey, where the only people who carry guns are law enforcement and criminals, period (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt;, there are some &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; rare exceptions). I now live in Georgia, where anyone can walk into WalMart and walk out with a gun - and many people walk around the store with handguns on their belts, something that&amp;#8217;s still foreign to&amp;nbsp;me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my eighteenth birthday, I went to the police department in my home town to begin the process of purchasing the target pistol that my father had offered as a gift. For those of you who aren&amp;#8217;t familiar with how gun (specifically handgun - it&amp;#8217;s significantly easier for shotguns and rifles) ownership works in the northeast, here&amp;#8217;s the gist of it (my memory may be a bit hazy, and some of it may have been explained&amp;nbsp;poorly):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I went to the police department and met with the chief, whom I already knew personally through&amp;nbsp;family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I paid a fee of approximately $100 and filled out about six pages of paperwork, including a full history of my addresses and a lengthy&amp;nbsp;questionnaire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was fingerprinted - all ten fingers, three sets of&amp;nbsp;prints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I filled out consent forms for federal and state background checks and consents for mental health records&amp;nbsp;searches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These were all sent out to the respective&amp;nbsp;agencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About a month later, the chief called to tell me that he&amp;#8217;d received the replies from the federal and state governments, and they came back &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt; (which is to be expected, as I had no mental health history and no criminal&amp;nbsp;record).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He then sent out form letters to the three non-related character references I had specified on my application, requesting them to assert under penalty of perjury whether they believed that I posed any danger to myself or others, if I were allowed to purchase a&amp;nbsp;firearm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The letters were all returned by my references. The chief then sent the completed paperwork back to the state government, which issued me a state firearms purchaser identification card, entitling me to purchase firearms and ammunition. I was also issued - as requested - a Permit to Purchase a Handgun, which entitled me to purchase one (1) handgun within 90 days of the date of&amp;nbsp;issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt;, so that&amp;#8217;s quite a process. All in all, it took two or three months to&amp;nbsp;complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finally received my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ID&lt;/span&gt; card and permit - which had to be picked up in person - I headed out to a local gun store to find the model I wanted. And I did. I turned the purchase permit over to the salesperson, who called the state government to verify its validity. We finalized the details of the transaction and I inspected the merchandise and filled out some last paperwork. The gun I&amp;#8217;d purchased was then marked with a &amp;#8220;sold&amp;#8221; sticker and had a copy of the invoice attached, and was locked in a safe for me to pick up in seven days, when the mandatory waiting period was over. When I returned a week later, one of the two spent cartridges from the gun (shipped with it by the manufacturer) was sent to the state police for future forensic&amp;nbsp;use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Jersey is widely regarded as having some of the strictest gun control laws in the country. And none of that is enough. There was never a follow-up. There was no ongoing monitoring that I&amp;#8217;m aware of. I&amp;#8217;ve heard more stories than I can remember of people being convicted of crimes or involved in domestic violence situations, and then using their legally-purchased and registered firearms in future crimes. It makes no sense to me that we live in a world where Amazon knows what items I&amp;#8217;m interested in today, but the authorities can&amp;#8217;t figure out to take my gun away if I assault someone. There was also never a mandatory proficiency or safety test, either written or at a real firing&amp;nbsp;range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is it that we live in a country where operation of a motor vehicle - a device which &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be fatal when operated improperly - requires a written examination, a practical demonstration of skill, and an ongoing demonstration of responsibility (traffic police), but the possession and operation of a firearm does not? It makes no sense. I don&amp;#8217;t want to minimize the effects of poor driving decisions, they certainly claim many lives, but there&amp;#8217;s no avoiding the fact that firearms were - and in many cases, are - &lt;em&gt;designed&lt;/em&gt; to&amp;nbsp;kill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose that most of my feelings on this are based on two of my core beliefs, which run contrary to many gun-rights activists: (1) that my only use for a firearm is target shooting, and it doesn&amp;#8217;t really matter to me how quickly I can buy one, and (2) that our military has tanks and nukes, and the idea of &amp;#8220;defending my Freedom [against a government takeover]&amp;#8221; with any legally-purchased weapon is impossible, regardless of whether or not it&amp;#8217;s simply&amp;nbsp;paranoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether openly or not, many gun rights activists base their positions on a romanticized fictional &amp;#8220;past America&amp;#8221;, where everyone was good, owned guns, defended themselves, and was self-sufficient. Even if that past world existed (in reality it was quite violent; the violence just isn&amp;#8217;t remembered in the Utopian narrative), it&amp;#8217;s certainly not today. The past America they speak of was a time when most gun owners had been so since childhood (it was merely a part of living), likely had many fewer violent influences, and could count on swift justice. Let&amp;#8217;s also remember the technology of this past age: I might be &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt; with gun rights activists going back to this mythical past, if they also could only have a six-shot revolver that takes a few minutes to&amp;nbsp;reload.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But despite what gun rights activists try to tell us, the problem here is not hardcore criminals. It&amp;#8217;s people who may or may not have criminal or suspicious pasts, who decide to act on their violent ideas. It&amp;#8217;s people who can walk into a store and buy a weapon or magazine that holds twenty or fifty rounds of ammunition - something which has no legitimate use other than mass killing. It&amp;#8217;s people who can borrow or steal guns from family or friends, because those firearms weren&amp;#8217;t treated with the proper respect and safety by their legal owners. It&amp;#8217;s the belief by some that there&amp;#8217;s a legitimate reason to obtain a gun in less than a week, or a month, or months. It&amp;#8217;s the ironic dichotomy of the people who believe that Snowden was a traitor and mass surveillance is fine, but registering guns is an unconstitutional invasion of privacy. And it has to stop. I dare say, if every mass shooting in the past decade or two was carried out by a Muslim or an immigrant or anyone other than a white Christian, half of the roadblocks to a safe America would&amp;#8217;ve&amp;nbsp;disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To everyone who takes a literal reading of the Constitution and says that the second amendment grants every American the right to posses and carry as many and whatever kind of firearms they want, I make three&amp;nbsp;comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;falsely shouting &amp;#8216;fire&amp;#8217; in a crowded theater.&amp;#8221; We have a Supreme Court for a reason: that the framers knew the Constitution would have to be interpreted differently with&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you stand against gun registration or regulation, please keep in mind that your precious second amendment begins with the phrase, &amp;#8220;A well regulated Militia.&amp;#8221; Even if you don&amp;#8217;t believe that this is equivalent to a modern-day standing army, it clearly does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; say, &amp;#8220;Everybody gets all the firearms they want,&amp;nbsp;period.&amp;#8221;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;Life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness.&amp;#8221; They weren&amp;#8217;t put in that order by&amp;nbsp;mistake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Antman</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 20:02:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2016-06-13:2016/06/a-short-comment-on-gun-rights-in-america/</guid><category>politics</category><category>guns</category></item><item><title>Visualization of when I’m working on personal vs work projects</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2015/06/visualization-of-when-im-working-on-personal-vs-work-projects/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I was thinking the other day - as I was pushing out some final code reviews for work at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;11PM&lt;/span&gt; before taking a day off -
about how much work I do outside of &amp;#8220;work hours&amp;#8221;. And the answer is, I don&amp;#8217;t really know, especially when it comes to
projects that I really enjoy and find interesting. So, I decided to have some fun with &lt;a href="https://github.com/gitpython-developers/GitPython"&gt;GitPython&lt;/a&gt;
and find&amp;nbsp;out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result of this was &lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/misc-scripts/blob/master/whendoiwork.py"&gt;whendoiwork.py&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s a pretty simple script,
and also makes some pretty big assumptions, but I found the results interesting. Given some local directories which contain git clones
of my work repositories, and some which contain clones of my personal repos, it iterates over all* of the commits in them by me
(going by the git author name) in the last N days (default 365); it counts commits to personal repositories as +1 and to work
repositories as -1, and adds them to buckets per hour of day, per day of week. It then uses &lt;a href="http://matplotlib.org/"&gt;matplotlib&lt;/a&gt;
to build a heatmap, with the maximum commits per hour for work repos in blue and the maximum per hour for personal in&amp;nbsp;red.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t vouch that it&amp;#8217;s 100% accurate, but the results were interesting to me; while it seems like I tend to do a fair amount
of work in the evenings, compared to work on personal projects, all of my work for my employer is well contained in my normal
7-3 work&amp;nbsp;day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s an example of the output of this script, for my own work, run&amp;nbsp;with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;./whendoiwork.py -v -a /home/jantman/GIT -b /home/jantman/work/git -b /home/jantman/work/git/ops -d 365 -t &amp;#39;US/Eastern&amp;#39; --repoAlabel personal --repoBlabel work
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Note that this iterates over every commit in all of the git repos it finds, possibly multiple times. On my own
system (9G of git repos with a few hundred thousand commits), this took about 2&amp;nbsp;minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="heatmap of days of week and hours of day when I commit to work vs personal repos" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jantman/misc-scripts/master/whendoiwork.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find any bugs/issues with it, please pass them along by &lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/misc-scripts/issues"&gt;opening an issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Antman</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 21:20:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2015-06-05:2015/06/visualization-of-when-im-working-on-personal-vs-work-projects/</guid><category>git</category><category>commits</category><category>python</category><category>graphs</category><category>visualization</category></item><item><title>Jira to Trello Script</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2015/04/jira-to-trello-script/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I &lt;a href="/2015/03/my-new-found-love-of-trello-and-a-helpful-greasemonkey-script/"&gt;posted about&lt;/a&gt; how I&amp;#8217;ve
started using &lt;a href="https://trello.com/"&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; to keep track of my work and keep things flowing smoothly. It&amp;#8217;s been
absolutely wonderful, and I feel more productive and less stressed, and like I have a better idea of what&amp;#8217;s coming
up. The one thing that Trello is missing is time tracking. I don&amp;#8217;t need anything fancy, all I really wanted was to
be able to show a time estimate on my cards. I know I could&amp;#8217;ve just put the estimate right in the title of the cards,
but that seemed like a waste of&amp;nbsp;data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment we&amp;#8217;re using Jira at work, so I wrote &lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/misc-scripts/blob/master/jira2trello.py"&gt;jira2trello.py&lt;/a&gt;.
It&amp;#8217;s a pretty simple Python script that uses the &lt;a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/trello"&gt;trello&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/jira"&gt;jira&lt;/a&gt; packages from pypi to iterate over all cards on a specified Trello
board, and for each card that matches a configurable regular expression for ticket keys (i.e.
&lt;code&gt;.*((project1|project2|project3)-\d+):.*&lt;/code&gt;), the script&amp;nbsp;will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine if the Jira issue is a subtask, and if so, prefix its title with the issue key of the parent issue,
using the format of &lt;code&gt;PARENT-xxx -&amp;gt; CHILD-xxx&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look up the &amp;#8220;Original Estimate&amp;#8221; time tracking field in Jira, and if present, prepend it to the title of
the&amp;nbsp;card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regenerate the title of the card, using the current issue summary from&amp;nbsp;Jira.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move the card to a specified &amp;#8220;Done&amp;#8221; list if it&amp;#8217;s closed in&amp;nbsp;Jira.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few assumptions in the script about how the titles of cards are formed, namely that they follow the
&lt;code&gt;ISSUE-xxx: Summary Here&lt;/code&gt; format used by my &lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/userscripts#trellocontextmenu"&gt;TrelloContextMenu&lt;/a&gt;
Firefox userscript. But I hope that this might be of use to someone else as well. Please feel free to open issues
or submit pull requests for any improvements that would be helpful, including any assumptions I&amp;#8217;ve made that aren&amp;#8217;t
valid in your environment. The source can be found on GitHub: &lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/misc-scripts/blob/master/jira2trello.py"&gt;jira2trello.py&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Antman</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 05:58:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2015-04-10:2015/04/jira-to-trello-script/</guid><category>jira</category><category>trello</category><category>python</category><category>ticket</category><category>kanban</category></item><item><title>Idea for a Generic Method to Communicate Repository/Project Status</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2014/12/idea-for-a-generic-method-to-communicate-repositoryproject-status/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Update 2014-12-24: I actually did something with this. See &lt;a href="http://www.repostatus.org"&gt;repostatus.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, something funny, before my possibly-hair-brained&amp;nbsp;scheme:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.commitstrip.com/en/2014/11/25/west-side-project-story/"&gt;&lt;img alt="commitstrip.com &amp;quot;side project&amp;quot; comic strip" src="http://www.commitstrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Strip-Side-project-650-finalenglish.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I&amp;#8217;m not alone in having a mess of &lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman?tab=repositories"&gt;repositories on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;; I personally have over 90, and they&amp;#8217;re
all in various states of &amp;#8220;doneness.&amp;#8221; Some are working and undergoing active development. Some should be
working, but I no longer use them (and sometimes lack &amp;#8220;things&amp;#8221; needed to use them, especially the case
with projects linked to specific hardware). Some of them were ideas that never took off; some of these
I intend on finishing, and some I never want to touch&amp;nbsp;again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While GitHub has a &lt;a href="https://help.github.com/articles/about-releases/"&gt;Releases&lt;/a&gt; feature, at best (where everyone
understands and follows &lt;a href="http://semver.org/"&gt;semantic versioning&lt;/a&gt;), it can only differentiate &amp;#8220;initial development&amp;#8221;
(prior to stable public release) versions from those after them. It may be an indication of the usability or completeness
of the software, but not of its current state of&amp;nbsp;maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The questions that I&amp;#8217;d really like to be able to answer about a given project or repository&amp;nbsp;are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the &amp;#8220;completeness&amp;#8221; of the code? Should it be usable, or is it functionally&amp;nbsp;incomplete?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the status of development efforts? Is this actively developed, or supported (even if bugfix-only), or totally&amp;nbsp;abandoned?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d like to be able to easily communicate this to people who come across my work, and also
track it for my own needs - I have enough repositories with barely-started concepts that I
occasionally forget about them. I&amp;#8217;d also, of course, like to be able to know this information
about other peoples&amp;#8217; work as&amp;nbsp;well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, I thought that this should be a GitHub feature, exposed via the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; and the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UI&lt;/span&gt;. However,
there are a number of problems with&amp;nbsp;that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would require GitHub to implement the feature. Quite ironically, GitHub is &lt;a href="https://github.com/isaacs/github/issues/6"&gt;not very open&lt;/a&gt;
about issues and feature requests for their platform itself, and the only good way to suggest something is &lt;a href="https://github.com/isaacs/github"&gt;unofficial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would be tied to GitHub directly. When the next big thing comes along, or for projects using other services (like Gitorious, or even non-git hosting),
it would be rendered&amp;nbsp;useless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The status really describes the code/project itself, not the GitHub repository per se, so it should live with the&amp;nbsp;code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;#8217;m brainstorming a straightforward semi-standardized way of communicating this information. Assuming
it&amp;#8217;s not implemented in GitHub itself, but rather becomes part of the repository content, that poses some
interesting questions for both what information is communicated and how to communicate it. What follows is
really my brainstorming and initial ideas. I&amp;#8217;d very much appreciate it if anyone who&amp;#8217;s interested submits
their ideas and comments. I fully intend to start using something like this for my own projects but, not to
be too arrogant, I think it&amp;#8217;s a useful idea and could benefit from some accepted&amp;nbsp;standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-to-communicate"&gt;What to&amp;nbsp;Communicate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first question is what data to communicate. Ideally, this would be one of a standardized set of
repository/project status identifiers, along with a textual description that could be provided by
the author, for additional clarity. My humble suggestion (very much a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WIP&lt;/span&gt;) of the possible statuses,
along with the suggested (canonical) description of their&amp;nbsp;meanings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept&lt;/strong&gt; - Minimal or no implementation has been done&amp;nbsp;yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;WIP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Initial development is in progress, but there has not yet been a stable, usable release suitable for the&amp;nbsp;public.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suspended&lt;/strong&gt; - A &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WIP&lt;/span&gt; project that has had work stopped for the time being; the author(s) intend on resuming&amp;nbsp;work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abandoned&lt;/strong&gt; - A &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WIP&lt;/span&gt; project that has been abandoned; the author(s) do not intend on continuing&amp;nbsp;development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Active&lt;/strong&gt; - The project has reached a stable, usable state and is being actively&amp;nbsp;developed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inactive&lt;/strong&gt; - The project has reached a stable, usable state but is no longer being actively developed; support/maintenance will be provided as time&amp;nbsp;allows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unsupported&lt;/strong&gt; - The project has reached a stable, usable state but the author(s) have ceased all work on it. A new maintainer may be&amp;nbsp;desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assume that there might be some dissenting opinions on whether this list of statuses is complete, or perhaps too long.
However I feel that it&amp;#8217;s the minimum set required to describe a project along the two axes which I consider important:
usability (is the code here complete enough to &amp;#8220;work&amp;#8221; for something) and support/development status (is it being worked on,
or are there plans to do so in the future). I&amp;#8217;m certainly open to opinions on&amp;nbsp;this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-to-communicate-it"&gt;How to Communicate&amp;nbsp;It&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I view this as a more complex question technically, as doing this within the repository content (instead of in a GitHub &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt;)
necessarily involves polluting that repository. My main two technical requirements (at least with my own intended use in mind)
are that the status be readable both by human and machine, and that the status should be available in one place within the
repository (i.e. in only one place for both humans and machines, and not requiring any&amp;nbsp;transformation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best I&amp;#8217;ve been able to come up with so far is either including the status in a special file (likely a specially-named dotfile),
or including it in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;README&lt;/span&gt;. The dotfile method is optimized for machine-reading - it would be a single file, likely named
&amp;#8220;.repostatus.org&amp;#8221;, with a simple specified format. It&amp;#8217;s easy and cheap for a machine to find and parse, and shouldn&amp;#8217;t be too cumbersome
to add. But it pollutes the repository with another file, and worse, it would be quite unlikely to be found by a human who isn&amp;#8217;t
familiar with this practice, so it loses a lot in terms of human readability and&amp;nbsp;intuitiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, adding something special to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;README&lt;/span&gt; file is much more human-centric. The &amp;#8220;something&amp;#8221; could be a simple
string or link, or even better, a &lt;a href="http://shields.io/"&gt;badge&lt;/a&gt;. It would appear clearly when rendered on GitHub, and should also appear anywhere
else the readme is rendered (i.e. in online documentation or in packages of the project). However, this poses a few&amp;nbsp;challenges:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It wouldn&amp;#8217;t necessarily be possible to have a status that&amp;#8217;s machine-readable but not rendered to the human observer. Sure, this
sort of goes against half of the purpose of this idea, but some people probably wouldn&amp;#8217;t want this extra piece of information
cluttering up their &lt;span class="caps"&gt;README&lt;/span&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s possible to put comments in &lt;a href="http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/rst/restructuredtext.html#comments"&gt;rST&lt;/a&gt;,
but &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4823468/store-comments-in-markdown-syntax"&gt;markdown support&lt;/a&gt; isn&amp;#8217;t nearly as reliable,
being a bit of a&amp;nbsp;hack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is optimized for human readers. In order to be detected by machine, the repository would need to be searched for
a readme file (even assuming the convention of &amp;#8220;^&lt;span class="caps"&gt;README&lt;/span&gt;*&amp;#8221;, there&amp;#8217;s a myriad of possible file extensions that could be used),
which isn&amp;#8217;t necessarily a cheap operation (especially since it would require access to the file listing within the&amp;nbsp;repository).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Furthermore, machine detection would need to be able to either parse the markup (if any), or do string search on the file
contents. Once again, a more expensive&amp;nbsp;operation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id="current-theory"&gt;Current&amp;nbsp;Theory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, I&amp;#8217;m leaning towards this theory of&amp;nbsp;implementation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Badges are placed in the project&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;README&lt;/span&gt; indicating the status. The badges would be sourced from specified URLs, served
by &lt;a href="http://repostatus.org"&gt;repostatus.org&lt;/a&gt; and linked to specified URLs describing the status (likely of the form
http://repostatus.org/1.0/#active). Machine determination of status would be made by a string match for one of
the specified status URLs - nothing more is needed. It would be simple enough to simply specify that, for machine
determination, the first file in the repository (sorted in lexicographical order) beginning with &amp;#8220;readme&amp;#8221; (case-insensitive) and containing
a matching &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; determines the status. For human users, the badge image could be combined with descriptive alt-text, and
possibly followed by a more descriptive explanation, if the author chose so. This would eliminate the need for a fixed
set of possible readme file names, and the need for machine identification to be able to parse all possible&amp;nbsp;markups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The visual impact to the readme document (assuming it&amp;#8217;s rendered) would be minimal. Here are some quick takes on
a first set of badges, along with the alt text set on them (which could be changed by the user, or also included
in plain text next to the&amp;nbsp;badge).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="Repo Status: Concept - Minimal or no implementation has been done yet." src="http://img.shields.io/badge/repo%20status-Concept-ffffff.svg" /&gt; Repo Status: Concept - Minimal or no implementation has been done&amp;nbsp;yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="Repo Status: WIP - Initial development is in progress, but there has not yet been a stable, usable release suitable for the public." src="http://img.shields.io/badge/repo%20status-WIP-yellow.svg" /&gt; Repo Status: &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WIP&lt;/span&gt; - Initial development is in progress, but there has not yet been a stable, usable release suitable for the&amp;nbsp;public.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="Repo Status: Suspended - A WIP project that has had work stopped for the time being; the author(s) intend on resuming work." src="http://img.shields.io/badge/repo%20status-Suspended-orange.svg" /&gt; Repo Status: Suspended - A &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WIP&lt;/span&gt; project that has had work stopped for the time being; the author(s) intend on resuming&amp;nbsp;work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="Repo Status: Abandoned - A WIP project that has been abandoned; the author(s) do not intend on continuing development." src="http://img.shields.io/badge/repo%20status-Abandoned-000000.svg" /&gt; Repo Status: Abandoned - A &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WIP&lt;/span&gt; project that has been abandoned; the author(s) do not intend on continuing&amp;nbsp;development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="Repo Status: Active - The project has reached a stable, usable state and is being actively developed." src="http://img.shields.io/badge/repo%20status-Active-brightgreen.svg" /&gt; Repo Status: Active - The project has reached a stable, usable state and is being actively&amp;nbsp;developed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="Repo Status: Inactive - The project has reached a stable, usable state and is no longer being actively developed; support/maintenance will be done as time allows." src="http://img.shields.io/badge/repo%20status-Inactive-yellowgreen.svg" /&gt; Repo Status: Inactive - The project has reached a stable, usable state and is no longer being actively developed; support/maintenance will be done as time&amp;nbsp;allows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="Repo Status: Unsupported - The project has reached a stable, usable state but the author(s) have ceased all work on it. A new maintainer may be desired." src="http://img.shields.io/badge/repo%20status-Unsupported-lightgrey.svg" /&gt; Repo Status: Unsupported - The project has reached a stable, usable state but the author(s) have ceased all work on it. A new maintainer may be&amp;nbsp;desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the readme is (for some strange reason) primarily intended for a non-rendered view, it would be acceptable to
include just the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; to the status description, optionally with some human-readable&amp;nbsp;text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll probably start using something like this for my personal projects. I intend on even writing up a spec
for the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;README&lt;/span&gt;-based variant, along with some formatting and parsing/machine identification rules. Any and
all comments are welcome. This is the result of a few hours&amp;#8217; sporadic thought one afternoon, so I&amp;#8217;m sure there
are some major issues I haven&amp;#8217;t realized yet. Please pass them along, or tell me if this is of any interest to&amp;nbsp;you.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Antman</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 18:24:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2014-12-07:2014/12/idea-for-a-generic-method-to-communicate-repositoryproject-status/</guid><category>repository</category><category>project</category><category>git</category><category>github</category></item><item><title>How Yum and RPM Compare Versions</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2014/07/how-yum-and-rpm-compare-versions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently tripped up by a bug in Puppet, &lt;a href="https://tickets.puppetlabs.com/browse/PUP-1244"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PUP&lt;/span&gt;-1244&lt;/a&gt;,
dealing with how it compares package versions. All of Puppet&amp;#8217;s Package types assumed
&lt;a href="http://semver.org/"&gt;semantic versioning&lt;/a&gt;, and that&amp;#8217;s far from the case for RPMs and therefore Yum. This
manifested itself in how Puppet validates package installations - if a version was explicitly specified
and Yum/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt; could install it, puppet would shell out to them and install the package, but then report
a failure in its post-install validation, as the &lt;em&gt;exact&lt;/em&gt; version string specified isn&amp;#8217;t present.
For example, many RedHat/CentOS packages (such as those from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EPEL&lt;/span&gt;) include a release string with the major
version of the distribution they were packged for - i.e. &amp;#8220;.el5&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;.el6&amp;#8221;. If Puppet was instructed to
install package &amp;#8220;foo&amp;#8221; version &amp;#8220;1.2.3&amp;#8221;, but the actual package in the repositories was &amp;#8220;foo-1.2.3-el5&amp;#8221;,
Puppet would cause the package to be installed, but then report&amp;nbsp;failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cut a &lt;a href="https://github.com/puppetlabs/puppet/pull/2866"&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt; against the Puppet4 branch to
fix these issues, essentially re-implementing yum and rpm&amp;#8217;s version comparison logic in Ruby. It took
me a few days of research and sorting through source code (and in the process I found that &lt;code&gt;yum&lt;/code&gt;, despite
its use in so many distributions, has no unit tests at all) but I finally got it finished. In the process,
I found out exactly how&amp;#8230; weird&amp;#8230; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s version comparison rules&amp;nbsp;are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="package-naming-and-parsing"&gt;Package Naming and&amp;nbsp;Parsing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt; package names are made up of five parts; the package name, epoch, version, release, and architecture.
This format is commonly referred to as the acronym &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEVRA&lt;/span&gt;. The epoch is not always included; it is assumed
to be zero (0) on any packages that lack it explicitly. The format for the whole string is &lt;code&gt;n-e:v-r.a&lt;/code&gt;.
For my purposes, I was only really concerned with comparing the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EVR&lt;/span&gt; portion; Puppet knows about package names
and the bug herein was with what Puppet calls the &amp;#8220;version&amp;#8221; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EVR&lt;/span&gt; in yum/rpm parlance). Parsing is pretty&amp;nbsp;simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is a &lt;code&gt;:&lt;/code&gt; in the string, everything before it is the epoch. If not, the epoch is&amp;nbsp;zero.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is a &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;remaining&lt;/em&gt; string, everything before the first &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; is the version,
  and everything after it is the release. If there isn&amp;#8217;t one, the release is considered&amp;nbsp;null/nill/None/whatever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="how-yum-compares-evr"&gt;How Yum Compares&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EVR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the package string is parsed into its &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EVR&lt;/span&gt; components, yum calls &lt;code&gt;rpmUtils.miscutils.compareEVR()&lt;/code&gt;,
which does some data type massaging for the inputs, and then calls out to &lt;code&gt;rpm.labelCompare()&lt;/code&gt;
(found in &lt;code&gt;rpm.git/python/header-py.c&lt;/code&gt;). &lt;code&gt;labelCompare()&lt;/code&gt; sets each epoch
to &amp;#8220;0&amp;#8221; if it was null/Nonem, and then uses &lt;code&gt;compare_values()&lt;/code&gt; to compare each &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EVR&lt;/span&gt; portion, which in turn falls through
to a function called &lt;code&gt;rpmvercmp()&lt;/code&gt; (see below). The algorithm for &lt;code&gt;labelCompare()&lt;/code&gt; is as&amp;nbsp;follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set each epoch value to 0 if it&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;null/None.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare the epoch values using &lt;code&gt;compare_values()&lt;/code&gt;. If they&amp;#8217;re not equal, return that result, else
   move on to the next portion (version). The logic within &lt;code&gt;compare_values()&lt;/code&gt; is that if one is empty/null
   and the other is not, the non-empty one is greater, and that ends the comparison. If neither of
   them is empty/not present, compare them using &lt;code&gt;rpmvercmp()&lt;/code&gt; and follow the same logic; if one
   is &amp;#8220;greater&amp;#8221; (newer) than the other, that&amp;#8217;s the end result of the comparison. Otherwise, move
   on to the next component&amp;nbsp;(version).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare the versions using the same&amp;nbsp;logic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare the releases using the same&amp;nbsp;logic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If all of the components are &amp;#8220;equal&amp;#8221;, the packages are the&amp;nbsp;same.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real magic, obviously, happens in &lt;code&gt;rpmvercmp()&lt;/code&gt;, the rpm library function to compare two
versions (or epochs, or releases). That&amp;#8217;s also where the madness&amp;nbsp;happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="how-rpm-compares-version-parts"&gt;How &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt; Compares Version&amp;nbsp;Parts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt; is written in C. Converting all of the buffer and pointer processing for these strings
over to Ruby was quite a pain. That being said, I didn&amp;#8217;t make this up, this is actually the
algorithm that &lt;code&gt;rpmvercmp()&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;lib/rpmvercmp.c&lt;/code&gt;) uses to compare version &amp;#8220;parts&amp;#8221;
(epoch, version, release). This function returns 0 if the strings are equal, 1 if &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; (the
first string argument) is newer than &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; (the second string argument), or -1 if
&lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is older than &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt;. Also keep in mind that this uses pointers in C, so it works by removing
a sequence of 0 or more characters from the front of each string, comparing them, and then repeating
for the remaining characters in each string until something is unequal, or a string reaches its&amp;nbsp;end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the strings are binary equal (&lt;code&gt;a == b&lt;/code&gt;), they&amp;#8217;re equal, return&amp;nbsp;0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loop over the strings, left-to-right.&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trim anything that&amp;#8217;s not &lt;code&gt;[A-Za-z0-9]&lt;/code&gt; or tilde (&lt;code&gt;~&lt;/code&gt;) from the front of both&amp;nbsp;strings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If both strings start with a tilde, discard it and move on to the next&amp;nbsp;character.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If string &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; starts with a tilde and string &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; does not, return -1 (string &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is older);
   and the inverse if string &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; starts with a tilde and string &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; does&amp;nbsp;not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;End the loop if either string has reached zero&amp;nbsp;length.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the first character of &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is a digit, pop the leading chunk of continuous digits from
   each string (which may be &amp;#8221; for &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; if only one &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; starts with digits). If &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; begins
   with a letter, do the same for leading&amp;nbsp;letters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the segement from &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; had 0 length, return 1 if the segment from &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; was numeric, or
   -1 if it was alphabetic. The logical result of this is that if &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; begins with numbers
   and &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; does not, &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is newer (return 1). If &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; begins with letters and &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; does not,
   then &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is older (return -1). If the leading character(s) from &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; were both
   numbers or both letters, continue&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the leading segments were both numeric, discard any leading zeros and &lt;em&gt;whichever one is longer
   wins&lt;/em&gt;. If &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is longer than &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; (without leading zeroes), return 1, and vice-versa. If
   they&amp;#8217;re of the same length, continue&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare the leading segments with &lt;code&gt;strcmp()&lt;/code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; in Ruby). If that returns a non-zero
   value, then return that value. Else continue to the next iteration of the&amp;nbsp;loop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the loop ended (nothing has been returned yet, either both strings are totally the same or they&amp;#8217;re
   the same up to the end of one of them, like with &amp;#8220;1.2.3&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;1.2.3b&amp;#8221;), then the longest wins -
   if what&amp;#8217;s left of &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is longer than what&amp;#8217;s left of &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt;, return 1. Vice-versa for if what&amp;#8217;s
   left of &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; is longer than what&amp;#8217;s left of &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt;. And finally, if what&amp;#8217;s left of them is the same
   length, return&amp;nbsp;0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well there you have it. Quite convoluted. And full of things like the &amp;#8220;~&amp;#8221; magic character (&amp;#8220;~1&amp;#8221; is always
older than&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;9999zzzz&amp;#8221;).&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Antman</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 23:31:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2014-07-11:2014/07/how-yum-and-rpm-compare-versions/</guid><category>rpm</category><category>yum</category><category>puppet</category><category>versions</category></item><item><title>Blog Moved from Self-hosted WordPress to Pelican on GitHub Pages</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2014/03/blog-moved-from-self-hosted-wordpress-to-pelican-on-github-pages/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I just finally finished my migration from self-hosted WordPress to &lt;a href="http://getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;, a Python-based
static site generator, hosted on &lt;a href="http://pages.github.com/"&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s not only easier and free, but also the
first step in my plan to migrate off of my &lt;a href="http://linode.com"&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VM&lt;/span&gt; and onto a mix of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EC2&lt;/span&gt; and free&amp;nbsp;services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m sure this post will be &lt;a href="/2009/02/wordpress-installation-finished/"&gt;around in five years&lt;/a&gt; when there&amp;#8217;s a smarter way
to do all this, but until then&amp;#8230;&amp;nbsp;yay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hit a number of bumps during the migration, mainly around &lt;a href="/2014/02/converting-wordpress-posts-to-pelican-markdown/"&gt;Migrating &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; posts from WordPress to Markdown in Pelican&lt;/a&gt;
and migrating &lt;a href="/2014/03/wordpress-to-pelican-with-disqus-comments/"&gt;WordPress comments to Disqus&lt;/a&gt;, but in the end everything
seems to be working. Hopefully someone will find this and save a few hours or days of work if they try the same&amp;nbsp;thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post-go-live I still had some issues - Disqus was displaying an&amp;nbsp;error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were unable to load Disqus. If you are a moderator please see our troubleshooting&amp;nbsp;guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;on all posts created after the WordPress migration, and FeedBurner rejected my attempts to change the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; feed &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; to
its new value (though I&amp;#8217;m pretty sure that&amp;#8217;s because I neglected to drop the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TTL&lt;/span&gt; on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; record, and I can&amp;#8217;t
find a way to tell Feedburner to purge it from&amp;nbsp;cache).&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Antman</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 14:14:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2014-03-01:2014/03/blog-moved-from-self-hosted-wordpress-to-pelican-on-github-pages/</guid><category>blog</category><category>wordpress</category><category>pelican</category><category>github</category></item><item><title>Planning Migration from WordPress to Static Site</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2014/01/planning-migration-from-wordpress-to-static-site/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Right now, this blog, my email, and a whole bunch of other services are
hosted on a &lt;a href="http://linode.com"&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt; Xen &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VM&lt;/span&gt;. I don&amp;#8217;t really keep up
to date with administration and upgrades the way I used to, and
honestly, I&amp;#8217;d rather spend my time working on other things (like
actually writing all of the blog posts that I&amp;#8217;ve been planning to. The
first thing I&amp;#8217;ve identified for migration is this blog itself. It&amp;#8217;s
currently on WordPress and, frankly, I don&amp;#8217;t either need nor like it.
But there are some features I like. I&amp;#8217;d like to end up with a static
site generator, hosted from either S3 or GitHub Pages. I know that means
I&amp;#8217;ll lost comments (unless I move to a third-party, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JS&lt;/span&gt;-based comment
system like &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/"&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt;, which means I&amp;#8217;ll lose
&lt;em&gt;control&lt;/em&gt; over my comments) but I suppose I can live with that. What I
really want is something simple, static, cheap or free (that I&amp;#8217;ll likely
put behind a small ec2 instance running nginx for&amp;nbsp;redirects/rewrites).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m still in the planning phase, and trying to come up with a
feature-by-feature comparison of my options. I&amp;#8217;ll likely post that when
I finally have it done (at the moment it&amp;#8217;s in a very rough &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0AnHh-ye5DNiNdF9DWkJrT2kzSkNsNVp6cjMzLXJ6VEE&amp;amp;usp=sharing"&gt;Google Docs
spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;).
I&amp;#8217;m trying to round up my static site generator options and see which
ones will do most, if not all, of what I want (though I still haven&amp;#8217;t
discounted using hosted wordpress if it comes down to it). Here are the
features I currently &amp;#8220;use&amp;#8221; (have) on my WordPress&amp;nbsp;blog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User-defined permalinks to&amp;nbsp;posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; feed of blog (currently powered by FeedBurner) and of&amp;nbsp;comments)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Categories (a post can be in multiple&amp;nbsp;categories)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Category and Tag&amp;nbsp;pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;per-Category and per-Tag feeds&amp;nbsp;(&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tag cloud &amp;#8220;widget&amp;#8221; in&amp;nbsp;sidebar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Themes. I actually like my current &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;theme&amp;#8230;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visitor statistics (currently self-hosted
    &lt;a href="http://piwik.org/"&gt;Piwik&lt;/a&gt;, formerly Google&amp;nbsp;Analytics)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post publishing via cron&amp;#8217;ed script (&lt;em&gt;see below&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Draft/Pending status (i.e. let me save a partial post, and let me
    save a complete post but mark it &amp;#8220;pending&amp;#8221; so I can just publish it&amp;nbsp;later)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commenting (this will probably be the big sticking&amp;nbsp;point)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syntax&amp;nbsp;hilighting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As &amp;#8220;weird&amp;#8221; as this is, I write all my posts in raw &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;, and am
    perfectly happy doing&amp;nbsp;that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;Subscribe via Email&amp;#8221; FeedBurner&amp;nbsp;widget&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Sitemap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter&amp;nbsp;box/widget&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pingbacks (not that these are really useful for anything other than
    spam these&amp;nbsp;days)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic or manual post excerpts for feeds,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote publishing via &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPC&lt;/span&gt;/Android app (not that I&amp;#8217;ve used it
    more than once or&amp;nbsp;twice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advertising - I currently use Google AdSense on my blog. The revenue
    from my tiny hit count isn&amp;#8217;t enough to offset the cost of a Linode,
    but if I moved to a much less expensive hosting service, it might be
    worth considering (you can&amp;#8217;t run ads on the free hosted WordPress,
    and I doubt you can on GitHub Pages&amp;nbsp;either).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should be updating this post when I do some more research and have a
comparison of the&amp;nbsp;options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note on &amp;#8220;Post publishing via cron&amp;#8217;ed script&amp;#8221; - sometimes I sit down and
write half a dozen or so blog posts at a time. But I don&amp;#8217;t want them all
to show up immediately, and spam the few people who still use &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt;
readers after the death of Google Reader. So I set the posts to
&amp;#8220;Pending&amp;#8221; status, and I have a cron&amp;#8217;ed script that runs every weekday
morning and publishes the one oldest &amp;#8220;pending&amp;#8221; post. Who knows if this
actually does any good or&amp;nbsp;not&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 15:15:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2014-01-01:2014/01/planning-migration-from-wordpress-to-static-site/</guid><category>blog</category><category>jekyll</category><category>pelican</category><category>python</category><category>static site</category><category>wordpress</category></item><item><title>Random Links for Wednesday, October 24th</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/10/random-links-for-wednesday-october-24th/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Some random interesting links from Slashdot for&amp;nbsp;today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.slashdot.org/story/12/10/23/2038220/the-greatest-battle-of-the-personal-computing-revolution-lies-ahead"&gt;The Greatest Battle of the Personal Computing Revolution Lies Ahead
    -
    Slashdot&lt;/a&gt;.
    A bit of a rant, but makes some good points that are close to my
    heart, and unfortunately far from the thoughts of many&amp;nbsp;non-techies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://tos-dr.info/"&gt;Terms of Service; Didn&amp;#8217;t Read&lt;/a&gt; - an
    interesting&amp;nbsp;project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://yro.slashdot.org/story/12/10/21/208206/how-patent-trolls-harm-the-economy"&gt;How Patent Trolls Harm the Economy -
    Slashdot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;another issue close to my&amp;nbsp;heart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.datacenterknowledge.com/archives/2012/10/17/how-google-cools-its-armada-of-servers/"&gt;How Google Cools Its Armada of Servers » Data Center&amp;nbsp;Knowledge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/about/datacenters/gallery/#/"&gt;Data centers – Google Data
    centers&lt;/a&gt; - A
    photo tour of Google data centers, by Google, along with a &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/+google/posts/Gk8ScjPX23n"&gt;Google+
    post&lt;/a&gt; about the
    architecture photographer who did this&amp;nbsp;work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://tech.slashdot.org/story/12/10/22/0518231/darpa-funds-a-300-software-defined-radio-for-hackers"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DARPA&lt;/span&gt; Funds a $300 Software-Defined Radio For Hackers -
    Slashdot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;way&amp;nbsp;cool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://map.honeynet.org/"&gt;Honeynet Map&lt;/a&gt; - &amp;#8220;realtime&amp;#8221; map of
    cybersecurity incidents, from the Honeynet&amp;nbsp;Project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://science.slashdot.org/story/12/10/17/1741225/malware-is-rampant-on-medical-devices-in-hospitals"&gt;Malware Is &amp;#8216;Rampant&amp;#8217; On Medical Devices In Hospitals -
    Slashdot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a bit scary, but unfortunately not that hard to guess. I&amp;#8217;ve seen
(probably unpatched) Windows 2000 workstations on hospital&amp;nbsp;networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To top off the scary posts: &lt;a href="http://news.slashdot.org/story/12/10/17/0325236/researcher-reverse-engineers-pacemaker-transmitter-to-deliver-deadly-shocks"&gt;Researcher Reverse-Engineers Pacemaker
    Transmitter To Deliver Deadly Shocks -&amp;nbsp;Slashdot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 12:01:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-10-24:2012/10/random-links-for-wednesday-october-24th/</guid><category>appliancization</category><category>cooling</category><category>datacenter</category><category>google</category><category>healthcare</category><category>legal</category><category>links</category><category>malware</category><category>pacemaker</category><category>patents</category><category>radio</category><category>SDR</category><category>security</category></item><item><title>Custom Tombstone and Road Sign Pictures</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/10/custom-tombstone-and-road-sign-pictures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On the lighter side, I found a few web sites by &lt;a href="http://www.pixbytom.com/"&gt;Tom
Blackwell&lt;/a&gt; that do some fun stuff with text
overlays on images. seems like a nice little tool for those
end-of-project powerpoints, or to send out the monthly &amp;#8220;most rolled-back
commits&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;medal&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tombstonebuilder.com/index.php"&gt;Custom Tombstone&amp;nbsp;Maker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Image of tombstone, with 'Your Text Goes Here' carved into it" src="/GFX/my_tombstone.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.customroadsign.com/"&gt;CustomRoadSign.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Highway sign with 'Your Text Goes Here' written on it" src="/GFX/menusign.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.custommotelsign.com/"&gt;CustomMotelSign.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Motel-style sign with 'Your Text Goes Here' written on it" src="/GFX/motelsign.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.getamedal.com/"&gt;GetAMedal.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Gold medal with 'Your Text Goes Here' written on it" src="/GFX/medal.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 07:02:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-10-16:2012/10/custom-tombstone-and-road-sign-pictures/</guid><category>graphics</category><category>humor</category><category>road sign</category><category>sign</category><category>tombstone</category></item><item><title>All-Mechanical Computer Instructional Video</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/10/all-mechanical-computer-instructional-video/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I saw a link to &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s1i-dnAH9Y4"&gt;this YouTube
video&lt;/a&gt; shared on &lt;a href="http://everythingsysadmin.com/2012/10/mechanical-computer-instructio.html"&gt;Tom
Limoncelli&amp;#8217;s
blog&lt;/a&gt;.
It&amp;#8217;s a 1953 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; Navy instructional video about an all-mechanical fire
control computer. Yes, I really mean a &lt;em&gt;computer&lt;/em&gt; that can solve
continuously changing 25-variable fire control problems using only
mechanical means (gears, cams, etc.). Think about it for a minute - it&amp;#8217;s
truly mind-boggling. And really gives one an amazing appreciation for
the power of a simple pocket calculator, and the amazing engineering
that went into solving these problems before electronic computers. I&amp;#8217;m
usually not much of a math geek, but I watched the whole 40 minute video
and was in awe of both the simple ability to use three arms and a pin to
multiply numbers, and the amazingly precise engineering and machining it
would take to translate various rotation inputs into landing a shell on
a moving ship miles away. It&amp;#8217;s a really good watch, and will probably
leave you astonished by both how far technology has come (and what we
take for granted every day), and by the fact that feats of engineering
like this one worked quite&amp;nbsp;well.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 20:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-10-12:2012/10/all-mechanical-computer-instructional-video/</guid><category>mechanical computer</category></item><item><title>New Job</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/09/new-job/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today is my last day in my almost-year-long stint as a System
Administrator at &lt;a href="http://www.techtarget.com/"&gt;TechTarget&lt;/a&gt;. Monday, I
start a new contract-to-perm position as a Linux Engineer with &lt;a href="http://cmgdigital.com/"&gt;Cox
Media Group Digital &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Strategy&lt;/a&gt;. I can&amp;#8217;t say a
whole lot about the new job, other than it will hopefully be a great
change for me, and they make heavy use of
&lt;a href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to get a bit of an
idea of what they&amp;#8217;re about, here&amp;#8217;s a &lt;a href="https://github.com/coxmediagroup/jobs/blob/master/ethos.rst"&gt;document on their departmental
ethos&lt;/a&gt;.
Hopefully I&amp;#8217;ll be able to post more useful information here, and post
more often, in the future. I&amp;#8217;m really psyched about the new&amp;nbsp;gig.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 12:36:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-09-28:2012/09/new-job/</guid><category>cmg</category><category>coxmedia</category><category>job</category><category>techtarget</category></item><item><title>Piwik Web Analytics, and some unfortunate stats about my blog</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/08/piwik-web-analytics-and-some-unfortunate-stats-about-my-blog/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Back in March when I selected a new template for this blog, I
&lt;a href="/2012/03/new-blog-theme/"&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; that I was looking into open source
self-hosted web analytics tools to replace &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/"&gt;Google
Analytics&lt;/a&gt;. There were a few reasons
for this; most importantly, it started from a discussion with some
privacy-conscious coworkers, who said that they use
&lt;a href="http://noscript.net/"&gt;NoScript&lt;/a&gt; and specifically block Google from
tracking them (which also breaks Google Analytics). This was a serious
issue for me, as I no longer process server-side logs but relied solely
on Google Analytics for traffic information. So, I decided to try
something other than Google and ended up settling on
&lt;a href="http://piwik.org/"&gt;Piwik&lt;/a&gt; as my solution. I will say, in full
disclosure, that the amount of information Piwki gives is a bit scary; I
can watch users navigate this blog in realtime, and even the initial
dashboard page gives a list of the most recent visitors, with their &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt;
address, country of origin, browser, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;, and the pages they visited.
However my decision was made on two main points: first, that I wanted
something withich could use server-side &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; to log visits (albeit with a
lot less information) of people who had JavaScript or tracking disabled,
and second, that if &lt;em&gt;someone&lt;/em&gt; is going to have such amazingly detailed
information on my visitors, it should be me, so I can ensure that I&amp;#8217;m
the only person who has access to it and that it isn&amp;#8217;t used for the
wrong&amp;nbsp;purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside: The only revenue I get from this site is through &lt;a href=""&gt;Google
AdSense&lt;/a&gt;, which isn&amp;#8217;t a whole lot given the low traffic (certainly
not enough to pay for the hosting). Other than that, I keep this blog
to try and share my knowledge with others, and hope that someone else
can find the solution to their problem here instead of doing the work
that I did. So, I find analytics very helpful; I check my stats now
and then, go back and update or add to the most popular posts, and try
to write relevant posts if it seems like a lot of people are finding
their way here for something slightly different than the actual post
they landed on. Unfortunately, that last point isn&amp;#8217;t as easy since
&lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2011/10/making-search-more-secure.html"&gt;Google switched to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTPS&lt;/span&gt; Search for logged-in users on October 18th,
2011&lt;/a&gt;
- I can no longer use Piwik see the search keywords that got Google
users to my site. Luckily, these are still available through &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/"&gt;Google
Webmaster Tools&lt;/a&gt; (via
Traffic -&gt; Search Queries on the left menu), though it adds an
additional step and removes some of my motivation to check regularly
and make sure people are getting useful content. Also, perhaps most
importantly, it doesn&amp;#8217;t let me associate search query with other stats
like time on page, so even if one search query was very popular, I
have no way of knowing whether all those people actually read the
page, or took one look at it and&amp;nbsp;left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like Piwki. I don&amp;#8217;t use most of it terribly often, but it gives
me a nice overview visits graph on the WordPress dashboard (via the
&lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/wp-piwik/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;WP&lt;/span&gt;-Piwik&lt;/a&gt; plugin),
infinitely detailed information (most of which I haven&amp;#8217;t even looked at)
in the Piwki web interface, and nightly email reports of visits to the
site. It also supports multiple sites, so I have it on my ancient
&lt;a href="http://wiki.jasonantman.com"&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;, my
&lt;a href="http://redmine.jasonantman.com"&gt;Redmine&lt;/a&gt; instance, and even
&lt;a href="/2012/03/adding-piwik-web-analytics-integration-to-viewvc/"&gt;ViewVC&lt;/a&gt;.
I&amp;#8217;d highly recommend it; it&amp;#8217;s full-featured (beyond anything I can even
comprehend,&amp;nbsp;really)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was recently looking through the stats for this blog, and came by some
unfortunate, though not surprising, trends. Below is the graph of visits
per day, from April 1, 2012 through today (August 26,&amp;nbsp;2012):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="blog visits chart" src="/GFX/blog_visits.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#8217;s probably not terribly unusual for a site with as much technical
    content as mine (and mostly professional stuff, not just for
    hobbyists), my weekend traffic is usually a full 50% lower than
    weekday traffic. This can also be seen in the graph of visits by
    visitor&amp;#8217;s local time, which is decidedly biased towards the 9am-5pm
    window:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="blog visits chart by visitor local
    time" src="/GFX/blog_visits_localtime.png" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    I guess there&amp;#8217;s nothing I can really do about that, and it just
    gives me a nice maintenance window at 4am on Sunday mornings&amp;nbsp;:)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking at the overall graph, there also appears to be quite a bit
    of oscillation of the average visits over time. It&amp;#8217;s nothing
    terribly large, but at a guess, I&amp;#8217;d attribute it to my sporadic&amp;nbsp;posting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Though it&amp;#8217;s not visible in these graphs, this site has an 80% bounce
    rate (the percent of visitors that viewed only one page and then
    left the site). I guess that&amp;#8217;s also not terribly unusual for a site
    with mostly how-to information on a wide variety of&amp;nbsp;topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To add a little more information to some of the previous items, here
    is the chart of my &lt;a href="http://feedburner.google.com"&gt;Feedburner&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt;/Atom feed, since I started using Feedburner in February. The
    number of subscribers is in green, and the reach (number of people
    who actually clicked through to a post) is in blue:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Feedburner stats" src="/GFX/feedburner_stats.png" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    This is a clear indication of something even stronger than the
    &amp;#8220;bounce rate&amp;#8221;; the apparently high number of people who subscribe to
    and then unsubscribe from my feed (if these stats are accurate). To
    me, this is an even stronger indication that what I really need to
    do is post useful content on a more regular basis - I have a
    tendency to blog in spurts, and either start a draft and never
    finish it, or write a few posts and set them to &amp;#8220;pending&amp;#8221; status
    with the intent of publishing them over a few days&amp;#8230; and then
    forget the last&amp;nbsp;part.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2012 13:18:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-08-26:2012/08/piwik-web-analytics-and-some-unfortunate-stats-about-my-blog/</guid><category>blog</category><category>google analytics</category><category>piwik</category></item><item><title>SysAdmin Links of The Day</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/04/sysadmin-links-of-the-day/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A few links that I&amp;#8217;ve had in my &amp;#8220;mention in a blog post&amp;#8221; category for a&amp;nbsp;while:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazure/archive/2012/03/09/summary-of-windows-azure-service-disruption-on-feb-29th-2012.aspx"&gt;Summary of Windows Azure Service Disruption on Feb 29th, 2012 -
    Windows Azure - Site Home - &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MSDN&lt;/span&gt;
    Blogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; detailed and interesting post on what caused the Windows
Azure cloud outage on February 29th, 2012. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IMHO&lt;/span&gt; many of these
failures were predictable, and the bulk of the outage was caused by
a combination of inputs not being checked for validity in code, or
the invalid case not being handled&amp;nbsp;properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://highscalability.com/blog/2012/3/12/google-taming-the-long-latency-tail-when-more-machines-equal.html"&gt;High Scalability - High Scalability - Google: Taming the Long
    Latency Tail - When More Machines Equals Worse&amp;nbsp;Results&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://everythingsysadmin.com/2012/03/fear-of-rebooting.html"&gt;Everything Sysadmin: Fear of&amp;nbsp;Rebooting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://everythingsysadmin.com/2012/03/using-statements-of-undeniable.html"&gt;Everything Sysadmin: Using statements of &amp;#8220;Undeniable&amp;nbsp;Value&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 21:18:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-04-24:2012/04/sysadmin-links-of-the-day/</guid><category>azure</category><category>failure</category><category>microsoft</category><category>sysadmin</category></item><item><title>Instagram - Scaling a Startup</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/04/instagram-scaling-a-startup/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you keep up with news on the &amp;#8216;net, you may have heard about photo
sharing startup &lt;a href="http://instagr.am"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, which was &lt;a href="http://finance.fortune.cnn.com/2012/04/09/breaking-facebook-buying-instagram-for-1-billion/?section=magazines_fortune"&gt;purchased by
Facebook for $1
Billion&lt;/a&gt;
just 9 days after they released their Android app. Well, not only are
they based mostly on open source software (well, yeah, pretty much a
given for web startups these days), but they&amp;#8217;ve dealt with scaling
issues like a million new users in 12 hours, and they&amp;#8217;re &lt;a href="http://instagram-engineering.tumblr.com/post/20541814340/keeping-instagram-up-with-over-a-million-new-users-in"&gt;talking about
it&lt;/a&gt;.
There&amp;#8217;s the &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/12/how-to-scale-a-1-billion-startup-a-guide-from-instagram-co-founder-mike-krieger/"&gt;slide deck to a talk that co-founder Mike Krieger
gave&lt;/a&gt;
on TechCrunch and
&lt;a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/89025069/Mike-Krieger-Instagram-at-the-Airbnb-tech-talk-on-Scaling-Instagram"&gt;Scribd&lt;/a&gt;,
along with a &lt;a href="http://highscalability.com/blog/2012/4/16/instagram-architecture-update-whats-new-with-instagram.html"&gt;High Scalability article about
it&lt;/a&gt;,
and an &lt;a href="http://highscalability.com/blog/2012/4/9/the-instagram-architecture-facebook-bought-for-a-cool-billio.html"&gt;earlier High Scalability article that gives an overview of the
company and some details of what and how they&amp;#8217;re
running&lt;/a&gt;.
Instagram Engineering also has a
&lt;a href="http://instagram-engineering.tumblr.com/"&gt;tumblr&lt;/a&gt; account, with a bunch
of cool posts like &lt;a href="http://instagram-engineering.tumblr.com/post/20541814340/keeping-instagram-up-with-over-a-million-new-users-in"&gt;Keeping Instagram up with over a million new users
in twelve
hours&lt;/a&gt;
(which specifically mentions &lt;a href="http://github.com/etsy/statsd/"&gt;statsd&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://blog.bitbucket.org/2011/05/17/tracking-slow-requests-with-dogslow/"&gt;dogslow&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://pgfouine.projects.postgresql.org/"&gt;PGFouine&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://github.com/Instagram/node2dm"&gt;node2dm&lt;/a&gt; and some database stuff)
and &lt;a href="http://instagram-engineering.tumblr.com/post/13649370142/what-powers-instagram-hundreds-of-instances-dozens-of"&gt;What Powers Instagram: Hundreds of Instances, Dozens of
Technologies&lt;/a&gt;
which talks about their &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; and hosting (Ubuntu 11.04 on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EC2&lt;/span&gt;), load
balancing (nginx, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; and Amazon Elastic Load Balancer), Django, Redis,
Solr, Munin,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a really cool company, doing some &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; cool stuff, at a
&lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; large scale, and growing&amp;nbsp;fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On another note, I&amp;#8217;m continuing my attempt to read all of the excellent
Puppet articles on &lt;a href="http://www.masterzen.fr/blog/archives/"&gt;Brice Figureau&amp;#8217;s (aka masterzen)
blog&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s taking a while, as
it&amp;#8217;s really good, in-depth information that I want to rememeber, but I&amp;#8217;d
highly recommend it for anyone working with&amp;nbsp;Puppet.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 19:31:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-04-24:2012/04/instagram-scaling-a-startup/</guid><category>dogslow</category><category>facebook</category><category>high scalability</category><category>instagram</category><category>node2dm</category><category>pgfouine</category><category>puppet</category><category>scaling</category><category>statsd</category></item><item><title>A Collection of Great Links on Monitoring, SysAdmin, Scaling, etc.</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/04/a-collection-of-great-links-on-monitoring-sysadmin-scaling-etc/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve had a bunch of tabs open in my browser for a while - stuff that I
read, thought was wonderful, and wanted to comment on. At risk of
letting it pile up forever, here&amp;#8217;s a collection of links that I thought
were really interesting or&amp;nbsp;insightful&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.mongodb.org/post/172254834/mongodb-is-fantastic-for-logging"&gt;MongoDB is Fantastic for
    Logging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was looking into some log storage ideas, and came by this post
(on the MongoDB blog) about why Mongo is well-suited to storing&amp;nbsp;logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sonian.com/cloud-monitoring-sensu/"&gt;Sensu&lt;/a&gt; - a
    Ruby-based cloud-oriented monitoring system. It uses &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AMQP&lt;/span&gt;/RabbitMQ
    to communicate between the clients and server, which is a really big
    part of what I think monitoring should&amp;nbsp;be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://highscalability.com/"&gt;High Scalability&lt;/a&gt; - this is one of the
    few blogs I follow on a regular basis. Some really wonderful stuff,
    and great food for&amp;nbsp;thought.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://everythingsysadmin.com/2012/03/fear-of-rebooting.html"&gt;Everything Sysadmin: Fear of
    Rebooting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A great article on Tom Limoncelli&amp;#8217;s blog about why we fear
rebooting machines and why this is bad - moreover, why we should
reboot&amp;nbsp;often.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://techblog.netflix.com/2012/02/fault-tolerance-in-high-volume.html"&gt;The Netflix Tech Blog: Fault Tolerance in a High Volume,
    Distributed
    System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a &lt;em&gt;really, really&lt;/em&gt; cool post NetFlix about how latency
increases in a single subsystem can bring down their whole &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; in
seconds, and how they combat this. Really cool&amp;nbsp;stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/news/2012/04/exclusive-a-behind-the-scenes-look-at-facebook-release-engineering.ars/1"&gt;Ars Technica - Exclusive: a behind-the-scenes look at Facebook
    release
    engineering&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ars Technical is more or less &amp;#8220;mainstream media&amp;#8221; to me, but this
is a really interesting writeup on Facebook&amp;#8217;s release engineering
process, albeit at a higher level. Specifically, it talks about
their automation, phased rollouts, rollbacks, and how they release
the Facebook codebase as a single giant binary, sent out via&amp;nbsp;BitTorrent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/monitoringsucks/blog-posts"&gt;Monitoring Sucks blog posts
    (github)&lt;/a&gt; - The
    &amp;#8220;monitoing sucks&amp;#8221; movement really speaks to me, having worked
    extensively with Nagios, Cacti, and similar technologies.
    Specifically, having rolled out monitoring in a variety of &amp;#8220;weird&amp;#8221;
    scenarios (a lot of monitoring devices or whole networks behind &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NAT&lt;/span&gt;,
    on dynamic &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; connections, or otherwise unreachable from a central
    server), I&amp;#8217;ve felt a lot of pain in the current want of doing
    things. There are a lot of &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; good thoughts linked here,
    especially the &lt;a href="http://jedi.be/blog/2012/01/03/monitoring-wonderland-survey-introduction"&gt;&amp;#8220;wonderland&amp;#8221; series by Patrick
    Debois&lt;/a&gt;
    and the &lt;a href="http://holmwood.id.au/~lindsay/2012/01/09/monitoring-sucks-latency-sucks-more"&gt;&amp;#8220;Latency sucks&amp;#8221; series by Lindsay
    Holmwood&lt;/a&gt;.
    This really got me thinking about my ideal monitoring system, which
    among other things, would integrate the &amp;#8220;alerting&amp;#8221; functions of
    Nagios with graphing/trending and correlation, would be based on
    some sort of message queue architecture (that supports multiple
    levels of proxies that could gracefully support &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NAT&lt;/span&gt; and multiple
    hops), and would be configured almost totally on the originating
    &amp;#8220;client&amp;#8221; (unlike the pain of distributed&amp;nbsp;Nagios/Icinga).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://assets.en.oreilly.com/1/event/65/Metrics-driven%20Engineering%20at%20Etsy%20Presentation.pdf"&gt;Mike Brittain - Metrics Driven Engineering at Etsy (3.&lt;span class="caps"&gt;2MB&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;presentation slides. I&amp;#8217;d &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; to see the video. Some really good
ideas about putting the science back into being a SysAdmin. Also
mentions a few tools I really want to play around with (including
ganglia, graphite, logster and StatsD). Also mentions adding &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;
memory usage and time to Apache logs, which I don&amp;#8217;t believe I never
thought&amp;nbsp;of.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some really thoughtful posts from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;R. I.&lt;/span&gt; Pienaar on &lt;a href="http://www.devco.net/archives/2011/03/19/thinking_about_monitoring_frameworks.php"&gt;Thinking about
    monitoring
    frameworks&lt;/a&gt;
    and &lt;a href="http://www.devco.net/archives/2011/04/04/monitoring_framework_composable_architectures.php"&gt;Composable
    Architectures&lt;/a&gt;.
    Some really good stuff, but what else would you expect from someone
    &lt;a href="https://github.com/ripienaar/"&gt;like this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 10:24:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-04-21:2012/04/a-collection-of-great-links-on-monitoring-sysadmin-scaling-etc/</guid><category>amqp</category><category>etsy</category><category>facebook</category><category>limoncelli</category><category>links</category><category>mongodb</category><category>monitoring</category><category>monitoringsucks</category><category>netflix</category><category>sensu</category></item><item><title>Rsync on an Android phone</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/04/rsync-on-an-android-phone/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while, there are some files that I want kept in sync
between my Android-based phone and one of my Linux (or Mac, or any Unix,
or maybe Windows too, but I use Linux&amp;#8230;) boxes. Yeah, I can copy them
over manually via &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; or even something a bit simpler like
&lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=lysesoft.andftp"&gt;AndFTP&lt;/a&gt;
(assuming you can &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCP&lt;/span&gt; to the target machine). But that&amp;#8217;s a real pain for
anything like my &lt;a href="http://keepass.info/"&gt;KeePass&lt;/a&gt; (well, actually
&lt;a href="http://www.keepassx.org/"&gt;KeePassX&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.android.keepass"&gt;KeePassDroid&lt;/a&gt;)
password database, that I might add something to at any time and forget
to sync. I also try to occasionally (waiting in line?) backup &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;, call
logs, etc. on my phone, and like to have those synced back to the
desktop&amp;nbsp;automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the solution: &lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=eu.kowalczuk.rsync4android"&gt;rsync backup for
Android&lt;/a&gt;,
a &lt;a href="http://rsync.samba.org/"&gt;rsync&lt;/a&gt; client for Android that includes
Tasker plugins (there are a few things about the app that I don&amp;#8217;t like,
but it seems to be the only option at the moment), and
&lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=net.dinglisch.android.taskerm"&gt;Tasker&lt;/a&gt;,
an automation framework for Android.Tasker is one of the few Android
apps that I&amp;#8217;ve actually bought (i.e. not free/no-cost), and is currently
selling for $6.49. It&amp;#8217;s an incredibly capable task automator, very much
akin to &lt;a href="http://www.twofortyfouram.com/"&gt;Locale&lt;/a&gt; on steroids. On the
down side, Tasker can eat up battery life if you don&amp;#8217;t configure it
intelligently, and it&amp;#8217;s not &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; 100% reliable when interacting with
the system. On the positive side, Tasker can identify practically any
combination of states in the android system (from hardware and software
events to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; location, time, signal status, etc.) and perform almost
any task on the system based on this information. Sure, this specific
problem could be solved with a cron replacement (which Android lacks, of
course), but Tasker can do things like play specific audio files when
you get an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt; from a specific number, mute audio at certain &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;
locations, or turn WiFi on when I get home and off when I leave the
house. It also has a plugin architecture, and rsync backup for Android
happens to have a plugin that works with&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, our goal is to have a daily, bi-directional, newest-file-wins sync
between a directory on our Android phone and a directory on a computer.
I&amp;#8217;m not going to go into a lot of the computer-side stuff, mainly
because that varies quite a bit between operating systems, and also
because my personal setup is a bit paranoid in terms of security. For
the computer side, we&amp;#8217;ll need a machine that can be SSHed to from the
Internet (either a static &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; or a known hostname/dynamic &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt;), a user
that can run rsync over &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt;, and a directory that&amp;#8217;s writable&amp;nbsp;(obviously).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy and install the
    &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.dinglisch.android.taskerm"&gt;Tasker&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=eu.kowalczuk.rsync4android"&gt;rsync backup for
    Android&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure the rsync stuff on the computer. In the simplest form,
    we&amp;#8217;ll just need a user that can login and run rsync, and a directory
    to sync from/to &lt;em&gt;(note: this should be a directory used only for
    syncing the&amp;nbsp;phone&amp;#8230;).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the rsync backup for Android app. Use Menu -&gt; Generate Keys to
    generate a new pair of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; keys, and then get the public key setup
    on the target computer. See &lt;a href="http://android.kowalczuk.eu/rsync4android/"&gt;the developer&amp;#8217;s web
    site&lt;/a&gt; for&amp;nbsp;instructions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once keys are setup, create a new profile called &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt;-droid&amp;#8221;. Set the
    local directory to a new empty directory (I used &lt;code&gt;/sdcard/sync&lt;/code&gt;),
    enter the remote host address, port, username, and remote directory,
    and select the private &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; key that you created. Check off &amp;#8220;rsync on
    reverse direction&amp;#8221;. As this program is just a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; wrapper around
    normal rsync binaries, you can specify additional options to the
    rsync command; my string ended up being
    &lt;code&gt;-vHrltDuO --chmod=Du+rwx,go-rwx,Fu+rw,go-rw --no-perms&lt;/code&gt;. If it
    helps, at the bottom of the screen you can see the actual rsync
    command line that will be run. Save when&amp;nbsp;done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save the profile, then long-press it and select &amp;#8220;Duplicate&amp;#8221;. Change
    the name to &amp;#8220;droid-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221;, uncheck &amp;#8220;rsync in reverse direction&amp;#8221;, and
    change your additional options as needed (mine became
    &lt;code&gt;-vHrltDu --chmod=Dug+rwx,o-rwx,Fug+rw,o-rw --no-perms&lt;/code&gt;). Save when&amp;nbsp;done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a test file in the sync directory on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt;, and a different
    one in the sync directory on the&amp;nbsp;droid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One at a time, in the rsync backup app, tap on the profile names. If
    all goes well, the syncs should run, and both files will now be in
    both places. If there are any problems, the output should help; the
    most likely issues are probably permissions, rsync command options,
    or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;keys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long-press each profile, select &amp;#8220;Edit&amp;#8221;, and check off &amp;#8220;Close log
    window after job is done&amp;#8221;. Save&amp;nbsp;profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now fire up Tasker. Click the &amp;#8220;+&amp;#8221; at the bottom of the screen to
    create a new profile, call it &amp;#8220;sync&amp;#8221;, and click the check&amp;nbsp;mark.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the First Context panel, tap Time, and select when you want the
    jobs to run; I chose 03:01. Tap the check&amp;nbsp;mark.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the Task Selection panel, tap New Task. Give it a name, like&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;sync2&amp;#8221;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the Task Edit panel, tap the &amp;#8220;+&amp;#8221; button at the bottom left, tap
    Plugin, tap &amp;#8220;rsync backup for Android&amp;#8221;, click the &amp;#8220;Edit&amp;#8221; button on
    the Configuration line, and select the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt;-droid rsync profile. Tap
    the check mark in the lower left to&amp;nbsp;save.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat the last step for the droid-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt; rsync&amp;nbsp;profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap the check box in the lower left. This saves the&amp;nbsp;profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the main Tasker screen, make sure there&amp;#8217;s a green check to the
    right of the profile you just added, and that the button at the
    bottom right of the screen is set to&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;On&amp;#8221;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming this all went well, the next time the time you specified rolls
around, your sync should run. If you gave the task a name in step 12,
you can setup additional profiles to run it at other times (or use the
repeat logic&amp;nbsp;builtin).&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 20:40:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-04-04:2012/04/rsync-on-an-android-phone/</guid><category>android</category><category>rsync</category><category>tasker</category></item><item><title>Github as a repository in Redmine</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/03/github-as-a-repository-in-redmine/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As a follow-up to my &lt;a href="/2012/03/cvs-to-svn-to-git/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt; to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SVN&lt;/span&gt; to Git&lt;/a&gt;
post, I have the &lt;a href="http://www.php-ems-tools.com"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMS&lt;/span&gt; Tools&lt;/a&gt;
repository migrated from my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SVN&lt;/span&gt; to
&lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/php-ems-tools"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. Since I&amp;#8217;m moving the
website and all development to a &lt;a href="http://www.redmine.org/"&gt;Redmine&lt;/a&gt;
instance, the next step is setting up Github to work as a revision
control repository in redmine. Well, it&amp;#8217;s dead simple. I just followed
the instructions for the &lt;a href="http://mentalized.net/journal/2009/08/03/redmine_plugin_github_hook/"&gt;Redmine plugin: Github
hook&lt;/a&gt;
, with the exception that I followed the &lt;a href="http://www.redmine.org/projects/redmine/wiki/HowTo_keep_in_sync_your_git_repository_for_redmine"&gt;redmine instructions for
setting up the repository
clone&lt;/a&gt;
instead of Step #2 in the plugin instructions. All worked well, though
I&amp;#8217;ll admit I only tried it talking to redmine over plain &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt;, not&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTPS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 21:36:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-03-27:2012/03/github-as-a-repository-in-redmine/</guid><category>git</category><category>github</category><category>redmine</category></item><item><title>New Blog Theme</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/03/new-blog-theme/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a follow-up to my &lt;a href="/2012/03/some-thoughts-on-choosing-a-new-wordpress-theme/"&gt;Some Thoughts on Choosing a New Wordpress
Theme&lt;/a&gt; post
from a few days ago, I decided on the
&lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/themes/admired"&gt;Admired&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://wp-ultra.com/themes/admired/"&gt;theme&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/103391260195864203534/posts"&gt;Brad
Thomas&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s
amazingly full-featured and has a good set of options. I had to manually
change a few things in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt; (I wanted to tweak the top bar colors a
bit in a way that&amp;#8217;s not supported in the options), but overall it was a
very simple transition. While it&amp;#8217;s unfortunately very far from valid
&lt;a href="http://validator.w3.org/check?verbose=1&amp;amp;uri=http://blog.jasonantman.com/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
or
&lt;a href="http://jigsaw.w3.org/css-validator/validator?profile=css3&amp;amp;warning=0&amp;amp;uri=http://blog.jasonantman.com/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
it seems quite&amp;nbsp;nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you happen to read this post and see anything wrong with the theme,
or it doesn&amp;#8217;t display properly for you, please leave a comment below
(with browser version and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;, if you&amp;nbsp;please).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next project, continuing on from my &lt;a href="/2012/03/inaccuracies-in-google-analytics-for-website-stats/"&gt;Inaccuracies in Google Analytics
for Website
Stats&lt;/a&gt;
post, is to compare the two self-hosted JavaScript-based open source
Google Analytics alternatives I&amp;#8217;ve identified
(&lt;a href="http://piwik.org/"&gt;Piwik&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.openwebanalytics.com/"&gt;Open Web
Analytics&lt;/a&gt;) and try one out on my site
(keeping in mind that my server is pretty heavily loaded, and I don&amp;#8217;t
want to push it over the edge). Once I come to some sort of conclusion
on that, I&amp;#8217;ll get back to some useful&amp;nbsp;posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 19:25:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-03-20:2012/03/new-blog-theme/</guid><category>blog</category><category>theme</category><category>wordpress</category></item><item><title>Some Thoughts on Choosing a New Wordpress Theme</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/03/some-thoughts-on-choosing-a-new-wordpress-theme/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;#8217;m going to choose a new theme for my blog. The current theme
is &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/themes/inove"&gt;iNove&lt;/a&gt; (albeit an older
version with some custom modifications), and I feel like it looks a bit
messy and has gotten a bit cluttered, so it&amp;#8217;s time to find something
new. I like the 2-column layout, and have a few other things I&amp;#8217;m looking
for - specifically, aside from something with advanced features like
lots of widget support and hooks, something that has good visual
separation between different posts and widgets. I also really want
something, if possible, with relative column widths. My current home and
work desktops both have dual monitors, and the minimum resolution I have
on one screen is 1920x1080. When I look at my blog in a maximized
window, about half the screen width is wasted with empty space. So,
ideally, I&amp;#8217;d like a theme that&amp;#8217;s based on relative widths, probably with
a &amp;#8220;min-width&amp;#8221; property so it wouldn&amp;#8217;t get compressed to an absurdly
narrow width on small&amp;nbsp;screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/"&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt; (as noted in
the &lt;a href="/privacy-policy/"&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;) for visitor statistics on this
blog (more about that in a moment). So, I took a peek at the breakdown
of visitors by screen resolution, and saw that for the past year, 94% of
the 27,500 visits had a screen width of 1024px or more (and the majority
of the others looked like mobile device resolutions, so they&amp;#8217;d probably
zoom the page correctly). So, my first gut reaction was to assume that I
could use a theme approximately 1000px wide. Unfortunately, there&amp;#8217;s two
main problems with that: first, as mentioned by &lt;a href="http://css-tricks.com/screen-resolution-notequalto-browser-window/"&gt;Chris Coyier on
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;-Tricks.com&lt;/a&gt;,
just because someone has a given screen resolution doesn&amp;#8217;t mean their
browser window (let alone the viewport) is that size. As a matter of
fact, I usually have my main browser window set at about 80% of the
width of one of my monitors, with my instant messaging client
&lt;a href="http://pidgin.im/"&gt;Pidgin&lt;/a&gt; taking up the rest of the space. So there&amp;#8217;s
one inaccuracy. There&amp;#8217;s a potentially much greater inaccuracy in my
stats as well, which I&amp;#8217;m going to discuss in a &lt;a href="/2012/03/inaccuracies-in-google-analytics-for-website-stats/"&gt;separate
post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 11:48:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-03-17:2012/03/some-thoughts-on-choosing-a-new-wordpress-theme/</guid><category>analysis</category><category>analytics</category><category>blog</category><category>google</category><category>logging</category><category>stats</category><category>theme</category><category>wordpress</category></item><item><title>Inaccuracies in Google Analytics for Website Stats</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/03/inaccuracies-in-google-analytics-for-website-stats/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I use Google Analytics for visitor stats on this blog. Not because I&amp;#8217;m
trying to direct-market to my readers or become Big Brother, but for a
number of simple&amp;nbsp;reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#8217;s simple - no software for me to update, and nothing that needs
    to run on my server and read through giant log files every night.
    Google does it all for&amp;nbsp;me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gives a lot more information than I can get from just web server&amp;nbsp;logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because of Google&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;big brother&amp;#8221; tracking, and the vast number of
    sites that they track people on, I can tell things I&amp;#8217;d have no other
    way of knowing, like how long someone stayed on my&amp;nbsp;page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They tell me &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt; stats like which search keywords brought the
    most people to my site and which posts are the most popular, which I
    keep in mind when writing new stuff and updating older&amp;nbsp;posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They tell me information about client operating system and browser
    version, which I think tells quite a bit about my&amp;nbsp;audience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As far as I know, they&amp;#8217;re pretty good at filtering out anything
    other than an actual human&amp;nbsp;visitor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They tell me stats that have no real use to me, but are just cook -
    like what countries my visitors are from, what type of Internet
    connection they&amp;#8217;re on, their screen resolution,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously not for google, but for me, all of these stats are totally
anonymous - I just get percentages or numbers of visits, it&amp;#8217;s not like I
can see all of the details per-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; address. The most important aspect to
me is just the ease of use - I sign up and put a little snippet of code
on my pages, and I get an amazing dashboard interface with all of this
information. Nothing to install and update on my server, and (most
importantly, since I&amp;#8217;m now running everything of mine on one virtualized
server) no massive program to run as a cron job that has to read all my
server log&amp;nbsp;files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I was talking with a couple of my co-workers, specifically
about the stats that I get from Google Analytics. While I know it&amp;#8217;s not
uncommon to run &lt;a href="http://noscript.net/"&gt;NoScript&lt;/a&gt; especially among the
more security- and privacy-conscious groups of people, I was a bit
disturbed to hear that they all block Google&amp;#8217;s tracking code in their
browsers via NoScript. I assume there&amp;#8217;s also a percentage of people who
still just turn off JavaScript alltogether (although I can&amp;#8217;t imagine how
they use the modern Web), and many who use the &lt;a href="http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en"&gt;Google Analytics
Opt-Out&lt;/a&gt; feature. So,
especially with as technical an audience as I have, I guess that means
I&amp;#8217;m likely missing a large number of visitors in my stats. On one hand,
I want to respect the privacy of my visitors, and respect their desire
to opt-out of advanced tracking. On the other hand, since I no longer
parse web server logs for statistics, these privacy-conscious visitors
aren&amp;#8217;t even showing up in what I think of as my monthly visit count, or
in my information on what posts and search keywords are most popular,
which I only use for &amp;#8220;good&amp;#8221; purposes - to make my blog more useful. So
that&amp;#8217;s a bit of a&amp;nbsp;conundrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll admit that I do run &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/adsense/"&gt;Google AdSense
Ads&lt;/a&gt; on my blog, and I&amp;#8217;m sure there are
some people who block the ads. On one hand, that upsets me a bit; I run
this blog to try and share information that I find or learn with others,
and the hosting costs aren&amp;#8217;t insignificant. If I can get paid to just
show some ads, to try and help offset the cost of running the site, I
think that&amp;#8217;s good. And if other people can help support the site by just
letting the ads stay on the page, why not? On the other hand, my hosting
costs $50/month (granted the server also handles all of my email, and a
&lt;em&gt;whole bunch&lt;/em&gt; of other sites). I&amp;#8217;ve been participating in Google AdSense
since March 5, 2010 (two years and two weeks), and my &amp;#8220;estimated
earnings&amp;#8221; are currently $80. The payout is in $100 increments. So, I
haven&amp;#8217;t seen a cent from it in two years, so I&amp;#8217;ve given up being
concerned with it. If you want to be nice, and find my posts
interesting, click on one of the ads. Unfortunately, unless I get
famous, the ads aren&amp;#8217;t going to come close to offsetting even part of
the cost of running the&amp;nbsp;site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google itself
&lt;a href="http://support.google.com/googleanalytics/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=55610"&gt;says&lt;/a&gt;,
&amp;#8220;In order for Google Analytics to record a visit, the visitor must have
JavaScript, images, and cookies enabled for your website.&amp;#8221; There seems
to be some buzz about this on the &amp;#8216;net, and I&amp;#8217;ve seen
&lt;a href="http://garmahis.com/tips/google-analytics/#use-Google-Analytics-without-JavaScript"&gt;a&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://djangosnippets.org/snippets/2338/"&gt;number&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://translate.google.com/translate?hl=en&amp;amp;sl=nl&amp;amp;u=http://andrescholten.nl/google-analytics-zonder-javascript/"&gt;of&lt;/a&gt;
(translated; &lt;a href="http://andrescholten.nl/google-analytics-zonder-javascript/"&gt;original post in
Dutch&lt;/a&gt;)
posts advocating building a request to a Google Analytics &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GIF&lt;/span&gt; manually
on the server side, and then including it as an image element inside a
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;noscript&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag in the page. While this is probably one of the nicer
solutions (and much more likely to reduce double-counting), it doesn&amp;#8217;t
capture any of the advanced data (screen resolution, etc.) that
JavaScript-based Analytics does, and more importantly, I imagine that
many of the Ad blocking extensions also block traffic to
google-analytics.com, so this is an incremental improvement at best.
There are also
&lt;a href="http://www.vdgraaf.info/google-analytics-without-javascript.html"&gt;quite&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://blog.datalicious.com/google-analytics-without-javascript-rss-xml-e"&gt;a&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://blogs.walkerart.org/newmedia/2009/11/12/building-walkers-mobile-site-google-analytics-without-javascript-pt2/"&gt;few&lt;/a&gt;
posts about how to make a request to Analytics purely server-side. This
has a few disadvantages as well; it bypasses the google domain
blacklisting problem that the client-side image has, but it also means
you lose the client &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; address (and therefore geolocation), and that you
double-track any user who allows javascript (so you need a separate
profile, and then need to average out the results). It also means that
you track every search engine and bot that crawls your site, and
possibly every person who clicks a link and then hits &amp;#8220;back&amp;#8221; before the
page finishes loading. I found another blogger who &lt;a href="http://www.realityburst.com/battle-of-the-inaccuracies-how-accurate-is-google-analyticsawstatsstatpress"&gt;commented
about&lt;/a&gt;
the wide disparity he saw between Google Analytics, the
&lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/statpress/"&gt;StatsPress&lt;/a&gt; WordPress
plugin, and &lt;a href="http://awstats.sourceforge.net/"&gt;AWstats&lt;/a&gt; (a server-side
log file&amp;nbsp;analyzer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;solution?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the options have a down side, but I&amp;#8217;m looking for something
that&amp;#8217;s the best I can reasonably do. As much as I&amp;#8217;d rather not, I&amp;#8217;m
going to look into self-hosted alternatives to Google Analytics (a
self-hosted JavaScript-based stats provider), in the hopes that NoScript
users will be more friendly to scripts coming from my own domain, and
sending requests to my own domain, than ones from Google or other major
trackers. I don&amp;#8217;t think I want to try anything that parses web server
logs as a primary approach, as I don&amp;#8217;t think I could ever get a
meaningful comparison to Google Analytics or something else&amp;nbsp;JavaScript-based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did have one other idea which I think is interesting, though a bit of
an overhead. I could have Apache (or, more likely, a Perl script called
in the Apache configuration) generate a random string for each request,
and save it in an Apache environment variable. The environment variable
would then be added to a field in the server logs, and also added (via
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; or whatever else generates the pages server-side) as a custom
parameter for the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JS&lt;/span&gt; tracking code, enabling page hits to be correlated
between the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JS&lt;/span&gt; tracking and the server logs. Assuming the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JS&lt;/span&gt; tacking
backend stores its data in a sane format (and as raw data, not just
aggregated), and at the cost of a serious performance penalty, a
server-side statistics program like
&lt;a href="http://awstats.sourceforge.net/"&gt;AWstats&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href="http://www.webalizer.org/"&gt;Webalizer&lt;/a&gt; could be patched to lookup the
unique identifier in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JS&lt;/span&gt; stats data store, and ignore all hits which
were tracked that&amp;nbsp;way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m going to start by looking into self-hosted open source alternatives
to Google Analytics, which I&amp;#8217;ll post about sometime hopefully&amp;nbsp;soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 11:46:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-03-17:2012/03/inaccuracies-in-google-analytics-for-website-stats/</guid><category>analytics</category><category>google</category><category>logging</category><category>statistics</category><category>stats</category></item><item><title>Petit for Log Analysis</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/02/petit-for-log-analysis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently discovered the
&lt;a href="http://crunchtools.com/software/petit/"&gt;petit&lt;/a&gt; program for log
analysis. It&amp;#8217;s a simple tool to pull out useful information from syslog
logs in a variety of ways. I&amp;#8217;ve only used it a few times so far, mainly
on logs from problems I&amp;#8217;ve already solved but didn&amp;#8217;t know the cause of
at first. So far, it&amp;#8217;s proven quite useful. Here are a few&amp;nbsp;examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;petit --wordcount /var/log/messages&lt;/code&gt; - displays ordered count of
    words appearing in the log. My first step, especially if &amp;#8220;warning&amp;#8221;,
    &amp;#8220;error&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;fatal&amp;#8221; shows up near the&amp;nbsp;top&amp;#8230;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;petit --hash --fingerprint /var/log/messages&lt;/code&gt; - hashes the log,
    removes filters (such as numerics, datestamp), and displays count of
    matching lines. Absolutely wonderful for web error logs, as it
    removes client &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; addresses, line numbers,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;petit --mgraph /var/log/messages&lt;/code&gt; - graph messages per minute for
    the first hour of the log (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ASCII&lt;/span&gt; of&amp;nbsp;course)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;petit --hgraph /var/log/messages&lt;/code&gt; - same as above, but messages per
    hour for the first&amp;nbsp;day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Petit will also read from stdin with the &amp;#8212;Xgraph options, so you
    can &lt;code&gt;cat logfile | grep word | petit --mgraph&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just one note - this tool appears to work only on standard syslog
formatted logs. If some non-datestamped lines managed to work their way
into the log (i.e. someone used echo &gt;&gt; logfile instead of &lt;code&gt;logger&lt;/code&gt;),
it will&amp;nbsp;choke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to Scott McCarty for this wonderful&amp;nbsp;tool!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 11:57:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-02-21:2012/02/petit-for-log-analysis/</guid><category>analysis</category><category>log</category><category>logging</category><category>petit</category><category>syslog</category></item><item><title>Two Interesting Conference Presentations</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/01/two-interesting-conference-presentations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two interesting presentations - which, unfortunately, I only heard the
audio for (they came up in my podcast playlist during my commute&amp;nbsp;today).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the non-techie-geeks out there, &lt;a href="http://www.oscon.com/oscon2011/public/schedule/detail/18941"&gt;All Your Brains Suck - Known Bugs
And Exploits In Wetware: &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSCON&lt;/span&gt; 2011 - O&amp;#8217;Reilly Conferences, July 25 -
29, 2011, Portland,
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an
interesting talk from Paul Fenwick. Yes, it&amp;#8217;s from a techie conference
(&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wetware_(brain)"&gt;wetware&lt;/a&gt; == the brain),
but it&amp;#8217;s mostly psychology-based, and covers some &lt;span class="caps"&gt;REALLY&lt;/span&gt; interesting
things about how the human brain works, especially with an emphasis on
how the brain is manipulated in advertising and&amp;nbsp;otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the techie-geeks among us (well, given the other link, &amp;#8220;geeks&amp;#8221; would
be too vague), &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y0mHo7SMCQk&amp;amp;list=PLC394849408B5F203&amp;amp;index=5&amp;amp;feature=plpp_video"&gt;Velocity 2011: Theo Schlossnagle, &amp;#8220;Career
Development&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;.
It&amp;#8217;s a bit of a rant, but a good talk for us infrastructure/ops people,
and developers as well, and covers some thoughts on both careers and how
we should do out&amp;nbsp;jobs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 21:07:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-01-25:2012/01/two-interesting-conference-presentations/</guid></item><item><title>Firefox QR Code Generator</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/01/firefox-qr-code-generator/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick little tip, I happened by the &lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/mobile-barcoder/"&gt;Mobile
Barcoder&lt;/a&gt;
Firefox add-on the other day. It&amp;#8217;s a Firefox add-on that generates &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Qr_code"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;QR&lt;/span&gt;
Code&lt;/a&gt; barcodes for text or links,
right in your browser. While my Droid3 has a full keyboard, sometimes I
still want to quickly send links from my desktop browser session to my
phone. Firefox Sync helps a lot but is a bit slow on the phone (since I
usually have 100+ tabs open between all of my desktop Firefox sessions),
and email is an option but a bit&amp;nbsp;slower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two caveats about this add-on&amp;nbsp;though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The feature to generate a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;QR&lt;/span&gt; code for the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; of the current page
    shows up in the status bar, which isn&amp;#8217;t shown in modern versions of
    Firefox. You&amp;#8217;ll need to enable the &lt;a href="https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/what-add-bar"&gt;Add-on
    bar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It uses the
    &lt;a href="http://mobilecodes.nokia.com/"&gt;http://mobilecodes.nokia.com/&lt;/a&gt;
    server to generate barcodes, so it&amp;#8217;s dependent on connectivity and
    that&amp;nbsp;service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 23:06:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-01-10:2012/01/firefox-qr-code-generator/</guid><category>barcode</category><category>firefox</category><category>mobile</category><category>Mozilla</category><category>qr code</category></item><item><title>Blackberry Oops</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2011/10/blackberry-oops/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;ve been following the tech news lately, you&amp;#8217;ve probably heard at
least a bit about the
&lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2011/10/12/tech/mobile/blackberry-outage/"&gt;massive&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/technology/2011/10/blackberry-outage-spreads-to-u-s/"&gt;blackberry&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/10/14/technology/rim-struggles-to-overcome-blackberry-outages.html?_r=1"&gt;outage&lt;/a&gt;
over the past three days. While yes, it&amp;#8217;s the first truly grand failure
of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIM&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s infrastructure in their 12-year history, it&amp;#8217;s also a wonderful
case&amp;nbsp;study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently the outage started Monday morning with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIM&lt;/span&gt; infrastructure in
Europe, the Middle East and Asia. However, by Wednesday, it had become a
global outage/slowdown of BlackBerry infrastructure (specifically the
parts that go through &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIM&lt;/span&gt; - email, web browsing, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BBM&lt;/span&gt;; voice calls
and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MMS&lt;/span&gt; were unaffected). With BlackBerry&amp;#8217;s market share falling,
Android&amp;#8217;s rapidly growing (and Android slowly becoming a viable
enterprise option), and the launch of the iPhone 4S just around the
corner, the timing of this couldn&amp;#8217;t be worse for&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIM&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIM&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s original
&lt;a href="http://www.rim.com/newsroom/service-update.shtml"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; about the
problem, at 21:30 on Tuesday October 11th,&amp;nbsp;was,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The messaging and browsing delays that some of you are still
experiencing were caused by a core switch failure within &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIM&lt;/span&gt;’s
infrastructure. Although the system is designed to failover to a
back-up switch, the failover did not function as previously tested. As
a result, a large backlog of data was generated and we are now working
to clear that backlog and restore normal service as quickly as
possible. We sincerely apologise for the inconvenience caused to many
of you and we will continue to keep you&amp;nbsp;informed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#8217;t been able to find much more technical information than that -
a &lt;a href="http://www.computerworld.com/s/article/9220736/RIM_global_outage_caused_by_core_switch_failure_fix_under_way"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNET&lt;/span&gt; article from
Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;
goes into as much depth as anything I could find. I did find one mention
(misplaced the link) that the core switch in question uses technology
from &amp;#8220;multiple vendors&amp;#8221;. So what follows is part common sense (for me&amp;#8230;
why not for a multi-national corporation?) and part speculation. If
you&amp;#8217;re unfamiliar with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIM&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s architecture, the pertinent points are that
all Internet-bound traffic (browsing, email, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BBM&lt;/span&gt;) is piped through
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIM&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s data centers, where it&amp;#8217;s encypted and who-knows-what-else&amp;#8217;ed
(perhaps
&lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052970204612504576608561811929654.html"&gt;monitored&lt;/a&gt;)
before going back out onto the &amp;#8216;net. In the Enterprise market, their big
claim is encryption/security, and monitoring/management/policy
enforcement on&amp;nbsp;handsets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First main point: &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIM&lt;/span&gt; is a &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt; company. The thought that they rely on
an (apparently custom) core switch - a &lt;em&gt;single&lt;/em&gt; core switch for multiple
&lt;em&gt;continents&lt;/em&gt; - is amazing. It&amp;#8217;s even more amazing that they&amp;#8217;d let such a
large part of their infrastructure ride on an architecture with,
apparently, an untested failover mechanism. Of course I don&amp;#8217;t know all
the details, but I&amp;#8217;d hope that for a single piece of hardware which is
so critical, they&amp;#8217;d a) have a cold spare physically nearby so a
replacement wouldn&amp;#8217;t take a day or two, and b) if they can&amp;#8217;t do an
online failover test, at least have a full lab environment to test the
failover&amp;nbsp;in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second main point: Their big claim through all of this is that they
didn&amp;#8217;t lose any data - email, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BBM&lt;/span&gt;, etc. - it just got delayed. So if
there was a core switch failure in their data center serving &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMEA&lt;/span&gt;, and
the next day global services slowed to a crawl, the only thing that
comes to mind to me is a waterfall; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMEA&lt;/span&gt; went down, and they started
rerouting traffic to their North America data center. The increased load
- probably a disaster recovery plan they never truly tested or even
planned - brought everything to a screeching halt, and caused them to
resort to simply caching messaging and pushing it out bit by bit as the
infrastructure could handle.&amp;nbsp;Oops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what are my (admittedly poorly-informed) thoughts on&amp;nbsp;this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scaling out works. Scaling up - especially with single points of
    failure, or N+1 redundancy - is dangerous. If &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIM&lt;/span&gt; had scaled out and
    used regional data centers, with a close-to-commodity core and as
    much redundancy as possible, this wouldn&amp;#8217;t have happened. Sure,
    infrastructure costs money. But if that one &amp;#8220;core switch&amp;#8221; had been
    1,000 devices spread across multiple racks in multiple data centers,
    this never would have happened. And the devices would be
    comparatively cheap enough to probably keep spares on hand too. And
    regularly test their failover procedures. To all of the big
    businesses (apparently like &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIM&lt;/span&gt;) who still think that big iron is
    the only way to do things right&amp;#8230; maybe it&amp;#8217;s time to take a hard
    look at that, and compare your architecture to that of the modern,
    new, hip giants like Google and Facebook. Grids and clusters. Nodes
    that can fail without anyone blinking. Scaling out might not fix
    every problem, but having half the world on a single core switch
    with N+1 redundancy probably isn&amp;#8217;t smart&amp;nbsp;either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disasters need to be planned for. Every possible contingency needs
    to be planned for. Plans need to be tested, regularly. If your giant
    core switch goes down and the failover doesn&amp;#8217;t &amp;#8220;function as
    previously tested&amp;#8221;, there&amp;#8217;s a serious problem both in your disaster
    planning, and in your validation and test procedure. If you have
    half of your customer base riding on a failover plan that isn&amp;#8217;t
    &lt;em&gt;regularly&lt;/em&gt; tested or otherwise validated, that&amp;#8217;s bad. While I can
    argue that the whole architecture - given this massive point of
    failure - could stand to be re-thought, the real issue here is with
    test/validation methodologies and procedures. For a company with 70
    million users, having a piece of infrastructure this critical fail,
    and the failover &amp;#8216;not work as tested&amp;#8217; is a very serious&amp;nbsp;issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damage control is important. As I said, I can only imagine that the
    severe service degradation outside of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMEA&lt;/span&gt; was due to rerouting data
    from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMEA&lt;/span&gt; to the remaining functional data center(s). Such a
    solution should only be considered if it has been tested, or at
    least has engineering validation. If it was part of the disaster
    recovery plan, it obviously isn&amp;#8217;t actually a suitable solution, and
    served only to increase the scope of the outage. If it wasn&amp;#8217;t part
    of the disaster recovery plan, and was decided on-the-fly, someone
    really didn&amp;#8217;t do their research and engineering before putting the
    fix in place. A workable solution should have been planned ahead of
    time. And if one wasn&amp;#8217;t, it&amp;#8217;s very bad practice - this outage shows
    the results - to put in place a fix that hasn&amp;#8217;t been thought&amp;nbsp;out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a company whose business is so telecom-focused, this seems like a
glaringly bad design that shouldn&amp;#8217;t be acceptable in a&amp;nbsp;telecom.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 22:20:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2011-10-13:2011/10/blackberry-oops/</guid><category>blackberry</category><category>outage</category></item><item><title>New server, and looking for work</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2011/09/new-server-and-looking-for-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;First off, I&amp;#8217;ve moved this blog from a server in my basement to
&lt;a href="http://www.linode.com"&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt; virtual hosting, in preparation for my
move from New Jersey to an apartment in Georgia. This will mark the
first time since 2001 (when I was 14) that I didn&amp;#8217;t have at least a
publicly-accessible Linux server in my home. It also means that, as sad
as it is, the rack will probably all be either going in Ebay or to scrap
(after a good &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gutmann_method"&gt;Guttmann
wipe&lt;/a&gt;, of&amp;nbsp;course).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="server rack" src="/GFX/rack_2011-09-27_small.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m a bit sad to give up hosting &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; myself and having my beautiful
per-zone, per-domain, hourly &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; statistics, but that was my first move,
and Linode&amp;#8217;s web-based &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; manager is much nicer than my collection of
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; scripts, MySQL backend, and rndc reload wrapper (and I no longer
need &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BIND&lt;/span&gt; split-horizon since the hosting is remote). Mail was next, and
I&amp;#8217;ve got one web server moved and the other on the way. The biggest
disappointment is losing my testbed for all the fun stuff I can&amp;#8217;t do (or
doesn&amp;#8217;t make sense) with a virtualized hosting provider -
&lt;a href="http://puppetlabs.com/"&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt;, real &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISC&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BIND9&lt;/span&gt;, Cisco CatOS and
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IOS&lt;/span&gt; devices, &lt;a href="http://www.bacula.org"&gt;Bacula&lt;/a&gt;, running my own edge
router, etc. There&amp;#8217;s at least a handful of current production Rutgers
services and tools that got their start here as projects in my spare
time. But I&amp;#8217;m sure I&amp;#8217;ll make up somehow, and I&amp;#8217;m planning on putting
aside some money for a massive new desktop to run a slew of&amp;nbsp;VMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a second note, the one thing holding back my move to Georgia is,
well, my lack of a job there. I&amp;#8217;m really just starting to look around,
and am very much hoping to find something comparable to my current
position at Rutgers - a group supporting diverse services, doing mainly
architecture and implementation of new services, a good dose of
automation and custom tool development, and hopefully also some work
with performance and availability monitoring (think
&lt;a href="http://www.nagios.org"&gt;Nagios&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.cacti.net/"&gt;Cacti&lt;/a&gt;),
logging, etc. And, of course, something that&amp;#8217;s network-focused, whether
wireless or wired. Maintaining some data center space/physical
infrastructure and occasionally working with my hands is fun too. So, if
you know anyone who&amp;#8217;s hiring a Linux/open source dude in the general
vicinity of Athens, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GA&lt;/span&gt; (including Atlanta and the surrounding area),
please give me a heads-up, or pass them along to
&lt;a href="http://resume.jasonantman.com"&gt;resume.jasonantman.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 19:35:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2011-09-27:2011/09/new-server-and-looking-for-work/</guid><category>linode</category><category>move</category><category>rack</category><category>servers</category></item><item><title>Article on theInquirer.net</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2011/07/article-on-theinquirer-net/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I guess it&amp;#8217;s pretty strange that I just found out about it now, three
years later, but there&amp;#8217;s an &lt;a href="http://www.theinquirer.net/inquirer/news/1026958/citibank-infuriating-customers-linux-hostile-site"&gt;article on
TheInquirer.net&lt;/a&gt;
about Citibank&amp;#8217;s website not allowing Linux, that heavily quotes &lt;a href="/2008/08/linux-choice-updates-citibank-issues/"&gt;a blog
post of mine&lt;/a&gt; about the
issue.&amp;nbsp;Cool.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 15:55:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2011-07-11:2011/07/article-on-theinquirer-net/</guid><category>citibank</category><category>linux</category><category>me</category></item><item><title>A Quick Review of Mint.com - from both a user and programmer perspective</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2011/07/a-quick-review-of-mint-com-from-both-a-user-and-programmer-perspective/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For those of you who are unfamiliar with
&lt;a href="http://www.mint.com"&gt;Mint.com&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;#8217;s a free online personal finance
site that allows you to track spending across all of your bank accounts
and manage budgets and financial goals. Once upon a time it was a nice
little Web 2.0 startup, now it&amp;#8217;s owned by Intuit. The service is free,
but it&amp;#8217;s ad supported, albeit in an unintrusive way - &amp;#8220;partner&amp;#8221; services
(credit cards, savings accounts, etc.) are recommended. I&amp;#8217;ve been using
it for about two weeks now, with a goal of tracking my spending,
developing a budget and getting a better handle on my present and future
finances. So here are some of my impressions, considering that the
service is still growing but has been around for a&amp;nbsp;while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&amp;nbsp;Good:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Account Sync&lt;/strong&gt; - Some things I&amp;#8217;ve read online suggest that Mint
    now uses the &lt;a href="http://yodlee.com"&gt;Yodlee&lt;/a&gt; service to sync
    transactions from your financial institutions. Whatever they use,
    they seem to be able to sync transactions and account balances from
    all of my accounts, even ones at a few small investment companies.
    The sync is fast, and they do push notifications (low balance, large
    deposits, etc.) very well. They even seem to support many more
    institutions than Quicken last time I used it (2010 I&amp;nbsp;think).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Budgets&lt;/strong&gt; - Mint has a very nice, clean, simple monthly budget
    implementation. You tell it how much you want to spend in a given
    category in a month, and it shows a nice horizontal bar graph of how
    far through your allotment you are. It even makes some suggestions,
    and sets baseline budgets by category based on previous spending.
    About the only problem is when my bi-weely pay checks fall on odd
    weeks in the month. Most of my bills are due near the end of the
    month, and if my pay check happens to be around the same time my
    bills are due, I&amp;#8217;ll have quite a bit less cash on hand at the
    beginning of the next month than the budgets&amp;nbsp;reflect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Categorization&lt;/strong&gt; - they do it very well. One of their big selling
    points is their categorization engine, and it seemed to get about
    80% of my purchases right, from day one. That&amp;#8217;s much better than
    anything else I&amp;#8217;ve seen. The only down side is that they only look
    at the Vendor name, not the description - so when I use my debit
    card and the vendor name is &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NYCE&lt;/span&gt; Transaction&amp;#8221; but the store
    name/address is in the description, Mint is hopelessly lost. They
    offer rules to put transactions in category, but only exact matching
    on the vendor name, so there&amp;#8217;s no way to tell it to look at a
    description that includes &amp;#8220;123 Main St&amp;#8221;. From a programmer&amp;#8217;s
    perspective, they should allow rules based on either vendor name
    &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; description, and maybe they should let the user highlight or
    specify the part that matches (or a&amp;nbsp;RegEx?).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apps&lt;/strong&gt; - I haven&amp;#8217;t tried the iOS ones, but the Android app is
    pretty nice. It gives a nice quick picture of your spending and
    account balances, how you&amp;#8217;re doing with your monthly budget, and any
    alerts/messages. Transaction history isn&amp;#8217;t easily accessible and is
    per-account only, so it&amp;#8217;s hard to answer &amp;#8220;hmmm, how much did it cost
    last time I was here?&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;where did I get lunch last Tuesday?&amp;#8221;, but
    it&amp;#8217;s still handy enough to tell me how much I have left in my
    Entertainment budget, or whether I should put this big purchase on
    my credit or debit&amp;nbsp;card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals&lt;/strong&gt; - Mint has a good idea with goals - it includes a number
    of pre-configured financial goals like paying off credit card debt,
    saving for retirement, or stashing away some emergency cash. But in
    order to function correctly, you must have a specific, dedicated
    account for each goal. I guess this is where Mint makes money - they
    suggest accounts with specific attributes (high interest, high
    liquidity, whatever) from their partners. But there doesn&amp;#8217;t appear
    to be a way to set up a Goal without associating it with a dedicated
    account, and (as per some forum posts I read, I haven&amp;#8217;t tried this)
    you can&amp;#8217;t associate a cash asset account with a goal, so there&amp;#8217;s no
    way to track my progress on building the Depression fund I keep
    under my&amp;nbsp;mattress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Bad/Room for&amp;nbsp;Improvement:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer Service&lt;/strong&gt; - I don&amp;#8217;t know when Mint was bought up by
    Intuit, but to me, they have the feel of an agile Web 2.0 property
    that was bought up by a slow-moving bureaucratic company unable to
    keep up with customer demands or the amount of support requests.
    They use &lt;a href="http://getsatisfaction.com/"&gt;GetSatisfaction&lt;/a&gt;, a new-age
    forum-based customer &amp;#8220;community&amp;#8221; provider, for customer service. But
    their forums are filled with feature request threads that have
    &amp;#8220;we&amp;#8217;ll bring it up to Product Development and get back to you&amp;#8221;
    responses over half a year old. There appears to be very little
    follow-through or feedback on feature requests, and poor
    announcement/communication surrounding the one feature that was
    recently brought in to an invitation-only beta. Unfortunately, I get
    the general feeling (and I&amp;#8217;ve found this far too many times lately)
    that they were originally a cutting-edge, agile, fast-paced, &amp;#8220;cool&amp;#8221;
    service, developed by a team that probably stayed up all night
    coding a cool feature their users were asking for, that&amp;#8217;s now been
    swallowed up by a behemoth that wants a 6-month-long risk assessment
    before writing a line of&amp;nbsp;code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cash Tracking&lt;/strong&gt; - I understand that Mint makes money from
    recommending the services of lenders, banks, etc. But if you want to
    monetize every single feature, you&amp;#8217;re bound to fail. In this
    respect, Mint&amp;#8217;s total lack of cash accounting is a serious failure
    for many of their users (and the forums are filled with threads to
    this effect). The site allows users to manually input cash
    transactions, but that&amp;#8217;s about it. You can deduct the amount from an
    automatically-synced &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ATM&lt;/span&gt; withdrawal (just your last &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ATM&lt;/span&gt; withdrawal,
    no choice if you have multiple &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ATM&lt;/span&gt; accounts, or you and your
    partner/spouse both use the same Mint account), but that just
    complicates things further. There&amp;#8217;s also no logic of tracking cash
    on hand - you can create a &amp;#8220;Asset&amp;#8221; (cash) account, but you have to
    manually update the balance. If you&amp;#8217;re like me and use cash for
    small purchases, or often get meals at local places that only accept
    cash, this becomes quite a bit of a hassle. Even more so if, like
    me, you&amp;#8217;ve ever lost an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ATM&lt;/span&gt; card on a holiday weekend, and now keep
    some actual cash in the house. Honestly, I think this is my biggest
    complaint about Mint, and the one that&amp;#8217;s most likely to keep me
    looking for alternatives. More importantly, this has been requested
    and voted for over and over on their support forums for over a year,
    with no informational response. For a company whose developers
    aggregate and analyze data from thousands of banks, I&amp;#8217;d think that
    letting users type in a series of dollar amounts and then totaling
    it up would be pretty&amp;nbsp;easy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheduled Transactions&lt;/strong&gt; - On the plus side, Mint parses the &amp;#8220;next
    payment due&amp;#8221; date out of credit card and loan account information,
    so it gives you nice (email, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;, and web) alerts a configurable
    number of days before. However, it doesn&amp;#8217;t even have a feature to
    set calendar reminders for when bills are due, so I&amp;#8217;m still stuck
    opening Mint and Google Calendar if I need to figure out whether I
    can make that big purchase today or if I should wait until my next
    pay check. This was also a very commonly requested feature on their
    forums, and apparently they have an invitation-only beta running.
    But I responded to the thread a few days late, so I wasn&amp;#8217;t given an
    invitation. As far as I can tell, there was never an announcement of
    the beta, and I never got a chance to check a &amp;#8220;please let me beta
    test&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forecasting&lt;/strong&gt; - This is my #2 biggest issue with Mint, after the
    lack of cash tracking. And the other one most likely to drive me
    either to another service, to write my own software (again), or to
    go back to a spreadsheet. Mint is great at tracking your transaction
    history, your account balances and net worth, and your current
    monthly budget. But it has absolutely no concept of financial
    forecasting or balance predictions. If you&amp;#8217;re on a tight budget,
    this can be a problem. At the moment, I have a spreadsheet were I
    keep a list of all of my regularly recurring expenses (in date order
    over the month), my pay dates, and the combined balance of my
    checking/savings accounts. I can easily see what (within reason, not
    counting discretionary expenses) my cash on hand will be at any time
    in the month. This seems like a no-brainer necessary feature for a
    site like Mint, and combined with its great budgeting features,
    could provide a wonderful picture of what to expect in the next
    month or two, and when I should plan on making that unusually large&amp;nbsp;purchase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Couples/Families&lt;/strong&gt; - My girlfriend and I both use Mint, and have
    somewhat combined finances (but not accounts). It doesn&amp;#8217;t make sense
    for us to have two Mint accounts, since it would be a real pain to
    keep track of. But, on the other hand, having all of our accounts in
    one Mint isn&amp;#8217;t an ideal solution either. I can categorize
    transactions, but there&amp;#8217;s no easy way to track &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; the purchase
    was for, short of duplicating (or triplicating - Me, Her, Both) all
    of the categories. I&amp;#8217;m trying something with tags, but it&amp;#8217;s a real
    kludge in Mint&amp;#8217;s search interface to get a list of transactions
    filtered by category &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; tag. Also, the account name doesn&amp;#8217;t show
    up in the transactions list unless you pull down the Detail box for
    a transaction, so it&amp;#8217;s troublesome to look through a list and sort
    out whose cards everything was&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miscellaneous:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passwords.&lt;/strong&gt; In order to sync data from my banks, I have to supply
    mint.com with all of my login credentials. I understand that, until
    banks enter the 21st century (and be smart about it - even a less
    likely possibility) this is just the way it is, and I can&amp;#8217;t blame
    Mint for a system imposed by the banks. But still, I&amp;#8217;m not too happy
    about the idea of Mint storing in plain text (I assume, since they
    need to pass them on to the bank) my username and password for all
    of my banking sites. I got some comfort knowing that the site is
    owned by Intuit - a company that, if not totally security-minded, is
    at least big enough not to fold overnight after a breach. Maybe one
    day, banks and credit card companies will let me specify separate
    credentials specific to third-party software and websites, which I
    could then revoke with my &amp;#8220;master&amp;#8221; password. Until then, I guess
    this is just a risk I have to live&amp;nbsp;with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importing Transactions&lt;/strong&gt; - Mint only supports importing up to 3
    months of transaction data per account. Some institutions provide
    less than that. Obviously Intuit doesn&amp;#8217;t want people switching from
    their paid software, so the two &lt;span class="caps"&gt;YEARS&lt;/span&gt; of transactions I meticulously
    categorized in Quicken are now useless to me in Mint. However, I
    guess I can&amp;#8217;t really fault them too much on this one. Firstly, that
    would be a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LOT&lt;/span&gt; of data for them to store. It would also be much more
    of a headache to try and ensure that the export formats of whatever
    software packages they support are properly&amp;nbsp;parsed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mint does a lot of things well. And it&amp;#8217;s a nice clean interface. But
there are also some key features missing, which I feel like I really
need. So, for the time being, I&amp;#8217;m going to keep using mint, but also
explore what other options are available, and look into anyone who
offers an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; for pulling transaction data that might actually be
powerful enough for me to use to write my own web-based app (since my
attempts at pulling &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OFX"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OFX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feeds only
worked for about half my accounts). If you don&amp;#8217;t care as much about
tracking cash spending/cash on hand, and are financially stable enough
that you don&amp;#8217;t need to forecast the next month or two, Mint is&amp;nbsp;wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 22:03:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2011-07-03:2011/07/a-quick-review-of-mint-com-from-both-a-user-and-programmer-perspective/</guid><category>finance</category><category>mint</category><category>review</category></item><item><title>Links for Wednesday, June 8, 2011</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2011/06/links-for-wednesday-june-8-2011/</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://it.toolbox.com/blogs/bridging-gaps/what-is-a-systems-architect-9995"&gt;What is a Systems&amp;nbsp;Architect?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 10:55:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2011-06-08:2011/06/links-for-wednesday-june-8-2011/</guid></item><item><title>Links for Thursday, April 28, 2011</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2011/04/links-for-thursday-april-28-2011/</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.technologyreview.com/computing/37295/page1/#photo"&gt;Inside Facebook’s Not-So-Secret New Data Center - Technology&amp;nbsp;Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2011 10:55:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2011-04-28:2011/04/links-for-thursday-april-28-2011/</guid></item><item><title>Links for Wednesday, January 5, 2011</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2011/01/links-for-wednesday-january-5-2011/</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-31001_3-20027202-261.html"&gt;Big media fails to turn ISPs into copyright cops | Media Maverick -
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNET&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://redtape.msnbc.com/2011/01/court-cops-can-search-cell-phone-without-warrant.html"&gt;Court: No warrant needed to search cell phone - The Red Tape
    Chronicles -&amp;nbsp;msnbc.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 11:55:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2011-01-05:2011/01/links-for-wednesday-january-5-2011/</guid></item><item><title>Net Neutrality - What is it, and what will the recent FCC decision do?</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/12/net-neutrality-what-is-it-and-what-will-the-recent-fcc-decision-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_neutrality"&gt;Net Neutrality&lt;/a&gt; is a
&lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt; issue these days, and one that&amp;#8217;s exploded out of the geek
circles into mainstream media. I&amp;#8217;ll admit that it seems like there are
endless variations on exactly what people consider Net Neutrality to be
(or what it &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be). The general goal of Net Neutrality is to
ensure that Internet Service Providers (ISPs) provide (relatively)
unfiltered access to the Internet to their customers. Specifically, that
if a given customer pays for a level of service - i.e. 10 Mbps
downstream speed and 2.5 Mbps upstream speed - they receive that speed
no matter what they are accessing. The goal of Net Neutrality is to
require ISPs to treat their connections as a &amp;#8220;common carrier&amp;#8221;, much like
telephone companies or freight trucks. Within reason (excepting
explosives and other hazardous materials), &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; will ship a package for a
given rate based only on what it weighs and how far it&amp;#8217;s going (since
the Internet is run by many companies, and data passes from one to
another, the distance portion of this analogy is constant). They don&amp;#8217;t
charge more based on what&amp;#8217;s in the box, and they don&amp;#8217;t ship come boxes
faster than others based simply on who sent it or what&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, over the past century, many laws have been created that
regulate the telephone industry. While there was a time when customers
had to rent their telephones from the phone company, long-standing
legislation states that a customer can hook any properly functioning
device into the phone network, and a customer can say whatever they want
over the phone and receive the same call quality, at the same&amp;nbsp;rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To try and summarize, the goal of Net Neutrality is to ensure that you,
the customer of an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; (whether cable, FiOS, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DSL&lt;/span&gt;, etc.), is entitled to
certain rights. Generally (the exact interpretation of this concept
varies) this&amp;nbsp;includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to connect any device you want to your Internet
    connection - any computer, game console, or other device, running
    any operating system or other&amp;nbsp;software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your ability to connect to any service (web site, protocol, etc.)
    that you want without it being intentionally degraded or slowed
    down, even if it&amp;#8217;s a service viewed to be a competitor of your&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your ability to transfer data to and from any other user of the
    Internet, regardless of who they&amp;nbsp;are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What could happen if Net Neutrality isn&amp;#8217;t&amp;nbsp;enforced?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me first say that most of the following is pure speculation. These
are things that &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; happen, but most have not yet actually been
done. Some have. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; industry seems to say that Net Neutrality is &amp;#8220;a
solution without a problem&amp;#8221;, but my personal view is that those are
generally good things. Preventing a problem from occurring is generally
better than fixing it after it&amp;#8217;s a problem. So here are a few scenarios
of what could happen if Net Neutrality isn&amp;#8217;t properly legislated and&amp;nbsp;enforced:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies like Cablevision, Comcast, Verizon, and other major ISPs
    also offer &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; services (Optimum, FiOS &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;, etc.) that include Video
    On Demand (VoD) as a separate paid service. Websites like Hulu and
    Netflix offer the same service, for free or a much cheaper rate.
    Without Net Neutrality, your &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; could intentionally slow down or
    block sites like Hulu or Netflix to force you to buy their more
    expensive service. Comcast has &lt;a href="http://www.computerworld.com/s/article/9198498/Comcast_demands_fees_for_Web_movie_viewing_Level_3_says"&gt;already
    tried&lt;/a&gt;
    to do something like this, asking Netflix&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; for a substantial
    fee to allow Comcast customers to access Netfix (that&amp;#8217;s a bit of an
    oversimplification, but gets the point). If this happens, it&amp;#8217;s most
    likely that Netfix will have to increase their fees substantially.
    Net Neutrality legislation would require ISPs like Comcast to treat
    all Internet traffic the same, whether it&amp;#8217;s from Netflix, Facebook,
    or my humble little&amp;nbsp;blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few ISPs (mainly Comcast) have already tried all-out blocking Peer
    to Peer (p2p) file sharing traffic such as bitTorrent, Kazaa, etc.
    While they cite copyright infringement as the reason, there are many
    people who use p2p file sharing to distribute legal files, such as
    the Linux operating system and other free software. Blocking all p2p
    traffic because some people use it for illegal purposes is based on
    a presumption of guilt, no different from outlawing steak knives
    because some people stab other people with&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Throughout the history of the Internet, some of the most popular and
    innovative technologies, including Google, Facebook, etc. have
    started out as small projects run by a few geeks and programmers. If
    ISPs were allowed to charge content providers (i.e. websites) to be
    viewed by the ISPs customers, it would limit innovation and new
    technologies to only the big businesses with enough money to pay
    these artificial&amp;nbsp;tolls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most ISPs also offer a phone service. It would be trivial for them
    to flat-out prevent their customers from using Vonage, Skype, iChat,
    etc. and force you to subscribe to their service. It&amp;#8217;s also possible
    for them to do this in a covert way - when Comcast blocked
    bitTorrent users, they did it in a way so clever that it took weeks
    for experts to figure&amp;nbsp;out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Without a mandate that any suitable device can connect to the
    network, your &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; could partner with, for example, Dell and
    Microsoft, and say that you could only get Internet access on a Dell
    computer running the latest version of Windows (yes, this is a bit
    of a stretch, but possible in an unregulated &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;market).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important fact to note here is that most people in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; don&amp;#8217;t have
much choice in terms of broadband ISPs - generally the only &amp;#8220;choice&amp;#8221; is
between the cable and phone companies, who provide more or less the same
service. With such limited choice, Internet users are effectively held
hostage by the policies of a handful of companies that control Internet&amp;nbsp;access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A short note on the History of the&amp;nbsp;Internet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to the ISPs &amp;#8220;solution without a problem&amp;#8221; view, I think this is
a solution that should have been implemented long ago. The network that
evolved into what we now know as the Internet, in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;, was first
developed in the 1970s. The project, ARPAnet, was developed by the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;
government for research purposes, and funded by taxpayer money. It
wasn&amp;#8217;t opened to commercial use until the early 1990s, when it was
privatized. While the development into what is now the Internet could
never have been foreseen at that time, Net Neutrality rules should have
been built in from the start when the project was handed over from the
federal government to the private sector. Regardless, it must be
remembered that the Internet is a technology that was originally
developed with taxpayer funds, for the country as a&amp;nbsp;whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;doing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, in short, not much. It appears that the Net Neutrality rules
delivered by the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt; earlier this week are, more than anything, a
compromise effort to make the issue just &amp;#8220;go away&amp;#8221;. The ISPs feel that
the rules aren&amp;#8217;t needed (and argue that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt; doesn&amp;#8217;t have the power
to make them), and most Net Neutrality proponents feel that the rules
pay only lip service to the goals of Net Neutrality. The main failings
already apparent in the rules&amp;nbsp;are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two of three major parts of the rules ignore wireless ISPs (cellular
    carriers). With the explosion of smartphones, it seems that wireless
    is not only the new frontier of the Internet, but the way that more
    and more people get Internet access. If Net Neutrality is
    legislated, it should be about the Internet - regardless of how a
    customer is connected to the&amp;nbsp;network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a provision for ISPs to be able to block or slow down
    traffic as is &amp;#8220;reasonable&amp;#8221; to operate their network, but there are
    no guidelines on what &amp;#8220;reasonable&amp;#8221; means, and it seems that the
    burden of proof would be on the customer to fight their &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; in court
    and show that something was&amp;nbsp;unreasonable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until very recently, ISPs generally didn&amp;#8217;t engage in the kind of
conduct that Net Neutrality rules would prohibit. The Internet as we
know it today is a product of a world with unwritten Net Neutrality
rules. Amazing sites and services like Facebook, Google, Twitter, and
many others started as experiments by a few dedicated people with little
to no budget. The fact that you can easily view web pages created by
anyone - like my blog - would be ended if website publishers had to pay
ISPs to be allowed through. The choice that you have in using your &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; or phone service, or something like Netflix or Vonage, is central to
the Internet as we know it, but is under attack. I know that many people
look at this as a &amp;#8220;problem for the geeks&amp;#8221;. We take the Internet for
granted. Over the next few days, every time you visit a web site or use
an Internet-based service, ask yourself: Would I be happy if I had to
pay for this? Would this even exist if the people who designed it had to
pay from day one? Make no mistake, if websites have to pay every &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; in
the country to be viewed, the days of wonderful free services sustained
by advertising revenue only will be long&amp;nbsp;gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In closing, I highly recommend reading an &lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2010/12/steve-wozniak-to-the-fcc-keep-the-internet-free/68294/"&gt;open letter on Net Neutrality
by Steve
Wozniak&lt;/a&gt;,
co-founder of Apple, genius, and guy who helped change the world as we
know&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other interesting&amp;nbsp;links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/timothy-karr/obama-fcc-caves-on-net-ne_b_799435.html"&gt;Obama &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt; Caves on Net Neutrality &amp;#8212; Tuesday Betrayal
    Assured&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huffington&amp;nbsp;Post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2010/12/21/fcc-we-didnt-impose-stricter-net-neutrality-regulations-on-wir/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt;: We didn&amp;#8217;t impose stricter net neutrality regulations on
    wireless because Android is
    open&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engadget&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://act.boldprogressives.org/sign/sign_netneutrality_3things/?akid=3050.937978.xH20je&amp;amp;rd=1&amp;amp;source=e1-netflix-fin&amp;amp;t=3"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt; breaks Obama&amp;#8217;s promise on Net Neutrality: 3 things you need to
    know&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BoldProgressives.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 09:07:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-12-23:2010/12/net-neutrality-what-is-it-and-what-will-the-recent-fcc-decision-do/</guid><category>free speech</category><category>freedom</category><category>internet</category><category>net neutrality</category></item><item><title>Links for Tuesday, November 23, 2010</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/11/links-for-tuesday-november-23-2010/</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/cs/2010/11/did_google_train_its_own_enemi.html"&gt;Did Google Arm Its Own Enemies With Android? - James Allworth - The
    Conversation - Harvard Business&amp;nbsp;Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 11:56:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-11-23:2010/11/links-for-tuesday-november-23-2010/</guid></item><item><title>Links for Friday, November 12, 2010</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/11/links-for-friday-november-12-2010/</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/news/2010/11/are-you-on-the-internet-or-something-else.ars"&gt;How will we know when the Internet is&amp;nbsp;dead?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.computerworld.com/17335/red_hat_announces_red_hat_enterprise_linux_6"&gt;Red Hat announces Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 - Computerworld&amp;nbsp;Blogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 11:55:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-11-12:2010/11/links-for-friday-november-12-2010/</guid></item><item><title>Motorola Droid: Rooted 2.0.1 to Rooted 2.2 (CyanogenMod)</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/09/motorola-droid-rooted-2-0-1-to-rooted-2-2-cyanogenmod/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As of this morning, my Motorola Droid was still running rooted 2.0.1
(build &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ESD56&lt;/span&gt;, baseband C_01.3E.01P) with SPRecovery 0.99.2b. Well
yesterday I for the random deletion of all &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt; bug again, and I decided
it&amp;#8217;s time to upgrade. I never upgraded to 2.1 - mainly out of laziness.
When it first came out, nobody had a patched update.zip yet to preserve
root. When I looked back into the situation a few weeks ago (when
Froyo/2.2 came out), I found that pretty much the whole community had
moved from patched update.zip&amp;#8217;s to full &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ROM&lt;/span&gt; images. I didn&amp;#8217;t want to
lose my apps, data, settings, etc. and couldn&amp;#8217;t find any instructions
that didn&amp;#8217;t include a wipe/reset, so I decided to keep putting it&amp;nbsp;off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, after yesterday&amp;#8217;s bug (and after I played with the Camera app on
an Incredible and saw how much nicer it is), I decided it was time to
bite the bullet and move to &lt;a href="http://www.cyanogenmod.com/"&gt;CyanogenMod&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ROMS&lt;/span&gt;. I performed the upgrade this morning, and it seems to have worked
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt;, though I haven&amp;#8217;t been using the phone very much since it&amp;nbsp;finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rooted 2.0.1 to CyanogenMod 2.2&amp;nbsp;procedure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m starting with a Motorola Droid, 2.0.1 (build &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ESD56&lt;/span&gt;), rooted,
baseband C_01.3E.01P, with SPRecovery&amp;nbsp;0.99.2b&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform full Nandroid backup through&amp;nbsp;SPRecovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;a href="market://search?q=com.riteshsahu.CallLogBackupRestore"&gt;Call Logs Backup &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;
    Restore&lt;/a&gt;
    (v1.8) to backup call&amp;nbsp;log.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;a href="market://search?q=com.riteshsahu.SMSBackupRestore"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt; Backup &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;
    Restore&lt;/a&gt; (v3.4)
    to backup &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;a href="market://search?q=com.boots.MyAppsList"&gt;MyAppsList&lt;/a&gt; to make a
    list of all installed apps as &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;, including market links. Save to
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SD&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;a href="market://search?q=com.happydroid.bookmarks"&gt;Bookmark Sort &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Backup
    Free&lt;/a&gt; to backup
    bookmarks to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SD&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;a href="market://search?q=com.metago.astro"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ASTRO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; file manager and
    backup &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ALL&lt;/span&gt; apps to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SD&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mount the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SD&lt;/span&gt; card on another computer and copy all the backups you
    just made to somewhere&amp;nbsp;safe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the rest of the procedure, I more or less followed the &lt;a href="http://wiki.cyanogenmod.com/index.php?title=Full_Update_Guide_-_Motorola_Droid"&gt;CyanogenMod
Droid Full
Update&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; install &lt;a href="market://search?q=com.koushikdutta.rommanager"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ROM&lt;/span&gt;
    Manager&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Premium.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flash ClockworkMod&amp;nbsp;Recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ROM&lt;/span&gt; Manager to backup current &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ROM&lt;/span&gt; to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SD&lt;/span&gt; card, copy the backup
    somewhere safe on another&amp;nbsp;computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ROM&lt;/span&gt; Manager - download CyanogenMod 6.0.0 for Droid with AWDLauncher
    and Google&amp;nbsp;Apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check off &amp;#8220;wipe data and cache&amp;#8221;, click&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone reboots into recovery, flashes new image, and boots to
    CyanogenMod Froyo (2.2, build &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FRG22D&lt;/span&gt;), still has baseband&amp;nbsp;C_01.3E.01P.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your Google account information to begin sync. Your Google
    data (calendar, contacts, etc.) should be synced as well as all of
    your Market apps. You will, however, lose all of your app&amp;nbsp;settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-Upgrade:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the upgrade, there were a few things I had to do, and a few issues
that I wasn&amp;#8217;t prepared for. Here&amp;#8217;s a list of them, and the solutions I
found (if any) in no particular&amp;nbsp;order&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restore bookmarks, call log, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;backup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All of my per-contact ringtones were gone. As far as I could find,
    there&amp;#8217;s no known good way of backing up and restoring&amp;nbsp;these.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I obviously lost the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HD&lt;/span&gt;-quality video hack I&amp;#8217;d applied to the Droid,
    as well as anything else I&amp;#8217;d done in the boot settings&amp;nbsp;file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I apparently lost the following apps (not restored when the phone
    synced with&amp;nbsp;Google):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.ztech.packagetracking"&gt;Package&amp;nbsp;Tracking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.googlecode.pythonforandroid"&gt;Python for&amp;nbsp;Android&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.googlecode.android_scripting"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SL4A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.mahoney.tetronimo"&gt;Tetronimo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following apps were added by CyanogenMod (or are new since&amp;nbsp;2.0.1):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;Chrome to Phone&lt;/a&gt; -
    &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/chrometophone/"&gt;chrometophone&lt;/a&gt; - send
    links from Chrome browser to your phone using some Google
    messaging&amp;nbsp;service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;Dev Tools&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;DPSManager&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;News and&amp;nbsp;Weather&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;Places&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2010/04/introducing-google-places.html"&gt;Google&amp;nbsp;Places&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;Spare Parts&lt;/a&gt; - apparently allows access to some settings not
    available through the Settings&amp;nbsp;menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;Speech&amp;nbsp;Recorder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;Superuser&lt;/a&gt; - App to graphically manage root&amp;nbsp;access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;Talk&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/talk/"&gt;Google&amp;nbsp;Talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;Terminal Emulator&lt;/a&gt; (somehow I have two&amp;nbsp;installed&amp;#8230;?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;Videos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;Voice&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/mobile/voice/"&gt;Google Voice&amp;nbsp;mobile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These apps had data associated with them which was somewhat
    important (I wrote the script below to handle the&amp;nbsp;move):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;Alarm Clock&amp;nbsp;Plus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;Barnacle WiFi&amp;nbsp;Tether&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;ConnectBot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;gReader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;Jewles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;Nagroid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had to re-set my notification sounds - Flutey Phone for incoming
    calls, Look at Me for messaging and Highwire for other&amp;nbsp;notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much to my pleasure, my WiFi settings, saved networks, etc.
    magically came back. Haven&amp;#8217;t checked bluetooth&amp;nbsp;yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to change my voicemail number (Settings -&gt; Call Settings -&gt;
    Voicemail Settings) to automatically wait and enter my&amp;nbsp;password.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, this script is obviously setup to do one app at a time,
hard-coded in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt; variable. It also assumes that the app data
directory is stored at&amp;nbsp;/sdcard/restore/$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nv"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;com.vp.alarmClockPlusDock&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nv"&gt;BIN_PATH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;/system/xbin/&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;DATA_PATH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;/data/data/&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;BACKUP_PATH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;PERMS_PATH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;/data/system/packages.list&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nv"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OWNER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;grep -i &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; /data/system/packages.list | awk &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;{ print $2}&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OWNER&lt;/span&gt;=$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OWNER&lt;/span&gt;=&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

/system/xbin/mv /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; /data/data/z
/system/xbin/mv /sdcard/restore/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
/system/xbin/rm -Rf /data/data/z

/system/xbin/chown -R 10069:10069 /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

/system/xbin/chmod 751 /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; -e  /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;/cache &lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
    /system/xbin/chmod -R 771 /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;/cache
&lt;span class="k"&gt;fi&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; -e /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;/databases &lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
    /system/xbin/chmod 771 /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;/databases
    /system/xbin/chmod 660 /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;/databases/*.db
&lt;span class="k"&gt;fi&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; -e /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;/files &lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
    /system/xbin/chmod -R 771 /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;/files
    /system/xbin/chmod 660 /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;/files/*
&lt;span class="k"&gt;fi&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; -e /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;/lib &lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
    /system/xbin/chown -R system:system /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;/lib
    /system/xbin/chmod -R 755 /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;/lib
&lt;span class="k"&gt;fi&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; -e  /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;/shared_prefs &lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
    /system/xbin/chmod 771 /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;/shared_prefs
    /system/xbin/chmod 660 /data/data/&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;$&lt;span class="caps"&gt;APP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;/shared_prefs/*
&lt;span class="k"&gt;fi&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DONE&lt;/span&gt;.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll update this now and then as I have more to add to&amp;nbsp;it&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2010 16:50:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-09-04:2010/09/motorola-droid-rooted-2-0-1-to-rooted-2-2-cyanogenmod/</guid><category>android</category><category>cyanogen</category><category>cyanogenmod</category><category>droid</category><category>root</category></item><item><title>Mediawiki Extension - Section Link To Top</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/08/mediawiki-extension-section-link-to-top/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;While working on a particularly long documentation page in MediaWiki
today, I came by a convenient little&amp;nbsp;extension:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Extension:SectionLinkToTop"&gt;Section Link To&amp;nbsp;Top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It adds a nice little &amp;#8220;top&amp;#8221; link next to the &amp;#8220;edit&amp;#8221; link in each section
header. Very useful for &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;pages.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 13:46:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-08-18:2010/08/mediawiki-extension-section-link-to-top/</guid><category>documentation</category><category>mediawiki</category></item><item><title>PHP Script to Dump Firefox Session</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/08/php-script-to-dump-firefox-session/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re anything like me, you often find yourself working on multiple
computers. Today I left a few tabs open in Firefox on my work laptop,
and wanted to continue reading from my desktop. Normally I&amp;#8217;d just grab
the laptop, or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RDP&lt;/span&gt; into it if it was my work desktop that had the open
tabs, but at the moment my girlfriend is neck-deep in WoW on the
MacBook. Having had this problem before (getting tabs back remotely, not
a laptop occupied with WoW), I started thinking about a&amp;nbsp;solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; have closed my local firefox session, moved the
sessionstore.js somewhere else, copied the one from the laptop over,
re-opened firefox, &amp;#8230; well, you get the&amp;nbsp;idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that sounds like a really sub-optimal solution. So I started looking
around a bit. It seems that sessionstore.js is &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;, but as per
&lt;a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=407110#c2"&gt;Mozilla bug
407110&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;#8217;s
not quite standards-compliant. Luckily, it seems that &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt; module
is quite tolerant, so once I stripped off the leading and trailing
parens from the file contents, it parsed quite&amp;nbsp;nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve written a small &lt;code&gt;dumpFirefoxSession.php&lt;/code&gt; script that reads the
sessionstore.js file (in cwd or a specified path), unserializes the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;
as an array, and then dumps the tabs. It dumps as either plain text or
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; (currently just elements inside the body, not a full &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; file).
The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; will include &lt;code&gt;ol&lt;/code&gt;s for each window listing the tabs, links to
the current content (sessionstore.js also holds history for each tab,
but I don&amp;#8217;t need this), and it shows which tab is currently&amp;nbsp;selected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can grab the script from github at:
&lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/misc-scripts/blob/master/nmap-xml-to-table.php"&gt;https://github.com/jantman/misc-scripts/blob/master/nmap-xml-to-table.php&lt;/a&gt;.
The current version is 3. You&amp;#8217;ll need &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; (probably 5) with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;support.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 21:17:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-08-17:2010/08/php-script-to-dump-firefox-session/</guid><category>firefox</category><category>PHP</category></item><item><title>My Droid Rooting Dilemma</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/08/my-droid-rooting-dilemma/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;My Droid is still running 2.0.1 rooted, with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SPS&lt;/span&gt; Recovery, just as it
was the week the 2.0.1 update was pushed out &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OTA&lt;/span&gt; - I&amp;#8217;d already rooted
it, disabled &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OTA&lt;/span&gt; updates, and performed a simple procedure to update and
keep&amp;nbsp;root.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My one complaint is that - as always happens with a new and cool
technology that gets widely adopted - it seems like the Android
community is being, well, dumbed down. When I first rooted my Droid, it
involved using the adb shell. Now, it&amp;#8217;s hard to find instructions that
aren&amp;#8217;t written exclusively for Windows - or even instructions that
actually explain what I&amp;#8217;m supposed to be doing or why it&amp;nbsp;works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that I haven&amp;#8217;t followed the Android world much lately, but it
seems to me that this should be really simple. The update.zip &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OTA&lt;/span&gt;
updates are just patches. I already have the device rooted on 2.0.1,
have disabled &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OTA&lt;/span&gt; updates, etc. So it seems to me that I should be able
to just unzip the update file, change whatever needs to be changed to
keep root, re-zip it, and upload it. If it wasn&amp;#8217;t already done (the
HowTo that I followed to update to rooted 2.0.1 doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to be
online anymore, and I can&amp;#8217;t find the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;), I should be able to just
change the update verification keys to accept&amp;nbsp;anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I guess it&amp;#8217;s time to continue my hours of research and see if I
can come up with anything. Everything I&amp;#8217;ve already found says that I
have to backup all of my apps and data and just flash a new &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ROM&lt;/span&gt;, but
that seems stupid. Why can&amp;#8217;t I just make use of this wonderful
patch-based updating and keep&amp;nbsp;root?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2010 09:14:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-08-16:2010/08/my-droid-rooting-dilemma/</guid><category>android</category><category>droid</category><category>root</category></item><item><title>Updated Android App List</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/08/updated-android-app-list/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s the current list of the apps that are running on my Droid and
seem interesting (I&amp;#8217;m still running 2.0.1, build &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ESD56&lt;/span&gt;). This is an
update to my earlier post, &lt;a href="/2010/02/my-android-apps/"&gt;My Android Apps&lt;/a&gt;,
so I left out everything that was already in that&amp;nbsp;post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list was generated with
&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.boots.MyAppsList"&gt;MyAppsList&lt;/a&gt;, though I did
massage it a bit after generation (mainly because it copied text that
was all on &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; line, though it does output &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; with market links and
the apps in li elements). The simple script to make the output a little
more blog-friendly&amp;nbsp;is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;cat apps.txt | sed &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;s/&amp;lt;\/li&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;\/li&amp;gt;  &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;/g&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; | sed &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;s///g&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; | sed &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;s/&amp;lt;\/font&amp;gt;//g&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; | sed &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;s///g&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.adobe.reader"&gt;Adobe Reader&lt;/a&gt; (v9.0.1) - full
    version of Adboe&amp;nbsp;Reader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.speedymarks.android.altitudeFree"&gt;Altitude
    Free&lt;/a&gt;
    (v1.0.5) - Shows your current altitude from&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.agilesoftresource"&gt;AndroZip&lt;/a&gt; (v1.0.1) - Good
    all-around file manager and archive&amp;nbsp;manager.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=sns.arcMedia.playerInterface.arm6"&gt;arcMedia&lt;/a&gt;
    (v0.24b) - Media (video)&amp;nbsp;player.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=net.szym.barnacle"&gt;Barnacle Wifi Tether&lt;/a&gt; (v0.5.1)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WiFi tethering for rooted Droids with stock kernel. See my &lt;a href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/08/wifi-tether-for-droid/"&gt;WiFi
tether for
Droid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=it.medieval.blueftp"&gt;Bluetooth File Transfer&lt;/a&gt;
    (v3.40) - Good tool for transferring arbitrary files, contacts, etc.
    over&amp;nbsp;bluetooth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=org.peterbaldwin.client.android.delicious"&gt;Bookmarking for
    Delicious.com&lt;/a&gt;
    (v1.3.2) - Delicious bookmarking, so I can now keep my Droid in sync
    with all of my desktops, laptops,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.mathpad.mobile.android.wt.unit"&gt;ConvertPad - Unit
    Converter&lt;/a&gt;
    (v1.4.2) Simple but full-featured unit converter. Need to know how
    many twips there are in a fathom? No&amp;nbsp;problem&amp;#8230;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.drivesafe.ly"&gt;DriveSafe.ly&lt;/a&gt; (v1.3.47) - cool
    app that reads incoming &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt; to you. Can automatically activate when
    it connects to&amp;nbsp;bluetooth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.noinnion.android.greader.reader"&gt;gReader&lt;/a&gt;
    (v1.6.8) - Good &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; reader with sync to Google Reader and automatic
    sync of articles for offline&amp;nbsp;viewing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.handcent.nextsms"&gt;Handcent &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (v3.2.6) -
    Just got this, still figuring it out, but appears to be a &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt;
    nicer messaging app with popups (including reply box) for incoming
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;, nicer view,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.vzw.hss.myverizon"&gt;My Verizon Mobile&lt;/a&gt; (v5.0)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verizon&amp;#8217;s app that shows your current monthly minute, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;, and
data usage, as well as other&amp;nbsp;stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.boots.MyAppsList"&gt;MyAppsList&lt;/a&gt; (v1.4 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BETA&lt;/span&gt;) -
    App used to generate this&amp;nbsp;list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.ztech.packagetracking"&gt;Package Tracking&lt;/a&gt;
    (v1.9b) - Simple package tracking for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt;, FedEx, etc. Unfortunately
    it doesn&amp;#8217;t provide any notifications and it only remembers one
    tracking number at a&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.pdanet"&gt;PdaNet&lt;/a&gt; (v2.42) - &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; or Bluetooth
    tethering (official client software is Mac and Windows&amp;nbsp;only).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.mm.network"&gt;Ping&lt;/a&gt; (v1.6.9) - Ping&amp;nbsp;app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.googlecode.pythonforandroid"&gt;Python for
    Android&lt;/a&gt; (v0) -
    Python interpreter for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SL4A&lt;/span&gt;. So far, it doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to be able to
    do too much in my&amp;nbsp;opinion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.biggu.shopsavvy"&gt;ShopSavvy&lt;/a&gt; (v3.6.6) - Scan a
    bar code, see the lowest prices for that product both online and in
    local&amp;nbsp;stores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.googlecode.android_scripting"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SL4A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (v0) -
    Scripting environment for Android with pluggable interpreters. So
    far, it seems to be missing a lot of Android classes that would make
    it useful for doing device-specific things (like listing installed&amp;nbsp;apps).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="market://search?q=com.javacodeland.android.voicememo"&gt;VoiceMemo&lt;/a&gt;
    (v1.0.1) - Simple voice memo app. I use it quite a bit, but there&amp;#8217;s
    no simple way to email SMSes, it only titles them by date and time
    recorded, and it doesn&amp;#8217;t keep the phone awake (recordings seem
    limited to 60 seconds or&amp;nbsp;so).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2010 13:19:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-08-15:2010/08/updated-android-app-list/</guid><category>android</category><category>droid</category></item><item><title>Links for Thursday, August 12, 2010</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/08/links-for-thursday-august-12-2010/</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/22712"&gt;Washington State Board for Community &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Technical Colleges Adopts &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CC&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BY&lt;/span&gt; for All Competitive Grants - Creative&amp;nbsp;Commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 10:55:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-08-12:2010/08/links-for-thursday-august-12-2010/</guid></item><item><title>Links for Tuesday, August 10, 2010</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/08/links-for-tuesday-august-10-2010/</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20100806143457345"&gt;Groklaw - Eben Moglen&amp;#8217;s LibrePlanet 2010 Keynote on the State of
    Free Software and the&amp;nbsp;Future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 10:55:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-08-10:2010/08/links-for-tuesday-august-10-2010/</guid></item><item><title>Putting the Why in Documentation</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/08/putting-the-why-in-documentation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I work as a Linux Sysadmin (among many other non-official titles) in a
small group that mainly provides services. We run wireless and student
computing labs across a whole campus, but other than that (and most of
that) is just back-end systems - web servers, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RADIUS&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt;, etc. As a
result, I write no end-user documentation. I generally think of this as
a blessing, since the people who read my documentation are people who
think (more or less) like&amp;nbsp;me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I&amp;#8217;ve just started writing the wiki page for a rather large
system I developed. And in writing the docs, and thinking about what was
missing from the (practically non-existent) documentation on the system
I was replacing, it got me thinking a lot about the documentation
writing process. Most of us have heard that there are two general types
of documentation - end-user docs and developer (and I&amp;#8217;m rolling SysAdmin
in here) documentation. End-user docs tell someone how to use what we
built. Developer docs tell people how to troubleshoot, fix, modify, and
extend it.&amp;nbsp;Usually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;#8217;s one very important piece that&amp;#8217;s missing from most
developer-level documentation I&amp;#8217;ve read: why it&amp;#8217;s built the way it is.
Sure, this isn&amp;#8217;t applicable in all instances. This is obviously ignored
by closed-source software developers when writing documentation for
release. And I&amp;#8217;m sure it&amp;#8217;s ignored in some larger shops just out of fear
that the interns will explain why they need to iterate a database result
set. But for those of us who are designing and building systems, I&amp;#8217;d
argue that documenting the reasons behind our decisions is much more
important than how-to-fix-it or how-to-rebuild-it documentation. Sure,
it&amp;#8217;s atrocious practice, but that can all be gleaned from examining a
live system or backups. But when it comes time for the next person (or
you or I, five years down the road) to re-design or drastically modify
our creations, some documentation of the decisions we made - and the
reasoning behind them - will be extremely&amp;nbsp;useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Case in point: My latest project started as performance analysis of a
large &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt; server using the &lt;a href="http://personal.cfw.com/~masneyb/"&gt;Masney &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LDAP&lt;/span&gt;
patch&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="http://www.isc.org/software/dhcp"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISC&lt;/span&gt;
DHCPd&lt;/a&gt;. After over a week of
performance testing and trying different configurations and theories
(all of which I &amp;#8220;documented&amp;#8221; in my text file lab notebook), we ended up
deciding to totally remove &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LDAP&lt;/span&gt; from the system, move to configuration
files generated from MySQL, and keep everything (including the logs) in
ramdisk. We found performance bottlenecks in both the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LDAP&lt;/span&gt; communication
and disk &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IO&lt;/span&gt;. We have the performance test output to prove it. We have
the results of dozens of tests with different configurations, as well as
a number of problems we identified with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LDAP&lt;/span&gt; patch. And from
testing, we have a handful of issues identified and fixed in the new
system, whose fixes aren&amp;#8217;t exactly&amp;nbsp;intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The previous system had pretty poor documentation, but even worse, it
was only functional documentation - what the system does, and how it
does it. There was no discussion of why the parsing script disregarded
lines with a certain string in them, why the daemon is restarted every
night, why &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LDAP&lt;/span&gt; was chosen in the first place, or any performance
metrics (so we had no original as-intended baseline to compare&amp;nbsp;against).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for those of you designing systems and documenting them (you *do*
document them, &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt;?), please include &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; in your documentation.
The next time someone needs to fix or tweak or re-engineer the system,
they&amp;#8217;ll be able to figure out what happens on line 123 of the init
script themselves. But it might take them hours to figure out &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; it&amp;#8217;s
done, or &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; it&amp;#8217;s done &lt;em&gt;that way&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 14:51:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-08-06:2010/08/putting-the-why-in-documentation/</guid><category>documentation</category><category>sysadmin</category></item><item><title>Short Update</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/08/short-update/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Just a short update&amp;#8230; I know I haven&amp;#8217;t posted anything in quite a
while, but I hope to get back into the habit of doing so&amp;#8230; or even
making daily posts like I had&amp;nbsp;wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="/2010/05/truck-totaled/"&gt;truck that was totaled&lt;/a&gt; has been
    replaced with a newer, nicer&amp;nbsp;one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve spent most of the past month working on a large &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt; project at
    work, which I hope to write about in depth at some&amp;nbsp;point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I bought the parts to make an Arduino-based &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OBD&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;II&lt;/span&gt; display, and I&amp;#8217;m
    slowly making some progress on it (mostly delayed because the $12
    &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HD44780&lt;/span&gt;-compatible&amp;#8221; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LCD&lt;/span&gt; display I bought doesn&amp;#8217;t work in 4-bit&amp;nbsp;mode).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 14:31:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-08-06:2010/08/short-update/</guid><category>arduino</category><category>dhcp</category><category>truck</category></item><item><title>Truck Totaled</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/05/truck-totaled/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Since so many people seem to have missed all of the communications via
&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com"&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt; (well, I can&amp;#8217;t blame them, I spend
less time there every time they make an &amp;#8220;improvement&amp;#8221;), I guess I should
give in and post something to my usually-so-professional blog,
explaining a bit about what happened to my
&lt;a href="/2009/07/update-on-my-f-250-icom-mobile-antennas-strobes/"&gt;beautiful&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/2009/02/truck-wiring-and-lighting-part-i/"&gt;truck&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;#8217;d put so
much &lt;a href="/2009/02/custom-truck-console/"&gt;work&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago - 08:43 on Saturday, May 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;, 2010 - I was involved in a
&amp;#8220;bit&amp;#8221; of an accident with my truck while driving down to my dad&amp;#8217;s place
in Hunterdon county. I was &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?q=41.017828,-74.217229&amp;amp;num=1&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;sll=41.018107,-74.218228&amp;amp;sspn=0.007026,0.016512&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=41.017834,-74.217217&amp;amp;spn=0.007026,0.016512&amp;amp;z=17"&gt;on 208
Northbound&lt;/a&gt;
in Franklin Lakes right across from the Colonial Rd intersection (maybe
8 minutes from home?), early in the morning. I really don&amp;#8217;t have any
desire to tell the &lt;em&gt;whole detailed&lt;/em&gt; story again, but bottom like: there
were three geese crossing the highway, and someone got the brilliant
idea to rapidly decelerate from 60 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MPH&lt;/span&gt; to allow the birds to safely
cross. I still can&amp;#8217;t provide for the account of where every vehicle on
the road went, but there was a half-second of various drivers making
evasive maneuvers, me jamming on the brake and horn, and my truck having
a fast introduction to the ass-end of a box&amp;nbsp;truck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily nobody was injured, though I did have neck pain for a day or two
after. The guy who decided to stop/cut left (in front of the box truck)
drove happily off into the sunrise, the guy in a blacked out &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SUV&lt;/span&gt; who had
been between the box truck and my vehicle (obscuring most of the truck
from my view) also, as far as I know, departed. Once I got the airbags
out of my way and the door kicked open, my former vehicle was on its way
to the body&amp;nbsp;shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must say, while I had an absolutely horrendous experience with
&lt;a href="http://www.geico.com"&gt;geico&lt;/a&gt; when this same vehicle was stolen a year
and a half ago, they were actually pretty good this time around. The
accident happened on a Sunday, I took Monday off of work to get a rental
car and deal with the claim (yeah, it turns out my policy didn&amp;#8217;t have
the rental coverage, much to my surprise&amp;#8230;) and the claims agent came
out Tuesday (less than 48 hours after the accident) to make an estimate.
He totaled the truck - the motor was even broken loose of all of the
mounts - and I had a check in my hand (minus the balance of the
financing) 12 days after the accident. So&amp;#8230; my experience with Geico
this time around was much better. I guess as long as there&amp;#8217;s a vehicle
for them to look at, they&amp;#8217;re happy. Though I&amp;#8217;m switching to Progressive
for the next&amp;nbsp;vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, that&amp;#8217;s the story. Assuming Enterprise car rental is playing nice,
I&amp;#8217;ll be picking up the truck I just bought tomorrow&amp;nbsp;morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/truck2009-07-03/P1010185.JPG"&gt;&lt;img alt="truck
photo" src="/GFX/truck2009-07-03/P1010185_small.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/f250accident/2010-05-01_08.51.21.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="truck
photo" src="/GFX/f250accident/640x480/2010-05-01_08.51.21.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/f250accident/2010-05-01_08.54.54.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="truck
photo" src="/GFX/f250accident/640x480/2010-05-01_08.54.54.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/f250accident/2010-05-01_09.08.29.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="truck
photo" src="/GFX/f250accident/640x480/2010-05-01_09.08.29.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/f250accident/2010-05-01_09.36.40.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="truck
photo" src="/GFX/f250accident/640x480/2010-05-01_09.36.40.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/f250accident/2010-05-01_10.21.26.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="truck
photo" src="/GFX/f250accident/640x480/2010-05-01_10.21.26.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/f250accident/2010-05-01_10.22.03.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="truck
photo" src="/GFX/f250accident/640x480/2010-05-01_10.22.03.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/f250accident/2010-05-01_10.22.16.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="truck
photo" src="/GFX/f250accident/640x480/2010-05-01_10.22.16.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/f250accident/2010-05-01_10.22.29.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="truck
photo" src="/GFX/f250accident/640x480/2010-05-01_10.22.29.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/f250accident/2010-05-01_10.22.40.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="truck
photo" src="/GFX/f250accident/640x480/2010-05-01_10.22.40.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/f250accident/2010-05-01_10.23.34.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="truck
photo" src="/GFX/f250accident/640x480/2010-05-01_10.23.34.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2010 18:28:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-05-16:2010/05/truck-totaled/</guid><category>accident</category><category>EMS</category><category>ford</category><category>mva</category><category>truck</category></item><item><title>Web-based collaboration/documentation software</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/04/web-based-collaborationdocumentation-software/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This question was posted both to the
&lt;a href="http://www.sage.org/lists/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SAGE&lt;/span&gt;-members&lt;/a&gt; list
(&lt;a href="http://mailman.sage.org/pipermail/sage-members/2010/msg00788.html"&gt;thread&lt;/a&gt;)
and to
&lt;a href="http://serverfault.com/questions/136416/free-web-based-software-for-team-collaboration-documentation"&gt;ServerFault&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking for some advice here, as my search has turned up to be pretty&amp;nbsp;fruitless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My group (9 people - SAs, programmers, and two network guys) is
looking for some sort of web tool to&amp;#8230; ahem&amp;#8230; &amp;#8220;facilitate increased
collaboration&amp;#8221; (we didn&amp;#8217;t use a buzzword generator, I swear). At the
moment, we have an unified ticketing system that&amp;#8217;s braindead, but is
here to stay for political/logistical reasons. We&amp;#8217;ve got 2 wikis
(&amp;#8220;old&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;new&amp;#8221;), neither of which fulfill our needs, and are
therefore not used very often. We&amp;#8217;re looking for a free (as in both
cost and open source) web-based&amp;nbsp;tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Management side:&lt;br /&gt;
 Wants to be able to track project status, who&amp;#8217;s doing what, whether
deadlines are being met, etc. Doesn&amp;#8217;t want full-fledged &amp;#8220;project
management&amp;#8221; app, just something where we can update &amp;#8220;yeah this was
done&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;waiting for Bob to configure the widgets&amp;#8221;.
&lt;a href="http://www.teambox.com"&gt;TeamBox&lt;/a&gt; was suggested, but it seems almost
too gimmicky (Twitter/Facebook ripoff?), and doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to meet any
of the other requirements that I see coming&amp;nbsp;up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-management side:&lt;br /&gt;
 - flexible, powerful wiki for all documentation (i.e. includes good
tables, easy markup, syntax highlighting, etc.)&lt;br /&gt;
 - good full text search of everything (i.e. type in a hostname and
get every instance anyone ever uttered that name)&lt;br /&gt;
 - task lists or ToDo lists, hopefully about to be grouped into a
number of &amp;#8220;projects&amp;#8221;&lt;br /&gt;
 - file uploads&lt;br /&gt;
 - &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; or Atom feeds, email alerts of&amp;nbsp;updates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re open to doing some customizations (adding some features,
notification/feeds, searching, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SVN&lt;/span&gt; integration, etc.) but need
something F/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt; that will run under&amp;nbsp;Apache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My conundrum is that most of the choices I&amp;#8217;ve found so far fall into
one of these categories:&lt;br /&gt;
 - project management/task tracking with poor
wiki/documentation/knowledge base support&lt;br /&gt;
 - wiki with no task tracking support&lt;br /&gt;
 - ticketing system with everything else bolted on (we already have
one that we&amp;#8217;re stuck with)&lt;br /&gt;
 - code-centric application (we do little &amp;#8220;development&amp;#8221;, mostly &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SA&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;work)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any&amp;nbsp;suggestions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, lacking that, any comments on which software would be easiest to
add the lacking features to (hopefully ending up with something that
actually looks good and works&amp;nbsp;well)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m still awaiting responses from both &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SAGE&lt;/span&gt; and ServerFault, but I have
a strong feeling that most of the suggestions will fall into one of the
major categories I already identified,&amp;nbsp;mainly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project management/task tracking with poor wiki/documentation
    support (a la&amp;nbsp;TeamBox)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wiki with no task tracking&amp;nbsp;support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ticketing system with everything else added in (useless since we
    already have to use a different ticketing&amp;nbsp;system).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something code-centric, i.e. built around a software development
    workflow, which isn&amp;#8217;t&amp;nbsp;us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I have a very strong feeling that whatever solution we end up going
with, we&amp;#8217;ll need to spend quite a bit of time bolting on whatever else
we need. Adding a full-featured wiki to another package isn&amp;#8217;t going to
be very easy&amp;#8230; especially since TeamBox is written in RoR, and we&amp;#8217;re
mostly &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;guys.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 16:43:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-04-27:2010/04/web-based-collaborationdocumentation-software/</guid><category>collaboration</category><category>documentation</category><category>project management</category><category>Projects</category><category>wiki</category></item><item><title>What is System Administration?</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/04/what-is-system-administration/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently reading an interesting article, &amp;#8220;from tasks to
assurances: redefining system administration&amp;#8221;, by &lt;a href="http://www.cs.tufts.edu/~couch/"&gt;Alva L.
Couch&lt;/a&gt;, in the April 2010 issue of
&lt;a href="http://www.usenix.org/publications/login/"&gt;;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LOGIN&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/a&gt;. He makes a lot of
good points, mainly that system administration has been defined by
tasks, but should really be defined by assurances (a much more abstract
concept). This does make a lot more sense, and perhaps will aid me in
finally coming up with a succinct (but complete) answer for when people
ask me what I&amp;nbsp;do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It bears mention that my role as an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SA&lt;/span&gt; probably isn&amp;#8217;t the same as many
others. Working at a University has its perks - and one is definitely
the inclination towards research, tinkering, and trying new things.
Another is the extremely tight budget - I&amp;#8217;d estimate that only about 25%
of what my group supports (software-wise) actually has a vendor behind
it. Most of those services have primary admins assigned to&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group I work in is composed of 9 people (including myself). We&amp;#8217;re
responsible for the architecture (specifically authentication,
network-side stuff) for residential/dorm networking (ResNet), all of the
student computing labs (\~1,000 user stations) as well as printing
therein, the University-wide wireless network (from physical
installation through support), and a few other services. That doesn&amp;#8217;t
include all of the usual ancillary stuff - mail, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt;, web apps,
storage, etc. It would probably surprise most corporate &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; types that we
more or less function as an independent unit - we share certain
services, like Nagios monitoring, with other groups, but do most of our
work as a single standalone&amp;nbsp;unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My own job (since I&amp;#8217;m currently the only part-time person in our group)
is probably &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; different from most SAs. I&amp;#8217;m the primary admin for
only one user-visible service, which is in the process of being phased
out (and is very lightly used currently). For the most part, I&amp;#8217;d
describe myself as a &amp;#8220;floating&amp;#8221; admin - I&amp;#8217;m usually assigned whatever
problems come up that are in my knowledge area (or more than the primary
admin can cram into a work week), and also do quite a bit of research
(mainly suitability analysis of new technologies). I&amp;#8217;m also the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DR&lt;/span&gt; guy,
and am in the process of implementing across the board an automated
installation, configuration, recovery and backup system for all of our
Linux/Unix boxes. As ironic as this may seem, while I&amp;#8217;m not the primary
admin for any of our major services, if one of the boxes than run them
falls over, it&amp;#8217;s more or less my responsibility to get it back up and
running. Or at least have the plans and procedures for that laid&amp;nbsp;out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something that is also quite different from many enterprise shops is our
software budget - which is almost non-existent. Except for a few
services - some of the stuff used to administer the Windows and Mac lab
machines, the printing systems, and the wireless stuff, we&amp;#8217;re pretty
much exclusively open source. As a result, there&amp;#8217;s rarely a vendor to
fall back on, and &amp;#8220;fixing a problem&amp;#8221; can often involve hours of reading&amp;nbsp;source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an aside, I once had a phone screen where the interviewer asked me
about a difficult problem I recently solved, and what my methodology
was. I ran through about 20 steps. When I finished the list, the
interviewer asked me, &amp;#8220;at what point would you call the vendor for
support?&amp;#8221; My response: &amp;#8220;vendor? what&amp;nbsp;vendor?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;#8217;m trying to think up a good answer to what I do, and what the other
SAs in my group do. There&amp;#8217;s the work in progress so&amp;nbsp;far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We provide many different services to our users (all University
faculty, staff, students, etc.). It&amp;#8217;s my job to ensure that those
services are as reliable as possible, function correctly, are secure,
and work as well as possible. When something does fail, no matter what
it is, it&amp;#8217;s my job to get it back to normal. And when a new technology
emerges that may increase the quality, reliability or security of a
service we offer, it&amp;#8217;s my job to evaluate it and, if it is found to be
worthy, implement&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2010 09:08:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-04-24:2010/04/what-is-system-administration/</guid><category>sysadmin</category><category>system administration</category></item><item><title>Happy April Fool’s Day</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/04/happy-april-fools-day/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s April 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;, also known as April Fool&amp;#8217;s Day. While I,
unfortunately, haven&amp;#8217;t planned any pranks or jokes myself this year (I
guess I&amp;#8217;ve just been too busy), I always try to find as many of
&lt;a href="http://www.google.com"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;s jokes as possible. Despite being a
behemoth, and raking in billions of dollars, they still seem to keep an
excellent sense of humor, both for everyone and at a very technical&amp;nbsp;level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s what I found this year (updated as I find&amp;nbsp;them):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="topeka" src="/GFX/topeka-hp.gif" /&gt;
   Google name change to Topeka - &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2010/04/different-kind-of-company-name.html"&gt;blog
    post&lt;/a&gt;,
    &lt;a href="http://money.cnn.com/2010/04/01/technology/google_april_fools/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNN&lt;/span&gt;
    Money&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topeka, Kansas changes name to Google, Kansas. Google changes name
to&amp;nbsp;Topeka.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search result timing - A Google search for &amp;#8220;Jason Antman&amp;#8221; was
    completed in &amp;#8220;2.00 shakes of a lamb&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;tail&amp;#8221;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a side note, I&amp;#8217;m quite sad that the Store Anything &lt;a href="https://spreadsheets.google.com/viewform?hl=en&amp;amp;formkey=dEx3d1BSR1Ntb0hvdEpJNkJvaUI2Z2c6MQ"&gt;beta test
form&lt;/a&gt;
(&lt;a href="/GFX/viewform.html"&gt;local copy&lt;/a&gt;)doesn&amp;#8217;t work. When they asked what
object I wanted to store, I checked &amp;#8220;other&amp;#8221; for &amp;#8220;exotic matter&amp;#8221;, and
entered the following description of why I should be allowed to test the&amp;nbsp;service:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily for google, the exotic matter that I intend to store has a
negative mass. Not only is it much simpler for me to let Google&amp;#8217;s
massive engineering team (the same one that figured out how to run
their search engine on SkyLab and the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WOPR&lt;/span&gt;) figure out how to store
such a substance, but it also means that I should be able to receive
storage for free. In fact, my collection of negative mass matter
should be large enough (no pun intended) to offset the entire cost of
Store&amp;nbsp;Antyhing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, Google has a history of April Fool&amp;#8217;s pranks that goes back to
the earliest days. Much can be found about them
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google's_hoaxes"&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;. But by far my
favorite was last year, when (in an apparent showing of how easy it is
for them to make changes to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GWS&lt;/span&gt; and roll them out over their entire
infrastructure) they changed the Server &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt; header to a number of
random and humorous names, including Microsoft &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IIS&lt;/span&gt;/3.0, Apache/0.8.4,
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HAL&lt;/span&gt; 9000, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WOPR&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CERN&lt;/span&gt;, and&amp;nbsp;SkyNet.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 07:44:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-04-01:2010/04/happy-april-fools-day/</guid></item><item><title>Downtime past few days, coping with storms</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/03/downtime-past-few-days-coping-with-storms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As far as I can see from &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/"&gt;Google
Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, though I&amp;#8217;m now up to about
4,000 visitors per month for this blog, it seems like most are one-time
visitors. So hopefully the few hiccups of the past few days weren&amp;#8217;t
noticed (except by me, and my mailserver&amp;#8230;). As many of you in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;
may know, New Jersey was hit by a pretty big nor&amp;#8217;easter last weekend and
my area was
&lt;a href="http://www.northjersey.com/news/bergen/87665172_Weekend_storm_thrashes_Wyckoff.html"&gt;especially&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.northjersey.com/news/87704777_Ridgewood_power_outages_could_last_for_days.html"&gt;hard&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.northjersey.com/news/87852727_Downed_trees__power_lines_bring_Glen_Rock_to_a_near_standstill.html"&gt;hit&lt;/a&gt;.
I lost power for about five hours Saturday night (the 13th) and again
for an hour or so the next morning. Needless to say, these were both
much longer than my small UPSes could cope with (the smaller of the two
has a mere 12 minutes of runtime with brand new batteries). While I do
have a small (2500W) gas generator, it was buried in the back of the
garage. The time it would take to dig it out and string extension cords
from the UPSes to a relatively dry area outside would probably be more
than 12 minutes - not to mention that as first lieutenant
(second-in-command) of the town&amp;#8217;s volunteer &lt;a href="http://www.midlandparkambulance.com/"&gt;ambulance
corps&lt;/a&gt;, I was running in the
opposite direction once things got&amp;nbsp;bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, the problems caused or uncovered by the power loss were
relatively&amp;nbsp;minor:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The batteries in my smaller &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; lasted about 90 seconds. I&amp;#8217;d noticed
    the bad battery light a few weeks ago, but put it off (hey, it&amp;#8217;s my
    home setup, I don&amp;#8217;t exactly have a budget).
    &lt;a href="http://www.refurbups.com"&gt;RefurbUPS&lt;/a&gt;, where I got the two &lt;span class="caps"&gt;APC&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SU1000NET&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s, got me a replacement &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RBC6&lt;/span&gt; (aftermarket, not original
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;APC&lt;/span&gt;) in two days, for around $73. Unfortunately, my Tripp Lite
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMART2200RMXL2U&lt;/span&gt; (unfortunately without the external battery pack)
    also just had its orange light pop on, so there goes another&amp;nbsp;$90.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The battery replacement caused another short (\~5 minute) downtime
    tonight, including my router. Unfortunately the router is plugged
    into the smaller of the two UPSes, and none of my current boxes have
    more than one power supply. Mistake. Especially considering my
    limited resources. On the positive side, I took the opportunity to
    move all of the equipment onto &lt;a href="http://www.liebert.com/product_pages/Product.aspx?id=6&amp;amp;hz=60"&gt;Liebert
    MicroPOD&lt;/a&gt;s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The external &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SATA&lt;/span&gt; disk for my desktop used to store media is dead.
    I&amp;#8217;m getting incessant read errors, followed by offlining the disk,
    on two &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; adapters and internal &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SATA&lt;/span&gt;. I guess I should have a
    better surge protector for the&amp;nbsp;desktop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few of my boxes didn&amp;#8217;t come up clean, mainly due to entropy in the
    configs, or services that were never &lt;code&gt;chkconfig&lt;/code&gt;&amp;#8216;ed. Well, I don&amp;#8217;t
    use any configuration management at&amp;nbsp;home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the disks in my storage server (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAID&lt;/span&gt; 1+0 of 6x 36.4Gb 10k &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCSI&lt;/span&gt; disks) died - actually a few days before the power outage. I
    was able to find a new replacement on Ebay, with warranty, for about&amp;nbsp;$40.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many of my internal services - including a lot of the
    &lt;a href="http://www.nagios.org"&gt;Nagios&lt;/a&gt; checks - use a separate gigabit
    management network, run off of an older GigE aggregation switch.
    This was on the smaller &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt;, so it went down quick. As both this and
    my main switch are of the same series, perhaps an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPS&lt;/span&gt; unit would be
    worth the&amp;nbsp;money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plans for the&amp;nbsp;future:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get &lt;a href="http://reductivelabs.com/products/puppet/"&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt; working at
    home. As part of this, buy a spare server so I can migrate services
    one at a time to a puppet-ized version, test, and then rebuild
    (while the production machine is still&amp;nbsp;running).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the future, given my limited infrastructure, purchasing dual
    power supply machines - and putting the PSes on separate UPSes -
    would be a good&amp;nbsp;thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure the Tripp Lite &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; to do load&amp;nbsp;shedding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; management software to bring down boxes in a logical&amp;nbsp;order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power savings is also important - so I&amp;#8217;m thinking about rebuilding
    things using &lt;a href="http://www.xen.org/"&gt;Xen&lt;/a&gt;, and using live migration to
    both distribute load logically under normal circumstances, and to
    move around loads in the event of power failure (kill
    non-critical/internal-only stuff, consolidate the&amp;nbsp;rest).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 22:27:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-03-17:2010/03/downtime-past-few-days-coping-with-storms/</guid><category>availability</category><category>power</category><category>reliability</category><category>UPS</category><category>uptime</category></item><item><title>Links for Friday, March 12, 2010</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/03/links-for-friday-march-12-2010/</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.linuxinsider.com/rsstory/69467.html"&gt;Linux News: Legal: Apple&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTC&lt;/span&gt; Suit: All About&amp;nbsp;Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.standalone-sysadmin.com/blog/2010/03/flashback-infrastructure-upgrades-through-forest-fires/"&gt;Flashback: Infrastructure Upgrades through Forest Fires |
    Standalone&amp;nbsp;Sysadmin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2010 11:48:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-03-12:2010/03/links-for-friday-march-12-2010/</guid></item><item><title>Cablevision Reaches out to touch someone</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/03/cablevision-reaches-out-to-touch-someone/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As has been in the news (and advertised to high hell) for the past few
days here in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NJ&lt;/span&gt;, Cablevision and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ABC&lt;/span&gt; are involved in a feud. Cablevision
is advertising everywhere - I heard at least 4 ads on the drive home
from work about how &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ABC&lt;/span&gt; is making unreasonable demands, asking for $40M,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, then I found something more interesting. I stopped at a friend&amp;#8217;s
after work and turned on the (Cablevision) cable box. Strange. It was a
full-screen ad from Cablevision about the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ABC&lt;/span&gt; situation. And it seemed
to go on forever. But&amp;#8230; huh? The cable box was tuned to channel&amp;#8230;
1999. I changed the channel, and got regular &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when I got home and turned on &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; cable box - which was last tuned
to channel 47 and is setup to resume on the last channel it was tuned to
- it also started up to the Cablevision ad on channel&amp;nbsp;1999.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To anyone who&amp;#8217;s read Jonathan Zittrain&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Future-Internet-How-Stop/dp/0300151241/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1267669057&amp;amp;sr=8-1"&gt;The Future of the Internet and
How to Stop
It&lt;/a&gt;,
this is as clear an indication of the problems with appliancization as&amp;nbsp;anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t take this lightly. It has some serious implications. Specifically,
the basics of what Cablevision&amp;nbsp;did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pushed out a new software version to all of their cable boxes, very
    quickly, that added a new&amp;nbsp;channel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed an arbitrary setting in the configuration of their
    customer&amp;#8217;s boxes (the channel that displays at power on)&amp;nbsp;remotely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea that Cablevision can control all of their customer&amp;#8217;s boxes
remotely, and this quickly, is a bit disturbing. If any of you have ever
checked out the diagnostic mode on a Scientific Atlanta box, you&amp;#8217;d know
that it&amp;#8217;s more or less a full computer (the &amp;#8220;channels&amp;#8221; are actually
streaming media over &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt;) and the amount of control that Cablevision has
is virtually&amp;nbsp;limitless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(The automatic channel change has been confirmed by a number
&lt;a href="http://bumped.org/tek/2010/03/03/abc7-vs-cablevision-abc-may-go-off-the-air-march-7th-here-we-go-again/"&gt;of&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.northjersey.com/arts_entertainment/030110_Disney_ABC_may_go_dark_on_Cablevision_in_New_York.html"&gt;other&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://blogs.app.com/inthemoney/2010/03/02/attention-cablevision-customers-here-we-go-again/comment-page-1/"&gt;people&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 21:21:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-03-03:2010/03/cablevision-reaches-out-to-touch-someone/</guid><category>appliance</category><category>cablevision</category><category>freedom</category></item></channel></rss>