<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/cacti.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2009 15:36:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Project Announcement - PHPsa</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/09/project-announcement-phpsa/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;So, here&amp;#8217;s the &amp;#8220;official&amp;#8221; scoop on the new project that I&amp;#8217;m
planning/starting to work on. I&amp;#8217;m calling it PHPsa for now, and it&amp;#8217;s
going to (hopefully) be an integrated dashboard/portal for SysAdmins.
While there are a number of tools that fit into this general category
(perhaps with &lt;a href="http://www.alienvault.com/home.php?section=News"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSSIM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
being the closest, though it&amp;#8217;s security-minded), I feel that there&amp;#8217;s a
real gap in terms of tool integration. My daily workflow, which includes
multiple trips to and correlation among Nagios, Cacti, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt;,
Puppet, logs, and other tools really leaves something to be desired. So,
I&amp;#8217;m setting out to create a modular SysAdmin dashboard that unifies many
of the common SysAdmin-related tools into a modular&amp;nbsp;dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first overall design goals that I&amp;#8217;ve set&amp;nbsp;are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A modular, plugin-based architecture that allows admins to select
    which features/tools they want, and allows easy development of new&amp;nbsp;modules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design with legacy tools in mind - easy ways to tie in to tools that
    weren&amp;#8217;t written with PHPsa in mind, both in terms of linking to
    information and gathering/unifying&amp;nbsp;information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RBAC&lt;/span&gt;, including per-module rules and the possibility for a limited
    read-only view (client/user&amp;nbsp;mode).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use of data sources, specifically web-based/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;REST&lt;/span&gt; APIs where
    available, and databases otherwise, from existing tools with as
    little modification as&amp;nbsp;possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for database abstraction, though I&amp;#8217;ll be using&amp;nbsp;MySQL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eventually, implement &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; feeds of pertinent&amp;nbsp;information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balance Ajax/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHTML&lt;/span&gt; with the desire for important things to have
    canonical, static, bookmark-able&amp;nbsp;URLs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here are some of the things that I&amp;#8217;m planning on integrating, with
obvious bias towards getting my own projects done before I integrate
pre-existing&amp;nbsp;tools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://multibindadmin.jasonantman.com"&gt;MultiBindAdmin&lt;/a&gt;, my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; and
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt; administration tool (specifically geared towards split-view &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt;
    with the inside view behind&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NAT&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://rackman.jasonantman.com/"&gt;RackMan&lt;/a&gt;, my tool for mapping
    devices&amp;#8217; physical locations in racks (and tacking&amp;nbsp;patching).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My simple config tool for
    &lt;a href="http://www.puppetlabs.com"&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://nagios.org/"&gt;Nagios&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cacti.net/"&gt;Cacti&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nathan Hubbard&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.machdb.org/"&gt;MachDB&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bacula.org/en/"&gt;Bacula&lt;/a&gt; (monitoring/status&amp;nbsp;only).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syslog via &lt;a href="http://www.rsyslog.com/"&gt;rsyslog&lt;/a&gt; (or any other
    syslog-to-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SQL&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;solution).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Possibly a front-end to &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/"&gt;Google
    Analytics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of my custom scripts for graphing SpamAssassin, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; queries,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some sort of Apache log analysis, like
    &lt;a href="http://www.mrunix.net/webalizer/"&gt;Webalizer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail log analysis, possibly
    &lt;a href="http://awstats.sourceforge.net/"&gt;AWstats&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the first big issues that I&amp;#8217;m going to&amp;nbsp;tackle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General layout. Specifically, how to handle a more-or-less
    consistent layout while integrating tools that weren&amp;#8217;t designed for
    PHPsa. I&amp;#8217;ll probably end up using iFrames (or even a frameset) for
    tools that don&amp;#8217;t integrate&amp;nbsp;well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to correlate data/objects between different tools (i.e. how to
    display information from Nagios, Cacti, MultiBindAdmin and MachDB
    for a given&amp;nbsp;host?).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I want to use a templating engine like
    &lt;a href="http://www.smarty.net/"&gt;Smarty&lt;/a&gt; or hand-code all of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How will I handle&amp;nbsp;plugins?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much code do I want to re-write and how much can I use as-is
    from other tools? And, on a related note, how much existing data can
    I access easily from other tools, vs having to use grabber scripts
    that dump data in&amp;nbsp;MySQL?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 2010-02-03&lt;/strong&gt;: I think this may become a semi-official project
for me at $work, which means that I&amp;#8217;ll be able to dedicate quite a bit
more time to it. Unfortunately, it also means that I will, most likely,
have to give up Nathan Hubbard&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.machdb.org/"&gt;MachDB&lt;/a&gt; in
favor of &lt;a href="http://www.ocsinventory-ng.org/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OCS&lt;/span&gt; Inventory &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a more
mature project that already includes inventory support for Linux,
Windows and&amp;nbsp;Mac.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2009 15:36:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-09-29:2009/09/project-announcement-phpsa/</guid><category>bind</category><category>cacti</category><category>dns</category><category>Nagios</category><category>PHPsa</category><category>Projects</category><category>puppet</category><category>rsyslog</category><category>sysadmin</category><category>syslog</category></item><item><title>Cable Management, Power Measurements, Major Outage, Cacti</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/03/cable-management-power-measurements-major-outage-cacti/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;So, once again, still really busy. But a few new&amp;nbsp;things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, my racks both at home and at the apartment are atrocious. They
have no cable management at all. Both started with 1-3 machines, and no
real plans for upgrades (since they&amp;#8217;re just my personal/development
machines). Unfortunately, the &amp;#8220;rack&amp;#8221; (a metal workshop shelving unit) at
home now has 8 machines and a host of ancillary equipment. The one at
the apartment - an actual 42U rack - has 5 plus a few switches,
rackmount &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KMM&lt;/span&gt;, etc. They&amp;#8217;re both a jumble of wires in the back.
Unfortunately, it seems like cable management hardware is *epxensive*.
$30 for a 2U metal blank with a few plastic split D-rings, or almost $40
for a 2-meter vertical hunk of plastic channel with slits in the sides?
So, I&amp;#8217;ve been vaguely considering what it will take to fabricate some
cable management hardware of my own. Probably just building something
out of rack blanks for the horizontal off of the switches, and buying
some sort of vertical channel for power and networking/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;KVM&lt;/span&gt;. Man, those
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;KVM&lt;/span&gt; cables sure do take up a lot of space. Also at the moment, at home
my power is all coming directly out of two UPSs, whereas at the
apartment it&amp;#8217;s straight from mains off of a surge suppressor. I&amp;#8217;s like
to buy another &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; for the apartment from RefurbUPS.com, where I got the
ones from home, and also add a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDU&lt;/span&gt; at home and a vertical power strip at
the&amp;nbsp;apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, at the apartment, the roommates and I have had some discussion
lately about how much power the machines draw. This mainly stemmed from
our plans to move this June, into a rented house with two more people.
This seems to be falling through, so I don&amp;#8217;t have to worry about moving
and re-cabling everything, but I&amp;#8217;m still interested in finding out how
much power is being drawn. Granted, my UPSs at home give me a
more-or-less good idea of power consumption, but I&amp;#8217;d like to know in
detail. The ideal solution would be a clamp ammeter around the mains
line to the equipment - one with a serial interface. Unfortunately, I
can&amp;#8217;t seem to find such a thing, short of a digital multimeter left on
all the time. So, I guess I&amp;#8217;ll be looking around, and if I can&amp;#8217;t find
anything specific, maybe I&amp;#8217;ll work on a microcontroller that can read
1-200mV in 1mV increments, and use it with an inductive clamp ammeter
(usual output for them is 1mV per&amp;nbsp;A).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, on Monday I got into work and couldn&amp;#8217;t access my mailserver. Weird.
I never even got any Nagios alerts. I checked Nagios and&amp;#8230; nothing. As
in no connection. I &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;d home and pinged both boxes, but nothing. The
switch showed the mail server totally offline, and the Nagios box
plugged connected but &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ZERO&lt;/span&gt; data out. I reset the counters and waited.
Still nothing. After an hour or so of poking around, I determined that
both devices were on the same 6-port group on the switch, and nothing
else there was up too. So, after five long hours, I got someone back
home to switch the cables. Still nothing. On a hunch, I asked to have
her check the mail server (the &amp;#8220;new&amp;#8221; Sun Blade 150) and, sure enough, it
wasn&amp;#8217;t powered on. A click of the power button, and the mail server was
back online. Along with an ominous last email from Nagios, stating that
the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; running my switch lost power, and 6 minutes later, was going
down hard. Then&amp;nbsp;quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t usually have power outages. So I&amp;#8217;ll admit, when I added some of
the new machines, I committed a high sin - I &amp;#8220;never got around&amp;#8221; to
setting up everything power-wise. I also have the switch running off of
an old BackUPS &lt;span class="caps"&gt;500VA&lt;/span&gt; unit, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt;, without automatic self-tests. As a
result of all&amp;nbsp;this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The little &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; powering the switch only held out for 6-7 minutes. As
    a result, once that died, the bigger units didn&amp;#8217;t even matter, as
    all hope was lost. This needs to be on a bigger &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; - maybe one of
    the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;1000VA&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s until it gets its&amp;#8217;&amp;nbsp;own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APCupsd requires a network to initiate shutdown, so the rest of the
    machines came down hard (as confirmed by looking through log&amp;nbsp;files).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The SunBlade was never setup to power on after power interruption,
    so it just sat there like a&amp;nbsp;brick.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most disturbingly, while my Nagios/monitoring box is up (according to
the switch, power draw figures from the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt;, and the lights, as
confirmed by someone on-site), it&amp;#8217;s dead. No ping, nothing out. I&amp;#8217;ll
have to look into it, but it made me realize that this really is my only
way of analyzing problems. That needs to&amp;nbsp;stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe one day I&amp;#8217;ll have the money for a nice &lt;a href="http://www.apc.com/products/family/index.cfm?id=223"&gt;SmartUPS
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or even a
&lt;a href="http://www.apc.com/products/family/index.cfm?id=189"&gt;Symmetra&lt;/a&gt; - though
getting 208V into my basement is even more of a dream than spending
$4000 on a&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I decided (after all this) to setup graphing of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; data (load,
voltage in and out, temp, capacity, run time, etc.). While I haven&amp;#8217;t
gotten around to setting up &lt;a href="http://www.zenoss.com/"&gt;Zenoss&lt;/a&gt; yet, I did
a quick (well, 4 hours later I&amp;#8217;m done configuring it)
&lt;a href="http://www.cacti.net/"&gt;Cacti&lt;/a&gt;installation on my web server (I should
already have it running on the monitoring box, but who knows what that
will look like when I get&amp;nbsp;home).&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 01:02:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-03-06:2008/03/cable-management-power-measurements-major-outage-cacti/</guid><category>apc</category><category>cable management</category><category>cacti</category><category>disaster</category><category>monitoring</category><category>power distribution</category><category>power failure</category><category>rack</category><category>UPS</category></item></channel></rss>