<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/digg.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2007-09-28T13:22:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>*nix</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/09/nix/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-09-28T13:22:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-09-28:2007/09/nix/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;First off, my Sun blog should be coming sometime this weekend/early next
week. If I post anything interesting there, I&amp;#8217;ll be sure to cross-post&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning at work, while reading &lt;a href="http://digg.com"&gt;Digg&lt;/a&gt;, I came by
two interesting links that got me thinking:
&lt;a href="http://www.foogazi.com/2007/09/27/5-reasons-your-parents-should-use-linux/"&gt;5 Reasons Your Parents Should Use
Linux&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href="http://warpedvisions.org/2006/12/30/ten-things-linux-distros-get-right-that-ms-doesnt/"&gt;Ten Things Linux Distros Get Right (That &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt;
Doesn&amp;#8217;t)&lt;/a&gt;.
Now, I&amp;#8217;ll admit, my *nix experience is pretty much limited to Linux.
I&amp;#8217;ve used &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BSD&lt;/span&gt; a few times, but only as pre-built images for embedded
systems like my &lt;a href="http://www.soekris.com"&gt;Soekris&lt;/a&gt; boxen. I&amp;#8217;ve used
Solaris mainly just as a user/web developer in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; at work. And while I
now have a work computer running Solaris 10 and a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SXDE&lt;/span&gt; image on my
laptop, I&amp;#8217;m still relatively new - and, given that I&amp;#8217;m now doing
hardware support and wireless work, I don&amp;#8217;t even know what I need
another machine in the office&amp;nbsp;for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, the second link got me thinking. Specifically, about
something I read in &lt;a href="http://www.catb.org/~esr/writings/taoup/"&gt;The Art of Unix
Programming&lt;/a&gt; [Wikipedia] by
Eric S. Raymond (available online
&lt;a href="http://www.catb.org/~esr/writings/taoup/html/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) with regards to
interface design. One quote that I was able to find in the online
version, comes from Chapter 11, under the subtitle &amp;#8220;Tradeoffs between
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; and Visual Interfaces&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;Resistance to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; interfaces tends to
decrease as users become more expert. In many problem domains, users
(especially frequent
users) reach a crossover point at which the concision and expressiveness
of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; becomes more valuable than avoiding its mnemonic load. Thus, for
example, computing novices prefer the ease of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; desktops, but
experienced users often gradually discover that they prefer typing
commands to a&amp;nbsp;shell.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is another similar
quote in the book, mentioning how resistance to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; drops as
&lt;em&gt;typing speed&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;increases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, in some areas I&amp;#8217;m still bound to Windows. Though my only
personal use for it is to control an ancient Umax Mirage IIse &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCSI&lt;/span&gt;
scanner (with only Windows and Mac drivers), I ultimately need to touch
it now and then - whether on my mother&amp;#8217;s box (she claims she has to have
Windows and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt; Office because &amp;#8220;that&amp;#8217;s what businesses use&amp;#8221;) or as admin
of the four boxes at the &lt;a href="http://www.midlandparkambulance.com"&gt;Ambulance
Corps&lt;/a&gt; where I&amp;nbsp;volunteer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, whenever I am (unfortunately) pushed into the task of working
on a Windows box, I always feel something lacking. To be blunt, I don&amp;#8217;t
see how experienced users can deal with it. And this isn&amp;#8217;t just an issue
of multiple desktops, or reliability (I expect my desktop to have months
of uptime, and my servers to have years). This isn&amp;#8217;t just pro-Linux,
it&amp;#8217;s anti-Windows. Linux is great. Solaris seems wonderful, and I can&amp;#8217;t
want to move my servers over. And, believe it or not, due to playing
around with the Solaris Management Console, for the first time in 5
years, I plan on running X on my servers.
What this is, is a talk about total workflow. Years ago, I reached the
point where I am more comfortable at the command line, or in an
Ncurses-style &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt;, than in&amp;nbsp;X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I an attribute this to two factors - verbosity and speed. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; is as
verbose as anything can get. I remember setting a static &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; on a Windows
box. I had to navigate the Start menu, open up the control panel, the
network thingy, click on the network card, and work through a series of
dialogs. In Linux, I clicked on the terminal icon, typed &amp;#8220;sudo ifconfig
eth0 up 192.168.0.211&amp;#8221; and then a password. Done. Likewise, refreshing a
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt; lease on Windows requires a whole bunch of &amp;#8220;repair connection&amp;#8221;
nonsense, whereas in Linux all it requires is &amp;#8220;dhclient eth0&amp;#8221;. The
bottom line I know what I&amp;#8217;m doing. Windows should have an option to let
me quickly do&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speed is a related issue. Click, click-click, drag, click, click&amp;#8230;.
what about just typing? Even for people who aren&amp;#8217;t &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt;-friendly, there&amp;#8217;s
Ncurses. YaST2, the SuSE/openSuSE administration tool, has both &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; and
Ncurses interfaces. I always use the Ncurses interface. Why? Because
I&amp;#8217;ve been using it for years. I know that if I want to add a user
through YaST, I hit the down arrow 7 times, tab once, down 5, enter. Tab
once more to bring up the add user dialog. I can do this in well under a
second. What&amp;#8217;s the bottom line? Well, first of all, my hands are already
on the keyboard. That&amp;#8217;s where they like to stay. That&amp;#8217;s where they&amp;#8217;re
comfortable. My fingers need to move a *lot* less to navigate with the
arrow keys, tab, and enter than they do to use a mouse. If you know what
you&amp;#8217;re doing, if you already know what you&amp;#8217;re looking for, then a mouse
is slower than the speed of thought (or&amp;nbsp;reaction).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where&amp;#8217;s the Windows bashing? Simple. How do people at Microsoft deal
with this? How does the guy who *wrote* that network settings dialog
deal with navigating the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; every time, even though he already knows
exactly what he wants to do - and probably the system calls to do&amp;nbsp;it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that every time I sit down at a Windows machine, I
wonder how the most popular &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; is one that doesn&amp;#8217;t give any thought to
advanced users. I know that I can type faster than I can move a mouse,
why don&amp;#8217;t you let me use that? More importantly, why didn&amp;#8217;t Microsoft
ever think that people would use computers on a network? When I
installed Solaris, I wanted to edit a config file. I hadn&amp;#8217;t customized
&lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; yet, hadn&amp;#8217;t installed any other software, nothing. Yet, I
was able to open up a terminal and grab my .emacs file from my laptop in
one line&amp;nbsp;(scp).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be totally honest, the question running through my mind is something
like &amp;#8220;everything is so much quicker on Linux. How do experts deal with&amp;nbsp;Windows?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Digg"></category><category term="Eric S Raymond"></category><category term="linux"></category><category term="solaris"></category><category term="sun"></category><category term="Unix"></category></entry></feed>