<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog - disaster</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/disaster.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2010-01-20T21:25:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Federal Government: Ignoring what we learned 5,000 years ago</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/01/federal-government-ignoring-what-we-learned-5000-years-ago/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-01-20T21:25:00-05:00</published><updated>2010-01-20T21:25:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-01-20:/2010/01/federal-government-ignoring-what-we-learned-5000-years-ago/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Being a volunteer
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emergency_medical_technician"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and at
times an outdoorsy-type person, I occasionally get emails from friends
about disaster-related topics. Especially in the post-9/11 days.
Recently, I got an email asking me if I&amp;#8217;d seen the Department of
Homeland Security&amp;#8217;s disaster preparedness site,
&lt;a href="http://www.ready.gov"&gt;ready.gov&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;d heard …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Being a volunteer
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emergency_medical_technician"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and at
times an outdoorsy-type person, I occasionally get emails from friends
about disaster-related topics. Especially in the post-9/11 days.
Recently, I got an email asking me if I&amp;#8217;d seen the Department of
Homeland Security&amp;#8217;s disaster preparedness site,
&lt;a href="http://www.ready.gov"&gt;ready.gov&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;d heard a bit about it, but hadn&amp;#8217;t
really looked around. The site&amp;#8217;s main premise is to educate people about
how to prepare for a disaster - &amp;#8220;get a kit&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;make a plan&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;be&amp;nbsp;informed&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site&amp;#8217;s own &lt;a href="http://www.ready.gov/america/about/index.html"&gt;About
page&lt;/a&gt; states that it is
&amp;#8220;designed to educate and empower Americans to prepare for and respond to
emergencies including natural and man-made disasters. The goal of the
campaign is to get the public involved and ultimately to increase the
level of basic preparedness across the&amp;nbsp;nation.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step on the site, &lt;a href="http://www.ready.gov/america/getakit/index.html"&gt;&amp;#8220;Get a
Kit&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;, includes a list
of supplies to have on hand as a basic disaster kit. The introduction to
the page&amp;nbsp;reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may need to survive on your own after an emergency. This means
having your own food, water, and other supplies in sufficient quantity
to last for at least three days. Local officials and relief workers
will be on the scene after a disaster, but they cannot reach everyone
immediately. You could get help in hours, or it might take days. In
addition, basic services such as electricity, gas, water, sewage
treatment, and telephones may be cut off for days, or even a week or&amp;nbsp;longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will admit, I assumed this would be geared more towards urbanites, not
those of us in the suburbs or rural America (the latter generally being
more accustomed to self-sufficiency), so I adjusted my expectations
accordingly. At first glance, it seems to include most of the things
that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMT&lt;/span&gt; in me would want it&amp;nbsp;to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food and&amp;nbsp;water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First aid&amp;nbsp;kit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrench or pliers to turn off gas&amp;nbsp;line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prescription&amp;nbsp;medications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bleach (as a disinfectant and for water&amp;nbsp;purification)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fire&amp;nbsp;extinguisher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I found a number of things obviously missing. Sure, some are
minor - matches but no mention of fuel, bleach but not even coffee
filters to remove particulate matter from water. I also find it comical
that so many years after the Cold War &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Duck_and_cover"&gt;&amp;#8220;Duck and
Cover&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; approach to nuclear
safety, the government is now telling people to
&lt;a href="http://www.ready.gov/america/makeaplan/shelter_in_place.html"&gt;Shelter-In-Place&lt;/a&gt;
in the event of a biological attack - by covering their doors and
windows with plastic&amp;nbsp;sheeting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But by far the most egregious omission from the list - something learned
by man at least 5,000 years ago, and taught to every Boy Scout - is the
simplest tool: a knife. Yup, that&amp;#8217;s right, the Disaster Kit list doesn&amp;#8217;t
include &lt;strong&gt;any variety of cutting implement&lt;/strong&gt;. I don&amp;#8217;t know if whoever
wrote up the list is just scared of getting sued when little Bobby finds
the knife and kills himself, or whether they&amp;#8217;re really that stupid. But
I, for one, never leave my house without some variety of the oldest real
tool devised by man, and can&amp;#8217;t imagine anyone thrown into any sort of
&amp;#8220;survival&amp;#8221; situation without at least a rudimentary way to cut, scrape,
pry, etc. I&amp;#8217;d say that if I were without utilities or organized public
safety for &amp;#8220;at least three days&amp;#8221;, I&amp;#8217;d sure want to be able to make
simple repairs, fashion simple tools, or perhaps cut&amp;nbsp;something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On another (albeit less important) note, there are still &lt;em&gt;many, many&lt;/em&gt;
Americans, not just in rural areas, who have a fireplace or wood stove.
What about a few days&amp;#8217; worth of&amp;nbsp;wood?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="disaster"></category><category term="EMS"></category><category term="government"></category><category term="preparedness"></category></entry><entry><title>Cable Management, Power Measurements, Major Outage, Cacti</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/03/cable-management-power-measurements-major-outage-cacti/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-03-06T01:02:00-05:00</published><updated>2008-03-06T01:02:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-03-06:/2008/03/cable-management-power-measurements-major-outage-cacti/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, once again, still really busy. But a few new&amp;nbsp;things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, my racks both at home and at the apartment are atrocious. They
have no cable management at all. Both started with 1-3 machines, and no
real plans for upgrades (since they&amp;#8217;re just my personal/development
machines). Unfortunately …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, once again, still really busy. But a few new&amp;nbsp;things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, my racks both at home and at the apartment are atrocious. They
have no cable management at all. Both started with 1-3 machines, and no
real plans for upgrades (since they&amp;#8217;re just my personal/development
machines). Unfortunately, the &amp;#8220;rack&amp;#8221; (a metal workshop shelving unit) at
home now has 8 machines and a host of ancillary equipment. The one at
the apartment - an actual 42U rack - has 5 plus a few switches,
rackmount &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KMM&lt;/span&gt;, etc. They&amp;#8217;re both a jumble of wires in the back.
Unfortunately, it seems like cable management hardware is *epxensive*.
$30 for a 2U metal blank with a few plastic split D-rings, or almost $40
for a 2-meter vertical hunk of plastic channel with slits in the sides?
So, I&amp;#8217;ve been vaguely considering what it will take to fabricate some
cable management hardware of my own. Probably just building something
out of rack blanks for the horizontal off of the switches, and buying
some sort of vertical channel for power and networking/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;KVM&lt;/span&gt;. Man, those
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;KVM&lt;/span&gt; cables sure do take up a lot of space. Also at the moment, at home
my power is all coming directly out of two UPSs, whereas at the
apartment it&amp;#8217;s straight from mains off of a surge suppressor. I&amp;#8217;s like
to buy another &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; for the apartment from RefurbUPS.com, where I got the
ones from home, and also add a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDU&lt;/span&gt; at home and a vertical power strip at
the&amp;nbsp;apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, at the apartment, the roommates and I have had some discussion
lately about how much power the machines draw. This mainly stemmed from
our plans to move this June, into a rented house with two more people.
This seems to be falling through, so I don&amp;#8217;t have to worry about moving
and re-cabling everything, but I&amp;#8217;m still interested in finding out how
much power is being drawn. Granted, my UPSs at home give me a
more-or-less good idea of power consumption, but I&amp;#8217;d like to know in
detail. The ideal solution would be a clamp ammeter around the mains
line to the equipment - one with a serial interface. Unfortunately, I
can&amp;#8217;t seem to find such a thing, short of a digital multimeter left on
all the time. So, I guess I&amp;#8217;ll be looking around, and if I can&amp;#8217;t find
anything specific, maybe I&amp;#8217;ll work on a microcontroller that can read
1-200mV in 1mV increments, and use it with an inductive clamp ammeter
(usual output for them is 1mV per&amp;nbsp;A).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, on Monday I got into work and couldn&amp;#8217;t access my mailserver. Weird.
I never even got any Nagios alerts. I checked Nagios and&amp;#8230; nothing. As
in no connection. I &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;d home and pinged both boxes, but nothing. The
switch showed the mail server totally offline, and the Nagios box
plugged connected but &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ZERO&lt;/span&gt; data out. I reset the counters and waited.
Still nothing. After an hour or so of poking around, I determined that
both devices were on the same 6-port group on the switch, and nothing
else there was up too. So, after five long hours, I got someone back
home to switch the cables. Still nothing. On a hunch, I asked to have
her check the mail server (the &amp;#8220;new&amp;#8221; Sun Blade 150) and, sure enough, it
wasn&amp;#8217;t powered on. A click of the power button, and the mail server was
back online. Along with an ominous last email from Nagios, stating that
the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; running my switch lost power, and 6 minutes later, was going
down hard. Then&amp;nbsp;quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t usually have power outages. So I&amp;#8217;ll admit, when I added some of
the new machines, I committed a high sin - I &amp;#8220;never got around&amp;#8221; to
setting up everything power-wise. I also have the switch running off of
an old BackUPS &lt;span class="caps"&gt;500VA&lt;/span&gt; unit, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt;, without automatic self-tests. As a
result of all&amp;nbsp;this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The little &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; powering the switch only held out for 6-7 minutes. As
    a result, once that died, the bigger units didn&amp;#8217;t even matter, as
    all hope was lost. This needs to be on a bigger &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; - maybe one of
    the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;1000VA&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s until it gets its&amp;#8217;&amp;nbsp;own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APCupsd requires a network to initiate shutdown, so the rest of the
    machines came down hard (as confirmed by looking through log&amp;nbsp;files).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The SunBlade was never setup to power on after power interruption,
    so it just sat there like a&amp;nbsp;brick.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most disturbingly, while my Nagios/monitoring box is up (according to
the switch, power draw figures from the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt;, and the lights, as
confirmed by someone on-site), it&amp;#8217;s dead. No ping, nothing out. I&amp;#8217;ll
have to look into it, but it made me realize that this really is my only
way of analyzing problems. That needs to&amp;nbsp;stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe one day I&amp;#8217;ll have the money for a nice &lt;a href="http://www.apc.com/products/family/index.cfm?id=223"&gt;SmartUPS
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or even a
&lt;a href="http://www.apc.com/products/family/index.cfm?id=189"&gt;Symmetra&lt;/a&gt; - though
getting 208V into my basement is even more of a dream than spending
$4000 on a&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I decided (after all this) to setup graphing of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; data (load,
voltage in and out, temp, capacity, run time, etc.). While I haven&amp;#8217;t
gotten around to setting up &lt;a href="http://www.zenoss.com/"&gt;Zenoss&lt;/a&gt; yet, I did
a quick (well, 4 hours later I&amp;#8217;m done configuring it)
&lt;a href="http://www.cacti.net/"&gt;Cacti&lt;/a&gt;installation on my web server (I should
already have it running on the monitoring box, but who knows what that
will look like when I get&amp;nbsp;home).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="apc"></category><category term="cable management"></category><category term="cacti"></category><category term="disaster"></category><category term="monitoring"></category><category term="power distribution"></category><category term="power failure"></category><category term="rack"></category><category term="UPS"></category></entry></feed>