<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/education.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2009-02-17T22:32:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Online Exams and Reality</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/02/online-exams-and-reality/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-02-17T22:32:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-02-17:2009/02/online-exams-and-reality/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend recently showed me the syllabus for one of her classes, which
is partially given online through the &lt;a href="http://sakaiproject.org/portal"&gt;Sakai course management
system&lt;/a&gt;. At the bottom was a section on
course policies which stated, in part, that the &amp;#8220;Academic Integrity
policy is in full effect&amp;#8221;. Apparently, this professor is giving online
exams in Sakai. The policy goes on to state that not only is
collaborative test-taking not allowed, but also that use of any
resources (including a textbook) is not allowed. The policy states that
use of electronic resources (&amp;#8220;a second web browser&amp;#8221;) is also not
allowed, and that the course management system includes &amp;#8220;features&amp;#8221; to
prevent &amp;#8220;cheating&amp;#8221; - enumerated as a time stamp for every&amp;nbsp;answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me at least, this shows not only an unrealistic outlook, but also a
horrible lack of understanding about&amp;nbsp;technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does this professor actually expect that he can have students taken
    an exam at home, on a computer, and none of them will Google an
    answer? If so, he should take some steps to actually prevent such
    actions - like having the students take the exam in a proctored
    environment. If not, what is the purpose of this&amp;nbsp;intimidation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know I&amp;#8217;m not a programming wizard, but if someone can tell me the
    algorithm to determine whether or not a student is cheating - &lt;em&gt;based
    solely on their answers and the submission time of each answer&lt;/em&gt; -
    I&amp;#8217;d really like to be&amp;nbsp;enlightened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If professors want to administer exams online and prevent students from
using &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; outside resources, it seems to me like the only way to
realistically do this is to setup a human-proctored computer lab
(perhaps University-wide at a number of locations, available for members
of any class) that allows access only to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTPS&lt;/span&gt; for the course
management system and nothing else. All the human proctor would have to
do is sit in the room and make sure students aren&amp;#8217;t looking in textbooks
or conferring with each&amp;nbsp;other.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="cms"></category><category term="course management"></category><category term="education"></category></entry></feed>