<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog - facebook beacon blog linux NYSE</title><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/facebook-beacon-blog-linux-nyse.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2007-12-15T22:57:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Facebook Beacon; Linux in the Real World; Blog Updates</title><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/12/facebook-beacon-linux-in-the-real-world-blog-updates/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-12-15T22:57:00-05:00</published><updated>2007-12-15T22:57:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-12-15:/2007/12/facebook-beacon-linux-in-the-real-world-blog-updates/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, for one thing, I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking about making more changes to my
blog. For one, I was thinking about ditching Blogger and just doing
everything myself server-side. My only qualm about this is whether using
blogger (a Google product) raises my Google rankings - after all, Google
rankings are …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, for one thing, I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking about making more changes to my
blog. For one, I was thinking about ditching Blogger and just doing
everything myself server-side. My only qualm about this is whether using
blogger (a Google product) raises my Google rankings - after all, Google
rankings are a good thing. Also, I&amp;#8217;ve been toying around with the idea
of creating multiple feeds. Specifically, categorizing my posts into
descriptive categories, such as tech how-tos, tech news, personal views,
etc. and then offering either a combined feed or feeds of only a certain
category. If anyone actually reads this thing (I think most of my
readers come from searching specific topics, and probably only read that
post - though I don&amp;#8217;t have anything to support that). Obviously, to do
this, it would be easiest to handle the blog with software on my server,
probably something slightly&amp;nbsp;custom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="facebook-beacon"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#facebook-beacon"&gt;Facebook&amp;nbsp;Beacon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an update on Facebook Beacon, I came by
&lt;a href="http://yro.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=07/12/14/1620258&amp;amp;from=rss"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;
post on Slashdot, referencing a &lt;a href="http://www.computerworld.com/action/article.do?command=viewArticleBasic&amp;amp;articleId=9053002&amp;amp;intsrc=hm_list"&gt;ComputerWorld
article&lt;/a&gt;
questioning whether Facebook Beacon could possibly be sued, as it
appears to violate the Video Privacy Protection Act of 1988, which
prevents video rental agencies from disclosing the rental history of
their customers without a written release. Interesting&amp;nbsp;stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="linux-in-the-real-world"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#linux-in-the-real-world"&gt;Linux in the Real&amp;nbsp;World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being an avid Linux user, and a fan of both the functionality (from the
point of view of a user as well as a programmer) and religion of F/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt;,
I always like to hear stories of Linux (and other F/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt;) usage in the
&amp;#8220;real world&amp;#8221;. Especially situations where Linux is displacing Windows,
but really anything Linux-based in general. I can&amp;#8217;t wait for a Linux
cellphone that will do everything I want - though being a Verizon
customer, I doubt that will happen until they move to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GSM&lt;/span&gt; in a few
years. Some people accuse me of being anti-Microsoft. Sure, I am. Why
would I pay $200 for Windows when it doesn&amp;#8217;t do half of what my free
Linux does? I&amp;#8217;m not even going to touch on the moral aspects. But just
look at the &lt;a href="http://www.noooxml.org/petition"&gt;arguments against the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt;
standard&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft sure does do some
stupid stuff, and seems to miss the whole idea of the workings of
standards. If it only exists in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONE&lt;/span&gt; proprietary product, I don&amp;#8217;t see how
you can call it a&amp;nbsp;standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I found
&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/idg/IDG_002570DE00740E18002573B100020F62.html?ex=1355288400&amp;amp;en=1a1c847788830aeb&amp;amp;ei=5088&amp;amp;partner=rssnyt&amp;amp;emc=rss/ru/"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;
article from the New York Times, talking about how the New York Stock
Exchange is &amp;#8220;investing heavily&amp;#8221; in Linux on commodity x86 hardware,
replacing Unix mainframes, nonetheless. And what hardware are they
using? My beloved &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Proliants.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="facebook beacon blog linux NYSE"></category></entry></feed>