<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/firewall.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2009 19:05:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>Many Many Changes; Downtime</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/03/many-many-changes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I don&amp;#8217;t have time to go into a lot of detail, but I thought I&amp;#8217;d
give a recap of what&amp;#8217;s going on. I went down to Mount Holly, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NJ&lt;/span&gt;
yestserday morning - about a 2-/12 hour drive each way, and picked up a
41U rack for the basement. Pretty damn heavy, took me two hours to
disassemble it, wrangle it down the stairs, and get it back together.
It&amp;#8217;s an old round-hole rack, which didn&amp;#8217;t seem to matter much until I
found that the tabs of the Dell Rapid Rails are just a bit too big to
fit in it, so neither my rack &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KMM&lt;/span&gt; nor the rails for my mail server will
fit. A bigger problem, though, is that the guy told me it was the
standard &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HP&lt;/span&gt; 29&amp;#8221; deep, and I found it to be 28-1/4&amp;#8221; deep when I started
racking things up. So, though I just spent $200 on rails for old
Proliants, they&amp;#8217;re all about 1/2&amp;#8221; too long to&amp;nbsp;fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I also had Cablevision show up to install the new Optimum
Business with 5 static&amp;nbsp;IPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, last night around 9:00, I started the arduous task of (for the first
time ever) powering down &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ALL&lt;/span&gt; of my machines, moving them to the new
rack, and re-cabling. That took about 2-1/2 hours, after which my intent
was to bring up the new Optimum connection, configure the Vyatta router,
and roll over mail and web. From what I&amp;#8217;d read of the Vyatta docs it
seemed a relatively straightforward task, and being the stubborn jackass
that I am, I decied, &amp;#8220;hey, it&amp;#8217;s my personal site, it&amp;#8217;s low traffic, and
I want it up before I go to sleep. I&amp;#8217;ll roll over &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; I bring
everything&amp;nbsp;up.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was a &lt;strong&gt;very bad idea&lt;/strong&gt;. Vyatta isn&amp;#8217;t nearly as
simple as it seems - especially for someone who isn&amp;#8217;t really a network
(or at least router/firewall) guy. When they say Enterprise, they mean
robust. They also mean that week-long bootcamps aren&amp;#8217;t for naught. It
took me about half an hour to figure out that even if no &amp;#8220;firewall&amp;#8221;
ruleset is associated with an interface, it still has an implicit drop
all. And if you only want to firewall what&amp;#8217;s coming in from the outside
world, and let everything out, you need to add explicit allow all rules
to the in and out sides of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt; inteface and the out side of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WAN&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To top all this off, I had some serious still-unexplained &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt; problems
on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;, a serious issue since I just set all my hosts to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt; (which
I&amp;#8217;ll probably undo soon). So, Yesterday was network work from 7:30 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt; to
3 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt; today (including driving to pickup the rack). By the time 3 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt;
rolled around, I was quite unhappy that I decided to roll over &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; in
order to force myself to get things working, as I ended up going back to
FiOS for client access only. Today started around 10 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt;, and here I am -
6:30 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt;, and I just got things working partially right. I have mail
working - arguably the most important - for jasonantman.com only, though
I have yet to setup any&amp;nbsp;aliases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the web side, I&amp;#8217;m working to setup name-based vhosts for all of the
subdomains, but for some reason, blog is showing up for everything.
Luckily it works right. So we&amp;#8217;ll&amp;nbsp;see&amp;#8230;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2009 19:05:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-03-07:2009/03/many-many-changes/</guid><category>firewall</category><category>optimum</category><category>rack</category><category>router</category><category>wan</category></item></channel></rss>