<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog - flash</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/flash.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2008-08-25T12:37:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Linux, Choice, Updates, CitiBank issues</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/08/linux-choice-updates-citibank-issues/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-08-25T12:37:00-04:00</published><updated>2008-08-25T12:37:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-08-25:/2008/08/linux-choice-updates-citibank-issues/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update July 11, 2011&lt;/strong&gt; - I &lt;a href="/2011/07/article-on-theinquirer-net/"&gt;just found
out&lt;/a&gt; that this post is heavily
quote in &lt;a href="http://www.theinquirer.net/inquirer/news/1026958/citibank-infuriating-customers-linux-hostile-site"&gt;an article on
theinquirer.net&lt;/a&gt;
about this issue. Luckily (I don&amp;#8217;t know whether I made a difference or
not, certainly CitiBank never contacted me back), citicards.com now
works with Firefox on Linux. I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update July 11, 2011&lt;/strong&gt; - I &lt;a href="/2011/07/article-on-theinquirer-net/"&gt;just found
out&lt;/a&gt; that this post is heavily
quote in &lt;a href="http://www.theinquirer.net/inquirer/news/1026958/citibank-infuriating-customers-linux-hostile-site"&gt;an article on
theinquirer.net&lt;/a&gt;
about this issue. Luckily (I don&amp;#8217;t know whether I made a difference or
not, certainly CitiBank never contacted me back), citicards.com now
works with Firefox on Linux. I have no idea if it was a change made by
Citi, or a change with Firefox or Flash&amp;nbsp;Player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this blog has been less-than-active lately. Life has been pretty
busy, between a massive network upgrade at the &lt;a href="http://www.midlandparkambulance.com"&gt;ambulance
corps&lt;/a&gt; that I volunteer with, the
impending doom of a new semester at work, scheduling courses, and a few
personal projects. I do, however, have a long list of things to post,
including some notes on my upgrade to &lt;a href="http://www.nagios.org"&gt;Nagios 3&lt;/a&gt;,
my recent experience with the &lt;a href="http://www.pcengines.ch/alix.htm"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt; Engines
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ALIX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; board, some changes to
&lt;a href="http://tuxostat.jasonantman.com"&gt;tuxOstat&lt;/a&gt;, and my plans to upgrade to
Optimum Business cable with 5 static IPs - finally a real home for
&lt;a href="http://www.jasonantman.com"&gt;JasonAntman.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CitiCards Problems -&lt;/strong&gt; I had a somewhat unnerving experience this
morning. Having just gotten a Citibank credit card, and made my first
few purchases on it, I browsed to
&lt;a href="https://www.citicards.com"&gt;CitiCards.com&lt;/a&gt; to check my account summary.
I happened to be using a just-purchased &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IBM&lt;/span&gt; T41 laptop, running
&lt;a href="http://www.opensuse.org"&gt;OpenSuSE 11.0&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://www.getfirefox.com"&gt;FireFox3&lt;/a&gt;, so when I saw the page display
and then go completely blank, I suspected a problem with my Flash
plugin. Little did I know, but I tried the same page on 3 other
Linux/Firefox machines, with the same result. I put in a call to the
tech support line, and was gruffly informed by the representative that
Firefox was not supported, they were unable to support it, and, to
paraphrase, I should get another browser or f*** off. She was &lt;em&gt;very
well-aware&lt;/em&gt; of the issue, and stated that Citi would not fix it. At this
point, I stated that I thought I would cancel my card, and she told me
to have a nice day and hung&amp;nbsp;up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to go to step 2 of the Generic Problem Solving
Method,
and found &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;q=citicards.com+linux&amp;amp;btnG=Google+Search"&gt;hundreds of references to a problem with CitiCards.com on
Linux&lt;/a&gt;.
I read through a lot of conspiracy theory, but decided to test one of
the theories (and fixes). Sure enough, when I right-clicked on the blank
white screen, I got a Flash context menu. Clicking &amp;#8220;Play&amp;#8221; showed the ad,
and I was able to click the little &amp;#8220;X&amp;#8221; in the top right and bypass it,
gaining access to the normal main page. Never to be one to ignore a
conspiracy (or anti-Linux) theory, I pulled up the same page on a Mac.
Sure enough, that particular ad (set not to play and with an opaque
full-screen background) didn&amp;#8217;t show up. Hmm&amp;#8230; maybe there&amp;#8217;s something
to the theory put forth by the &lt;a href="http://stealcode.blogspot.com/2008/07/citibank-doesnt-like-linuxubuntu_27.html"&gt;guy who said CitiBank is blocking Linux
users&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to call back, and this time spoke with Susan at CitiCards tech
support. She was very understanding, and apologized for both the
inconvenience and the previous representative&amp;#8217;s attitude. She said that
she was aware of some issues with Firefox and Linux, but stated that
they are only unsupported so far as Tech Support won&amp;#8217;t walk a customer
using Linux or FireFox through any issue resolution, but that both the
browser and architecture should, theoretically, work. She didn&amp;#8217;t know
anything about a policy against Linux, or intentional blocking/sabotage.
She did say, however, that they are &amp;#8220;working on it&amp;#8221;. I did inform her
that the problem could probably be resolved by simply editing the Flash
ad to be properly transparent, or suppressing it for Linux
architectures, though I doubt that the information will make its&amp;#8217; way up
the food chain. Unfortunately, I can&amp;#8217;t seem to find a contact email for
anything site-related on&amp;nbsp;CitiCards.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is really a case of intentional blocking, it would be quite
infuriating - I filled out the application for the card on
FireFox3/Linux&amp;#8230; but then they block account&amp;nbsp;access?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully more of an update&amp;nbsp;tonight&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="citibank"></category><category term="citicards"></category><category term="firefox"></category><category term="flash"></category><category term="linux"></category></entry></feed>