<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/g1.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2008-10-27T08:12:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>T-Mobile G1 (Googlephone) and VoIP?</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/10/t-mobile-g1-googlephone-and-voip/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-10-27T08:12:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-10-27:2008/10/t-mobile-g1-googlephone-and-voip/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So&amp;#8230; what&amp;#8217;s the deal? Will anyone come out and definitively say what
the fate of VoIP&amp;nbsp;is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what I&amp;#8217;ve read, there are two distinct&amp;nbsp;issues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ease of developing VoIP applications on Android, given the lack
    of a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;stack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T-Mobile&amp;#8217;s shunning of VoIP over their 3G&amp;nbsp;network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Android&lt;/strong&gt; - obviously, if we want to see VoIP apps on the G1, Android
needs to support &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIP&lt;/span&gt;. And the best way to do this is with real, native
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; support. Even if VoIP possibilities are limited to WiFi, still, it
would be nice to have &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIP&lt;/span&gt; support and let my cell double as a WiFi VoIP
phone&amp;#8230; even if handoffs between APs are still nearly impossible. The
next question that begs to be asked is how well such a third-party app
can integrate with the phone. Will the user experience of receiving a
VoIP call be substantially similar to that of receiving a normal phone&amp;nbsp;call?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T-Mobile 3G&lt;/strong&gt; - I&amp;#8217;ve read, so far, that T-Mobile &amp;#8220;does not support&amp;#8221;
VoIP over their 3G network. What&amp;#8217;s this whole &amp;#8220;does not support&amp;#8221; thing?
I&amp;#8217;m still a bit confused about how their 3G network works&amp;#8230; do they
actively block 3G, or just not enable it? If the latter, doe this mean
that other &amp;#8220;non-standard&amp;#8221; things, such as SSHing to a non-standard port,
won&amp;#8217;t work? Does this mean that there will be other heavy restrictions
on what types of data are sent over the&amp;nbsp;network?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about tunneling &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIP&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IAX&lt;/span&gt;/whatever else over &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt;? Will the G1 be
capable of handling that at a relatively good&amp;nbsp;speed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve read that the G1 &amp;#8220;can&amp;#8217;t&amp;#8221; be tethered. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WTF&lt;/span&gt;? Firstly, what is this
&amp;#8220;can&amp;#8217;t&amp;#8221; thing? Couldn&amp;#8217;t a developer just write an app that&amp;#8217;s essentially
a proxy server, that proxies from some sort of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt;-based wired
connection to&amp;nbsp;3G?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, as has been written many times already, less than a week
from the G1&amp;#8217;s release, it seems that the &lt;strong&gt;openness&lt;/strong&gt; touted by Google
and T-Mobile is much less than that. With all their claims of openness,
I&amp;#8217;d expect a phone that will do anything - especially not be locked to
one carrier, given Google&amp;#8217;s history of opposing that (their bid for
700Mhz) - and a data plan that would allow anything over the air that my
home &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; will allow over the&amp;nbsp;wire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google: Have you forsaken all of your stated ideals at the prospect of
making some cash off of a&amp;nbsp;phone?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="cell"></category><category term="g1"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="phone"></category><category term="t-mobile"></category><category term="voip"></category></entry><entry><title>Update</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/10/update-3/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-10-24T12:50:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-10-24:2008/10/update-3/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been a long month and a half or so. A bunch of new projects at work
(and interviewing for a full-time position) and lots of school stuff,
all on top of having my truck stolen, dealing with insurance and the
police, and then recovering it, and dealing with insurance again. It&amp;#8217;s a
long long story, which I posted as a Note on&amp;nbsp;facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.php-ems-tools.com"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMS&lt;/span&gt; Tools&lt;/a&gt; is due for a major
revision, and hopefully this will include, among other things, the
following new&amp;nbsp;features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I18n"&gt;i18n&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install-time choice of using MySQL or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LDAP&lt;/span&gt; as a roster and
    authentication storage&amp;nbsp;system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some vastly more efficient changes to the database schema,
    specifically dealing with&amp;nbsp;scheduling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m still working on some other big projects, namely the migration of
this blog to &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/"&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;, the migration of
&lt;a href="http://www.jasonantman.com"&gt;JasonAntman.com&lt;/a&gt; to some real &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CMS&lt;/span&gt; (Joomla,
Drupal, etc.), and migration of my home internet connection from
residential FiOS to &amp;#8220;business-grade&amp;#8221; Optimum Online (cable) - which will
probably see a slight decrease in reliability from the amazing levels of
FiOS, but will give me five static IPs and no ports&amp;nbsp;blocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there&amp;#8217;s been a wrench thrown into all of my plans for
big projects (not even mentioning the projects that have been cast aside
- &lt;a href="http://www.tuctruck.org"&gt;TuxTruck&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://jantman.dyndns.org:10011/tuxostat/"&gt;tuxOstat&lt;/a&gt; which is now down,
and a bunch of others. That wrench is the &lt;a href="http://www.t-mobileg1.com/"&gt;T-Mobile
G1&lt;/a&gt;, the GooglePhone finally come to
fruition. I was psyched about Android when I first heard about it, and
the idea of finally having a phone that I can develop for without
learning a new language sounds amazing. I&amp;#8217;ll admit that at $180 with a
2-year contract, plus $80/month for service (split about 50/50 between
the voice plan and the unlimited data plan) it doesn&amp;#8217;t make the best
financial sense for someone whose car was stolen and now has 2 vehicles
- only one of which I can afford - but I&amp;#8217;m really excited. I&amp;#8217;ve heard
some not-so-good things about the quality of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;, and some of the
apps currently available, but within a few months, I&amp;#8217;d assume that the
effects of open development will cause it to greatly surpass the
functionality of my current Treo 700p, running my beloved Palm &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; (which
I&amp;#8217;ve been dedicated to for the better part of seven&amp;nbsp;years).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the all-around flexibility of Android and its&amp;#8217; apps is definitely
one of the biggest selling points, my own interest is mainly in the
ability to quickly develop Java apps that bring my already-existing
web-based forms and data to the desktop of my phone. It&amp;#8217;s the simplicity
that is my biggest interest - even for simple purposes, like converting
the web-based fuel log I keep for my car(s) to a dedicated Java-based
form on my&amp;nbsp;phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay&amp;nbsp;tuned&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="android"></category><category term="g1"></category><category term="google"></category></entry></feed>