<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/gige.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://newblog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2008-02-26T11:32:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>February 26, 2008</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2008/02/february-26-2008/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-02-26T11:32:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2008-02-26:2008/02/february-26-2008/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, while I haven&amp;#8217;t made much progress on anything interesting -
mainly my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NMS&lt;/span&gt; comparison or any of my other projects - due to my busy
schedule, I did get an hour or two to clean up my network at the
apartment, swapping out my 24-port Linksys switch in my room for the
5-port Netgear previously used for printing. I threw all of the printers
and the print server on their own &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VLAN&lt;/span&gt; on the main 3com&amp;nbsp;switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve also started thinking more about &lt;a href="http://www.mythtv.org/"&gt;MythTV&lt;/a&gt; -
I use it for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; in my room (feeding a grossly insufficient 21&amp;#8221; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CRT&lt;/span&gt;
monitor), and my roommate has a Dell &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GX270&lt;/span&gt; by the big &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; in the living
room, though it was running Freevo (and now has a dead tuner and no &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt;,
or something like that). So, I decided that I might do things right -
drop a 5- or 8-port GigE switch in the apartment, put GigE NICs in the
two boxes with tuners (putting MythTV on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GX270&lt;/span&gt; also), and setting up
a centralized system. The problem is that the ideal solution would be a
single dedicated back-end system for storage and control, with the two
tuner/video out boxes just providing A/V I/O. Unfortunately, the two
boxes with tuners are both high-spec&amp;#8217;ed P4&amp;#8217;s, and I&amp;#8217;m not sure what I
can come up with in terms of a server for the&amp;nbsp;backend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, &lt;em&gt;the question for anyone who may be
reading&lt;/em&gt; - I&amp;#8217;d like to setup a good amount (1-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;2TB&lt;/span&gt;) of storage for
this. My roommate wants a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAID&lt;/span&gt; configuration, but I don&amp;#8217;t see the need
for videos - if I lose my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; recordings, I set MythTV to record it again
the next time it&amp;#8217;s on. Anyway, I have an 8-bay external &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCAI&lt;/span&gt; enclosure
and cards in all of the servers, but &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCSI&lt;/span&gt; disks are expensive. I was
thinking of going to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SATA&lt;/span&gt; 3.0. Most likely, I&amp;#8217;d get some sort of 4-8
disk enclosure, start with 1-3 disks in the 400-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;750GB&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the question - what type of system specs would be needed to stream
audio and video, uncompressed, perhaps even &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDTV&lt;/span&gt; (we have the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; and
cable box, would just need an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HD&lt;/span&gt; tuner) to remote storage over the
network? I was thinking of doing either a Linux master MythTV backend
with eSATA cards, or letting each &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; computer be its&amp;#8217; own backend, and
then doing Solaris/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ZFS&lt;/span&gt; with iSCSI or ATAoE. Any suggestions? I&amp;#8217;m pretty
much thinking of using a PowerEdge 2550 for&amp;nbsp;this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&amp;#8217;m also filling up my backup disks at home, and don&amp;#8217;t want to
shorten my expiration cycle. My nightly backup runs put quite a strain
on my main Fast Ethernet &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;, so I&amp;#8217;ve been planning for a while on
moving to GigE. My thought at home is to setup a second, separate GigE
switch/lan, with GigE NICs in all of the servers. Not exactly cheap, but
I can pickup a Linux-/Solaris-compatible Negear &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GA311&lt;/span&gt; for around $40, in
addition to the Intel Pro/1000 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XT&lt;/span&gt; and Asante GigaNIC that I already
have. The problem here is finding a good GigE switch - I&amp;#8217;d really like
something with Telnet, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SNMP&lt;/span&gt;, VLANs, the&amp;nbsp;works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, I highly recommend reading the &lt;a href="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20080221184924826"&gt;Groklaw story on
Microsoft&amp;#8217;s latest pledge for
interoperability&lt;/a&gt;.
I especially liked the one quote from the &lt;a href="http://www.ecis.eu/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ECIS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years now, Microsoft has either failed to implement or has
actively corrupted a range of truly open standards adopted and
implemented by the rest of the industry. Unless and until that
behaviour stops, today&amp;#8217;s words mean&amp;nbsp;nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More fundamentally, today&amp;#8217;s announcement is still all about the rest
of the world interoperating with Microsoft on Microsoft&amp;#8217;s own terms,
not the other way&amp;nbsp;around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s even links to &lt;em&gt;ten&lt;/em&gt; previous Microsoft statements promising&amp;nbsp;interoperability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, this is a promise to interoperate with old-fashioned
competitors. It doesn&amp;#8217;t enable interoperability with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;, which is
not compatible with patent licenses, and that is Microsoft&amp;#8217;s true&amp;nbsp;competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Michael Cunningham, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VP&lt;/span&gt; and General Counsel of Red&amp;nbsp;Hat:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eight years ago the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;U.S.&lt;/span&gt; regulatory authorities, and four years ago
the European regulators made clear to Microsoft that its refusal to
disclose interface information for its monopoly software products
violates the law. So, it is hardly surprising to see even Microsoft
state today that “interoperability across systems is an important
requirement” and announce a “change in [its] approach to
interoperability.” Of course, we’ve heard similar announcements
before, almost always strategically timed for other effect. Red Hat
regards this most recent announcement with a healthy dose of
skepticism. Three commitments by Microsoft would show that it really
means what it is announcing&amp;nbsp;today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit to open standards: Rather than pushing forward its
    proprietary, Windows-based formats for document processing, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt;,
    Microsoft should embrace the existing &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt;-approved, cross-platform
    industry standard for document processing, Open Document Format
    (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ODF&lt;/span&gt;) at the International Standards Organization’s meeting next
    week in Geneva. Microsoft, please demonstrate implementation of an
    existing international open standard now rather than make press
    announcements about intentions of future standards&amp;nbsp;support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit to interoperability with open source: Instead of offering a
    patent license for its protocol information on the basis of
    licensing arrangements it knows are incompatible with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt; –
    the world’s most widely used open source software license –
    Microsoft should extend its Open Specification Promise to all of
    the interoperability information that it is announcing today will
    be made available. The Open Specification Promise already covers
    many Microsoft products that do not have monopoly market
    positions. If Microsoft were truly committed to fostering openness
    and preventing customer lock-in, it would extend this promise to
    the protocol and interface information it intends to disclose
    today. There is no explanation for refusing to extend the Open
    Specification Promise to “high-volume” products, other than a
    continued intention on Microsoft’s part to lock customers into its
    monopoly products, and lock out competitors through patent&amp;nbsp;threats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit to competition on a level playing field: Microsoft’s
    announcement today appears carefully crafted to foreclose
    competition from the open source community. How else can you
    explain a “promise not to sue open source developers” as long as
    they develop and distribute only*/ “non-commercial”
    implementations of interoperable products? This is simply
    disingenuous. The only hope for reintroducing competition to the
    monopoly markets Microsoft now controls – Windows, Office, etc. –
    is through commercial distributions of competitive open source
    software&amp;nbsp;products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amen!!!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="GigE"></category><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="mythtv"></category><category term="sata"></category><category term="storage"></category></entry></feed>