<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/google.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2012-10-24T12:01:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Random Links for Wednesday, October 24th</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/10/random-links-for-wednesday-october-24th/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-24T12:01:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-10-24:2012/10/random-links-for-wednesday-october-24th/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some random interesting links from Slashdot for&amp;nbsp;today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.slashdot.org/story/12/10/23/2038220/the-greatest-battle-of-the-personal-computing-revolution-lies-ahead"&gt;The Greatest Battle of the Personal Computing Revolution Lies Ahead
    -
    Slashdot&lt;/a&gt;.
    A bit of a rant, but makes some good points that are close to my
    heart, and unfortunately far from the thoughts of many&amp;nbsp;non-techies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://tos-dr.info/"&gt;Terms of Service; Didn&amp;#8217;t Read&lt;/a&gt; - an
    interesting&amp;nbsp;project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://yro.slashdot.org/story/12/10/21/208206/how-patent-trolls-harm-the-economy"&gt;How Patent Trolls Harm the Economy -
    Slashdot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;another issue close to my&amp;nbsp;heart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.datacenterknowledge.com/archives/2012/10/17/how-google-cools-its-armada-of-servers/"&gt;How Google Cools Its Armada of Servers » Data Center&amp;nbsp;Knowledge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/about/datacenters/gallery/#/"&gt;Data centers – Google Data
    centers&lt;/a&gt; - A
    photo tour of Google data centers, by Google, along with a &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/+google/posts/Gk8ScjPX23n"&gt;Google+
    post&lt;/a&gt; about the
    architecture photographer who did this&amp;nbsp;work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://tech.slashdot.org/story/12/10/22/0518231/darpa-funds-a-300-software-defined-radio-for-hackers"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DARPA&lt;/span&gt; Funds a $300 Software-Defined Radio For Hackers -
    Slashdot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;way&amp;nbsp;cool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://map.honeynet.org/"&gt;Honeynet Map&lt;/a&gt; - &amp;#8220;realtime&amp;#8221; map of
    cybersecurity incidents, from the Honeynet&amp;nbsp;Project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://science.slashdot.org/story/12/10/17/1741225/malware-is-rampant-on-medical-devices-in-hospitals"&gt;Malware Is &amp;#8216;Rampant&amp;#8217; On Medical Devices In Hospitals -
    Slashdot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a bit scary, but unfortunately not that hard to guess. I&amp;#8217;ve seen
(probably unpatched) Windows 2000 workstations on hospital&amp;nbsp;networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To top off the scary posts: &lt;a href="http://news.slashdot.org/story/12/10/17/0325236/researcher-reverse-engineers-pacemaker-transmitter-to-deliver-deadly-shocks"&gt;Researcher Reverse-Engineers Pacemaker
    Transmitter To Deliver Deadly Shocks -&amp;nbsp;Slashdot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="appliancization"></category><category term="cooling"></category><category term="datacenter"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="healthcare"></category><category term="legal"></category><category term="links"></category><category term="malware"></category><category term="pacemaker"></category><category term="patents"></category><category term="radio"></category><category term="SDR"></category><category term="security"></category></entry><entry><title>Some Thoughts on Choosing a New Wordpress Theme</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/03/some-thoughts-on-choosing-a-new-wordpress-theme/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-17T11:48:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-03-17:2012/03/some-thoughts-on-choosing-a-new-wordpress-theme/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;#8217;m going to choose a new theme for my blog. The current theme
is &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/themes/inove"&gt;iNove&lt;/a&gt; (albeit an older
version with some custom modifications), and I feel like it looks a bit
messy and has gotten a bit cluttered, so it&amp;#8217;s time to find something
new. I like the 2-column layout, and have a few other things I&amp;#8217;m looking
for - specifically, aside from something with advanced features like
lots of widget support and hooks, something that has good visual
separation between different posts and widgets. I also really want
something, if possible, with relative column widths. My current home and
work desktops both have dual monitors, and the minimum resolution I have
on one screen is 1920x1080. When I look at my blog in a maximized
window, about half the screen width is wasted with empty space. So,
ideally, I&amp;#8217;d like a theme that&amp;#8217;s based on relative widths, probably with
a &amp;#8220;min-width&amp;#8221; property so it wouldn&amp;#8217;t get compressed to an absurdly
narrow width on small&amp;nbsp;screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/"&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt; (as noted in
the &lt;a href="/privacy-policy/"&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;) for visitor statistics on this
blog (more about that in a moment). So, I took a peek at the breakdown
of visitors by screen resolution, and saw that for the past year, 94% of
the 27,500 visits had a screen width of 1024px or more (and the majority
of the others looked like mobile device resolutions, so they&amp;#8217;d probably
zoom the page correctly). So, my first gut reaction was to assume that I
could use a theme approximately 1000px wide. Unfortunately, there&amp;#8217;s two
main problems with that: first, as mentioned by &lt;a href="http://css-tricks.com/screen-resolution-notequalto-browser-window/"&gt;Chris Coyier on
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;-Tricks.com&lt;/a&gt;,
just because someone has a given screen resolution doesn&amp;#8217;t mean their
browser window (let alone the viewport) is that size. As a matter of
fact, I usually have my main browser window set at about 80% of the
width of one of my monitors, with my instant messaging client
&lt;a href="http://pidgin.im/"&gt;Pidgin&lt;/a&gt; taking up the rest of the space. So there&amp;#8217;s
one inaccuracy. There&amp;#8217;s a potentially much greater inaccuracy in my
stats as well, which I&amp;#8217;m going to discuss in a &lt;a href="/2012/03/inaccuracies-in-google-analytics-for-website-stats/"&gt;separate
post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="analysis"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="blog"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="logging"></category><category term="stats"></category><category term="theme"></category><category term="wordpress"></category></entry><entry><title>Inaccuracies in Google Analytics for Website Stats</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/03/inaccuracies-in-google-analytics-for-website-stats/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-17T11:46:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-03-17:2012/03/inaccuracies-in-google-analytics-for-website-stats/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I use Google Analytics for visitor stats on this blog. Not because I&amp;#8217;m
trying to direct-market to my readers or become Big Brother, but for a
number of simple&amp;nbsp;reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#8217;s simple - no software for me to update, and nothing that needs
    to run on my server and read through giant log files every night.
    Google does it all for&amp;nbsp;me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gives a lot more information than I can get from just web server&amp;nbsp;logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because of Google&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;big brother&amp;#8221; tracking, and the vast number of
    sites that they track people on, I can tell things I&amp;#8217;d have no other
    way of knowing, like how long someone stayed on my&amp;nbsp;page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They tell me &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt; stats like which search keywords brought the
    most people to my site and which posts are the most popular, which I
    keep in mind when writing new stuff and updating older&amp;nbsp;posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They tell me information about client operating system and browser
    version, which I think tells quite a bit about my&amp;nbsp;audience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As far as I know, they&amp;#8217;re pretty good at filtering out anything
    other than an actual human&amp;nbsp;visitor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They tell me stats that have no real use to me, but are just cook -
    like what countries my visitors are from, what type of Internet
    connection they&amp;#8217;re on, their screen resolution,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously not for google, but for me, all of these stats are totally
anonymous - I just get percentages or numbers of visits, it&amp;#8217;s not like I
can see all of the details per-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; address. The most important aspect to
me is just the ease of use - I sign up and put a little snippet of code
on my pages, and I get an amazing dashboard interface with all of this
information. Nothing to install and update on my server, and (most
importantly, since I&amp;#8217;m now running everything of mine on one virtualized
server) no massive program to run as a cron job that has to read all my
server log&amp;nbsp;files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I was talking with a couple of my co-workers, specifically
about the stats that I get from Google Analytics. While I know it&amp;#8217;s not
uncommon to run &lt;a href="http://noscript.net/"&gt;NoScript&lt;/a&gt; especially among the
more security- and privacy-conscious groups of people, I was a bit
disturbed to hear that they all block Google&amp;#8217;s tracking code in their
browsers via NoScript. I assume there&amp;#8217;s also a percentage of people who
still just turn off JavaScript alltogether (although I can&amp;#8217;t imagine how
they use the modern Web), and many who use the &lt;a href="http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en"&gt;Google Analytics
Opt-Out&lt;/a&gt; feature. So,
especially with as technical an audience as I have, I guess that means
I&amp;#8217;m likely missing a large number of visitors in my stats. On one hand,
I want to respect the privacy of my visitors, and respect their desire
to opt-out of advanced tracking. On the other hand, since I no longer
parse web server logs for statistics, these privacy-conscious visitors
aren&amp;#8217;t even showing up in what I think of as my monthly visit count, or
in my information on what posts and search keywords are most popular,
which I only use for &amp;#8220;good&amp;#8221; purposes - to make my blog more useful. So
that&amp;#8217;s a bit of a&amp;nbsp;conundrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll admit that I do run &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/adsense/"&gt;Google AdSense
Ads&lt;/a&gt; on my blog, and I&amp;#8217;m sure there are
some people who block the ads. On one hand, that upsets me a bit; I run
this blog to try and share information that I find or learn with others,
and the hosting costs aren&amp;#8217;t insignificant. If I can get paid to just
show some ads, to try and help offset the cost of running the site, I
think that&amp;#8217;s good. And if other people can help support the site by just
letting the ads stay on the page, why not? On the other hand, my hosting
costs $50/month (granted the server also handles all of my email, and a
&lt;em&gt;whole bunch&lt;/em&gt; of other sites). I&amp;#8217;ve been participating in Google AdSense
since March 5, 2010 (two years and two weeks), and my &amp;#8220;estimated
earnings&amp;#8221; are currently $80. The payout is in $100 increments. So, I
haven&amp;#8217;t seen a cent from it in two years, so I&amp;#8217;ve given up being
concerned with it. If you want to be nice, and find my posts
interesting, click on one of the ads. Unfortunately, unless I get
famous, the ads aren&amp;#8217;t going to come close to offsetting even part of
the cost of running the&amp;nbsp;site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google itself
&lt;a href="http://support.google.com/googleanalytics/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=55610"&gt;says&lt;/a&gt;,
&amp;#8220;In order for Google Analytics to record a visit, the visitor must have
JavaScript, images, and cookies enabled for your website.&amp;#8221; There seems
to be some buzz about this on the &amp;#8216;net, and I&amp;#8217;ve seen
&lt;a href="http://garmahis.com/tips/google-analytics/#use-Google-Analytics-without-JavaScript"&gt;a&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://djangosnippets.org/snippets/2338/"&gt;number&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://translate.google.com/translate?hl=en&amp;amp;sl=nl&amp;amp;u=http://andrescholten.nl/google-analytics-zonder-javascript/"&gt;of&lt;/a&gt;
(translated; &lt;a href="http://andrescholten.nl/google-analytics-zonder-javascript/"&gt;original post in
Dutch&lt;/a&gt;)
posts advocating building a request to a Google Analytics &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GIF&lt;/span&gt; manually
on the server side, and then including it as an image element inside a
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;noscript&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag in the page. While this is probably one of the nicer
solutions (and much more likely to reduce double-counting), it doesn&amp;#8217;t
capture any of the advanced data (screen resolution, etc.) that
JavaScript-based Analytics does, and more importantly, I imagine that
many of the Ad blocking extensions also block traffic to
google-analytics.com, so this is an incremental improvement at best.
There are also
&lt;a href="http://www.vdgraaf.info/google-analytics-without-javascript.html"&gt;quite&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://blog.datalicious.com/google-analytics-without-javascript-rss-xml-e"&gt;a&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://blogs.walkerart.org/newmedia/2009/11/12/building-walkers-mobile-site-google-analytics-without-javascript-pt2/"&gt;few&lt;/a&gt;
posts about how to make a request to Analytics purely server-side. This
has a few disadvantages as well; it bypasses the google domain
blacklisting problem that the client-side image has, but it also means
you lose the client &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; address (and therefore geolocation), and that you
double-track any user who allows javascript (so you need a separate
profile, and then need to average out the results). It also means that
you track every search engine and bot that crawls your site, and
possibly every person who clicks a link and then hits &amp;#8220;back&amp;#8221; before the
page finishes loading. I found another blogger who &lt;a href="http://www.realityburst.com/battle-of-the-inaccuracies-how-accurate-is-google-analyticsawstatsstatpress"&gt;commented
about&lt;/a&gt;
the wide disparity he saw between Google Analytics, the
&lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/statpress/"&gt;StatsPress&lt;/a&gt; WordPress
plugin, and &lt;a href="http://awstats.sourceforge.net/"&gt;AWstats&lt;/a&gt; (a server-side
log file&amp;nbsp;analyzer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;solution?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the options have a down side, but I&amp;#8217;m looking for something
that&amp;#8217;s the best I can reasonably do. As much as I&amp;#8217;d rather not, I&amp;#8217;m
going to look into self-hosted alternatives to Google Analytics (a
self-hosted JavaScript-based stats provider), in the hopes that NoScript
users will be more friendly to scripts coming from my own domain, and
sending requests to my own domain, than ones from Google or other major
trackers. I don&amp;#8217;t think I want to try anything that parses web server
logs as a primary approach, as I don&amp;#8217;t think I could ever get a
meaningful comparison to Google Analytics or something else&amp;nbsp;JavaScript-based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did have one other idea which I think is interesting, though a bit of
an overhead. I could have Apache (or, more likely, a Perl script called
in the Apache configuration) generate a random string for each request,
and save it in an Apache environment variable. The environment variable
would then be added to a field in the server logs, and also added (via
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; or whatever else generates the pages server-side) as a custom
parameter for the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JS&lt;/span&gt; tracking code, enabling page hits to be correlated
between the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JS&lt;/span&gt; tracking and the server logs. Assuming the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JS&lt;/span&gt; tacking
backend stores its data in a sane format (and as raw data, not just
aggregated), and at the cost of a serious performance penalty, a
server-side statistics program like
&lt;a href="http://awstats.sourceforge.net/"&gt;AWstats&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href="http://www.webalizer.org/"&gt;Webalizer&lt;/a&gt; could be patched to lookup the
unique identifier in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JS&lt;/span&gt; stats data store, and ignore all hits which
were tracked that&amp;nbsp;way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m going to start by looking into self-hosted open source alternatives
to Google Analytics, which I&amp;#8217;ll post about sometime hopefully&amp;nbsp;soon.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="analytics"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="logging"></category><category term="statistics"></category><category term="stats"></category></entry><entry><title>Android 2.0.1 update</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/12/android-2-0-1-update/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-12-10T19:52:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-12-10:2009/12/android-2-0-1-update/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, I updated my Droid to Android 2.0.1 today. I&amp;#8217;ll be honest that it
didn&amp;#8217;t work the way I&amp;#8217;d hoped. When I woke up this morning (December
10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; 2009) I had an alert dialog on screen telling me that an update
was ready. It gave me three options: &amp;#8220;Install Now&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;Install Later&amp;#8221; and
&amp;#8220;More Info&amp;#8221;. The More Info screen didn&amp;#8217;t show me anything useful. Well,
I clicked the &amp;#8220;Later&amp;#8221; option, figuring that when I got home tonight I&amp;#8217;d
turn on WiFi, do a packet capture on the router, and save all of the
traffic (specifically including the name of the update server). Well, it
kept reminding me all day at annoyingly short intervals - probably about
every 10 minutes or so. Finally, when I was home and had the WiFi setup,
I went to try it again and&amp;#8230; yup&amp;#8230; when I clicked on the &amp;#8220;System
Update&amp;#8221; button in Settings, the only option I had was &amp;#8220;Reboot and&amp;nbsp;Install&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So&amp;#8230; first big bitch about the Droid&amp;#8230; Verizon pushed out the update
without my consent. I kept hitting &amp;#8220;Later&amp;#8221; because that was the only way
to get the popup to go away. Apparently. after X times of hitting Later
(and each time your only real options are Later or Now) it will download
the update by itself. Once the update is downloaded, I&amp;#8217;m assuming that
it &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; just automatically install on the next reboot. That would be
a bitch thing to&amp;nbsp;do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the &amp;#8220;More Info&amp;#8221; screen, which provides (as far as I can tell)
the only release notes for the update,&amp;nbsp;states:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This software update includes enhancements to your &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DROID&lt;/span&gt; by Motorola.
Approximate install time: 6-10 Mins. You will be unable to use your
device or make emergency calls for the duration of the install. The
software updates automatically, and your &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DROID&lt;/span&gt; will power off and on
as part of this software update. For more information please visit:
&lt;a href="www.verizonwireless.com/droidsupport"&gt;www.verizonwireless.com/droidsupport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not too helpful. And pretty&amp;nbsp;cryptic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immediately when the phone turned back on, the first thing I noticed is
that the spin-style unlock button has been replaced with an iPhone-style
slide button, and the same for the mute feature. Maybe it&amp;#8217;s just me, but
I also noticed that the on screen keyboard seems to react better to
quick keypresses - perhaps they&amp;#8217;ve enabled multitouch for&amp;nbsp;this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I wasn&amp;#8217;t able to find much release documentation from
Google other than the &lt;a href="http://developer.android.com/sdk/android-2.0.1.html"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt;
changes&lt;/a&gt; - no full
release notes or changelog like I&amp;#8217;d like. And not even a summary of
changes that I could&amp;nbsp;find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VZW&lt;/span&gt; droid support site, I found a &lt;a href="http://learning.verizonwireless.com/learning/Droid_Motorola_Software_Update.pdf"&gt;link to a
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
of &amp;#8220;Why to Update&amp;#8221; (&lt;a href="/GFX/Droid_Motorola_Software_Update.pdf"&gt;local
copy&lt;/a&gt;).
This sheet lists the enhancements made by the update
(&amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AP&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ESD56&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;BP&lt;/span&gt;:C_01.3E.01P&amp;#8221;, build &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ESD56&lt;/span&gt;)&amp;nbsp;as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; stability is&amp;nbsp;improved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Battery life is&amp;nbsp;improved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camera auto focus functionality is improved, and time between shots
    is&amp;nbsp;reduced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhancements for three-way&amp;nbsp;calling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audio for incoming calls is&amp;nbsp;improved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When receiving a call on call waiting, the speakerphone now remains&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bluetooth functionality is improved; background echo is&amp;nbsp;eliminated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved Bluetooth phone book transfer of contacts to in-vehicle
    Bluetooth&amp;nbsp;solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After closing a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; application, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; icon will now automatically
    be removed from the notification&amp;nbsp;panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users can now receive &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MMS&lt;/span&gt; messages after an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMS&lt;/span&gt; message is&amp;nbsp;received.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MMS&lt;/span&gt; may now be sent to seven-digit&amp;nbsp;addresses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google contact merging has been updated to accommodate seven-digit&amp;nbsp;numbers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual Voice Mail notices now arrive&amp;nbsp;instantaneously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The corporate calendar widget user interface is&amp;nbsp;updated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tiny one-page (and very styish - looks like and in-store
advertising piece) sheet obviously isn&amp;#8217;t anything that could pass for
release notes, especially from Google. It doesn&amp;#8217;t even mention anything
about the changed unlock&amp;nbsp;button!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll keep looking around to find a real feature summary/release
notes/changelog, but here&amp;#8217;s my running list (I&amp;#8217;ll update) of what I&amp;#8217;ve&amp;nbsp;found:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the unlock slider to a straight&amp;nbsp;line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On screen keyboard typing seems&amp;nbsp;faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photo taking &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; considerably faster, though it&amp;#8217;s still painfully
    slow - it used to take about 10 seconds from shutter button to ready
    to capture next image, it&amp;#8217;s now about 5&amp;nbsp;seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UI&lt;/span&gt; seems to be a bit more responsive&amp;nbsp;overall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I haven&amp;#8217;t checked yet, but I&amp;#8217;ve seen some forum posts about lost
    contacts and Facebook sync&amp;nbsp;issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="android"></category><category term="droid"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="motorola"></category><category term="verizon"></category></entry><entry><title>Using Google Maps to produce usable, printable maps</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/12/using-google-maps-to-produce-usable-printable-maps/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-12-01T14:11:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-12-01:2009/12/using-google-maps-to-produce-usable-printable-maps/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a follow-up to my &lt;a href="/2009/11/making-maps-from-gis-data-with-inkscape/"&gt;Making maps from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GIS&lt;/span&gt; data with
Inkscape&lt;/a&gt; post. After
playing around with Inkscape for quite a while, and coming up with the
dismal results seen in that post, I decided there has to be an easier
way. A little Googling turned up &lt;a href="http://www.wipeout44.com/video/misc/google_maps_large.asp"&gt;this video
tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on
how to print large scale maps from Google Maps. It turns out that the
Google Maps &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; will honor almost any pixel resolution that it&amp;#8217;s passed.
The &lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/1146"&gt;Screengrab&lt;/a&gt;
add-on for Firefox has the wonderful capability of being able to capture
a screengrab of page content, at actual resolution, regardless of screen
resolution. So load up a 5000x5000 pixel Google Map, use the Screengrab
addon, and end up with a full 5000x5000 pixel image&amp;nbsp;file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After testing this a bit, I decided to go the Google Maps route. This
also has a lot of other added bonuses - I can store my overlay data in
simple &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt; files, add and remove layers on-the-fly, and also make it
available online (and, theoretically, to any Google Maps-equipped device
used by responders). This even opens up the possibility of using paper
maps as a last resort, and providing the Fire Department with live
hydrant maps on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;-enabled handheld devices and&amp;nbsp;phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quirks, however, may need some serious photoshopping (err, rather,
&lt;a href="http://www.gimp.org/"&gt;gimp&lt;/a&gt;ing) to&amp;nbsp;fix:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With all of the background color, how will this look when&amp;nbsp;printed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I make the town borders easily defined? It would be a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt;
    of raster editing to remove the background color of areas outside of&amp;nbsp;town.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I overlay a grid for a street name&amp;nbsp;index?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step was to setup a large Google Map to develop with. I used
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; and Monte Ohrt&amp;#8217;s
&lt;a href="http://www.phpinsider.com/php/code/GoogleMapAPI/"&gt;GoogleMapAPI&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;
wrapper class. It was simple enough to setup a big (3300x5100px) map,
zoom out in Firefox, and start adding some stuff. My examples and
development pages, if you want to take a peek at the code, are available
in &lt;a href="/GFX/googleMaps.tar.gz"&gt;googleMaps.tar.gz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step was to draw a polygon for the outline of the town. I
found some very detailed information on how to get zip code boundary
lines on Matt Cutts&amp;#8217;
&lt;a href="http://www.mattcutts.com/blog/fun-with-zip-codes/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;. Apparently,
he&amp;#8217;s a Google software engineer, heading up their webspam team. I
grabbed the files from the Census, as described, and came up with the
boundary for my zip code looking&amp;nbsp;like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;        60      -0.741427638843858E+02       0.409963180802469E+02
      -0.741375870000000E+02       0.410075970000000E+02
      -0.741308870000000E+02       0.410061970000000E+02
      -0.741308870000000E+02       0.410061970000000E+02
      -0.741307260000000E+02       0.410032600000000E+02
      -0.741326870000000E+02       0.409955970000000E+02
      -0.741278870000000E+02       0.409943970000000E+02
      -0.741280870000000E+02       0.409938970000000E+02
      -0.741327870000000E+02       0.409853970000000E+02
      -0.741352870000000E+02       0.409830970000000E+02
      -0.741369600000000E+02       0.409818620000000E+02
      -0.741410520000000E+02       0.409821940000000E+02
      -0.741412870000000E+02       0.409826970000000E+02
      -0.741412870000000E+02       0.409826970000000E+02
      -0.741417870000000E+02       0.409847970000000E+02
      -0.741427870000000E+02       0.409863970000000E+02
      -0.741482870000000E+02       0.409868970000000E+02
      -0.741536880000000E+02       0.409899970000000E+02
      -0.741510880000000E+02       0.409929970000000E+02
      -0.741531880000000E+02       0.409965970000000E+02
      -0.741571880000000E+02       0.409988970000000E+02
      -0.741557880000000E+02       0.410013970000000E+02
      -0.741461870000000E+02       0.410018970000000E+02
      -0.741400870000000E+02       0.410065970000000E+02
      -0.741375870000000E+02       0.410075970000000E+02
END
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As per Matt&amp;#8217;s instructions, I stripped off the first and last lines,
converted everything to normal decimal notation, and built it into a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;array:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary = array();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.137587, 41.007597);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.130887, 41.006197);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.130887, 41.006197);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.130726, 41.003260);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.132687, 40.995597);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.127887, 40.994397);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.128087, 40.993897);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.132787, 40.985397);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.135287, 40.983097);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.136960, 40.981862);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.141052, 40.982194);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.141287, 40.982697);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.141287, 40.982697);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.141787, 40.984797);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.142787, 40.986397);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.148287, 40.986897);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.153688, 40.989997);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.151088, 40.992997);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.153188, 40.996597);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.157188, 40.998897);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.155788, 41.001397);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.146187, 41.001897);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.140087, 41.006597);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;$MP_boundary[] = array(-74.137587, 41.007597);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Though this data doesn&amp;#8217;t seem exactly 100% accurate (at least by my
knowledge of the town, and every map I can find) it&amp;#8217;s quite close and a
very good&amp;nbsp;start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll update later this week when I have some more&amp;nbsp;done&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="catrography"></category><category term="emergency"></category><category term="EMS"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="maps"></category><category term="PHP"></category></entry><entry><title>Android links - maps, dial a phone number</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/11/android-links-maps-dial-a-phone-number/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-22T10:25:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-11-22:2009/11/android-links-maps-dial-a-phone-number/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;ve used Google search from an Android device to search for a
business, you&amp;#8217;ve probably noticed the two interesting &amp;#8220;buttons&amp;#8221; to the
right of the search listing - &amp;#8220;Get Directions&amp;#8221; and a button for the
phone number. It turns out, these are pretty easy to&amp;nbsp;implement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;#8220;Get Directions&amp;#8221; link is a simple link to &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com"&gt;Google
Maps&lt;/a&gt; like &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?daddr=42+Pierce+Ave,+Midland+Park,+NJ+07432"&gt;This
One&lt;/a&gt;.
The links are actually pretty&amp;nbsp;simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;http://maps.google.com/maps?daddr=42+Pierce+Ave%2C+Midland+Park%2C+&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NJ&lt;/span&gt;+07432&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Get Directions&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It just uses a regular Google Maps &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;, with the destination address
encoded. When the link is clicked in the Android browser, a dialog pops
up asking the user whether he wants to open it with the browser or the
Maps application. If Maps is selected, it automatically opens with the
address from the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; in the destination input box, the phone&amp;#8217;s current
location as the start input, and gives easy access to directions and&amp;nbsp;navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The telephone links are a bit more interesting. Apparently, the Android
browser uses the Phone app to handle the &amp;#8220;tel&amp;#8221; scheme, as defined by
&lt;a href="http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc3966"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RFC&lt;/span&gt; 3966&lt;/a&gt;.Therefore, clicking a
link&amp;nbsp;like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="na"&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;tel:2015555555&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;201-555-5555&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;on Android will bring up the Phone app and pre-enter the digits for
2015555555. Luckily, it doesn&amp;#8217;t automatically dial the number. If you
want to give it a try and are using Android:
&lt;a href="tel:2015555555"&gt;201-555-5555&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final step is how to implement this. I don&amp;#8217;t know if most mobile
browsers (Blackberry? iPhone?) also support the &amp;#8220;tel&amp;#8221; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URI&lt;/span&gt; scheme, or how
they&amp;#8217;ll handle Google Maps links. But if you&amp;#8217;re looking to include
Android-specific content, the user agent string from my Motorola Droid
(Android 2.0) looks&amp;nbsp;like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Mozilla/5.0 (Linux; U;Android 2.0; en-us; Droid Build/ESD20) AppleWebKit/530.17 (KHTML, like Gecko) Version/4.0 Mobile Safari/530.17
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I know that there are a number of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; classes out there to detect
browsers (like &lt;a href="http://chrisschuld.com/projects/browser-php-detecting-a-users-browser-from-php/"&gt;Chris Schuld&amp;#8217;s
browser.php&lt;/a&gt;)
and some things to detect mobile device capabilities (like
&lt;a href="http://wurfl.sourceforge.net/nphp/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;WURFL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://freshmeat.net/projects/tera_wurfl/"&gt;Tera
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;WURFL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, both using the
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wurfl"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;WURFL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; data). However, if you just
need to know whether your user is on Android or not, I&amp;#8217;d personally
recommend just checking the user agent string for &amp;#8220;Linux&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;Android&amp;#8221; and
&amp;#8220;WebKit&amp;#8221; until a better browser identification system is found, as these
are not likely to change in the near&amp;nbsp;future.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="android"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="html"></category></entry><entry><title>Weekend of Code (Android)</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/11/weekend-of-code-android/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-12T01:35:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-11-12:2009/11/weekend-of-code-android/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Droid is here (literally, sitting in my pocket), and I have the next
two days off of work - plus the weekend. Minus personal commitments,
that&amp;#8217;s about two full (call it 16 hour) days to get some work done.
While I have lots of things that could use my attention - a number of
neglected projects, my big new PHPsa project, and some server
consolidation at home - I&amp;#8217;ve decided to dedicate the time to Android&amp;nbsp;development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve got the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ADK&lt;/span&gt; installed and running, and the emulator is wonderful
(especially with the Droid skin). And I know it&amp;#8217;s wrong, but I think I&amp;#8217;m
going to be developing the first app for Android 2.0 (especially given
the new
&lt;a href="http://developer.android.com/reference/android/provider/ContactsContract.html"&gt;ContactsContract&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; in&amp;nbsp;5).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m having a few issues with &lt;a href="http://subclipse.tigris.org/"&gt;Subclipse&lt;/a&gt;,
even on the latest OpenSuSE 11.1, and still have a few things I want to
do on the phone&amp;#8230; but hopefully I&amp;#8217;ll have a beta build of the app by
the end of the weekend. I&amp;#8217;ve already done most of the data modeling and
sketched out the&amp;nbsp;storyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not going to say much about what the app is until it&amp;#8217;s ready, but
it&amp;#8217;s something targeted at people like me - SysAdmins with way too many
things on their plate for their number of waking&amp;nbsp;hours.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="android"></category><category term="google"></category></entry><entry><title>Droid!</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/11/droid/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-11-10T08:46:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-11-10:2009/11/droid/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t like writing posts with a low useful content quotient, but here&amp;nbsp;goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having only one new (i.e. not used) phone in eight years - and the
one new one was a Treo 700p, obsolete when I bought it - I decided to
bite the bullet. I bought a Droid! While I was almost dead-set on it
before I even held it in the store, my feelings of love at first sight
were even more clear when I started to play around with&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here&amp;#8217;s a little overview of what I did first, what my
plans/questions are, and what&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First&amp;nbsp;minutes/day:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unpack everything and start to figure things out. Test phone, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;,&amp;nbsp;data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IMAP&lt;/span&gt; email for my personal account (need to look into&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IMAP&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IDLE&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go through the entire Settings menu and try to set things up. Find
    out that the default apps can&amp;#8217;t be removed. The app screen, by
    default, is pretty&amp;nbsp;full&amp;#8230;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Export my contacts from my Palm (no sync cable, had to use
    &lt;a href="http://php-pdb.sourceforge.net/"&gt;php-pdb&lt;/a&gt; to export a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSV&lt;/span&gt;, then
    manually edit &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ALL&lt;/span&gt; of them in&amp;nbsp;Gmail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after having the phone for about 12 hours, here&amp;#8217;s what I&amp;#8217;ve installed
on&amp;nbsp;it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen (Google Labs)&lt;/strong&gt; - Great podcatcher app. The speaker is a
    bit too quiet for easy listening on the drive to work, so I&amp;#8217;ll need
    to get one of those &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FM&lt;/span&gt; radio&amp;nbsp;interfaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AnyCut&lt;/strong&gt; - allows creation of arbitrary shortcuts on the desktop,
    including direct&amp;nbsp;dial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ConnectBot&lt;/strong&gt; - full-featured &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; client including key-based auth
    and storage of multiple user/host&amp;nbsp;settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meebo &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IM&lt;/span&gt; client. It does &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AIM&lt;/span&gt;, which is nice, but doesn&amp;#8217;t do&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IRC&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Android Battery Dog&lt;/strong&gt; - App that graphs battery voltage,
    temperature, capacity over time and also stores a simple &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSV&lt;/span&gt; log
    (which I intend to parse out later for historical&amp;nbsp;data).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bookmarking for Delicious&lt;/strong&gt; - Allows saving of bookmarks to
    &lt;a href="del.icio.us"&gt;del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt; (but not&amp;nbsp;retrieval).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To Do List&lt;/strong&gt; - A very simple To Do list app, until I find
    something that works with Google Tasks. No&amp;nbsp;syncing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VoiceMemo (JavaCodeLand.com)&lt;/strong&gt; - A really simple voice memo&amp;nbsp;app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WiFinder (PGMsoft)&lt;/strong&gt; - Pretty much useless. Shows a scan of WiFi
    networks, but only shows encryption, channel number, and signal
    strength in&amp;nbsp;bars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The few problems I&amp;#8217;ve noticed so&amp;nbsp;far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The touch-sensitive buttons along the bottom row (specifically the
    search button) seem to be right where my thumb wants to rest when
    holding the phone in landscape&amp;nbsp;mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As others have mentioned, the camera quality isn&amp;#8217;t great, but it&amp;#8217;s
    much better than my Treo&amp;nbsp;700p.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My list for future&amp;nbsp;research/development:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;WAP&lt;/span&gt; pages for my web-based personal finance app, fuel log,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IMAP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IDLE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tasks/to do app that syncs with Google&amp;nbsp;Tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href="http://oreilly.com/catalog/9780596007836"&gt;Cycle System&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to quickly mute all sounds on the&amp;nbsp;phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to do tones by person or group for not only ringtones (phone)
    but also &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;, Email, etc. Also, a way to set certain hours of the
    day when audible alerts will be disabled, other than a specified
    whitelist (email, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;,&amp;nbsp;etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verizon Visual&amp;nbsp;Voicemail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do some development with the geolocation &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Console on the&amp;nbsp;phone?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCP&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SFTP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; listings (perhaps a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WAP&lt;/span&gt; version of my script that pulls from
    &lt;a href="http://www.schedulesdirect.org/"&gt;SchedulesDirect&lt;/a&gt; (unfortunately,
    due to their redistribution policy, this is a private, authenticated&amp;nbsp;page).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nagios&amp;nbsp;checker/notifier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;reader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;WAP&lt;/span&gt; page for &lt;a href="http://www.php-ems-tools.com"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMS&lt;/span&gt; Tools&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;callin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to handle &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IMAP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;folders?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Script to backup Gmail contacts, other data stored with&amp;nbsp;Google.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thunderbird Gmail contact&amp;nbsp;sync.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A wifi scanner/survey software that shows all of the important stuff
    like signal strength in dbm, noise floor,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something like kismet that integrates the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; and wifi&amp;nbsp;scanning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="android"></category><category term="droid"></category><category term="google"></category></entry><entry><title>First big Android … fisaco</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/09/first-big-android-fisaco/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-09-29T08:44:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-09-29:2009/09/first-big-android-fisaco/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, I wanted to call this a $#!\^storm, but I don&amp;#8217;t think it&amp;#8217;s grown
to those proportions yet. But any new platform will have its hiccups,
and Google is relatively new to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here&amp;#8217;s the news. Google issued a legal Cease and Desist order to a
developer Steve Kondik (known as
&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/cyanogen"&gt;Cyanogen&lt;/a&gt;). The story goes something like
this&amp;#8230; Steve is an active Android developer, doing a lot of work on the
lower-level stuff (lower level than apps), including multi-touch and
more home screens. His changes are essentially at the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;-level, and
Android doesn&amp;#8217;t have a full-fledged package management/patching
mechanism like Linux distros, so making use of them requires recompiling
stuff and re-flashing the device with a new &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ROM&lt;/span&gt; image (since the
installation apps can&amp;#8217;t handle stuff this low-level). Here&amp;#8217;s the rub: in
order to work on a device, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ROM&lt;/span&gt; image needs to include both
closed-source Google apps and proprietary (device manufacturer) drivers.
While these apps and drivers are available for download, the license
terms prohibit redistribution. But in order for Steve to create a
fully-functional &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ROM&lt;/span&gt; image, he has to include the closed&amp;nbsp;code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some writeups on this at &lt;a href="http://www.linux-mag.com/cache/7544/1.html"&gt;Linux
Magazine&lt;/a&gt; and a good, timely
analysis at &lt;a href="http://www.linuxinsider.com/rsstory/68237.html?wlc=1254230361"&gt;Linux
Insider&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s also a clarification by Google&amp;#8217;s Dan Morrill on the &lt;a href="http://android-developers.blogspot.com/2009/09/note-on-google-apps-for-android.html"&gt;Android
Developers&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what&amp;#8217;s my take on all this (not that another guy taking about this
is&amp;nbsp;needed)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I think this is relatively minor. The community will work
around it, whether with Google&amp;#8217;s blessing or not. The bigger issue
that&amp;#8217;s coming to light is the fact that Google isn&amp;#8217;t simply altruistic,
they&amp;#8217;re a for-profit entity. They have every right to be, and they have
every right to exercise some amount of control over Android. The
community needs to realize that Android isn&amp;#8217;t a silver bullet, and isn&amp;#8217;t
even the Linux of the phone world. On the other hand, Google needs to
realize two important facts: 1) the openness of Android is what&amp;#8217;s
driving developers to it, and they need to do all they can to continue
that, and 2) most of those developers are flat-out used to running Linux
with an all-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt; system, and aren&amp;#8217;t used to the concept of not being able
to roll their own&amp;nbsp;distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;#8217;s my&amp;nbsp;advice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google should further decouple their Apps from the Android platform.
    Specifically, instead of requiring users to back things up, they
    should provide a redistributable application that installs their
    other apps. &lt;em&gt;Allow a user to flash a bare-bones community &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ROM&lt;/span&gt; image,
    and then pull whatever else they want from Google.&lt;/em&gt; If Google
    intends on toeing the line that Android is Free but the (Google)
    Apps aren&amp;#8217;t, then Google should provide an acceptable means for
    users of community &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ROM&lt;/span&gt; images to easily and painlessly re-install
    the closed Google apps on that&amp;nbsp;image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google should require that handset manufacturers do the same. Create
    a redistributable application that can be part of community &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ROM&lt;/span&gt;
    images, which will (via tethering or whatever) download and install
    any proprietary device-specific drivers that are&amp;nbsp;needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bottom line of my opinion - it&amp;#8217;s fine if Google exercises their full
control over their own closed apps. But they should provide an avenue
for non-technical end-users to easily upgrade a community (i.e. Free)
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ROM&lt;/span&gt; image with the expected Google Apps and device manufacturer&amp;nbsp;software.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="android"></category><category term="google"></category></entry><entry><title>New Projects</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/07/new-projects/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-07-16T14:05:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-07-16:2009/07/new-projects/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In terms of ongoing projects, I should be updating RackMan sometime
soon, and also adding the demo&amp;nbsp;site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve begun to move &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; for all of my domains in-house, mostly because
since everything is behind &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NAT&lt;/span&gt;, it&amp;#8217;s a real pain to manage &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; entries
in two places (one of them being GoDaddy&amp;#8217;s web interface). Because of
the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NAT&lt;/span&gt; issue, I&amp;#8217;m also writing my own &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BIND&lt;/span&gt; configuration tool,
currently named &lt;a href="http://multibindadmin.jasonantman.com"&gt;MultiBIND
Admin&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to managing
multiple zones in a sane way, it stores all configuration in MySQL.
Among other things, it can store different &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; addresses for A records
for the inside and outside views. Zone files can either be pulled by a
script on the name server (push capability is being worked on) or
downloaded (for uploading to a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; hosting provider like&amp;nbsp;GoDaddy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my final project for my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt; web design class, I&amp;#8217;m going to be making
some &amp;#8220;mashup&amp;#8221; with RackMan, Google Maps, Google Visualizer, Nagios, and
a few other&amp;nbsp;tools&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay&amp;nbsp;tuned&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bind"></category><category term="dns"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="PHPsa"></category><category term="rackman"></category></entry><entry><title>T-Mobile G1 (Googlephone) and VoIP?</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/10/t-mobile-g1-googlephone-and-voip/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-10-27T08:12:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-10-27:2008/10/t-mobile-g1-googlephone-and-voip/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So&amp;#8230; what&amp;#8217;s the deal? Will anyone come out and definitively say what
the fate of VoIP&amp;nbsp;is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what I&amp;#8217;ve read, there are two distinct&amp;nbsp;issues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ease of developing VoIP applications on Android, given the lack
    of a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;stack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T-Mobile&amp;#8217;s shunning of VoIP over their 3G&amp;nbsp;network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Android&lt;/strong&gt; - obviously, if we want to see VoIP apps on the G1, Android
needs to support &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIP&lt;/span&gt;. And the best way to do this is with real, native
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; support. Even if VoIP possibilities are limited to WiFi, still, it
would be nice to have &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIP&lt;/span&gt; support and let my cell double as a WiFi VoIP
phone&amp;#8230; even if handoffs between APs are still nearly impossible. The
next question that begs to be asked is how well such a third-party app
can integrate with the phone. Will the user experience of receiving a
VoIP call be substantially similar to that of receiving a normal phone&amp;nbsp;call?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T-Mobile 3G&lt;/strong&gt; - I&amp;#8217;ve read, so far, that T-Mobile &amp;#8220;does not support&amp;#8221;
VoIP over their 3G network. What&amp;#8217;s this whole &amp;#8220;does not support&amp;#8221; thing?
I&amp;#8217;m still a bit confused about how their 3G network works&amp;#8230; do they
actively block 3G, or just not enable it? If the latter, doe this mean
that other &amp;#8220;non-standard&amp;#8221; things, such as SSHing to a non-standard port,
won&amp;#8217;t work? Does this mean that there will be other heavy restrictions
on what types of data are sent over the&amp;nbsp;network?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about tunneling &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIP&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IAX&lt;/span&gt;/whatever else over &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt;? Will the G1 be
capable of handling that at a relatively good&amp;nbsp;speed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve read that the G1 &amp;#8220;can&amp;#8217;t&amp;#8221; be tethered. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WTF&lt;/span&gt;? Firstly, what is this
&amp;#8220;can&amp;#8217;t&amp;#8221; thing? Couldn&amp;#8217;t a developer just write an app that&amp;#8217;s essentially
a proxy server, that proxies from some sort of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt;-based wired
connection to&amp;nbsp;3G?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, as has been written many times already, less than a week
from the G1&amp;#8217;s release, it seems that the &lt;strong&gt;openness&lt;/strong&gt; touted by Google
and T-Mobile is much less than that. With all their claims of openness,
I&amp;#8217;d expect a phone that will do anything - especially not be locked to
one carrier, given Google&amp;#8217;s history of opposing that (their bid for
700Mhz) - and a data plan that would allow anything over the air that my
home &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; will allow over the&amp;nbsp;wire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google: Have you forsaken all of your stated ideals at the prospect of
making some cash off of a&amp;nbsp;phone?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="cell"></category><category term="g1"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="phone"></category><category term="t-mobile"></category><category term="voip"></category></entry><entry><title>Update</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/10/update-3/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-10-24T12:50:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-10-24:2008/10/update-3/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been a long month and a half or so. A bunch of new projects at work
(and interviewing for a full-time position) and lots of school stuff,
all on top of having my truck stolen, dealing with insurance and the
police, and then recovering it, and dealing with insurance again. It&amp;#8217;s a
long long story, which I posted as a Note on&amp;nbsp;facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.php-ems-tools.com"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMS&lt;/span&gt; Tools&lt;/a&gt; is due for a major
revision, and hopefully this will include, among other things, the
following new&amp;nbsp;features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I18n"&gt;i18n&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install-time choice of using MySQL or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LDAP&lt;/span&gt; as a roster and
    authentication storage&amp;nbsp;system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some vastly more efficient changes to the database schema,
    specifically dealing with&amp;nbsp;scheduling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m still working on some other big projects, namely the migration of
this blog to &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/"&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;, the migration of
&lt;a href="http://www.jasonantman.com"&gt;JasonAntman.com&lt;/a&gt; to some real &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CMS&lt;/span&gt; (Joomla,
Drupal, etc.), and migration of my home internet connection from
residential FiOS to &amp;#8220;business-grade&amp;#8221; Optimum Online (cable) - which will
probably see a slight decrease in reliability from the amazing levels of
FiOS, but will give me five static IPs and no ports&amp;nbsp;blocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there&amp;#8217;s been a wrench thrown into all of my plans for
big projects (not even mentioning the projects that have been cast aside
- &lt;a href="http://www.tuctruck.org"&gt;TuxTruck&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://jantman.dyndns.org:10011/tuxostat/"&gt;tuxOstat&lt;/a&gt; which is now down,
and a bunch of others. That wrench is the &lt;a href="http://www.t-mobileg1.com/"&gt;T-Mobile
G1&lt;/a&gt;, the GooglePhone finally come to
fruition. I was psyched about Android when I first heard about it, and
the idea of finally having a phone that I can develop for without
learning a new language sounds amazing. I&amp;#8217;ll admit that at $180 with a
2-year contract, plus $80/month for service (split about 50/50 between
the voice plan and the unlimited data plan) it doesn&amp;#8217;t make the best
financial sense for someone whose car was stolen and now has 2 vehicles
- only one of which I can afford - but I&amp;#8217;m really excited. I&amp;#8217;ve heard
some not-so-good things about the quality of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;, and some of the
apps currently available, but within a few months, I&amp;#8217;d assume that the
effects of open development will cause it to greatly surpass the
functionality of my current Treo 700p, running my beloved Palm &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; (which
I&amp;#8217;ve been dedicated to for the better part of seven&amp;nbsp;years).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the all-around flexibility of Android and its&amp;#8217; apps is definitely
one of the biggest selling points, my own interest is mainly in the
ability to quickly develop Java apps that bring my already-existing
web-based forms and data to the desktop of my phone. It&amp;#8217;s the simplicity
that is my biggest interest - even for simple purposes, like converting
the web-based fuel log I keep for my car(s) to a dedicated Java-based
form on my&amp;nbsp;phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay&amp;nbsp;tuned&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="android"></category><category term="g1"></category><category term="google"></category></entry><entry><title>Backups of data in the ether</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/03/backups-of-data-in-the-ether/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-03-06T12:11:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-03-06:2008/03/backups-of-data-in-the-ether/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;#8217;ve often told mystified people that hosted services - the free
ones - aren&amp;#8217;t required to backup your data, and you should probably do
it yourself, I usually didn&amp;#8217;t worry about this very much - all of my web
apps are on my own boxes, as well as my email. However, out of
curiosity, I spent about 15 minutes the other day coding up a little
hack of a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; script to keep track of what applications I use a lot
(specifically web-based ones that I can&amp;#8217;t easily have my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; keep track
of). After a day of trying to click the little &amp;#8220;update&amp;#8221; boxes on a
simple page when I used something, I realized how much of my data is
actually out of my own control. Maybe not anything critical, but
convenience stuff like &lt;a href="http://reader.google.com/"&gt;Google Reader&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://del.icio.us/"&gt;del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt; for *all* of my bookmarks, and
occasionally &lt;a href="http://docs.google.com/"&gt;Google Docs&lt;/a&gt; when I&amp;#8217;m going to be
hopping from place to place, or may be using a machine that I don&amp;#8217;t
trust to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SFTP&lt;/span&gt; something back&amp;nbsp;home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I decided to go about backing up some of this. The solution I aimed
for was simple - a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BASH&lt;/span&gt; script that runs nightly via cron, and dumps the
data into my home directory on my main storage/backup&amp;nbsp;server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Reader seemed to be one of the most difficult - no easy &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;
scheme, but I found a &lt;a href="http://blog.tobez.org/?p=49"&gt;simple script&lt;/a&gt; that
makes use of Perl &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CPAN&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s
&lt;a href="http://search.cpan.org/~gray/WebService-Google-Reader-0.07/"&gt;WebService::Google::Reader&lt;/a&gt;module
to grab a complete feed list. After seemingly an hour of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CPAN&lt;/span&gt; updates
and dependencies scrolling down my&amp;nbsp;screen,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Calendar Backup:&lt;br /&gt;
Wonderfully simple. Go into Settings, copy the URLs to the private
calendar links (I used iCal format), and wget&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;del.icio.us&amp;nbsp;backup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;curl --user usernam:pass -o myDelicious.xml -O &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;https://api.del.icio.us/v1/posts/all&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Google Reader Backup:&lt;br /&gt;
Still in the works - Perl problems on my backup&amp;nbsp;machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Docs Backup:&lt;br /&gt;
Hopefully soon, though nothing important lives&amp;nbsp;there.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="backups"></category><category term="del.icio.us"></category><category term="docs"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="reader"></category></entry><entry><title>Google Loves Me! and Monitoring System Testing</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/02/google-loves-me-and-monitoring-system-testing/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-02-05T03:15:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-02-05:2008/02/google-loves-me-and-monitoring-system-testing/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I happened to visit Google Webmaster Tools tonight. On the down side, a
lot more of my redirected pages
(&lt;a href="http://jantman.dyndns.org:10011/"&gt;jantman.dyndns.org:10011&lt;/a&gt;) are
indexed than those from the domain
(&lt;a href="http://www.jasonantman.com"&gt;jasonantman.com&lt;/a&gt;). On the positive side,
my search stats are quite impressive - for example, &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?num=50&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;safe=off&amp;amp;q=hpadu&amp;amp;btnG=Search"&gt;searching
&amp;#8220;hpadu&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;
(the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HP&lt;/span&gt; Proliant Array Diagnostic Utility) gives my
&lt;a href="http://www.jasonantman.com"&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt;as the #9 result - searching &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=hpasm+sles10&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;&amp;#8220;hpasm
sles10&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; shows my
site as #3! Most amazingly, there are only two &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HP&lt;/span&gt; pages above mine in
both of the&amp;nbsp;queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess trying to put every bit of knowledge I pick up in my blog or
wiki pays off. And hopefully some people are getting&amp;nbsp;help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On another note, later this week I&amp;#8217;m going to setup two virtual machines
on my spare PowerEdge 650 to test some &lt;a href="/2008/01/network-monitoring.html"&gt;network monitoring
systems&lt;/a&gt;
- specifically, &lt;a href="http://www.hyperic.com/products/hq_oss.html"&gt;Hyperic
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HQ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://www.opennms.org/"&gt;OpenNMS&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://www.groundworkopensource.com/products/os-overview.html"&gt;Groundwork Open
Source&lt;/a&gt;.
Thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.johnmwillis.com"&gt;John&lt;/a&gt;, Peter, and &lt;a href="http://jeffgehlbach.com/"&gt;Jeff
G&lt;/a&gt;. (of OpenNMS) for finding my little-known
blog and suggesting I try them. I don&amp;#8217;t know how much I&amp;#8217;ll be able to
run on this poor system (2.4GHz P-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;III&lt;/span&gt; is the fastest I have, but &lt;span class="caps"&gt;768MB&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt; is a bit weak), but I&amp;#8217;ll do the best I can, and post my&amp;nbsp;results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One comment - I can&amp;#8217;t seem to find a feature list for
&lt;a href="http://www.opennms.org/"&gt;OpenNMS&lt;/a&gt;, so I may be wrong, but it looks like
&lt;a href="http://www.hyperic.com/products/hq_oss.html"&gt;Hyperic &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HQ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; may be in the
lead at the moment, simply because it seems to include built-in asset
tracking with hardware discovery - something that takes me way too long
to manually keep up-to-date. On another side-note, the web site for
&lt;a href="http://www.groundworkopensource.com/products/os-overview.html"&gt;Groundwork Open
Source&lt;/a&gt;
leaves a sour taste in my mouth, as it&amp;#8217;s pretty sparse - there&amp;#8217;s a lot
of space given to the Enterprise edition, but not much text about the
Open Source&amp;nbsp;version.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="google"></category><category term="groundwork"></category><category term="hyperic"></category><category term="montoring"></category><category term="opennms"></category></entry></feed>