<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog - gps</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/gps.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2018-03-06T16:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>DIY Raspberry Pi Zero GPS Track Logger</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2018/03/diy-raspberry-pi-zero-gps-track-logger/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-06T16:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-03-06T16:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jason Antman</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2018-03-06:/2018/03/diy-raspberry-pi-zero-gps-track-logger/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Simple &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DIY&lt;/span&gt; Raspberry Pi Zero &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; logger, with code and&amp;nbsp;instructions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I was out hiking with one of my dogs when I realized that I didn&amp;#8217;t know the exact length of the route we were taking. We were at the &lt;a href="http://arabiaalliance.org/explore/plan-your-visit/visit-davidson-arabia-nature-preserve/"&gt;Davidson-Arabia Nature Preserve&lt;/a&gt;, part of the Arabia Mountain National Heritage Area, only about 20 minutes from home. It&amp;#8217;s a wonderful afternoon hike for me since it&amp;#8217;s so close to home and the trails are easy. It&amp;#8217;s also a laid back hike - the area is only about 2.1 square miles (5.4 sq. km.) bordered on all sides by well-traveled roads or suburban neighborhoods and dominated by Arabia Mountain and a lake - with many trails and high traffic, so I&amp;#8217;m less concerned about navigation than I would be in the backcountry. However, since my usual route covers portions of two trails and a cut-through between them, I don&amp;#8217;t know what the actual distance&amp;nbsp;is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first it seemed like the logical solution to this would be tracking hikes on my phone using one of the many apps for this (or a similar) purpose. But that didn&amp;#8217;t seem like a good solution to me for a number of reasons. First, my current phone is an aging Samsung Galaxy S6 (I tend to buy the best phone available at the time, and keep it until it dies) and the battery life is far from what it used to be. I carry an external battery pack for it, but frequently polling &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; position is extremely power intensive on any phone; I&amp;#8217;d rather leave my phone for tasks that actually require it  like communication, weather, and checking some of the great digital maps that are available. More importantly, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; antennas in most smartphones seem to be rather position sensitive and I haven&amp;#8217;t gotten very good results recording an accurate track with my phone in my pocket or belt holster, let alone in my pack (where it often is on more challenging&amp;nbsp;terrain).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started looking at the commercial &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; loggers available online, but few of them seemed like compelling choices for the cost. Then I realized that I could probably piece one together at no cost using parts that I already had, namely a &lt;a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/products/raspberry-pi-zero/"&gt;RaspberryPi Zero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;, and the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01JIYWUBA/"&gt;10Ah external battery pack&lt;/a&gt; I use for my phone. It turns out that the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000FPILZG/"&gt;Deluo 31-311-01 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I bought a decade ago has been lost to time, likely thrown out in one of the electronics purges I&amp;#8217;ve done over the past few years. But I was able to get a new SiRF Star &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IV&lt;/span&gt;-based &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B008200LHW/"&gt;GlobalSat &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BU&lt;/span&gt;-353-S4 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on Amazon. The manufacturer&amp;#8217;s specifications sound quite nice and even though the &lt;a href="http://www.catb.org/gpsd/hardware.html"&gt;gpsd hardware list&lt;/a&gt; rates it extremely poorly, once I received it in the mail I unboxed it and set it on the sill inside my window and was able to get a very accurate fix in about a&amp;nbsp;minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-result"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#the-result"&gt;The&amp;nbsp;Result&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/pizero_gpslogger_1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Photograph of finished hardware next to playing card deck for size comparison" src="/GFX/pizero_gpslogger_1_sm.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution I came up with uses the very stable and mature &lt;a href="http://www.catb.org/gpsd/"&gt;gpsd daemon&lt;/a&gt; to handle communication with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; and caching the last position information, and a small Python daemon to read from &lt;code&gt;gpsd&lt;/code&gt; and log to the RaspberryPi&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SD&lt;/span&gt; card using gpsd&amp;#8217;s full &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt; data format. The Pi itself is running the &lt;a href="https://www.raspbian.org/"&gt;Raspbian&lt;/a&gt; Linux distribution with virtually no customization, and all of the default services (plus &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt;) running out of laziness. I also added two status LEDs driven by the board&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPIO&lt;/span&gt;, to give visual indication of the position fix state and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SD&lt;/span&gt; card writes. Unlike many of the commercial &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; loggers available which log data every 60 seconds, my code defaults to 5-second intervals (that, along with most other parameters, are configurable via environment variables). My code (along with detailed instructions, an installation script, and a script to convert from gpsd &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt; format to standard &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GPS_Exchange_Format"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) is available at &lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/pizero-gpslog"&gt;https://github.com/jantman/pizero-gpslog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hardware"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#hardware"&gt;Hardware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/pizero_gpslogger_2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Photograph of finished hardware inside backpack" src="/GFX/pizero_gpslogger_2_sm.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This all fits conveniently in my hiking pack inside the mesh bag that the battery pack came in. I plan on putting the Pi and battery safely inside the main compartment (I can unzip it periodically to check that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; has a fix and is logging) and dangling the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; receiver out the zipper, affixed between the zipper pulls of the smaller compartment (with a hair elastic&amp;#8230;). This seems to be relatively horizontal, but I may also experiment with taping the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; to the carry handle on top of the pack, or packing all of it into the top outside&amp;nbsp;pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/pizero_gpslogger_3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Front angle pohotograph of GPS affixed to outside of pack" src="/GFX/pizero_gpslogger_3_sm.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/pizero_gpslogger_4.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Side angle photograph of GPS affixed to outside of pack" src="/GFX/pizero_gpslogger_4_sm.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s worth mention that my hardware choice was largely dependent on what I already had or what I thought I could reuse for other projects. While the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; receiver is small and lightweight - about 2&amp;#8221; (5cm) around and about 2 ounces (57g) - I could have saved a fair amount of space and some weight by purchasing a component &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; to connect to the Pi via &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPIO&lt;/span&gt; and mount directly to the Pi itself. I decided to get a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; model as it will be more useful to me for other projects as well. Some space and weight could also be saved by using a simpler microcontroller than the Pi Zero (this application certainly doesn&amp;#8217;t need the power of a Pi, or a full Linux system) but I used what I had&amp;nbsp;handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full system as I have it set up weighs 11.5 ounces (326g) which is quite heavy by the standards of serious hikers. However, 7 ounces (203g) of that is the 10,000mAh external battery pack which I already had for my cell phone. This battery can run the logger for 42 hours continuously, which is definitely overkill for my purposes. I could likely cut the weight in half if I used a more appropriately-sized battery; Anker, a company whose products I really like, makes a $15 &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B005X1Y7I2"&gt;3350mAh &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; battery pack&lt;/a&gt; that weighs in at just 3oz (85g), to say nothing of the lighter Pi-specific options&amp;nbsp;available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As-is, this hardware allows me to continuously log &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; fixes every 5 seconds for 42 hours, consuming about &lt;span class="caps"&gt;40MB&lt;/span&gt; for the data. Each data point is approximately 1400 bytes, and the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;8GB&lt;/span&gt; microSD card I use (5.6G free after &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; and software) has space to log about &lt;strong&gt;240 days&lt;/strong&gt; of data at this&amp;nbsp;interval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="initial-tests"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#initial-tests"&gt;Initial&amp;nbsp;Tests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first test, as described above, was just a test of the &amp;#8220;cold fix&amp;#8221; speed for the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BU&lt;/span&gt;-353-S4 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; after unboxing. Sitting on the sill inside a residential window with a view of half the sky at best, I got a fix accurate to 3-4 meters within about a&amp;nbsp;minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next test was placing the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; on the dash of my car during a quick five-mile trip to the grocery store and gas station. The results were shockingly accurate: not only did the unit perform perfectly as intended, but when I converted the logs to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPX&lt;/span&gt; format and used &lt;a href="http://www.gpsvisualizer.com/"&gt;gpsvisualizer.com&lt;/a&gt; to overlay them on Google Maps, I could clearly see my route down to which side of the road I was driving on, the exact space I parked in, and which gas pump I&amp;nbsp;used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also did a test of the total time that I can capture data using the 10Ah battery pack and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;8GB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SD&lt;/span&gt; card. This might be a very slight amount unrealistic, since the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; was stationary most of the time. After doing the above driving test I set the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; up on the inside sill of my bedroom window and let it run. And run. And drove to work the next day with it on the dashboard of my car, left it in the car during my work day (on the bottom floor of a 4-story parking deck, where a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; fix is impossible to get), drove home, put it back on the window sill, and eventually fell asleep. Sometime during the night, at the 42-hour mark, the battery finally gave out. The total space used for 42 hours of data was approximately&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;40MB&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="source-code"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#source-code"&gt;Source&amp;nbsp;Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For code, detailed hardware information, and instructions see: &lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/pizero-gpslog"&gt;https://github.com/jantman/pizero-gpslog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="embedded"></category><category term="gps"></category><category term="hiking"></category><category term="logger"></category><category term="raspberrypi"></category></entry><entry><title>SunSPOT; CarPC; MediaWiki Logging</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/05/sunspot-carpc-mediawiki-logging/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-05-07T10:03:00-04:00</published><updated>2008-05-07T10:03:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-05-07:/2008/05/sunspot-carpc-mediawiki-logging/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, finals season is upon me. That&amp;#8217;s probably why I haven&amp;#8217;t been
posting much lately (I haven&amp;#8217;t even been checking &lt;a href="http://reader.google.com/"&gt;Google
Reader&lt;/a&gt; - I&amp;#8217;ll have to delete a few thousand
entries when I get back into the swing of things). I&amp;#8217;ve been pretty
busy, between studying …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, finals season is upon me. That&amp;#8217;s probably why I haven&amp;#8217;t been
posting much lately (I haven&amp;#8217;t even been checking &lt;a href="http://reader.google.com/"&gt;Google
Reader&lt;/a&gt; - I&amp;#8217;ll have to delete a few thousand
entries when I get back into the swing of things). I&amp;#8217;ve been pretty
busy, between studying, projects, and work. I&amp;#8217;ll be working 4 days a
week through June 20th, as well as taking night classes 4 nigths a week
(unfortunately not the same 4 days) through July 3, in an effort to
graduate Rutgers on time (after transferring in and also switching
majors). Work after June 20th is up in the air - who knows how hard the
budget cuts will&amp;nbsp;hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My internship as the Sun Microsystems Campus Ambassador to Rutgers is
over on May 12th. I got a chance to do the Rutgers &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; Vendor Fair with
Sun, and met a few cool people - especially including Matt McGrath of
&lt;a href="http://www.conres.com/"&gt;Continental Resources&lt;/a&gt;, a Sun Strategic iForce
Partner, who&amp;#8217;s doing some wonderful things with the &lt;a href="http://www.sun.com/solutions/landing/industry/education/edu_essentials.jsp"&gt;Sun Education
Essentials Matching Grant
Program&lt;/a&gt;,
and &lt;a href="http://opsamericas.com/"&gt;Skip Paul&lt;/a&gt;, a Linux Systems Engineer for
Novell&amp;#8217;s Open Platform Solutions group. I also finally cracked open my
demo set of &lt;a href="http://www.sunspotworld.com/"&gt;SunSPOT&lt;/a&gt;s. Wonderful little
devices, radio, run Java on the bare metal, and have temperature
sensors, accelerometers, and liberal I/O. My first development exereice
will probably be making a temperature and acceleration data logger for
my truck, but there&amp;#8217;s surely more to come. They&amp;#8217;re&amp;nbsp;great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My newest project - which I&amp;#8217;m hoping to spend nearly the whole summer on
- is the &lt;a href="http://www.jasonantman.com/tuxtruck/"&gt;TuxTruck&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;ve been
frustrated with the lack of &amp;#8220;smartness&amp;#8221; in my truck (an 06 Ford F-250),
not to mention having to remember my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MP3&lt;/span&gt; player so I can listen to
podcasts on the way to work, and having so many gadgets in my truck. So,
the solution is obvious: a Linux-based
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carpc"&gt;CarPC&lt;/a&gt;. A nice little Mini-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ATX&lt;/span&gt; box
under a seat, with a 7&amp;#8221; pull-out touchscreen in the dash (replacing the
factory radio). It&amp;#8217;s a big, complicated, and expensive project - but I
want one, and I could use some experience with smaller systems.&lt;br&gt;
The major features I have&amp;nbsp;planned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Realtime &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-free bluetooth calls from my cell, with address book, routing
    to contact address, possibly voice&amp;nbsp;dialing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Realtime&amp;nbsp;weather&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OBD&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;II&lt;/span&gt; interface, for vehicle diagnostics and fuel
    efficiency/performance&amp;nbsp;profiling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audio - at a minimum searching and playing MP3s, and automatically
    downloading podcasts and throwing them in a playlist. Perhaps also
    an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FM&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;tuner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s not an easy project. So far, the major challenges seem to&amp;nbsp;be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No full-featured &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; navigation package available. The ones that are
    available don&amp;#8217;t seem to be too easy to integrate into my planned
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt;, which will allot them 800x420 pixels (on an 800x480 screen) and
    requre the bottom toolbar to be always&amp;nbsp;available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to handle processing of multiple data streams that require
    near-real-time processing - specifically, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; with text-to-speech,
    turn-by-turn directions, plus playing audio, plus responding to an
    incoming phone call in a timely manner, pausing the audio, and
    stopping &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; audio but continuing&amp;nbsp;navigation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whether to install a smaller stereo and use aux input for audio, or
    totally rip out the stereo, use an amp with the computer as its only
    input, and then how to control&amp;nbsp;volume?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be more to come in the future. For now, take a look at &lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/tuxtruck"&gt;the
TuxTruck github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update Saturday, March 2, 2013&lt;/strong&gt; - I&amp;#8217;m in the process of migrating my
legacy &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt; and Subversion repositories to
&lt;a href="http://github.com/jantman/"&gt;github.com&lt;/a&gt;. The forgotten &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SVN&lt;/span&gt; repository
for TuxTruck has been migrated there, and the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt; repository will soon
be moved there as well. Tuxtruck.org has been permanently taken offline
and redirected to the GitHub&amp;nbsp;repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mediawiki Logging&lt;/strong&gt; - I recently
had a situation where I had to confirm how much work someone had done on
a MediaWiki-based project. The Recent Changes page only goes back 30
days, and walking through the History of each page is a pain. After
looking around in the database a bit, I found a few tables of&amp;nbsp;interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table &amp;#8220;users&amp;#8221; includes fields &amp;#8220;user_touched&amp;#8221; (last time the user
    was updated) and &amp;#8220;user_editcount&amp;#8221; (a really simple count of the
    users&amp;#8217; number of&amp;nbsp;edits).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table &amp;#8220;recentchanges&amp;#8221; holds a lot of data&amp;#8230; seemingly the entire
    life of the&amp;nbsp;wiki&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="bluetooth"></category><category term="car"></category><category term="carpc"></category><category term="conres"></category><category term="gps"></category><category term="linux"></category><category term="mediawiki"></category><category term="novell"></category><category term="obd"></category><category term="rutgers"></category><category term="sun"></category><category term="sunspot"></category><category term="suse"></category><category term="tuxtruck"></category></entry><entry><title>Where have I gone?</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/03/where-have-i-gone/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-03-25T09:07:00-04:00</published><updated>2008-03-25T09:07:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-03-25:/2008/03/where-have-i-gone/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;#8217;s been a while since I posted. Things have been horribly busy
in the school world, and I have some new projects I&amp;#8217;m working on as
well. Unfortunately, due to limited resources at the moment, I haven&amp;#8217;t
been able to give Zenoss a try. If I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;#8217;s been a while since I posted. Things have been horribly busy
in the school world, and I have some new projects I&amp;#8217;m working on as
well. Unfortunately, due to limited resources at the moment, I haven&amp;#8217;t
been able to give Zenoss a try. If I eventually find a nice 25-30U rack
for the &lt;a href="http://www.jasonantman.com/wiki/index.php/Jasonantman.com_Hardware"&gt;hardware running
JasonAntman.com&lt;/a&gt;
(in the basement of my suburban home, so headroom is limited to about
six feet), I&amp;#8217;ll probably move one or two machines from my apartment back
there, reorganize things, and setup a Zenoss test (*if* I can get Xen
to play well with some &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; that has Zenoss RPMs, or give up and compile
from source).&lt;br&gt;
A few of my new&amp;nbsp;projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some embedded Linux&amp;nbsp;work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting my new &lt;a href="http://www.deluogps.com/product.php?id=10-311-00"&gt;Deluo &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WAAS&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; working with
    my eeePC, and eventually add software for mapping wireless&amp;nbsp;networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mount an external 2.4GHz antenna on my truck, so I can hop on
    &lt;a href="http://ruwireless.rutgers.edu/"&gt;RUwireless&lt;/a&gt; without leaving the
    comfort of my home on&amp;nbsp;wheels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a &amp;#8220;N&amp;#8221; wireless card and beta the wireless-N at&amp;nbsp;Rutgers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figure out development for PalmOS, and write a program to sync my
    Palm calendar with &lt;a href="http://calendar.google.com/"&gt;Google Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;over-the-air.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do some work with a radio scanner and a system at home for recording
    and logging (maybe even
    &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MDC-1200"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDC1200&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;decoding).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My pet peeve for the day - blogs and other websites that don&amp;#8217;t list a
date last updated. I&amp;#8217;ve been looking around for alternatives to
&lt;a href="http://cvs.codeyard.net/kpilot/"&gt;KPilot&lt;/a&gt;, and I have to look through
all of the Google results, and figure out how old they are based on
version numbers and which Palm devices are&amp;nbsp;listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, from Rutgers Telecommunications, this is what RUwireless looked
like over spring break, and the Monday that everyone came&amp;nbsp;back:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Rutgers daily traffic graph of sr02-hill012-svcs_vlan1000 on 2008-03-25" src="/GFX/blog/sr02-hill012-svcs_vlan1000-daily-2008-03-25-scaled.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="calendar"></category><category term="gps"></category><category term="kpilot"></category><category term="mdc1200"></category><category term="palm"></category><category term="rutgers"></category><category term="ruwireless"></category></entry></feed>