<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog - guns</title><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/guns.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2016-06-13T20:02:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>A Short Comment on Gun Rights in America</title><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/2016/06/a-short-comment-on-gun-rights-in-america/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-13T20:02:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-06-13T20:02:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Jason Antman</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2016-06-13:/2016/06/a-short-comment-on-gun-rights-in-america/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A diversion from &amp;#8220;all technical&amp;#8221; content, on gun ownership in&amp;nbsp;America.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This blog has, for many years, been unabashedly &amp;#8220;all tech.&amp;#8221; I&amp;#8217;ve often had second thoughts about that, wondering if I should give the rest of my self - my political, moral and ethical views - more of a voice. But I&amp;#8217;ve always put that aside - partially because this &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; comes up when I&amp;#8217;m looking for a new job and I don&amp;#8217;t really want to be remembered as that guy with the strongly disagreeing views, partially because I don&amp;#8217;t want people looking for technical content to be frustrated by my rants. And partially because it&amp;#8217;s just harder for me to convey political or social concepts in the way I intend than it is to convey technical ones. But after the events of the past 36 hours - and moreover, of the past decade-plus - I&amp;#8217;m going to deviate from that. &lt;strong&gt;Be advised&lt;/strong&gt; that if you have strong feelings on either side of the gun control debate, this probably isn&amp;#8217;t going to make you&amp;nbsp;happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m a gun owner. I have been since my eighteenth birthday, the day when I became legally able to exercise my second amendment rights in my then-home state of New Jersey. That was only a decade ago, but the impact of guns on America seems so shockingly different. I own a single .22-caliber target pistol; certainly dangerous as any firearm is, but essentially the bottom of the scale when it comes to lethality. It&amp;#8217;s designed to shoot paper, not much else. I&amp;#8217;ve been shooting off and on since I was in my early teens, mostly handguns and shotguns. Apparently unlike most people who are vocal gun owners, I&amp;#8217;ve never fired a shot at anything that is or was ever alive, unless you count paper. I&amp;#8217;ve never fired a shot outside of a shooting&amp;nbsp;range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve also never carried a gun in public, nor have I ever had a serious desire to. Despite what gun-rights activists claim about self-defense and defense of others, I think that the way police in this country are both trained and act in the field is a wonderful example of why firearm carry in public often doesn&amp;#8217;t work: we&amp;#8217;re talking about people whose &lt;em&gt;profession&lt;/em&gt; involves firearms, who must train and qualify with their guns annually (or more often), and still often can&amp;#8217;t hit a target in a real-life situation. As far as I&amp;#8217;m concerned, if someone wants to carry a firearm to defend themselves or others, they damn well better be shooting &lt;em&gt;every day&lt;/em&gt;, doing live-fire training, and completely confident that they could identify and hit a target in real life. To my knowledge, only the most elite units of the military do this. I grew up in New Jersey, where the only people who carry guns are law enforcement and criminals, period (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt;, there are some &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; rare exceptions). I now live in Georgia, where anyone can walk into WalMart and walk out with a gun - and many people walk around the store with handguns on their belts, something that&amp;#8217;s still foreign to&amp;nbsp;me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my eighteenth birthday, I went to the police department in my home town to begin the process of purchasing the target pistol that my father had offered as a gift. For those of you who aren&amp;#8217;t familiar with how gun (specifically handgun - it&amp;#8217;s significantly easier for shotguns and rifles) ownership works in the northeast, here&amp;#8217;s the gist of it (my memory may be a bit hazy, and some of it may have been explained&amp;nbsp;poorly):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I went to the police department and met with the chief, whom I already knew personally through&amp;nbsp;family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I paid a fee of approximately $100 and filled out about six pages of paperwork, including a full history of my addresses and a lengthy&amp;nbsp;questionnaire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was fingerprinted - all ten fingers, three sets of&amp;nbsp;prints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I filled out consent forms for federal and state background checks and consents for mental health records&amp;nbsp;searches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These were all sent out to the respective&amp;nbsp;agencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About a month later, the chief called to tell me that he&amp;#8217;d received the replies from the federal and state governments, and they came back &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt; (which is to be expected, as I had no mental health history and no criminal&amp;nbsp;record).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He then sent out form letters to the three non-related character references I had specified on my application, requesting them to assert under penalty of perjury whether they believed that I posed any danger to myself or others, if I were allowed to purchase a&amp;nbsp;firearm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The letters were all returned by my references. The chief then sent the completed paperwork back to the state government, which issued me a state firearms purchaser identification card, entitling me to purchase firearms and ammunition. I was also issued - as requested - a Permit to Purchase a Handgun, which entitled me to purchase one (1) handgun within 90 days of the date of&amp;nbsp;issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt;, so that&amp;#8217;s quite a process. All in all, it took two or three months to&amp;nbsp;complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finally received my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ID&lt;/span&gt; card and permit - which had to be picked up in person - I headed out to a local gun store to find the model I wanted. And I did. I turned the purchase permit over to the salesperson, who called the state government to verify its validity. We finalized the details of the transaction and I inspected the merchandise and filled out some last paperwork. The gun I&amp;#8217;d purchased was then marked with a &amp;#8220;sold&amp;#8221; sticker and had a copy of the invoice attached, and was locked in a safe for me to pick up in seven days, when the mandatory waiting period was over. When I returned a week later, one of the two spent cartridges from the gun (shipped with it by the manufacturer) was sent to the state police for future forensic&amp;nbsp;use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Jersey is widely regarded as having some of the strictest gun control laws in the country. And none of that is enough. There was never a follow-up. There was no ongoing monitoring that I&amp;#8217;m aware of. I&amp;#8217;ve heard more stories than I can remember of people being convicted of crimes or involved in domestic violence situations, and then using their legally-purchased and registered firearms in future crimes. It makes no sense to me that we live in a world where Amazon knows what items I&amp;#8217;m interested in today, but the authorities can&amp;#8217;t figure out to take my gun away if I assault someone. There was also never a mandatory proficiency or safety test, either written or at a real firing&amp;nbsp;range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is it that we live in a country where operation of a motor vehicle - a device which &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be fatal when operated improperly - requires a written examination, a practical demonstration of skill, and an ongoing demonstration of responsibility (traffic police), but the possession and operation of a firearm does not? It makes no sense. I don&amp;#8217;t want to minimize the effects of poor driving decisions, they certainly claim many lives, but there&amp;#8217;s no avoiding the fact that firearms were - and in many cases, are - &lt;em&gt;designed&lt;/em&gt; to&amp;nbsp;kill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose that most of my feelings on this are based on two of my core beliefs, which run contrary to many gun-rights activists: (1) that my only use for a firearm is target shooting, and it doesn&amp;#8217;t really matter to me how quickly I can buy one, and (2) that our military has tanks and nukes, and the idea of &amp;#8220;defending my Freedom [against a government takeover]&amp;#8221; with any legally-purchased weapon is impossible, regardless of whether or not it&amp;#8217;s simply&amp;nbsp;paranoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether openly or not, many gun rights activists base their positions on a romanticized fictional &amp;#8220;past America&amp;#8221;, where everyone was good, owned guns, defended themselves, and was self-sufficient. Even if that past world existed (in reality it was quite violent; the violence just isn&amp;#8217;t remembered in the Utopian narrative), it&amp;#8217;s certainly not today. The past America they speak of was a time when most gun owners had been so since childhood (it was merely a part of living), likely had many fewer violent influences, and could count on swift justice. Let&amp;#8217;s also remember the technology of this past age: I might be &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt; with gun rights activists going back to this mythical past, if they also could only have a six-shot revolver that takes a few minutes to&amp;nbsp;reload.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But despite what gun rights activists try to tell us, the problem here is not hardcore criminals. It&amp;#8217;s people who may or may not have criminal or suspicious pasts, who decide to act on their violent ideas. It&amp;#8217;s people who can walk into a store and buy a weapon or magazine that holds twenty or fifty rounds of ammunition - something which has no legitimate use other than mass killing. It&amp;#8217;s people who can borrow or steal guns from family or friends, because those firearms weren&amp;#8217;t treated with the proper respect and safety by their legal owners. It&amp;#8217;s the belief by some that there&amp;#8217;s a legitimate reason to obtain a gun in less than a week, or a month, or months. It&amp;#8217;s the ironic dichotomy of the people who believe that Snowden was a traitor and mass surveillance is fine, but registering guns is an unconstitutional invasion of privacy. And it has to stop. I dare say, if every mass shooting in the past decade or two was carried out by a Muslim or an immigrant or anyone other than a white Christian, half of the roadblocks to a safe America would&amp;#8217;ve&amp;nbsp;disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To everyone who takes a literal reading of the Constitution and says that the second amendment grants every American the right to posses and carry as many and whatever kind of firearms they want, I make three&amp;nbsp;comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;falsely shouting &amp;#8216;fire&amp;#8217; in a crowded theater.&amp;#8221; We have a Supreme Court for a reason: that the framers knew the Constitution would have to be interpreted differently with&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you stand against gun registration or regulation, please keep in mind that your precious second amendment begins with the phrase, &amp;#8220;A well regulated Militia.&amp;#8221; Even if you don&amp;#8217;t believe that this is equivalent to a modern-day standing army, it clearly does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; say, &amp;#8220;Everybody gets all the firearms they want,&amp;nbsp;period.&amp;#8221;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;Life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness.&amp;#8221; They weren&amp;#8217;t put in that order by&amp;nbsp;mistake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="politics"></category><category term="guns"></category></entry></feed>