<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/important-businessweek-vista-iphone-products.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://newblog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2007-12-11T15:36:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Commentary - Best Products, or most hype?</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2007/12/commentary-best-products-or-most-hype/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-12-11T15:36:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2007-12-11:2007/12/commentary-best-products-or-most-hype/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In my usual lunchtime &lt;a href="http://www.digg.com"&gt;Digg&lt;/a&gt; reading, I came by a
link to the &lt;a href="http://images.businessweek.com/ss/07/12/1210_bestworst_products/index_01.htm"&gt;BusinessWeek Most Important Products of
2007&lt;/a&gt;.
Given the number of cars, it&amp;#8217;s apparent that this is a very
consumer-oriented listing. But I was a bit surprised - the first four
products were all from Apple - the iPhone, MacBook Pro, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; X Leopard,
and Apple &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;. While some of these are definitely interesting, I really
don&amp;#8217;t think that any other than the iPhone could be considered truly
important or groundbreaking. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; X Leopard and the MacBook Pro may be
wonderful for Mac users, but they&amp;#8217;re not really anything &amp;#8220;new&amp;#8221; in the
sense of ideas - they&amp;#8217;re just updated versions with more/better
features. Given the amount of hype that surrounded it, it was clear that
the iPhone would be on this list. And I will admit that, despite my
moral objections to it (bricking phones that innocent users unlocked),
the iPhone is very nicely done. But it&amp;#8217;s not anything truly &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEW&lt;/span&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s a
step in progression. There were phones with cameras, phones that were
thin, phones with touchscreens, and phones that played MP3s. Apple just
pulled all - and some extra - into a very nice&amp;nbsp;package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what else was mentioned? The Dell &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XPS&lt;/span&gt; One, some Mac-ish all-in-one
Media Center &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt;. It puts everything my computer has in one &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OEM&lt;/span&gt; package,
and adds on Windows Media Center, just to make sure it won&amp;#8217;t do
everything you want. And it even puts the entire computer inside a
monitor-sized enclosure, so if you crack the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LCD&lt;/span&gt;, you have to send the
whole thing back to Dell. Don&amp;#8217;t even ask me how the Braun Pulsonic
electric razor made it onto this list. Or a 30&amp;#8221; Gateway &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LCD&lt;/span&gt; monitor.
Yes, it&amp;#8217;s a big monitor. And it has a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; tuner. That makes it one of the
most important products of the year? Of course, there&amp;#8217;s also a 60&amp;#8221;
Pioneer &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LCD&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;, the Tivo &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HD&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVR&lt;/span&gt;, and the Motorola Razr2. All jazzed-up
versions of old ideas. And I&amp;#8217;m not even going to mention Windows Vista,
arguably Microsoft&amp;#8217;s biggest flop (other than Windows &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ME&lt;/span&gt;), which appears
on the list - though they do mention, &amp;#8220;While many users hate it, there&amp;#8217;s
little question that the operating system is selling extremely well.&amp;#8221;.
They mention that Microsoft said, in October, that it
&lt;strong&gt;had shipped 88 million copies of Vista&lt;/strong&gt;. While I don&amp;#8217;t totally doubt that figure, it doesn&amp;#8217;t take
into account the users who bought a Dell with Vista and then dumped it
for Ubuntu. Or even the (I imagine rather large) number of users, like
many of my friends, who bought that new computer with Vista and
immediately loaded their old &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XP&lt;/span&gt; Pro&amp;nbsp;disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, after all of that nitpicking, what do I think is&amp;nbsp;missing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The desktop processor revolution, with 64-bit systems becoming quite&amp;nbsp;common.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Intel and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AMD&lt;/span&gt; dual- and quad-core CPUs being put in consumer&amp;nbsp;machines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intel &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VT&lt;/span&gt; hardware virtualization&amp;nbsp;technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OLPC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Asus eeePC (well, this is still to be&amp;nbsp;determined)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motorola cellphones moving to Linux (as well as other&amp;nbsp;companies)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The portion of the 700-MHz spectrum set for auction by the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt;. (well, not a consumer product, but it could revolutionize mobile communications if it falls into the right&amp;nbsp;hands).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><category term="important businessweek vista iphone products"></category></entry></feed>