<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog - internet</title><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/internet.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2010-12-23T09:07:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Net Neutrality - What is it, and what will the recent FCC decision do?</title><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/12/net-neutrality-what-is-it-and-what-will-the-recent-fcc-decision-do/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-12-23T09:07:00-05:00</published><updated>2010-12-23T09:07:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-12-23:/2010/12/net-neutrality-what-is-it-and-what-will-the-recent-fcc-decision-do/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_neutrality"&gt;Net Neutrality&lt;/a&gt; is a
&lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt; issue these days, and one that&amp;#8217;s exploded out of the geek
circles into mainstream media. I&amp;#8217;ll admit that it seems like there are
endless variations on exactly what people consider Net Neutrality to be
(or what it &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be). The general goal of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_neutrality"&gt;Net Neutrality&lt;/a&gt; is a
&lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt; issue these days, and one that&amp;#8217;s exploded out of the geek
circles into mainstream media. I&amp;#8217;ll admit that it seems like there are
endless variations on exactly what people consider Net Neutrality to be
(or what it &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be). The general goal of Net Neutrality is to
ensure that Internet Service Providers (ISPs) provide (relatively)
unfiltered access to the Internet to their customers. Specifically, that
if a given customer pays for a level of service - i.e. 10 Mbps
downstream speed and 2.5 Mbps upstream speed - they receive that speed
no matter what they are accessing. The goal of Net Neutrality is to
require ISPs to treat their connections as a &amp;#8220;common carrier&amp;#8221;, much like
telephone companies or freight trucks. Within reason (excepting
explosives and other hazardous materials), &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; will ship a package for a
given rate based only on what it weighs and how far it&amp;#8217;s going (since
the Internet is run by many companies, and data passes from one to
another, the distance portion of this analogy is constant). They don&amp;#8217;t
charge more based on what&amp;#8217;s in the box, and they don&amp;#8217;t ship come boxes
faster than others based simply on who sent it or what&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, over the past century, many laws have been created that
regulate the telephone industry. While there was a time when customers
had to rent their telephones from the phone company, long-standing
legislation states that a customer can hook any properly functioning
device into the phone network, and a customer can say whatever they want
over the phone and receive the same call quality, at the same&amp;nbsp;rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To try and summarize, the goal of Net Neutrality is to ensure that you,
the customer of an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; (whether cable, FiOS, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DSL&lt;/span&gt;, etc.), is entitled to
certain rights. Generally (the exact interpretation of this concept
varies) this&amp;nbsp;includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to connect any device you want to your Internet
    connection - any computer, game console, or other device, running
    any operating system or other&amp;nbsp;software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your ability to connect to any service (web site, protocol, etc.)
    that you want without it being intentionally degraded or slowed
    down, even if it&amp;#8217;s a service viewed to be a competitor of your&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your ability to transfer data to and from any other user of the
    Internet, regardless of who they&amp;nbsp;are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What could happen if Net Neutrality isn&amp;#8217;t&amp;nbsp;enforced?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me first say that most of the following is pure speculation. These
are things that &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; happen, but most have not yet actually been
done. Some have. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; industry seems to say that Net Neutrality is &amp;#8220;a
solution without a problem&amp;#8221;, but my personal view is that those are
generally good things. Preventing a problem from occurring is generally
better than fixing it after it&amp;#8217;s a problem. So here are a few scenarios
of what could happen if Net Neutrality isn&amp;#8217;t properly legislated and&amp;nbsp;enforced:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies like Cablevision, Comcast, Verizon, and other major ISPs
    also offer &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; services (Optimum, FiOS &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;, etc.) that include Video
    On Demand (VoD) as a separate paid service. Websites like Hulu and
    Netflix offer the same service, for free or a much cheaper rate.
    Without Net Neutrality, your &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; could intentionally slow down or
    block sites like Hulu or Netflix to force you to buy their more
    expensive service. Comcast has &lt;a href="http://www.computerworld.com/s/article/9198498/Comcast_demands_fees_for_Web_movie_viewing_Level_3_says"&gt;already
    tried&lt;/a&gt;
    to do something like this, asking Netflix&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; for a substantial
    fee to allow Comcast customers to access Netfix (that&amp;#8217;s a bit of an
    oversimplification, but gets the point). If this happens, it&amp;#8217;s most
    likely that Netfix will have to increase their fees substantially.
    Net Neutrality legislation would require ISPs like Comcast to treat
    all Internet traffic the same, whether it&amp;#8217;s from Netflix, Facebook,
    or my humble little&amp;nbsp;blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few ISPs (mainly Comcast) have already tried all-out blocking Peer
    to Peer (p2p) file sharing traffic such as bitTorrent, Kazaa, etc.
    While they cite copyright infringement as the reason, there are many
    people who use p2p file sharing to distribute legal files, such as
    the Linux operating system and other free software. Blocking all p2p
    traffic because some people use it for illegal purposes is based on
    a presumption of guilt, no different from outlawing steak knives
    because some people stab other people with&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Throughout the history of the Internet, some of the most popular and
    innovative technologies, including Google, Facebook, etc. have
    started out as small projects run by a few geeks and programmers. If
    ISPs were allowed to charge content providers (i.e. websites) to be
    viewed by the ISPs customers, it would limit innovation and new
    technologies to only the big businesses with enough money to pay
    these artificial&amp;nbsp;tolls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most ISPs also offer a phone service. It would be trivial for them
    to flat-out prevent their customers from using Vonage, Skype, iChat,
    etc. and force you to subscribe to their service. It&amp;#8217;s also possible
    for them to do this in a covert way - when Comcast blocked
    bitTorrent users, they did it in a way so clever that it took weeks
    for experts to figure&amp;nbsp;out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Without a mandate that any suitable device can connect to the
    network, your &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; could partner with, for example, Dell and
    Microsoft, and say that you could only get Internet access on a Dell
    computer running the latest version of Windows (yes, this is a bit
    of a stretch, but possible in an unregulated &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;market).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important fact to note here is that most people in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; don&amp;#8217;t have
much choice in terms of broadband ISPs - generally the only &amp;#8220;choice&amp;#8221; is
between the cable and phone companies, who provide more or less the same
service. With such limited choice, Internet users are effectively held
hostage by the policies of a handful of companies that control Internet&amp;nbsp;access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A short note on the History of the&amp;nbsp;Internet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to the ISPs &amp;#8220;solution without a problem&amp;#8221; view, I think this is
a solution that should have been implemented long ago. The network that
evolved into what we now know as the Internet, in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;, was first
developed in the 1970s. The project, ARPAnet, was developed by the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;
government for research purposes, and funded by taxpayer money. It
wasn&amp;#8217;t opened to commercial use until the early 1990s, when it was
privatized. While the development into what is now the Internet could
never have been foreseen at that time, Net Neutrality rules should have
been built in from the start when the project was handed over from the
federal government to the private sector. Regardless, it must be
remembered that the Internet is a technology that was originally
developed with taxpayer funds, for the country as a&amp;nbsp;whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;doing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, in short, not much. It appears that the Net Neutrality rules
delivered by the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt; earlier this week are, more than anything, a
compromise effort to make the issue just &amp;#8220;go away&amp;#8221;. The ISPs feel that
the rules aren&amp;#8217;t needed (and argue that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt; doesn&amp;#8217;t have the power
to make them), and most Net Neutrality proponents feel that the rules
pay only lip service to the goals of Net Neutrality. The main failings
already apparent in the rules&amp;nbsp;are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two of three major parts of the rules ignore wireless ISPs (cellular
    carriers). With the explosion of smartphones, it seems that wireless
    is not only the new frontier of the Internet, but the way that more
    and more people get Internet access. If Net Neutrality is
    legislated, it should be about the Internet - regardless of how a
    customer is connected to the&amp;nbsp;network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a provision for ISPs to be able to block or slow down
    traffic as is &amp;#8220;reasonable&amp;#8221; to operate their network, but there are
    no guidelines on what &amp;#8220;reasonable&amp;#8221; means, and it seems that the
    burden of proof would be on the customer to fight their &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; in court
    and show that something was&amp;nbsp;unreasonable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until very recently, ISPs generally didn&amp;#8217;t engage in the kind of
conduct that Net Neutrality rules would prohibit. The Internet as we
know it today is a product of a world with unwritten Net Neutrality
rules. Amazing sites and services like Facebook, Google, Twitter, and
many others started as experiments by a few dedicated people with little
to no budget. The fact that you can easily view web pages created by
anyone - like my blog - would be ended if website publishers had to pay
ISPs to be allowed through. The choice that you have in using your &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; or phone service, or something like Netflix or Vonage, is central to
the Internet as we know it, but is under attack. I know that many people
look at this as a &amp;#8220;problem for the geeks&amp;#8221;. We take the Internet for
granted. Over the next few days, every time you visit a web site or use
an Internet-based service, ask yourself: Would I be happy if I had to
pay for this? Would this even exist if the people who designed it had to
pay from day one? Make no mistake, if websites have to pay every &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; in
the country to be viewed, the days of wonderful free services sustained
by advertising revenue only will be long&amp;nbsp;gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In closing, I highly recommend reading an &lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2010/12/steve-wozniak-to-the-fcc-keep-the-internet-free/68294/"&gt;open letter on Net Neutrality
by Steve
Wozniak&lt;/a&gt;,
co-founder of Apple, genius, and guy who helped change the world as we
know&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other interesting&amp;nbsp;links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/timothy-karr/obama-fcc-caves-on-net-ne_b_799435.html"&gt;Obama &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt; Caves on Net Neutrality &amp;#8212; Tuesday Betrayal
    Assured&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huffington&amp;nbsp;Post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2010/12/21/fcc-we-didnt-impose-stricter-net-neutrality-regulations-on-wir/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt;: We didn&amp;#8217;t impose stricter net neutrality regulations on
    wireless because Android is
    open&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engadget&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://act.boldprogressives.org/sign/sign_netneutrality_3things/?akid=3050.937978.xH20je&amp;amp;rd=1&amp;amp;source=e1-netflix-fin&amp;amp;t=3"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt; breaks Obama&amp;#8217;s promise on Net Neutrality: 3 things you need to
    know&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BoldProgressives.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="free speech"></category><category term="freedom"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="net neutrality"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Comments: The Future of the Internet and How to Stop It, by Jonathan Zittrain</title><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/12/book-comments-the-future-of-the-internet-and-how-to-stop-it-by-jonathan-zittrain/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-12-03T17:34:00-05:00</published><updated>2009-12-03T17:34:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-12-03:/2009/12/book-comments-the-future-of-the-internet-and-how-to-stop-it-by-jonathan-zittrain/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week I happened to find a Barnes &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Noble gift card in my wallet,
with $75 left on it. What a wonderful discovery! One of the pile of
books that I ordered was &lt;a href="http://futureoftheinternet.org/"&gt;The Future of the Internet&amp;#8212;And How to Stop
It&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://futureoftheinternet.org/blog"&gt;by Jonathan
Zittrain&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;d fully intended …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week I happened to find a Barnes &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Noble gift card in my wallet,
with $75 left on it. What a wonderful discovery! One of the pile of
books that I ordered was &lt;a href="http://futureoftheinternet.org/"&gt;The Future of the Internet&amp;#8212;And How to Stop
It&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://futureoftheinternet.org/blog"&gt;by Jonathan
Zittrain&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;d fully intended to
read the book cover-to-cover, perhaps even digest the content a little,
before throwing my thoughts out there (presumably to get lost into the
vast sea of crap that makes up the &amp;#8220;blogosphere&amp;#8221;). But I just have to
get some thoughts down on&amp;nbsp;paper&amp;#8230;err&amp;#8230;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LCD&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, when I found out that Zittrain is a professor of Internet Law
at Harvard, it immediately told me two things. First, that he probably
sides with content producers and/or Big &amp;#8216;Net a bit too much. Second,
that he probably doesn&amp;#8217;t really understand what the hell he&amp;#8217;s talking
about, or why people made the choices they have. The fact that the first
chapter of the book, which talks about history, doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to mention
ARPAnet once only confirms this. But, the B&amp;amp;N summary sounded like the
book has a healthy dash of iPhone bashing, so I figured it&amp;#8217;s be a good
read. It was also written in 2008, so I figured that the ideas would be
&lt;em&gt;relatively current&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I&amp;#8217;m just under a quarter of the way into the book, and given the
vast mass of notes I&amp;#8217;ve penned in the margins, I think Mr/ Zittrain and
I wouldn&amp;#8217;t get along too well on a desert island. But I&amp;#8217;ll try to
contain my commentary - and attacks upon the author - until I&amp;#8217;m done
with the book. The thought currently in my mind is a very specific&amp;nbsp;one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many technologically savvy people think that bad code is simply a
Microsoft Windows issue. They believe that the Windows &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; and the
Internet Explorer browser are particularly poorly designed, and that
&amp;#8220;better&amp;#8221; counterparts (Linux and MacOS, or the Firefox and Opera
browsers) can help protect a user. This is not much added protection.
Not only do these alternative OSes and browsers have their own
vulnerabilities, but the fundamental problem is that the point of a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt;
- regardless of its &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; - is that its users can easily reconfigure it
to run new software from&amp;nbsp;anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be sure, Microsoft Windows has been the target of malware
infections for years, but this in part reflects Microsoft&amp;#8217;s dominant
market&amp;nbsp;share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, wow, is it 2004 again? I thought we&amp;#8217;d given up on the &amp;#8220;market share&amp;#8221;
argument. When Apache had 10% of the market share of web servers, people
said it wasn&amp;#8217;t attacked as often because of low market share. Well,
Apache
&lt;a href="http://news.netcraft.com/archives/2009/11/10/november_2009_web_server_survey.html"&gt;currently&lt;/a&gt;
has a 47% share of the market, compared to Microsoft&amp;#8217;s 21%, and it&amp;#8217;s
still more secure, more stable, and has fewer critical
vulnerabilities*. The same market share argument was made about Firefox
when it had 5% market share. Now, the share is projected between
&lt;a href="http://www.w3counter.com/globalstats.php"&gt;31.85%&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://www.w3schools.com/browsers/browsers_stats.asp"&gt;47%&lt;/a&gt;, and it
still has less serious vulnerabilities (ones that can actually damage
your computer) than Windows). I thought this &amp;#8220;market share&amp;#8221; argument was
done&amp;nbsp;with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most important is the thing that most Microsoft-biased pundits (and, of
course, Microsoft themselves) don&amp;#8217;t ever talk about: an amazingly large
number of servers run Linux. Especially e-commerce servers which house
loads of personal information and credit card numbers. Estimates for big
e-commerce sites put non-Windows OSes at 30-50%, and they&amp;#8217;re quite
popular among small sites that probably don&amp;#8217;t have well-trained
SysAdmins. So, if Windows wasn&amp;#8217;t really less secure, wouldn&amp;#8217;t we see
e-commerce servers getting compromised left and&amp;nbsp;right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;#8217;s a more important point here. It&amp;#8217;s about curtailing the
stupidity of users. I know, in Microsoft&amp;#8217;s defense, that Windows Vista
and Windows 7 are supposed to be better with this. But, at least in the
past, Windows had virtually no privilege separation. With a little code,
you could effect the whole system from an arbitrary binary - or worse,
with ActiveX, through the browser. I was dumbfounded that any user could
install a system-wide application. The real issue here, at least with
older Windows (I don&amp;#8217;t know much about the new ones) is that Windows,
from the beginning, wasn&amp;#8217;t written to be secure. Heck, it wasn&amp;#8217;t even
designed to be attached to a real&amp;nbsp;network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux does have real security advantages over Windows, and not just
because it has low market share. First is an actual, true implementation
of privilege separation. No matter what I do in my desktop web browser,
no matter what I run, even if I installed a Firefox plugin that wanted
to destroy my machine, it couldn&amp;#8217;t happen. No matter what I let some
random code do, it simply can&amp;#8217;t escape the confines of my user&amp;nbsp;account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, ok, I know what you&amp;#8217;re all saying right now. I can hear it from
here: &amp;#8220;but what if the moron does everything as root? what if they just
sudo anything that they&amp;#8217;re asked about?&amp;#8221; Well, I have answers to that,
too. My own distro of choice, &lt;a href="http://www.opensuse.org"&gt;OpenSuSE&lt;/a&gt;
greatly upset me when I went to install 11.1, and the installer showed a
default of one user account, automatic login, and the same password for
the user and root. That&amp;#8217;s just stupid. In fact, it&amp;#8217;s braindead, plain
and simple. I don&amp;#8217;t care how wonderful it would be to get Linux on every
desktop in the world, if we have to destroy every advantage that Linux
has over other OSes, it will be&amp;nbsp;worthless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I digress. In the end, it boils down to user education. And, in some
respects, I think that Linux has become too dumbed-down. There are
certain things that simply shouldn&amp;#8217;t be put in a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt;. Excuse my elitism,
but if you can&amp;#8217;t figure out how to configure Apache correctly from the
command line, you have no business running an Apache installation. The
same goes for countless other services and applications. So, what&amp;#8217;s my
solution? Well, here&amp;#8217;s what I do when I install Linux for non-technical
friends. Some of these things are training items, others are things that
I do in terms of configuration and, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IMHO&lt;/span&gt;, should be &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;/distro defaults
(unless you know some esoteric hidden switch to change&amp;nbsp;them).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable graphical login as root. This enforces proper use of sudo,
    and also prevents a user from becoming lazy and operating as root on
    a regular&amp;nbsp;basis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick a good, strong root password. Write it down on a post-it note
    and keep it somewhere near the computer. (Yes, I know what you&amp;#8217;re
    thinking. But if it&amp;#8217;s a home computer, anyone already in the house
    either is trusted, or will own the computer one way or another. I&amp;#8217;d
    rather have everyone in the house have access to the box, than a
    password that a remote attacker can easily brute&amp;nbsp;force.)*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable caching of sudo passwords in the desktop manager, if it
    already isn&amp;#8217;t done. This is a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; bad idea, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IMHO&lt;/span&gt;, and
    effectively defeats privilege separation. If someone needs to use
    sudo &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; often, they&amp;#8217;re either a knowledgeable user, or they&amp;#8217;re
    doing something&amp;nbsp;wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set the package manager to use the strictest key verification&amp;nbsp;settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide the user with extensive documentation (can be a list of
    links to helpful sites) that includes - &lt;em&gt;this is of paramount
    importance&lt;/em&gt; - a list of common Windows (or whatever &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; they&amp;#8217;re
    coming from) programs and their closest Linux equivalents. This is
    another measure to try and dissuade the user from searching for and
    installing arbitrary&amp;nbsp;code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give the user a good, simple explanation of what sudo is, what root
    is, and why they should be worried. One of my analogies - if I have
    time to explain it - is to think of the computer&amp;#8217;s security like a
    jewlery store. Your user account is the front door; only people who
    look honest are buzzed in, but they still can&amp;#8217;t do much damage. The
    root password is the combination to the vault; only very trusted
    people can get in, and they only open it when they absolutely have&amp;nbsp;to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable a wide range of trusted repositories by default. The more
    likely the user is to find a package in the repos already cached,
    the less likely they are to download arbitrary&amp;nbsp;code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain to the user that when you install software (as root), you&amp;#8217;re
    essentially giving the developer access to your system. Software
    should be screened by someone who knows what they&amp;#8217;re doing (i.e. the
    community) before you install&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I always tell people to *only* install software from the
    repositories I enable. If there&amp;#8217;s something they need and it isn&amp;#8217;t
    available, ask me (or ask the community) and I&amp;#8217;ll make a package and
    upload it to a suitable repository. The key here - and the most
    difficult part - is to conquer the Windows habit of installing
    software from disparate sources, and train the user that only
    software from their repositories, or other community-standard
    repositories, can be&amp;nbsp;trusted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show the user the correct patch/update procedure for their system.
    Depending on skill level and the level of attention you&amp;#8217;re willing
    to give them, it might be advisable to enable automatic updates (if
    the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; doesn&amp;#8217;t have a way to do it, then via&amp;nbsp;cron).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the user is a developer or needs to run any services, even just
    for development - i.e. Apache, MySQL, Postfix, etc. - properly
    secure them and give an overview &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; links to the proper security&amp;nbsp;procedures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup a second user account. Explain to the user that this is &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt;
    to be used for banking and other sensitive activities. Lock it down,
    make sure it&amp;#8217;s in a different group from the main user, don&amp;#8217;t
    install any Firefox&amp;nbsp;plugins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfotunately, a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of this is just breaking the bad administration
and security habits shared by most Windows&amp;nbsp;users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we&amp;#8217;re on the topic, a word about package managers. I&amp;#8217;m a Linux
sysadmin, and I believe in &amp;#8216;eating your own dog food&amp;#8217;. I&amp;#8217;ve used Linux
on all of my servers, desktops, and laptops for over 4 years now. I
haven&amp;#8217;t used Windows on a regular basis in ages. I&amp;#8217;d say I touch a
Windows box for about 5 minutes a month, and usually just to use a
browser. A few weeks ago, I was asked to install Windows on a desktop
for someone. I did. I then attempted to install Firefox. Using what I
remembered of Windows, I navigated to the &amp;#8220;Control Panel&amp;#8221; and clicked
(err&amp;#8230; double clicked) on &amp;#8220;Add and Remove Programs&amp;#8221;. Seems logical
enough. I then stared at the screen for about 30 seconds, trying to find
the Search box, where I could type in &amp;#8220;Firefox&amp;#8221;. Finally, I literally
began laughing out loud, when I remembered that Windows doesn&amp;#8217;t have
unified package management, and I&amp;#8217;d need to manually find the Firefox
binary on their web site, download it, and run whatever installer
program Firefox chooses to use. Same issue with updating software. I&amp;#8217;m
utterly perplexed, being a Linux user, that Windows and Mac people still
search through Google or multiple web sites just to find new software.
I&amp;#8217;m even more perplexed that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; update/patch program doesn&amp;#8217;t also
update all of the software on the system. It seems like the stone&amp;nbsp;ages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, one of the biggest failings of modern Linux package
management is the assumption (derived from multi-user systems) that all
software should be installed system-wide. Granted, it doesn&amp;#8217;t do a whole
lot to actually protect a single user if they install malicious software
available to just themselves (especially since most desktop installs
these days are probably used as single-user systems), but I really feel
that distros (especially desktop-oriented distros) should have an option
to easily install packages for just the current user, and possibly do
this by&amp;nbsp;default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t find the link right now, but I did find an interesting
article on Microsoft&amp;#8217;s old anti-Linux campaign (&amp;#8220;get the facts&amp;#8221;). One of
the things mentioned was that when Microsoft compared &amp;#8220;vulnerability
counts&amp;#8221;, they were actually comparing: 1) entire Linux distros vs just
the core Windows &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;, and 2) counting individual patches in Linux versus
patch sets released by &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt;. So, not only was &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt; literally counting apples
and oranges, but they were totally ignoring unfixed vulnerabilities.
Given Microsoft&amp;#8217;s habit of not fixing vulnerabilities - especially in
&amp;#8220;unsupported&amp;#8221; products - it&amp;#8217;s no wonder how they got the numbers to look
so&amp;nbsp;good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here&amp;#8217;s a thought. People are used to paying for an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; and for
software. Start a Linux vendor that sells a desktop, newbie-oriented
Linux distro. Charge a per-user flat rate for the distro and a bunch of
base packages, that includes X hours of telephone support. Charge per
hour/minute/whatever for additional support. Bundle in secure &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VNC&lt;/span&gt;,
secure remote access, etc. in a way that will allow support to remotely
access the computer, but preserve the privacy and security of the user
(perhaps an app that allows the user to initiate a reverse &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VNC&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt;
session to support). Lock down root access - allow the user to do it,
but remind them every time that, outside of a specified set of commands,
their actions will be logged and won&amp;#8217;t get full support. Then figure out
a way for support to write a shell script that&amp;#8217;s sent to the user to
perform administrative actions, which will all be listed in relatively
simple terms for the user to examine and approve. Finally, have a
&lt;em&gt;giant&lt;/em&gt; package repo, all of which is free or comes with paid support.
Any F/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt; packages that aren&amp;#8217;t already in the repo can be requested by a
customer, and for a flat fee for the first requesting customer (say,
$10) will be examined, approved, packaged, and added to the&amp;nbsp;repo.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="book"></category><category term="freedom"></category><category term="internet"></category></entry><entry><title>PCpro UK: Boycott ad-blocking Firefox, urges furious web designer</title><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/09/pcpro-uk-boycott-ad-blocking-firefox-urges-furious-web-designer/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-09-17T14:04:00-04:00</published><updated>2007-09-17T14:04:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-09-17:/2007/09/pcpro-uk-boycott-ad-blocking-firefox-urges-furious-web-designer/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When browsing through &lt;a href="http://digg.com/"&gt;Digg&lt;/a&gt; this morning, I came by a
story at PCpro &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt; entitled &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://www.pcpro.co.uk/news/news/124719/"&gt;Boycott ad-blocking Firefox, urges furious
web designer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;. This gentleman
stated that, &amp;#8220;Software that
blocks all advertisement is an infringement of the rights of website
owners and&amp;nbsp;developers.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I don&amp;#8217;t like giving press to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When browsing through &lt;a href="http://digg.com/"&gt;Digg&lt;/a&gt; this morning, I came by a
story at PCpro &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt; entitled &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://www.pcpro.co.uk/news/news/124719/"&gt;Boycott ad-blocking Firefox, urges furious
web designer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;. This gentleman
stated that, &amp;#8220;Software that
blocks all advertisement is an infringement of the rights of website
owners and&amp;nbsp;developers.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I don&amp;#8217;t like giving press to such a story, I found it alarming on
many&amp;nbsp;levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I&amp;#8217;ve never heard of rights of website owners and developers.
Being a &amp;#8220;website owner and developer&amp;#8221; myself, I understand that the web
is a dynamic medium. Moreover, I think of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; as what it is - a markup
language. It just tells a program (browser) how to display something in
a user-friendly style. I test my pages with Lynx, and expect them to
conform to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;/1.1. In other words, I believe that the Internet is an
information distribution tool. I expect, I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt;, my content to be
viewable by as many people as possible. I try to use simple markup and
make use of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ALT&lt;/span&gt; tags so that as many people as possible will be able to
view the content. I want it to make sense on as many platforms as
possible. I want people who need accessibility aids to be able to
understand it. In short, I want my content to reach as many people as&amp;nbsp;possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only is this developer trying to do something which is ignorant and
a case of being a flat-out bad citizen of the &amp;#8216;net, but he is trying to
fight against the progress which has so painstakingly been made in the
field of web standardization. I well remember when, not long ago at all,
I was handicapped by my choice of using Firefox. I still come by the odd
site which chose to use a component which is tied to Internet Explorer,
thereby alienating 35% of web&amp;nbsp;users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will admit that I am by no means the typical Internet user. The fact
that all of my some dozen or so machines (excepting one which I need to
use a legacy &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCSI&lt;/span&gt; flatbed scanner) run 100% Free/Open Source software. I
use Linux. OpenSolaris. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BSD&lt;/span&gt;. I believe that I have a right to examine
and modify the source code of the programs that I use. When choosing a
bug tracking system, I spent hours customizing an open-source
alternative because I was unwilling to use the closed-source option
which seemed to fit best. Therefore, I guess it is easy to understand
that I refuse to buy from, or even visit, a web site that doesn&amp;#8217;t
support&amp;nbsp;Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a browser war. This is not me simply deciding to flame
someone who isn&amp;#8217;t a F/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt; zealot. This boils down to a deeper issue that
can be seen all around us - including in the recent news surrounding the
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s auction of a portion of the 700MHz spectrum. The issue at hand
is the complacency of technology users, and the feeling by technology
providers that they can push anything they want on users. The concept
that providers are sending data to me, and that I can use that data
however I want (within the extent of the law) is getting&amp;nbsp;lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I watch &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;, I used to leave the room or pick up a book when a
commercial comes on. Now that I have a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PVR&lt;/span&gt; (specifically, MythTV), I can
record the shows I want, and then have commercials flagged for automatic
skipping before I watch them. When I decide to watch them, I have no
commercials. When I use the web, I select the content that I want. If I
don&amp;#8217;t want it, I don&amp;#8217;t get&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, another large issue at hand is the simple nature of digital
media. This applies to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; recording, music and movie sharing, software
piracy, etc. Digital media is not the same as analog media. An &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MP3&lt;/span&gt; (or,
for that matter, a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt;) is not the same as a tape. In product litigation,
there is a term known as &amp;#8220;perceived use&amp;#8221;. If you make a glass coffee
table that is exactly at knee height, it is perceived that eventually,
someone will try to sit on it. That&amp;#8217;s common sense. If it shatters and
kills them, it was your responsibility to foresee such an obvious
eventuality. It&amp;#8217;s only common sense that if something is flat and at
normal sitting level, someone will try to sit on&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, I would argue that when any content is distributed digitally,
you must foresee that it will be copied or altered. It is simply the
nature of the medium. If the recording industry didn&amp;#8217;t want people
ripping music from CDs, they should have kept releasing things on tape.
Even more so with DVDs - I&amp;#8217;m sure we all remember the push. Five years
ago, I was hard pressed to find a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt; in a local rental store. Today, I
haven&amp;#8217;t seen a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHS&lt;/span&gt; tape in years. The industry *pushed* the format on
us, and is now complaining when we use it in a brutally obvious way. If
I had to liken it to any legal phenomenon, I would pick entrapment. It&amp;#8217;s
not a far stretch to compare the recording industry&amp;#8217;s actions to those
of a police officer who leaves a car running, with the keys in the
ignition, and a sign on the windshield that says &amp;#8220;Take me for a spin
around the parking lot&amp;#8221; and then arrests someone for auto theft when
they leave the lot. If they industry is worried about piracy, it should
have been their obligation to look into exactly how easy piracy would
be, before they chose a distribution&amp;nbsp;medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In closing my rant, I will ask a few simple&amp;nbsp;questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it that the law, being as biased to corporate interests (and
against the individual) as it is, doesn&amp;#8217;t recognize the rights of the
individual to use what they legally purchased in a way that they see
fit? (i.e. if I buy a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt;, I should be able to make a backup copy on my
computer - even the &lt;em&gt;copyright law&lt;/em&gt; states&amp;nbsp;that).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long will it be before someone turns up an internal &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIAA&lt;/span&gt; memo
from ten years ago stating that the industry could increase its&amp;#8217; profits
by releasing music on a medium (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt;) that is prone to piracy, and then
fining the people who exploit that common&amp;nbsp;sense?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When they came out with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHS&lt;/span&gt; recorders, the industry was up in arms
about piracy. So, they got together and added a small amount on the
price of every blank tape, intended to reimburse the
labels/artists/networks for the copy that it would be used to make. Why
can&amp;#8217;t they just tack $3 onto every blank &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt;, $20 on every blank
hard drive, and stop suing college&amp;nbsp;kids?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="ad blocker"></category><category term="firefox"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="standards"></category></entry></feed>