<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/isp.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://newblog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2008-04-22T15:52:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Web Traffic for JasonAntman.com - Webalizer, Site Maps</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2008/04/web-traffic-for-jasonantmancom-webalizer-site-maps/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-04-22T15:52:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2008-04-22:2008/04/web-traffic-for-jasonantmancom-webalizer-site-maps/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been working on the design of a town council campaign site for a
friend - &lt;a href="http://www.mikennick08.com/"&gt;www.mikennick08.com&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s hosted
by an additional Apache vhost on my personal server (and running off of
port 10015 - ugh). I setup &lt;a href="http://www.mrunix.net/webalizer/"&gt;Webalizer&lt;/a&gt;
for him, so I figured I&amp;#8217;d give my own webalizer installation a check.
Wow - 30,215 hits this month alone. That reminded me of a problem with
my ignored hosts - 17,600 of those hits were Googlebot, and another
2,065 were Yandex (a Russian search&amp;nbsp;engine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazingly, though, it seems like Google is only indexing my blog. My
precious wiki seems out of whack, not to metion my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this reminded me of two long-overdue&amp;nbsp;tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get webalizer to properly ignore the common&amp;nbsp;bots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get sitemaps of my entire&amp;nbsp;site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, off to the&amp;nbsp;races!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I added Googlebot, Yandex, and a few others to webalizer.conf
with IgnoreAgent directives. Then, after clearing out my entire output
directory - and waiting a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LONG&lt;/span&gt; time for it to run - bingo! Real stats.
Down to about 8000 hits for the month, which seems more logical, even
including the \~2,000 hits from Google&amp;nbsp;feedfetcher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next stop was sitemaps. It tooks some &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; magic to hack apart the
MediaWiki sitemaps, put in the correct URLs (it was showing an
internal-only hostname), and drop all that and my Blogger rss.xml in an
index file. It&amp;#8217;s now 2 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt;, and it just crashed and burned - the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;
script worked fine, but for some reason my entries in
sitemaps_index.xml - which pointed to sitemaps in a subdirectory - came
back with errors. Well, something to work on&amp;nbsp;tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning I checked my backups and noticed that nothing had run in 3
days. It turns out I just had one failed job holding everything up. And
I screwed up - I was home this weekend and forgot to swap tapes. It&amp;#8217;ll
be another 2 weeks before I can. But, I took the time to setup a backup
status box on my administrative portal (more on that later) and will
also be revising my apparently ineffectual Nagios check&amp;nbsp;script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a few side notes: First, I&amp;#8217;m seriously thinking of dumping Verizon
FiOS. While I really like the service, their static &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; (business)
variant is $100/month for 15 Mbps down / 2 Mbps up, whereas
Cablevision&amp;#8217;s Optimum Business with static &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; is $55/month for 30 Mbps
down / 5 Mbps&amp;nbsp;up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the previous projects have been put on hold for the time being
(mainly because of impending final exams at school) - the new Gigabit
Ethernet switch for backups, testing Zenoss and upgrading monitoring (to
a new product or Nagios 3),&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bacula"></category><category term="bandwidth"></category><category term="connectivity"></category><category term="ISP"></category><category term="Nagios"></category><category term="webalizer"></category></entry></feed>