<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://newblog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/jobs.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2010 10:48:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hiring Technical People</title><link>http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2010/03/hiring-technical-people/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After seeing a link to it on the &lt;a href="http://www.sage.org"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SAGE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; mailing
list, I happened to read Mark Dennehy&amp;#8217;sblog post on &lt;a href="http://www.stochasticgeometry.ie/2008/04/25/tips-for-hiring-new-engineers/"&gt;Tips for hiring new
engineers&lt;/a&gt;.
I felt the need to make a few comments on some of his findings. Perhaps
someone in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt;, or a recruiter, will actually read this and learn a thing
or&amp;nbsp;two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basics of professional work – getting along with others, being
able to manage your time, being able to communicate clearly and well,
being able to work to deadlines – it is a waste of your time and mine
to put these in the job advert. You aren’t taking random people off
the street here – you’re hiring trained professionals who’ve working
in this field for some time. It’s nearly insulting to tell them not to
apply unless they play well with&amp;nbsp;others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there are some places where this is required. In the
public sector, at least, the job ad and description set up fixed
guidelines. If you have a job description that doesn&amp;#8217;t include &amp;#8220;plays
well with others&amp;#8221;, and the hire doesn&amp;#8217;t play well with others, it&amp;#8217;s
immensely difficult to fire them - the hire&amp;#8217;s failing wasn&amp;#8217;t listed in
the job&amp;nbsp;description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t have the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt; people write the technical requirements. You have
engineers, use&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to whole-heartedly agree with what Mark said about writing
technical requirements. I don&amp;#8217;t know why &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt; seems to think that they can
write &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; job descriptions - they wouldn&amp;#8217;t attempt it for most other
professionals. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; job descriptions should be left to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; people to write
- and, more importantly, people who actually understand what the person
will be&amp;nbsp;doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don’t class all those requirements as being absolutely necessary.
Have two lists – critical, mandatory skills; and skills which would be
advantageous to have. Because many professional engineers will look at
the mandatory skills listed and if we see some we don’t have, we won’t&amp;nbsp;apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also a very good point. Even when I&amp;#8217;m not actively looking for work, I
usually get a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of phone calls and emails from recruiters.
Especially if I update my resume on one of the big job sites or post a
consulting ad on CraigsList, I get inundated with emails and phone calls
(which I usually refer to email, unless they&amp;#8217;re from a big player). I
can&amp;#8217;t possibly spend the hours to read and apply to all of them. The
first ones that get deleted are from people who obvously didn&amp;#8217;t even
look at my resume - entry-level (operator) positions, Windows admins,
anything with a primary duty that isn&amp;#8217;t even near my skill set (i.e.
they just used keyword matching and never read&amp;nbsp;anything).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, I start looking through the descriptions and building two
lists - the ones that will likely get thrown out unless there&amp;#8217;s some
amazing thing that redeems them (i.e. a company that I really want to
work for) and the ones that I know I&amp;#8217;ll follow up on. Here are some of
the criteria I&amp;nbsp;use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Likely to&amp;nbsp;ignore:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read the job description and still can&amp;#8217;t figure out what I&amp;#8217;d be&amp;nbsp;doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The buzzword-to-content ratio is&amp;nbsp;horrible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The skills/requirements section lists every hot technology - a list
    that no human being can&amp;nbsp;master.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The skills/requirements section has far too disparate of a list -
    something that only an engineer, administrator, programmer, and
    hardware designer could&amp;nbsp;master.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow-up:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use of the &lt;a href="http://www.sage.org/field/jobs-descriptions.html"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SAGE&lt;/span&gt; Job
    Descriptions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An actual salary range, not &amp;#8220;varies with experience&amp;#8221; or&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;competitive&amp;#8221;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some description of &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;#8217;ll work - size of the team,
    responsibility, work environment,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examples of current things the team is working on, or examples of
    what I&amp;#8217;d be working&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skills/requirements broken down into mandatory and&amp;nbsp;optional/preferred.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A description that was obviously written by someone who understands
    the&amp;nbsp;technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In closing, I have a theory for companies (especially those in the
public sector that have stringent &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt;/hiring policies) listing jobs in
the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; sector: have both &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; write portions of the job
description. Have &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt; write a paragraph or two with all of their
non-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt;-specific stuff, and then have the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; hiring people (preferably
the manager the new hire will report to) write the rest. Put the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt;
stuff at the bottom. Break the skills/requirements lists down into
&amp;#8220;Technical Skills&amp;#8221; (further divided into Required and
Preferred/Optional/Bonus) and a &amp;#8220;Soft Skills&amp;#8221; section for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt; (with the
usual crap like &amp;#8220;works with a team&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;eligible for employment&amp;#8221;,&amp;nbsp;etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone&amp;#8217;s up in arms about the recession, high unemployment, and low
job openings. Logic would dictate that it&amp;#8217;s an employer&amp;#8217;s market - and,
to a large extent, it is. However, that doesn&amp;#8217;t mean that employers
don&amp;#8217;t need to worry about making the advertisement attractive and
descriptive. Actually, I&amp;#8217;d say it&amp;#8217;s the opposite - since I know that
there will likely be hundreds of other applicants, I only send a resume
in for jobs that I think I have a very good chance of getting. I&amp;#8217;m sure
I&amp;#8217;ve skipped over good positions just because the description didn&amp;#8217;t
communicate that to me - and I&amp;#8217;m sure I&amp;#8217;m not&amp;nbsp;alone.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2010 10:48:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2010-03-07:2010/03/hiring-technical-people/</guid><category>hiring</category><category>hr</category><category>jobs</category></item></channel></rss>