<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/lcd-projector-sflc-busybox-microsoft-windows-tv-streaming.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2007-12-07T16:29:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Windows advances, Cutting out the middle-man</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/12/windows-advances-cutting-out-the-middle-man/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-12-07T16:29:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-12-07:2007/12/windows-advances-cutting-out-the-middle-man/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I have a nice weekend of real-world non-technical activities ahead of
me. A welcome end to a week of insanely busy school work, and a welcome
break before the threat of exams 2 weeks away becomes real. I&amp;#8217;ve been
working on a few projects - centralized logging and analysis, some way
to easily tie Nagios, log analysis, traffic analysis, etc. into a
one-look heads-up display, and a few other things. I even got the power
adapter for my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LCD&lt;/span&gt; so that I can have a try at the &lt;a href="http://www.tomsguide.com/us/supersize-your-tv-for,review-342.html"&gt;giant wall-size &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LCD&lt;/span&gt;
projector&lt;/a&gt;.
However, reading through my usual &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; feeds today, I felt the urge to
comment on a few&amp;nbsp;things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, for those who haven&amp;#8217;t heard, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SFLC&lt;/span&gt; and the BusyBox developers
have filed &lt;a href="http://www.softwarefreedom.org/news/2007/dec/07/busybox/"&gt;another
lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;
alleging &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt; violations, this time against Verizon for distributing an
Actiontec router to FiOS customers, sans source code. I&amp;#8217;m a FiOS
customer (in fact, the very text you&amp;#8217;re looking at is coming to you
courtesy of residential fiber) but got in on the wagon before they were
giving away these &amp;#8220;fancy&amp;#8221; routers. It&amp;#8217;s good to see, though, that the
F/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt; world is standing up for its&amp;#8217; values, and perhaps the mainstream
proprietary world will start to understand that just because you can
give a copy of BusyBox to your friends doesn&amp;#8217;t mean they can disregard
the&amp;nbsp;license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Windows Advances?&lt;/strong&gt;
I came by &lt;a href="http://blogs.ittoolbox.com/linux/locutus/archives/if-the-gui-is-so-good-then-why-is-microsoft-dropping-it-20951?e=unrec#commentsForm"&gt;this blog
post&lt;/a&gt;
discussing the fact that, apparently, Windows 2008 is going to be able
to be installed in a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt;-only (yes, that&amp;#8217;s right, no &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt;)&amp;nbsp;mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not going to preach about Microsoft turning unix-y. Rather, I think
it just reiterates something that I&amp;#8217;ve said time and time
again:&lt;em&gt;I&amp;#8217;m setting up a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; server.
It&amp;#8217;s going to be administered in a web &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; or by scripts. Why should I
tie up &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt; and processor cycles to display a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; that, if the system
works right, will never be looked&amp;nbsp;at?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than seeing this
as some victory for Linux, Unix, etc., I take it a bit more
realistically (though still, perhaps, over-optimistically):
Maybe Microsoft is finally realizing that their one-size-fits-all
mentality doesn&amp;#8217;t work. That people want options. And, even more
mysteriously, that not everyone wants to have to buy the newest hardware
just to run an&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cutting out the Middle Man:&lt;/strong&gt;
I found and &lt;a href="http://www.internetnews.com/stats/article.php/3655796"&gt;article at
internetnews.com&lt;/a&gt;
entitled
&amp;#8220;The Young, Smart And Loaded Watch Online &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221;. Many parts of it
saddened me - like the thought of allowing providers to push
advertisement through my computer, or tracking my viewing habits in
great&amp;nbsp;detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this is something that&amp;#8217;s occurred to me many times. Firstly, I
already use &lt;a href="http://www.mythtv.org/"&gt;MythTV&lt;/a&gt; to watch tv. So,
realistically, I&amp;#8217;m already watching &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; on a computer. I have broadband
in both my home and apartment (and anywhere else I&amp;#8217;d want to be). I have
a coaxial cable coming from the wall, plugged into my computer. And I
have to hook a tuner up and capture the video. Why not cut out the
middle&amp;nbsp;man?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pay Cablevision somewhere around $30/month for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;. That covers not
only the content, but also the costs for them to maintain a vast network
of cable lines stretching from where-ever to my house. I already have
broadband, why not just get &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; over&amp;nbsp;that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, I doubt any provider would give me what I want. But let&amp;#8217;s
think about it for a moment. Their only cost is a datacenter somewhere.
I simply connect to a somehow-authenticated video stream over my
existing broadband connection, and watch &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;! All they need is a contract
to rebroadcast. They can even pay on a per-view basis, as they would be
able to tell who&amp;#8217;s connected to what at a given time. They just need a
data center with a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LOT&lt;/span&gt; of bandwidth, some sattelite or fiber video
lines, and a system to capture each channel they offer. It then just
gets&amp;nbsp;streamed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds wonderful to me. I&amp;#8217;m already paying for high-bandwidth, why not
pay a third-party to stream &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; to me instead of paying the cable
company? They don&amp;#8217;t need to maintain anywhere near the level of
infrastructure - no physical cabling, no satellites, and QoS would be
determined by each individuals&amp;#8217; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;. It would even allow me to have one
account and watch at home, at my apartment, or at&amp;nbsp;work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The catch, at least for me? Well, while this might be viable, the odds
are there would be a proprietary viewer application. That&amp;#8217;s bad.
Firstly, it&amp;#8217;s useless if you can&amp;#8217;t record it and watch it later, or
transfer it to another computer. But more importantly, the odds of such
a company embracing a standardized technology (like just streaming
everything over the web and depending on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSL&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt;-based
authentication) that will run on my Linux boxen is pretty&amp;nbsp;slim.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="lcd projector sflc busybox microsoft windows tv streaming"></category></entry></feed>