<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/mantis.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2008-12-17T16:44:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Verizon Wireless uses Mantis for ticketing</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/12/verizon-wireless-uses-mantis-for-ticketing/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-12-17T16:44:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-12-17:2008/12/verizon-wireless-uses-mantis-for-ticketing/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many times, I&amp;#8217;ve wished that I paid the $20 to get software for my &lt;a href="http://www.palm.com/us/products/smartphones/treo700p/"&gt;Treo
700p&lt;/a&gt; to record
phone calls. About a month or two ago, I had some issues with my phone
and had to call Verizon Wireless. The poor woman was trying to open a
ticket for me, but said that she was having some problems, as they were
moving from one ticketing system to another, she was having some issues
with the new one, and the old one was down at her&amp;nbsp;location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As she waited for a rep from another location to come on the line and
enter the ticket, I happened to remark that I work in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; and had been
doing some work with them (&lt;a href="http://eventum.mysql.com"&gt;Eventum&lt;/a&gt;) lately.
She mentioned that the old one was a proprietary system, but asked if
I&amp;#8217;d ever heard of &lt;a href="http://www.mantisbt.org/"&gt;Mantis&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, I said
that I had. And was then asked if I knew much about it, and whether I
might know what the problem she was having was caused by. Unfortunately,
I had to say no, as I&amp;#8217;d never used it for more than a few minutes. But I
did get to confirm that a company as large and closed (they won&amp;#8217;t
support Linux, their phones run closed &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s, and they block my port 80)
as Verizon is happily transitioning from closed-source proprietary
software to a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;d alternative. I also got another item to add to my
list of telephone tech support people who have asked me (the customer)
for&amp;nbsp;support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I don&amp;#8217;t see Verizon listed on the list of &lt;a href="http://www.mantisbt.org/directory.php"&gt;known Mantis
users&lt;/a&gt;, so I have no way to fully
confirm&amp;nbsp;this.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="mantis"></category><category term="ticketing"></category><category term="verizon"></category></entry></feed>