<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/microsoft.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://newblog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2012-04-24T21:18:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>SysAdmin Links of The Day</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2012/04/sysadmin-links-of-the-day/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-24T21:18:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2012-04-24:2012/04/sysadmin-links-of-the-day/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few links that I&amp;#8217;ve had in my &amp;#8220;mention in a blog post&amp;#8221; category for a&amp;nbsp;while:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazure/archive/2012/03/09/summary-of-windows-azure-service-disruption-on-feb-29th-2012.aspx"&gt;Summary of Windows Azure Service Disruption on Feb 29th, 2012 -
    Windows Azure - Site Home - &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MSDN&lt;/span&gt;
    Blogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; detailed and interesting post on what caused the Windows
Azure cloud outage on February 29th, 2012. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IMHO&lt;/span&gt; many of these
failures were predictable, and the bulk of the outage was caused by
a combination of inputs not being checked for validity in code, or
the invalid case not being handled&amp;nbsp;properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://highscalability.com/blog/2012/3/12/google-taming-the-long-latency-tail-when-more-machines-equal.html"&gt;High Scalability - High Scalability - Google: Taming the Long
    Latency Tail - When More Machines Equals Worse&amp;nbsp;Results&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://everythingsysadmin.com/2012/03/fear-of-rebooting.html"&gt;Everything Sysadmin: Fear of&amp;nbsp;Rebooting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://everythingsysadmin.com/2012/03/using-statements-of-undeniable.html"&gt;Everything Sysadmin: Using statements of &amp;#8220;Undeniable&amp;nbsp;Value&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="azure"></category><category term="failure"></category><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="sysadmin"></category></entry><entry><title>Leap Year Windows Azure Cloud Outage</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2012/03/leap-year-windows-azure-cloud-outage/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-20T18:12:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2012-03-20:2012/03/leap-year-windows-azure-cloud-outage/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#8217;t talked about Microsoft in quite a while (mainly because I
don&amp;#8217;t follow mainstream tech news as much anymore), but I happened by a
very interesting &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazure/archive/2012/03/09/summary-of-windows-azure-service-disruption-on-feb-29th-2012.aspx"&gt;post on the Windows Azure
blog&lt;/a&gt;
the other day. It&amp;#8217;s a very detailed postmortem of the major outage of
the Windows Azure cloud service which occurred from 4:00 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PST&lt;/span&gt; on
February 28&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; through 2:15 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt; on March 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;. Before I get into any of
the details, I should say that it really is a nice, well-done post. And
the fact that they&amp;#8217;re willing to do such a detailed, public postmortem -
and admit the failures that they did - is a step in the right direction
for Microsoft (a company that I don&amp;#8217;t particularly care for, to put it&amp;nbsp;lightly).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m going to glance over the majority of the post, though I highly
recommend that anyone interested in running web-scale services,
specifically highly available ones, read it. The general overview
(really just the points that are germane to my discussion) is as
follows: An agent running inside the guest &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VM&lt;/span&gt; instances (i.e. domU)
communicates with a counterpart on the host &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; (i.e. dom0) over an
encrypted channel, authenticated by certificate. The certs are generated
and passed from the guest to the host when the guest instance is first
initialized, which means when an app is first deployed, scaled out, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;
updated, or when an app is reinitialized on a new host. This cert was
generated for a 1-year validity period, by adding 1 to the integer year
- hence, the generation process failed on February 29th of a leap year,
as the cert end date wasn&amp;#8217;t valid. When the cert generation failed, the
guest agent essentially stopped cold. The host agent waited for a 25
minute timeout, then re-initialized the guest and started over. After
three of these failures, the host assumes there&amp;#8217;s a hardware error
(since the guest would have reported a more specific error otherwise),
declares itself in an error state, and tries to move its current
workload over to another host. Which re-initializes the guests on that
host, thereby causing a chain-reaction of failures in this case. Skip
forward the 2-1/2 hours it took them to identify the problem, and
further 2-1/2 hours to get a fix ready. They fast-tracked their fix to 7
clusters that had already been in the process of a software update, but
ended up with those clusters in an inconsistent state with
incompatibilities between the guest and host networking subsystems,
bringing down previously-unaffected instances on these&amp;nbsp;clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole scenario offers a few important points on both the
development and operations&amp;nbsp;sides:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inputs need error checking, and errors need to be raised.&lt;/strong&gt; So the
first problem here was the failed cert generation. I&amp;#8217;ll leave alone the
fact that, in my opinion, doing math on a the integer year of a date is
a high school or college programming mistake, and never should have been
made by someone doing platform coding for a major company (believe it or
not, 25% of years are leap years &amp;lt;/sarcasm&gt;). If whatever code was
generating the cert was smart enough to check the cert end date validity
and error out, that error should have been pushed up the stack to
somewhere where it could be handled - or, at least, sent to a central
log server that does error&amp;nbsp;trending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure communications when provisioning need an insecure error path.&lt;/strong&gt;
This is somewhat connected to the previous point. If the normal process
of creating a new instance and communicating errors up the stack relies
on certs and authentication or encryption, there should be some method
of communicating errors with &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; process either up the stack, or to a
separate event correlation/trending system. Errors with a
certificate-based system are not unusual, and even something as simple
as a vastly incorrect time set on the guests could have caused this same
problem. In environments where management/control communication between
levels of a system are encrypted or authenticated, there should be some
way for lower levels of the system to deliver a meaningful error message
&amp;#8220;somewhere&amp;#8221;. Even if this is just a syslog server or web service that
listens for errors and can escalate a warning when the numbers spike,
it&amp;#8217;s a useful alarm and debugging&amp;nbsp;tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autonomous systems shouldn&amp;#8217;t lightly assume hardware failures.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;#8217;s
arrogance for a host system to assume that just because it can&amp;#8217;t
instantiate new guests, a hardware failure exists. This entire incident
is a perfect example that, at least if hardware error indicators are
properly monitored, it&amp;#8217;s more likely for a software problem to be
falsely identified as a hardware problem than the other way around. All
of my points are somewhat related, but I can think of many more reasons
why a new guest can&amp;#8217;t be instantiated that are software-related rather
than&amp;nbsp;hardware-related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autonomous control mechanisms need historical trending, and need to
call for help if this looks wrong.&lt;/strong&gt; These host systems tried to
instantiate new guests three times, waiting 25 minutes in between, and
then declared themselves bad and tried to migrate guests to other hosts.
From what I understand, Microsoft got it right in having a &amp;#8220;kill switch&amp;#8221;
that prevented further migration of guests. What they didn&amp;#8217;t have right
was reporting of autonomous actions (guest migration) to a central
location that performs trending. The 25 minute timeout with three
attempts is a great safety feature, but if the status of guest creation
actions was reported to a central server, it would have been much more
quickly apparent that 100% of guest creations in the past, say, 10
minutes, had failed - across all clusters. I know plenty of shops that
do little, if any, real-time analysis and historical comparisons of
their log data. But when systems are designed to perform self-healing
and autonomous actions, it&amp;#8217;s imperative that these actions are tracked
in near-real-time, compared to historical averages, and that deviation
from a baseline is identified and escalated to&amp;nbsp;humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release procedures are more, not less, important when the sky is
falling.&lt;/strong&gt; The extended downtime of the last seven clusters was because
of an improperly &lt;span class="caps"&gt;QA&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;ed update that was pushed out bypassing the normal
release and testing procedures. As a matter of fact, it was so poorly
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;QA&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;ed that the update totally broke networking for the guest VMs, and
was still pushed out. I&amp;#8217;m sure this was more of a management/executive
decision than one made by the actual engineers, but organizations (even
management) need to understand that when the sky is falling, services
are down, and everybody is stressed, it&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; likely for mistakes and
oversights to happen, and this is when a proper, well-documented &lt;span class="caps"&gt;QA&lt;/span&gt; and
release procedure (including phased rollout) is &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; important.
Failure to follow these procedures results in exactly what happened in
this case - making an already bad problem much&amp;nbsp;worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; can&amp;#8217;t blame Microsoft specifically for all this (though the
whole thing would have been avoided if they just represented timestamps
as integers like the rest of us&amp;#8230;), but it is a good opportunity for us
all to learn from a major incident at a &amp;#8220;pretty well known&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;release procedures are most important when things are already going&amp;nbsp;wrong&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="azure"></category><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="outage"></category><category term="release"></category><category term="testing"></category><category term="windows"></category></entry><entry><title>Slashdot - A Public Funded “Microsoft Shop?”</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2010/03/slashdot-a-public-funded-microsoft-shop/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-04T21:27:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2010-03-04:2010/03/slashdot-a-public-funded-microsoft-shop/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just came by an interesting post on Slashdot, &lt;a href="http://science.slashdot.org/story/10/03/04/1416226/A-Public-Funded-Microsoft-Shop"&gt;A Public Funded
&amp;#8220;Microsoft
Shop?&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;.
The author works at a publicly-funded hospital and comments that he
received an email from management&amp;nbsp;stating:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information Services is strategically a Microsoft shop and when
talking to staff / customers we are to support this strategy. I no
longer want to see comments promoting other Operating&amp;nbsp;Systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, my anti-Microsoft buzzer went off. But the post also stated
that they were ordered to remove Firefox from any computers not
specifically authorized by management. As usual, the Slashdot
conversation degenerated into a proprietary vs open&amp;nbsp;debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I have to comment on the Microsoft issue, I have two remarks. First,
software (an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;, a browser, a text editor, whatever) is a tool. A tool
should be chosen base on whether it&amp;#8217;s the right one for the job, not
just because of who makes it. I&amp;#8217;d like to see a major construction
company state decree that they&amp;#8217;ll only buy Stanley and DeWalt tools.
What will their answer be when the plumbers realize that neither of
those companies make a simple pipe wrench? &amp;#8220;Use a hammer&amp;#8221;? Secondly, as
is evidenced by history, popularity is a relatively poor indicator of
quality, and always ephemeral. Wigs were popular for wealthy men. The
telegraph was popular, and many thought the telephone would never catch
on. The &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fluoroscope"&gt;fluoroscope&lt;/a&gt; was
popular for shoe fitting. Racism was popular. Smoking was popular. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BASIC&lt;/span&gt;
was the greatest programming language ever. Decisions based solely on
popularity are rarely good in the long&amp;nbsp;term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, alas, enough of the Microsoft-bashing. What struck me more was the
prohibition against Firefox, and what it means for technically-apt
employees. Times are changing, and many of the people now entering the
workforce are well-versed with technology. The days when employers could
expect to give their new hires initial computer training are long gone.
And, while many may not see it, the days when every new employee could
be expected to know only a common &amp;#8220;popular&amp;#8221; system (Windows, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt; Office,
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MSIE&lt;/span&gt;) are gone, too. Many people who work at universities, such as
myself, are seeing browser stats that report less than 40% Windows, with
an explosion of Mac-based users and (perhaps thanks to Android,
Netbooks, and Ubuntu) a strong growth in the Linux user&amp;nbsp;base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rutgers University student computing labs have both &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IE&lt;/span&gt; and Firefox
installed on the Windows machines (and we also have a *very* large
number of Mac or dual-boot Windows/Mac clients) and a walk through a
busy lab will reveal a strong majority of users on Firefox. Many
cash-strapped students, even the ones I knew a few years ago, were using
OpenOffice rather than pay for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A similar trend can be seen in the new hires and young professionals who
simply won&amp;#8217;t settle for a corporate cell phone - Windows Mobile, iPhone
or Android, they already have a phone and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; that they like, and
consider a part of their&amp;nbsp;lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a very simple point here - for an increasing number of people,
especially those now entering the workforce, technology is an
inextricable part of their lives. It&amp;#8217;s part of their sense of self, of
expression, of free choice. Telling many people what browser they can
and can&amp;#8217;t use is like telling a new hire a decade or two ago how their
handwriting had to look or what size note pad they could use. Asking
many of my (even non-techie) friends to switch cell phone &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; would be
like telling them what color clothes or tie they have to wear to work.
Telling the average 20-year-old that they can&amp;#8217;t use instant messenger or
facebook at work is like telling the average 40-year-old they can&amp;#8217;t
receive a phone call from their spouse or child. Most especially, with
the pervasiveness of Internet access, connected devices and choice in
browsers and other software, these choices are being seen as a part of
life, a part of&amp;nbsp;technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, and perhaps most importantly to many businesses, the role of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt;
as seen by the end-user is changing, and the role of technology in
productivity is changing. For many young college-educated workers, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt; is
more of a procurement avenue than a support system. Many would happily
install the software application of their choice (whether it is Firefox,
OpenOffice, or something else) on their own, without the worry of a
formal help desk. There&amp;#8217;s also the issue of productivity -
technologically proficient new hires are already used to a software
environment. They&amp;#8217;ve been able to choose their own applications, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;,
browser, etc. Forcing them to switch - especially if they have been
using an application for years and still do at home - will only result
in lower productivity and some amount of frustration. I know that I, for
one, have almost laughed when people advertising for Linux admin jobs
said I&amp;#8217;d be using the same Windows desktop environment as all of the&amp;nbsp;users.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="microsoft"></category></entry><entry><title>Microsoft submits driver code for Linux kernel</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2009/07/microsoft-submits-driver-code-for-linux-kernel/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-07-23T09:32:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2009-07-23:2009/07/microsoft-submits-driver-code-for-linux-kernel/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I read a very interesting &lt;a href="http://www.linux-mag.com/cache/7439/1.html"&gt;article on
Linux-Mag.com&lt;/a&gt; today. The
gist of it is that Microsoft (as happily announced in a &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/presspass/features/2009/Jul09/07-20LinuxQA.mspx"&gt;press
release&lt;/a&gt;)
has submitted 20,000 lines of code for inclusion into the kernel.
Specifically, the code is comprised of a number of drivers that will
enable Linux to run better under Microsoft&amp;nbsp;Hyper-V.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, that&amp;#8217;s right, Microsoft released code under GPLv2 and is asking for
it to be put in Linux. They released it under the license that they call
&amp;#8220;cancer&amp;#8221;. And the entire purpose is, essentially, saying &amp;#8220;we want your
project to run well as a guest under our&amp;nbsp;hypervisor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Linux Mag article did touch on some recent news, such as Microsoft&amp;#8217;s
&lt;a href="http://www.linux-mag.com/id/7325"&gt;lawsuit against TomTom&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/microsoft/news/2009/03/microsoft-and-tomtom-settle-patent-dispute.ars"&gt;settled in
late
March&lt;/a&gt;)
claiming that the Linux kernel infringes their &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VFAT&lt;/span&gt; patents and the 2004
&lt;a href="http://ec.europa.eu/comm/competition/antitrust/cases/decisions/37792/en.pdf"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EU&lt;/span&gt; antitrust case
(&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of things are immediately apparent to&amp;nbsp;me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only reason for this is so Linux will virtualize well under&amp;nbsp;Windows/Hyper-V.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to be making any similar effort to allow
    Windows to virtualize well under Xen (and it seems to me that many
    more people would want Windows on a reliable Linux host than the
    other way&amp;nbsp;around).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft reached a settlement with TomTom, but never did anything
    to indemnify the Linux community at&amp;nbsp;large.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; a Microsoft endorsement (or even recognition) of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft &lt;a href="http://www.linux-watch.com/news/NS6670466370.html"&gt;made
    threats&lt;/a&gt; about
    Linux violating &amp;#8220;over 228&amp;#8221; of its patents in&amp;nbsp;2007.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a
&lt;a href="http://www.kroah.com/log/linux/microsoft-linux-hyper-v-drivers.html"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;
on &lt;a href="http://www.kroah.com/log/"&gt;Greg Kroah-Hartman&amp;#8217;s blog&lt;/a&gt; (he&amp;#8217;s the
kernel maintainer who will - or will not - eventually be in charge of
the inclusion of the code). It should be noted that &lt;strong&gt;this all started&lt;/strong&gt;
due to a guy who I really admire, &lt;a href="http://linux-network-plumber.blogspot.com/"&gt;Stephen
Hemminger&lt;/a&gt;, the principal
engineer at Vyatta (whose router product I absolutely love, and their
mock advertisements are just as wonderful). Steve has a &lt;a href="http://linux-network-plumber.blogspot.com/2009/07/congratulations-microsoft.html"&gt;post on his
blog&lt;/a&gt;
giving the&amp;nbsp;background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what do &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; think should be done? Include the code. But first&amp;#8230; (I
know Microsoft doing all of this at once would be a dream, but maybe one
or two of them would be&amp;nbsp;nice)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If they haven&amp;#8217;t already done so, Microsoft should publicly recognize
    the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt; and all of its terms as being a legally binding&amp;nbsp;license.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior to having any Microsoft code included in the Linux kernel,
    Microsoft publicly states that the Linux kernel, as of the time they
    submitted their code, does not infringe on any Microsoft
    intellectual&amp;nbsp;property.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would be nice of Microsoft would agree to some level of
    cooperation with the Linux&amp;nbsp;community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft pledges to allow, support, and actively develop for
    Windows as a guest under Xen and&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;KVM&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><category term="gpl"></category><category term="kernel"></category><category term="linux"></category><category term="microsoft"></category></entry><entry><title>My Take on the MS TomTom Suit</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2009/03/my-take-on-the-ms-tomtom-suit/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-03-05T10:05:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2009-03-05:2009/03/my-take-on-the-ms-tomtom-suit/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;To keep it short, I&amp;#8217;m sure anyone who winds up here has already heard
about the recent Microsoft lawsuit against TomTom, alleging patent
infringement. Coverage has been extensive, including
&lt;a href="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20090226070041454"&gt;GrokLaw&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href="http://www.linux-mag.com/id/7258"&gt;Linux Magazine&lt;/a&gt;. While the
mentioned patents include car navigation technology (at least the names
of the patents seem amazingly vague) and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FAT&lt;/span&gt; . Most of the news stories
I&amp;#8217;ve read say that it&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;good for Linux&amp;#8221; and will never see the inside
of a&amp;nbsp;courtroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I&amp;#8217;m just a pessimist, but I see the idea behind this as much worse
than &amp;#8220;good for Linux&amp;#8221;. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt; chose one company to sue. TomTom just happens
to be not only a household name, but also posted a $1.2 Billion loss
last year. It seems to me this is more of a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FUD&lt;/span&gt; campaign than anything
else&amp;#8230; the best case for Microsoft is that they could strangle TomTom
in a legal battle, perhaps force them to go under, and then ensure a
media spin along the lines of &amp;#8220;Know that company that made the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; in
every car? They used Linux in it, they got sued by Microsoft, and
they&amp;#8217;re no&amp;nbsp;more.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I haven&amp;#8217;t always been a fan of TomTom - and am still bothered by
the fact that my (stolen, no longer in my possession) TomTom One ran
Linux but wouldn&amp;#8217;t give me a console or even let me see the filesystem -
I&amp;#8217;ll be watching this closely, and hoping that the powers that be will
not let the angry dinosaur crush a company over a series of patents that
are either horribly obvious (anyone other than Garmin having a claim to
any &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;-related idea is beyond me) or just horrible&amp;nbsp;(&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FAT&lt;/span&gt;?!?!?!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a final note - isn&amp;#8217;t it about time that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; finally dealt with
this damn software patent thing? Not only does it horribly stifle
innovation (not good to do in a bad economy), and I have a hard time
grasping the claim that Microsoft&amp;#8217;s developers are so all-powerful that
they&amp;#8217;re the only people that thought of technology X, but it&amp;#8217;s about
time that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; government got the balls to look Microsoft in the eyes
and say, &amp;#8220;you&amp;#8217;re not the only game in town anymore. Get used to&amp;nbsp;it.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="lawsuit"></category><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="patents"></category><category term="tomtom"></category></entry><entry><title>Internet Security, Microsoft Lies</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2008/09/internet-security-microsoft-lies/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-09-16T23:24:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2008-09-16:2008/09/internet-security-microsoft-lies/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet&amp;nbsp;Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this semester I&amp;#8217;m taking a class on Internet Security. Our textbook
is &lt;a href="http://search.barnesandnoble.com/booksearch/isbninquiry.asp?ean=1423901304"&gt;Management of Internet Security, 2nd
Edition&lt;/a&gt;
by Michael E. Whitman and Herbert J. Mattord. It seems pretty basic, and
very much focused on the management side of things (as opposed to
technical). The table of contents is as&amp;nbsp;follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to the Management of Information&amp;nbsp;Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning for&amp;nbsp;Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning for&amp;nbsp;Contingencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Security&amp;nbsp;Policy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing the Security&amp;nbsp;Program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security Management Models and&amp;nbsp;Practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk Management: Identifying and Assessing&amp;nbsp;Risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk Management: Assessing and Controlling&amp;nbsp;Risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protection&amp;nbsp;Mechanisms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personnel and&amp;nbsp;Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Law and&amp;nbsp;Ethics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Security Project&amp;nbsp;Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, given that it&amp;#8217;s really a &amp;#8220;management&amp;#8221; book, I can&amp;#8217;t say I&amp;#8217;m
surprised that it reads like an essay that was graded on a scale of
buzzwords-per-sentence. However, it seems to be missing the one chapter
that&amp;#8217;s the most important - actually, the only chapter that would be in
the book if I wrote it - &amp;#8220;How to get management to allocate the money
you need for proper security.&amp;#8221; In fact, skimming over the book, I found
a lot of content on general management planning, job descriptions,
sample policies, and a lot of other pie-in-the-sky stuff, but not one
concrete section dedicated to the most difficult part of security -
getting the &amp;#8220;resources&amp;#8221; to do it&amp;nbsp;right!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft&amp;nbsp;Lies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why we would spend time analyzing corporate mission statements in an
Internet Security class, I have no idea. That seems, to me, too much
like what we covered in &amp;#8220;Management of Technological Organizations.&amp;#8221;
But, we do, and one of the examples used is &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/About/default.mspx"&gt;Microsoft&amp;#8217;s Mission and
Values statement&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps,
being the F/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt; advocate that I am, my reading of it was a bit cynical.
Let&amp;#8217;s take a look at&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;At Microsoft, our mission and values are to help people and business
throughout the world realize their full potential.&amp;#8221; Well, we&amp;#8217;re off to a
good start. Aside from the fact that they want you to realize that
potential using &lt;strong&gt;only their software&lt;/strong&gt;, and use their power and money
to actively monopolize (or attempt to) most industries that they enter,
this seems pretty&amp;nbsp;run-of-the-mill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corporate Citizenship:&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8220;Every successful corporation has &lt;em&gt;a
responsibility to use its resources and influence to make a positive
impact on the world and its people&lt;/em&gt;. Microsoft’s Global Citizenship
Initiative is focused on mobilizing our resources across the company and
around the world, to create opportunities in the communities where we do
business, and to &lt;em&gt;fulfill our commitment to serving the public good
through innovative technologies and partnerships&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#8221; Well. Now we&amp;#8217;re
getting somewhere. Apparently &amp;#8220;a positive impact on the world and its
people&amp;#8221; is defined as trying to monopolize every sector that Microsoft
touches, whether attempting to crush and then buy-out the competition,
or through flat-out
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fear,_uncertainty_and_doubt"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FUD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and
billion-dollar marketing campaigns. Hmm&amp;#8230; innovative partnerships&amp;#8230; as
in&amp;nbsp;Novell?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Legal and Corporate Affairs:&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8220;Microsoft’s Legal and Corporate Affairs
Group works on the cutting edge of business and regulatory issues around
the world.&amp;#8221; Well, I can&amp;#8217;t argue with that, they sure are on the cutting
edge. What started with Bill Gates mailing out whiny letters about
pirated Altair &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BASIC&lt;/span&gt; has now turned into a global juggernaut, capable of
forcing the creation of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; standards at their whim, and successfully
quashing any dissent about obviously flawed and under-reviewed
&amp;#8220;standards&amp;#8221; (which, in fact, simply describe current software, rather
than setting any real&amp;nbsp;standard).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Values:&lt;/em&gt;As a company, and as individuals, we value &lt;strong&gt;integrity&lt;/strong&gt;,
&lt;strong&gt;honesty&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;openness&lt;/strong&gt;, personal excellence, &lt;strong&gt;constructive
self-criticism&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;continual self-improvement&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;mutual
respect&lt;/strong&gt;. We are committed to our customers and partners and have a
passion for technology. We take on big challenges, and pride ourselves
on seeing them through. &lt;strong&gt;We hold ourselves accountable to our
customers&lt;/strong&gt;, shareholders, partners, and employees by honoring our
commitments, providing results, and &lt;strong&gt;striving for the highest
quality&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;integrity&lt;/strong&gt; - i.e. not creating a draft &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; standard and then
    &lt;a href="http://www.networkworld.com/news/2007/083007-microsoft-employee-offered-incentives-for.html"&gt;offering monetary incentives for
    acceptance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;honesty&lt;/strong&gt; - when it works. Intentionally making Vista-Capable
    labeling so ambiguous that it even &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/09/business/09digi.html?_r=1&amp;amp;oref=slogin"&gt;confuses Microsoft
    executives&lt;/a&gt;?&amp;nbsp;Fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;openness&lt;/strong&gt; um&amp;#8230; did they seriously say that? Openness like&amp;#8230;
    protocol interoperability? Standards that can be implemented without
    patent violations? An &amp;#8220;Open Specification Promise&amp;#8221; that doesn&amp;#8217;t come
    with a &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/interop/osp/default.mspx"&gt;three page
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FAQ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;? Nope. Not&amp;nbsp;Microsoft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;constructive self-criticism&lt;/strong&gt; - Ok, I&amp;#8217;ll give them this one. They
    do, rarely, criticize themselves. Though &amp;#8220;constructive&amp;#8221; usually
    means making comments about the poor design of a previous product,
    and suggesting that everyone upgrade to the new&amp;nbsp;version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;continual self-improvement&lt;/strong&gt; - I&amp;#8217;ll give them this one too. In
    fact, they&amp;#8217;re so crazy about it that they&amp;#8217;ve been improving the same
    codebase for&amp;nbsp;decades!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mutual respect&lt;/strong&gt; - See&amp;nbsp;above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We hold ourselves accountable to our customers&lt;/strong&gt; - Ok. They &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt;
    offering to allow users to &lt;a href="http://download.microsoft.com/download/5/f/4/5f4c83d3-833e-4f11-8cbd-699b0c164182/royaltyoemreferencesheet.pdf"&gt;downgrade from Vista to
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;striving for the highest quality&lt;/strong&gt; - I don&amp;#8217;t think so. They&amp;#8217;re
    striving for products that have the highest &lt;em&gt;market share&lt;/em&gt;. As long
    as the quality is acceptable to the majority of users, and the
    products do what the majority of users need, that&amp;#8217;s fine. But
    wait&amp;#8230; apparently they even missed &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; goal with&amp;nbsp;Vista.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just the opinion of one person. My motivations may be diverse,
and surely there&amp;#8217;s a bit of zealotry in there. After all, if Ford told
me I couldn&amp;#8217;t put fog lights on my car myself, I had to bring it to the
dealer and pay $400, I&amp;#8217;d stop buying their cars - and make sure everyone
else knew what they did. But there&amp;#8217;s also my ever-present desire to make
sure people know both sides of the story, and all the facts. The
mainstream media (specifically dumbed-down television) rarely reports on
the less cheerful side of Microsoft, like the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#8220;standard&amp;#8221;
&lt;a href="http://www.networkworld.com/news/2007/083007-microsoft-employee-offered-incentives-for.html"&gt;scandal&lt;/a&gt;,
or the &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/09/business/09digi.html?_r=1&amp;amp;oref=slogin"&gt;Vista
letters&lt;/a&gt;,
or the
&lt;a href="http://yro.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=08/04/22/2032232&amp;amp;from=rss"&gt;Vista-Capable&lt;/a&gt;
fiasco. And I find this to be horribly disturbing. Many people don&amp;#8217;t
realize that there &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; alternatives to Microsoft products, even ones
that are provided by such big names as &lt;a href="http://www.sun.com"&gt;Sun
Microsystems&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.ibm.com"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IBM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But,
most striking, is Microsoft&amp;#8217;s overwhelming monopoly. Windows&amp;#8217; market
share is currently
&lt;a href="http://marketshare.hitslink.com/report.aspx?qprid=8"&gt;90.66%&lt;/a&gt; or higher.
I ask you, what other industries which affect not only consumers, but
nearly every aspect of our daily lives (as computing does) would be
allowed to have such a monopoly? It has happened in many other American
industries - oil, steel, the railroads, telephone service. Where is the
government&amp;nbsp;now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened to the America that made massive monopolies illegal? Have
we forgotten a supremely part of our history that began in 1980 with the
Sherman Act? Or even the recent events with Bell? In order to truly
stimulate competition in the software industry, and provide for not only
choice but the improved quality, reliability, and security that comes
with true software competition, something needs to be done. For
starters, how about breaking Microsoft into separate entities - browser,
Office, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;, server, etc. And - the important part - preventing any
package sales, discounts, or bundling between the separate types of
software (and separate&amp;nbsp;companies).&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="rutgers"></category><category term="school"></category><category term="security"></category></entry><entry><title>Microsoft and Novell Deliver Joint Virtualization Solution - or do they?</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2008/09/microsoft-and-novell-deliver-joint-virtualization-solution-or-do-they/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-09-11T11:40:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2008-09-11:2008/09/microsoft-and-novell-deliver-joint-virtualization-solution-or-do-they/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;From PRNewsWire: &lt;a href="http://www.prnewswire.com/cgi-bin/stories.pl?ACCT=104&amp;amp;STORY=/www/story/09-11-2008/0004883058&amp;amp;EDATE="&gt;Microsoft and Novell Deliver Joint Virtualization
Solution Through
Partners&lt;/a&gt;.
The headline of the press release: &amp;#8220;Supported by Dell and other channel
partners, solution includes &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SUSE&lt;/span&gt; Linux Enterprise Server running as
optimized guest on Windows Server 2008&amp;nbsp;Hyper-V.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, maybe I&amp;#8217;m not up on the news regarding my favorite distribution,
but it seems to me that a deal allowing SuSE to be virtualized as a
&lt;strong&gt;guest&lt;/strong&gt; under Windows is not only &amp;#8220;joint&amp;#8221;, but plain moronic. Despite
the marketing efforts of Microsoft, Unix-based systems (including Linux)
have always had the upper hand in availability, reliability, and&amp;nbsp;performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must say, from what I&amp;#8217;ve heard, Windows Server is getting *much*
better in these areas - and I&amp;#8217;ve even heard that the latest version
includes an option to install without a graphical environment, and even
includes a command-line that&amp;#8217;s useful. It&amp;#8217;s about&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it seems to me, that any virtualization deal between Microsoft
and a Linux distributor can provide only one logical solution: Windows
Server virtualized as a guest in a high-availability Linux host. More
importantly, without the insane per-processor licensing - a per-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;VM&lt;/span&gt;
instance license that&amp;#8217;s hardware-agnostic and allows VMs to be migrated
across hardware as the admin sees&amp;nbsp;fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and one more insight. If Microsoft wants to be a serious player in
the virtualization arena, here&amp;#8217;s a few &amp;#8220;simple&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get Windows Server to work correctly under Xen, VirtualBox, etc.
    Certify it. Provide the correct guest &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; tool&amp;nbsp;packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide simple management of Windows in a virtualized environment -
    minimally, a standard &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; server that&amp;#8217;s compatible with OpenSSH, a
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt;-less environment, and a serial&amp;nbsp;console.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get rid of per-processor licenses. Provide a basic license that
    allows for, say, 10 VMs to be running at once, and allows as many
    installs as needed - the only licensing is based on the amount of
    VMs actually running. i.e., if you have 10 VMs and one gets
    corrupted, you can bring that one down and online a back-up image,
    without violating the&amp;nbsp;license.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make licensing processor-agnostic. Want to migrate a Xen &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VM&lt;/span&gt; (Windows
    guest) from a dual-core Pentium to an 8-core Xeon, or even a 16
    processor &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SPARC&lt;/span&gt;? Sure, no&amp;nbsp;problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="novell"></category><category term="suse"></category><category term="virtualization"></category></entry><entry><title>Where are we going and what’s with the handbasket?</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2008/04/where-are-we-going-and-whats-with-the-handbasket/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-04-02T12:13:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2008-04-02:2008/04/where-are-we-going-and-whats-with-the-handbasket/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;#8217;s it. Not only did Verizon and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AT&lt;/span&gt;&amp;amp;T come out on top in the
&lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2008/03/20/fcc-releases-700mhz-auction-details-verizon-atandt-big-winners/"&gt;700MHz spectrum
auction&lt;/a&gt;
- promising an end to hopes of Google&amp;#8217;s utopian ideals of a truly open
network - but I just heard that &amp;#8220;Office Open &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221; &lt;a href="http://www.iso.org/iso/pressrelease.htm?refid=Ref1123"&gt;was approved as an
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; standard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think it even merits comment on my part. The world is run by
corporations. Corporations with more money than brains, hopes, or balls.
The 700MHz spectrum will become another copy of what American has now -
a resource (frequencies) that are &amp;#8220;owned by the people&amp;#8221;, yet controlled
by major corporations, and horribly biased
&lt;em&gt;against&lt;/em&gt; the interests of the&amp;nbsp;consumer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt; is now a standard. Is it any less flawed? No. Is it any
safer for me to implement? No. Does it even contain enough information
for me to implement? No. But it&amp;#8217;s a specification, and it&amp;#8217;s here. While
Jason Matusow may have stated that &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/jasonmatusow/archive/2008/02/26/open-xml-brm-day-2-thoughts.aspx"&gt;the patents related to the
technology are not a barrier to use - for anyone, in any country, for
all
time&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;,
I&amp;#8217;m still a bit worried about the issues that will crop up with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt; -
not to mention the fact that it&amp;#8217;s a standard squarely aimed at
eliminating choice (we all know Microsoft will push hard for
organizations not to use &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ODF&lt;/span&gt;) and preventing competition in a sector
already overwhelmingly dominated by &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, what happened in the past few weeks? A confirmation that the
governments and organizations of the world care little about the
individual, and fear change. They&amp;#8217;re owned by big business, and the
700MHz spectrum will end up being, at best, a marginal improvement over
the current restrictive cellular system. And big business doesn&amp;#8217;t even
have the balls to fight for itself. Or, even worse, doesn&amp;#8217;t worry about
vendor lock-in or proprietary software because, as long as they keep
bending over backwards to follow Microsoft&amp;#8217;s every whim, Microsoft will
always be there to help&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m surprised that even multinational corporations, who have a data
center filled with redundant systems, and fiber running in every
direction in case this or that &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CO&lt;/span&gt; goes up in flames, doesn&amp;#8217;t consider
closed standards, proprietary (possibly patent-encumbered) software, or
closed-source software to be as obvious a single point of failure as a
critical service running on a single desktop computer. Sure, your vendor
might tell you their software will achieve five-nines. But if they
discontinue support, or have a few bad quarters, and they won&amp;#8217;t fix it
for you, what&amp;nbsp;then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m just thankful that there are &lt;a href="http://blogs.sun.com/jonathan/"&gt;some
people&lt;/a&gt;, few and far between, that don&amp;#8217;t
fall into the&amp;nbsp;trap.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="700mhz"></category><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="ooxml"></category><category term="spectrum"></category></entry><entry><title>Microsoft $1.35B poorer</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2008/02/microsoft-135b-poorer/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-02-27T14:42:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2008-02-27:2008/02/microsoft-135b-poorer/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I almost forgot to link right to the&lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/mergersNews/idUSBRU00634320080227"&gt;article from Reuters about
the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EU&lt;/span&gt; fining
Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;
$1.35 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BILLION&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USD&lt;/span&gt; (899 million&amp;nbsp;euros).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft&amp;#8217;s monopolistic business practices are costing it billions of&amp;nbsp;dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IDEA&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
Actually be open. Open up all of your protocols, specifications, APIs.
Even start opening up some of your source code, under GPLv3, and
assigning patents to the &lt;a href="http://www.patent-commons.org/"&gt;Patent
Common&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.patent-commons.org/"&gt;s&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, your sales will go up. Maybe then Bill can donate the
next $1B in fines to some starving kids who need&amp;nbsp;laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously though, if I could get Windows Server under GPLv3, and do
whatever I want - fork it, whatever, I might buy a copy. I&amp;#8217;m sure a lot
of people would if they realized that they could change it, wouldn&amp;#8217;t get
locked in,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="patents"></category></entry><entry><title>Microsoft… again</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2008/02/microsoft-again/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-02-27T14:05:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2008-02-27:2008/02/microsoft-again/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20080227031234460"&gt;another Groklaw article on recent Microsoft
tribulations&lt;/a&gt;.
This really is starting to get disgusting. It&amp;#8217;s not that I hate
Microsoft, I don&amp;#8217;t. What I hate is their attitude, and their business
practices. Everyone else - I mean &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; - makes software that
interoperates with other vendors. Microsoft, even after a &lt;em&gt;billion&lt;/em&gt;
dollar fine, won&amp;#8217;t. Everyone else uses open, industry-accepted
standards. Microsoft doesn&amp;#8217;t. Many other vendors open up their code.
Microsoft tried to make some vague gesture to, but makes it incompatible
with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;d code (okay, okay, I know about &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ZFS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8230;) and says developers
can only use it in non-commercial projects. So they open a few things up
to hobbyists, and want a pat on the back. It boils down to how they
treat customers and developers. Not very well. I don&amp;#8217;t like that. I&amp;#8217;m
not going to start on the technical aspects of Windows, though it seems
to be getting better, a baby step at a time. But the bottom line is that
Microsoft actively tries to turn the software industry into a facist
dictatorship, where you do it Microsoft&amp;#8217;s way, or you&amp;#8217;re taken out back
and shot (ok, bought up and then shut&amp;nbsp;down).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, from the blog of Zeheda Bhorat, Open Source Programs Manager at&amp;nbsp;Google,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google believes &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt; would be an insufficient and unnecessary
standard, designed purely around the needs of Microsoft&amp;nbsp;Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can it be that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; - the International
Organization for &lt;em&gt;Standardization&lt;/em&gt; - would
actually consider a &lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt;,
competing standard for document formats. And one that&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.noooxml.org/argu-brief"&gt;as flawed as
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;? These guys are the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt;. They
practically run the world, at least technically. Why don&amp;#8217;t they have the
balls to look Microsoft in the eye and say, &amp;#8220;Hey, moron. We already
&lt;strong&gt;have&lt;/strong&gt; a document format
standard. It&amp;#8217;s called &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; 26300. If you want to have anything to do with
the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt;, which sets &lt;em&gt;standards&lt;/em&gt;,
you can take your 6,000 page specification, put it through a crosscut
paper-burning radiation-producing shredder, pay the $320 for a copy of
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO26300&lt;/span&gt;, and implement&amp;nbsp;it!&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="iso"></category><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="ooxml"></category></entry><entry><title>February 26, 2008</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2008/02/february-26-2008/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-02-26T11:32:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2008-02-26:2008/02/february-26-2008/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, while I haven&amp;#8217;t made much progress on anything interesting -
mainly my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NMS&lt;/span&gt; comparison or any of my other projects - due to my busy
schedule, I did get an hour or two to clean up my network at the
apartment, swapping out my 24-port Linksys switch in my room for the
5-port Netgear previously used for printing. I threw all of the printers
and the print server on their own &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VLAN&lt;/span&gt; on the main 3com&amp;nbsp;switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve also started thinking more about &lt;a href="http://www.mythtv.org/"&gt;MythTV&lt;/a&gt; -
I use it for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; in my room (feeding a grossly insufficient 21&amp;#8221; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CRT&lt;/span&gt;
monitor), and my roommate has a Dell &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GX270&lt;/span&gt; by the big &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; in the living
room, though it was running Freevo (and now has a dead tuner and no &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt;,
or something like that). So, I decided that I might do things right -
drop a 5- or 8-port GigE switch in the apartment, put GigE NICs in the
two boxes with tuners (putting MythTV on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GX270&lt;/span&gt; also), and setting up
a centralized system. The problem is that the ideal solution would be a
single dedicated back-end system for storage and control, with the two
tuner/video out boxes just providing A/V I/O. Unfortunately, the two
boxes with tuners are both high-spec&amp;#8217;ed P4&amp;#8217;s, and I&amp;#8217;m not sure what I
can come up with in terms of a server for the&amp;nbsp;backend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, &lt;em&gt;the question for anyone who may be
reading&lt;/em&gt; - I&amp;#8217;d like to setup a good amount (1-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;2TB&lt;/span&gt;) of storage for
this. My roommate wants a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAID&lt;/span&gt; configuration, but I don&amp;#8217;t see the need
for videos - if I lose my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; recordings, I set MythTV to record it again
the next time it&amp;#8217;s on. Anyway, I have an 8-bay external &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCAI&lt;/span&gt; enclosure
and cards in all of the servers, but &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCSI&lt;/span&gt; disks are expensive. I was
thinking of going to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SATA&lt;/span&gt; 3.0. Most likely, I&amp;#8217;d get some sort of 4-8
disk enclosure, start with 1-3 disks in the 400-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;750GB&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the question - what type of system specs would be needed to stream
audio and video, uncompressed, perhaps even &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDTV&lt;/span&gt; (we have the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; and
cable box, would just need an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HD&lt;/span&gt; tuner) to remote storage over the
network? I was thinking of doing either a Linux master MythTV backend
with eSATA cards, or letting each &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; computer be its&amp;#8217; own backend, and
then doing Solaris/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ZFS&lt;/span&gt; with iSCSI or ATAoE. Any suggestions? I&amp;#8217;m pretty
much thinking of using a PowerEdge 2550 for&amp;nbsp;this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&amp;#8217;m also filling up my backup disks at home, and don&amp;#8217;t want to
shorten my expiration cycle. My nightly backup runs put quite a strain
on my main Fast Ethernet &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;, so I&amp;#8217;ve been planning for a while on
moving to GigE. My thought at home is to setup a second, separate GigE
switch/lan, with GigE NICs in all of the servers. Not exactly cheap, but
I can pickup a Linux-/Solaris-compatible Negear &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GA311&lt;/span&gt; for around $40, in
addition to the Intel Pro/1000 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XT&lt;/span&gt; and Asante GigaNIC that I already
have. The problem here is finding a good GigE switch - I&amp;#8217;d really like
something with Telnet, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SNMP&lt;/span&gt;, VLANs, the&amp;nbsp;works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, I highly recommend reading the &lt;a href="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20080221184924826"&gt;Groklaw story on
Microsoft&amp;#8217;s latest pledge for
interoperability&lt;/a&gt;.
I especially liked the one quote from the &lt;a href="http://www.ecis.eu/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ECIS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years now, Microsoft has either failed to implement or has
actively corrupted a range of truly open standards adopted and
implemented by the rest of the industry. Unless and until that
behaviour stops, today&amp;#8217;s words mean&amp;nbsp;nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More fundamentally, today&amp;#8217;s announcement is still all about the rest
of the world interoperating with Microsoft on Microsoft&amp;#8217;s own terms,
not the other way&amp;nbsp;around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s even links to &lt;em&gt;ten&lt;/em&gt; previous Microsoft statements promising&amp;nbsp;interoperability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, this is a promise to interoperate with old-fashioned
competitors. It doesn&amp;#8217;t enable interoperability with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;, which is
not compatible with patent licenses, and that is Microsoft&amp;#8217;s true&amp;nbsp;competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Michael Cunningham, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VP&lt;/span&gt; and General Counsel of Red&amp;nbsp;Hat:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eight years ago the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;U.S.&lt;/span&gt; regulatory authorities, and four years ago
the European regulators made clear to Microsoft that its refusal to
disclose interface information for its monopoly software products
violates the law. So, it is hardly surprising to see even Microsoft
state today that “interoperability across systems is an important
requirement” and announce a “change in [its] approach to
interoperability.” Of course, we’ve heard similar announcements
before, almost always strategically timed for other effect. Red Hat
regards this most recent announcement with a healthy dose of
skepticism. Three commitments by Microsoft would show that it really
means what it is announcing&amp;nbsp;today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit to open standards: Rather than pushing forward its
    proprietary, Windows-based formats for document processing, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt;,
    Microsoft should embrace the existing &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt;-approved, cross-platform
    industry standard for document processing, Open Document Format
    (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ODF&lt;/span&gt;) at the International Standards Organization’s meeting next
    week in Geneva. Microsoft, please demonstrate implementation of an
    existing international open standard now rather than make press
    announcements about intentions of future standards&amp;nbsp;support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit to interoperability with open source: Instead of offering a
    patent license for its protocol information on the basis of
    licensing arrangements it knows are incompatible with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt; –
    the world’s most widely used open source software license –
    Microsoft should extend its Open Specification Promise to all of
    the interoperability information that it is announcing today will
    be made available. The Open Specification Promise already covers
    many Microsoft products that do not have monopoly market
    positions. If Microsoft were truly committed to fostering openness
    and preventing customer lock-in, it would extend this promise to
    the protocol and interface information it intends to disclose
    today. There is no explanation for refusing to extend the Open
    Specification Promise to “high-volume” products, other than a
    continued intention on Microsoft’s part to lock customers into its
    monopoly products, and lock out competitors through patent&amp;nbsp;threats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit to competition on a level playing field: Microsoft’s
    announcement today appears carefully crafted to foreclose
    competition from the open source community. How else can you
    explain a “promise not to sue open source developers” as long as
    they develop and distribute only*/ “non-commercial”
    implementations of interoperable products? This is simply
    disingenuous. The only hope for reintroducing competition to the
    monopoly markets Microsoft now controls – Windows, Office, etc. –
    is through commercial distributions of competitive open source
    software&amp;nbsp;products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amen!!!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="GigE"></category><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="mythtv"></category><category term="sata"></category><category term="storage"></category></entry><entry><title>Links for 2008-02-23</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2008/02/links-for-2008-02-23/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-02-25T11:20:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2008-02-25:2008/02/links-for-2008-02-23/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some links for&amp;nbsp;today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/news.ars/post/20080221-microsoft-launches-new-open-standards-interoperability-push.html"&gt;Microsoft&amp;#8217;s new promised on interoperability, open standards.
etc.&lt;/a&gt;
- somewhat ironic given the Office Open &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt; debacle on &amp;#8220;standards&amp;#8221;. &lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/journals/linux.ars/2008/02/21/red-hat-not-impressed-with-microsofts-interoperability-plans"&gt;And
Red Hat&amp;#8217;s worries about
it&lt;/a&gt;.
(Ars&amp;nbsp;Technica)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20080221184924826"&gt;Groklaw&amp;#8217;s lengthy analysis of the
promises&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.zdnet.com/threatchaos/"&gt;Pakistan removed from the Internet, causes global YouTube
outage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/theguardian/2008/feb/23/internet.usa"&gt;A Guardian article on the WikiLeaks
debacle&lt;/a&gt;
- perhaps the biggest affront to the First Amendment this&amp;nbsp;year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An&lt;a href="http://www.informationweek.com/story/showArticle.jhtml?articleID=206800800&amp;amp;cid=RSSfeed_IWK_All"&gt;InformationWeek article about some guys from BlackHat &lt;span class="caps"&gt;D.C.&lt;/span&gt; who said
that they will be able to crack &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GSM&lt;/span&gt; encryption in under 30 minutes with
$1,000 of technology or 30 seconds with
$100,000&lt;/a&gt;
(FPGAs - Maybe a cluster of&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PS3&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://citp.princeton.edu/memory/"&gt;A Princeton Unviersity blog about cold boots possibly able to crack the
Windows BitLocker system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.mozilla.com/blog/2008/02/21/500-million-firefox-downloads-complete-500-million-grains-in-progress/"&gt;Yay! Firefox has hit its&amp;#8217; 500 Millionth
download!!!&lt;/a&gt;
And there was much&amp;nbsp;rejoicing&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/news.ars/post/20080219-opera-browser-market-isnt-functioning-thanks-to-microsoft.html"&gt;An ArsTechnica article on Internet Explorer, what should be done to fix
it, and how there can still be a non-standards-compliant
browser&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://jeremy.linuxquestions.org/"&gt;Jeremy&amp;#8217;s Blog&lt;/a&gt; - the mind behind
&lt;a href="http://www.linuxquestions.org/"&gt;LinuxQuestions.org&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://jeremy.linuxquestions.org/2008/02/21/2007-linuxquestionsorg-members-choice-award-winners/"&gt;provides a recap
of the 2007 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LQ&lt;/span&gt; Members&amp;#8217; Choice
awards&lt;/a&gt;.
Some interesting winners were VirtualBox for virtualization package,
Debain for server distro, Knoppix for Live Distro, Eclipse for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IDE&lt;/span&gt;/Web
Development Environment, Python for language of the year, and - much to
my chagrin - vi/vim for&amp;nbsp;editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/whats-next-open-source-and-public-media"&gt;LinuxJournal article on What&amp;#8217;s Next for Open Source and Public
Meida&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.linuxinsider.com/rsstory/61803.html"&gt;LinuxInsider - &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EU&lt;/span&gt; taking Microsoft&amp;#8217;s promises with a grain of
salt&lt;/a&gt;, noting that &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt;
has made &amp;#8220;at least four similar statements&amp;#8221; in the&amp;nbsp;past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/"&gt;Chris Siebenmann&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href="http://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/SharingRisk"&gt;Where
the risk is with virtualization (and
iSCSI)&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/sysadmin/WirelessMachineRoom"&gt;Wireless, machine rooms, and the Asus
eeePC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/library/x-ooxmlstandard.html?ca=dgr-lnxw06OOXMLBigDeal&amp;amp;S_TACT=105AGX59&amp;amp;S_CMP=GR"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IBM&lt;/span&gt; DeveloperWorks - &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt;: What&amp;#8217;s the big
deal?&lt;/a&gt;
- outlining the technical objections to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt; as a standard. Linked from
a &lt;a href="http://rootprompt.org/article.php3?article=11548"&gt;rootprompt.org&lt;/a&gt;
article mentioning that &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt; is essentially a complete replication of
every chunk of data that a Microsoft Office application might possibly
save in a&amp;nbsp;file&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slashdot &lt;span class="caps"&gt;YRO&lt;/span&gt; - &lt;a href="http://yro.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=08/02/25/0159250&amp;amp;from=rss"&gt;a guy who got hist stock photos stolen, entered into a
long legal battle, and
won&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://seattlepi.nwsource.com/business/352442_vista23.html"&gt;Windows Vista Capable lawsuit granted class-action
status&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2008/02/23/AR2008022300693.html"&gt;Washington Post article on Hans Reiser&amp;#8217;s Geek Defense
strategy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="http://apple.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=08/02/23/1915254&amp;amp;from=rss"&gt;Slashdot post linking to news that Apple sent a cease-and-decist
order to the Hymn
Project&lt;/a&gt;,
which produces software to remove &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DRM&lt;/span&gt; from iTunes songs. Apple had their
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; remove all download links. (I guess the only solution is for us all
to buy bandwidth right from a&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8230;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.yahoo.com/s/ap/20080222/ap_on_hi_te/yahoo_shareholder_lawsuit"&gt;Yahoo&amp;#8217;s shareholders are suing it for not gobbling up the Microsoft
deal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/news.ars/post/20080220-disgruntled-customer-sues-comcast-over-p2p-throttling.html"&gt;Comcast getting sued &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AGAIN&lt;/span&gt; for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;P2P&lt;/span&gt;
filtering&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.wired.com/music/2008/02/riaa-training-v.html"&gt;A leaked &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIAA&lt;/span&gt; training video for
prosecutors&lt;/a&gt;,
going so far as to say that &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; piracy can lead to arrests for drugs,
weapons, or terrorism. It also includes instructions on how to get a
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIAA&lt;/span&gt; investigator certified as a court&amp;nbsp;expert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/02/21/fashion/21webgirls.html?_r=2&amp;amp;oref=slogin&amp;amp;oref=slogin"&gt;New York Times article on - gasp - women using the
Internet&lt;/a&gt;.
Linked from &lt;a href="http://yesthattom.livejournal.com"&gt;Tom Limoncelli&amp;#8217;s blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="apple"></category><category term="bitlocker"></category><category term="cellphone"></category><category term="EU"></category><category term="firefox"></category><category term="gsm"></category><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="ooxml"></category><category term="pakistan"></category><category term="riaa"></category><category term="virtualization"></category><category term="wikileaks"></category><category term="windows"></category><category term="youtube"></category></entry><entry><title>Links for the weekend of February 10, 2008</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2008/02/links-for-the-weekend-of-february-10-2008/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-02-10T23:07:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2008-02-10:2008/02/links-for-the-weekend-of-february-10-2008/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, I don&amp;#8217;t have much time for a real post. I&amp;#8217;m quite busy with school
work and prepping for an &lt;a href="http://www.opensolaris.org"&gt;OpenSolaris&lt;/a&gt; demo
at &lt;a href="http://ruslug.rutgers.edu"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RUSLUG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on this Tuesday. Also, I&amp;#8217;ve
pretty much finished my initial evaluation of &lt;a href="http://www.hyperic.com"&gt;Hyperic
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HQ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and, after reviewing the features of most of
the options, I&amp;#8217;m looking at &lt;a href="http://www.zenoss.com"&gt;Zenoss Core&lt;/a&gt; for the
next&amp;nbsp;round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, instead of anything interesting, a few news stories from the past
few&amp;nbsp;days:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slashdot - an interesting &lt;a href="http://yro.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=08/02/10/1251233&amp;amp;from=rss"&gt;article on search and seizure of
    electronic devices at&amp;nbsp;airports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From
    &lt;a href="http://asuseeehacks.blogspot.com/2008/02/security-alert-asus-eee-pc-vulnerable.html"&gt;asuseeehacks.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;,
    also &lt;a href="http://seclists.org/bugtraq/2008/Feb/0086.html"&gt;bugtraq&lt;/a&gt; - the
    Asus eeePC apparently has a root-level vulnerability in its&amp;#8217;
    out-of-the-box Xandros distro, involving Samba. For people like me
    who put a much better &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; on it, it&amp;#8217;s not a big&amp;nbsp;problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.informationweek.com/news/showArticle.jhtml?articleID=206106956"&gt;InformationWeek is
    reporting&lt;/a&gt;
    that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EU&lt;/span&gt; is investigating Microsoft - again. This time, for
    violating antitrust laws during its&amp;#8217; push for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MSOOXML&lt;/span&gt;. There&amp;#8217;s also
    &lt;a href="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20080208151410252"&gt;a small page at GrokLaw dedicated to this newest
    development&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/news.ars/post/20080207-controversial-college-funding-bill-passedp2p-proviso-intact.html"&gt;According to Ars
    Technica&lt;/a&gt;,
    the congressional bill on college funding that would require schools
    to filter out &lt;span class="caps"&gt;P2P&lt;/span&gt; traffic has &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PASSED&lt;/span&gt; in the House, with the
    filtering clause intact. Fine. Whatever. A gross invasion of
    privacy, and of college students&amp;#8217; rights, but that&amp;#8217;s nothing new.
    However, if I&amp;#8217;m sitting in my office at Rutgers and have a
    &lt;em&gt;single hiccup&lt;/em&gt; downloading
    the OpenSuSE Beta 1 via BitTorrent on April 17th, mark my words, my
    congressmen (and Rutgers administrators) will learn my phone number
    by&amp;nbsp;heart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://recordingindustryvspeople.blogspot.com/2008/02/judge-grants-eff-motion-for-leave-to.html"&gt;Some progress in Arista v. Does
    1-21&lt;/a&gt;,
    the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIAA&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s attack on Boston University students. But, unfortunately,
    the end of the McCarthy-esque tactics doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to be near yet
    and, even worse for me, neither does the likelihood that the
    recording industry will wake up and see what the market&amp;#8217;s asking
    for, and give me downloadable &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DRM&lt;/span&gt;-free music and&amp;nbsp;movies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="antitrust"></category><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="msooxml"></category><category term="opensolaris"></category><category term="p2p"></category><category term="privacy"></category><category term="riaa"></category><category term="rights"></category><category term="ruslug"></category></entry></feed>