<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/mythtv.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 10:37:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>LIRC and Hauppauge PVR-150 on OpenSuSE 11.0</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/09/lirc-and-hauppauge-pvr-150-on-opensuse-110/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Well, despite what&amp;#8217;s been said elsewhere, it &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; possible! It&amp;#8217;s a bit
error-ridden at first, but here is the procedure that I used to compile
and install the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PVR&lt;/span&gt;-150 patched &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LIRC&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;0.8.3-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, Download the tarball mentioned in the &lt;a href="http://www.blushingpenguin.com/mark/blog/?p=24"&gt;Version 3 blog
post&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href="http://www.blushingpenguin.com/mark/blog/"&gt;Marks
Braindump&lt;/a&gt;. You can pretty
much follow his instructions on the installation in the blog post, with
some changes that are specific to getting it to compile on OpenSuSE&amp;nbsp;11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, remove all traces of the OpenSuSE &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LIRC&lt;/span&gt; from you system.
    Uninstall the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPMS&lt;/span&gt; and everything else that goes with them. Then
    unload all of the kernel modules, especially lirc_i2c (if you have
    it&amp;nbsp;loaded).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your kernel source directory, run
    &lt;code&gt;make oldconfig &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make prepare.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your kernel source directory, run &lt;code&gt;make prepare scripts&lt;/code&gt; which,
    among other things, compiles the required &lt;code&gt;genksyms&lt;/code&gt; scurript.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was getting a compile error like &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;WARNING&lt;/span&gt;: Symbol version dump
    /usr/src/`uname -r`/Module.symvers is missing&amp;#8221;. Find out which
    kernel you&amp;#8217;re running (&lt;code&gt;uname -r&lt;/code&gt;). In yout kernel source directory,
    copy your Module.symvers file from /usr/src/linux-obj. I was running
    i386 architecture with the &amp;#8220;default&amp;#8221; kernel, so mine was located at
    &lt;code&gt;/usr/src/linux-obj/i386/debug/Module.symvers&lt;/code&gt;. Copy that into
    &lt;code&gt;/usr/src/linux&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the lirc (patched) directory, run &lt;code&gt;setup.sh&lt;/code&gt; as instructed. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DO&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NOT&lt;/span&gt; tell it to run configure - just save settings and&amp;nbsp;exit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit the generated &lt;code&gt;configure.sh&lt;/code&gt; file, adding a
    &lt;code&gt;--with-kerneldir=/usr/src/KERNELDIR&lt;/code&gt;, replacing &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KERNELDIR&lt;/span&gt; with the
    actual path to your kernel soruce (i.e. /usr/src/`uname&amp;nbsp;-r`).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt;. If no errors, &lt;code&gt;make install&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I decided to reboot at this point, and when I did, everything worked&amp;nbsp;perfectly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I found that I needed to explicitly specify &lt;code&gt;--device=/dev/lirc0&lt;/code&gt;
when starting &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LIRC&lt;/span&gt;, as well as not specifying a driver. I just took the
&lt;code&gt;/etc/init.d/lirc&lt;/code&gt; from the official OpenSuSE 11.0 package, commented
out line 108 in &lt;code&gt;makeargs()&lt;/code&gt; that adds the &lt;code&gt;-H $LIRC_DRIVER&lt;/code&gt; to the
args, and added &lt;code&gt;LIRC_DEVICE="/dev/lirc0"&lt;/code&gt; to the top after the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;INIT&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, figuring out this process took me a long time. I&amp;#8217;ve
reconstructed these instructions from various post-it notes, the
whiteboard next to my desk, and some bash history files and terminal
dumps. If this doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to work for you, please drop an email to
jason &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AT&lt;/span&gt; jason antman &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DOT&lt;/span&gt; com, with as much information as you have, and
I&amp;#8217;ll figure it out and update the&amp;nbsp;instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, finally, an up-to-date system &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AND&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.mythtv.org"&gt;MythTV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 10:37:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-09-01:2008/09/lirc-and-hauppauge-pvr-150-on-opensuse-110/</guid><category>hauppauge</category><category>linux</category><category>lirc</category><category>mythtv</category><category>opensuse</category><category>pvr-150</category><category>suse</category></item><item><title>Massive Updates</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/07/massive-updates/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I know I&amp;#8217;ve been quite for a while. I&amp;#8217;ve been quite busy. Unfortunately,
due to changing priorities, there are a lot of projects I&amp;#8217;ve been
working on, but few of them have gotten finished. A sampling, in no
specific&amp;nbsp;order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migrating my network/service monitoring to Nagios 3, &lt;em&gt;totally&lt;/em&gt;
    re-writing my config files to make use of the new features, and
    making one coherent list of all the services that should be in it
    and&amp;nbsp;aren&amp;#8217;t.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning to totally re-wire all networking at the &lt;a href="http://www.midlandparkambulance.com"&gt;ambulance corps
    building&lt;/a&gt; to eliminate some
    problems. This includes &lt;em&gt;building&lt;/em&gt; an 8U wall-mount rack, and also
    trying a &lt;a href="http://www.pcengines.ch/alix2c1.htm"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt; Engines &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ALIX&lt;/span&gt;.2c1&lt;/a&gt;
    board as a router (still undecided on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WAN&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DMZ&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WAN&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;WLAN&lt;/span&gt;).
    It also means a long day of work at some point in the future, and
    lots of cable&amp;nbsp;drops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://tuxostat.jasonantman.com"&gt;tuxOstat&lt;/a&gt;, the linux-controlled
    thermostat, is pretty much on the back burner. It&amp;#8217;s a stable beta
    with severely reduced functionality, but has been handling my
    cooling needs without any major bugs in the past month or so. It
    still only has a basic &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; interface and a very simple kludge of a
    web &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt;, but it works. Other modes (heating, fan only), predictive
    temperature calculation, other temperature/zone calculation modes,
    and physical controls (buttons, menu on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LCD&lt;/span&gt;) are still to come, as
    well as the move from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt; to Soekris (if I can ever figure it out,
    and get one with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt;). I now feel that an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ALIX&lt;/span&gt; board might be a
    better shot, as they take &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CF&lt;/span&gt; (more space than the Soekris), have a
    slightly faster processor, and also support &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; at about half the
    price&amp;nbsp;point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#8217;m considering moving my main web site to a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CMS&lt;/span&gt;, and letting the
    &lt;a href="http://www.jasonantman.com/wiki/"&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt; serve more as a knowledge&amp;nbsp;base.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#8217;m working on patching together a new access point for the
    ambulance corps, based on &lt;a href="http://pyramid.metrix.net/"&gt;Pyramid
    Linux&lt;/a&gt;. I needed something which would
    run on the Soekris net4526, had at least &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WEP&lt;/span&gt;, and supported some
    sort of captive portal. Pyramid has
    &lt;a href="http://dev.wifidog.org/"&gt;WifiDog&lt;/a&gt;, but that only wants to do local
    authentication or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RADIUS&lt;/span&gt;, and I wanted direct auth to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LDAP&lt;/span&gt; and MySQL
    logging. On the positive side, it just uses some &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; pages hosted
    under Apache to handle authentication - the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WAP&lt;/span&gt; redirects the user
    to a login page on a (separate) web server, the user does their
    stuff, and then the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WAP&lt;/span&gt; makes a request to the server to determine
    whether it should open up the firewall, keep the user locked down,
    or totally kick them. So, once I figure out some routing issues,
    I&amp;#8217;ll get back to working on the new project -
    &lt;a href="http://blacklabauth.jasonantman.com/"&gt;BlackLabAuth&lt;/a&gt;, a re-write of
    the WifiDog auth server software that&amp;#8217;s geared towards a
    closed-access network (i.e. only people and/or MACs already listed
    in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LDAP&lt;/span&gt; can login) with full logging to MySQL. I already have some
    code &lt;a href="http://cvs.jasonantman.com/BlackLabAuth"&gt;in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but some
    issues with my development Soekris board have slowed the project for
    the time being. When finished, I&amp;#8217;ll have not only the new auth
    server available for download (with documentation) but also a
    ready-to-run (well, some configuration time needed, but minor and
    scripted) image for the&amp;nbsp;net4526.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My desktop that I use for &lt;a href="http://www.mythtv.org/"&gt;MythTV&lt;/a&gt; filled up
    its&amp;#8217; disk. Totally. I ordered a cheap Syba &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SATA&lt;/span&gt; card (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PCI&lt;/span&gt;) from
    NewEgg, along with a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;500GB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WD&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SATA&lt;/span&gt;-150 disk, but no luck. Though the
    card (Syba / Initio 1622 chipset, shows up as Class 0106: 1101:1622
    (rev 02)) said it was supported under Linux, the driver &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt; mentioned
    nothing about it. Some investigation on the Syba website turned up a
    zipped archive. After extraction, I found a readme that gave (poor)
    instructions on how to re-compile a kernel, and warned that you &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MUST&lt;/span&gt;
    have 2.6.15. Oh well, I wasn&amp;#8217;t going to give up 2.6.16.27 (the
    newest &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;d kernel for OpenSuSE 10.1). The standard drivers for it
    didn&amp;#8217;t appear until 2.6.25 or so. So&amp;#8230; after many debates with
    myself as to whether I should blow away my whole MythTV installation
    and upgrade from the now-ancient 10.1, I decided that I&amp;#8217;ll only be
    in my apartment for another year, I should make it last. Some
    investigation turned up a $24 Silicon Image-based card that should
    work fine, and it&amp;#8217;s now in the&amp;nbsp;mail&amp;#8230;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m sure I missed something big, but I&amp;#8217;ll update as needed, and attempt
to make it a daily habit to post something interesting or, at the very
least, hard-to-find. After all, I&amp;#8217;m sure that I use this blog and my
wiki as an informational resource (my bad memory) more than anyone else&amp;nbsp;would&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2008 12:28:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-07-17:2008/07/massive-updates/</guid><category>access point</category><category>alix</category><category>BlackLabAuth</category><category>mythtv</category><category>Nagios</category><category>pc engines</category><category>soekris</category><category>tuxostat</category><category>WifiDog</category><category>wireless</category></item><item><title>February 26, 2008</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/02/february-26-2008/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Well, while I haven&amp;#8217;t made much progress on anything interesting -
mainly my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NMS&lt;/span&gt; comparison or any of my other projects - due to my busy
schedule, I did get an hour or two to clean up my network at the
apartment, swapping out my 24-port Linksys switch in my room for the
5-port Netgear previously used for printing. I threw all of the printers
and the print server on their own &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VLAN&lt;/span&gt; on the main 3com&amp;nbsp;switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve also started thinking more about &lt;a href="http://www.mythtv.org/"&gt;MythTV&lt;/a&gt; -
I use it for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; in my room (feeding a grossly insufficient 21&amp;#8221; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CRT&lt;/span&gt;
monitor), and my roommate has a Dell &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GX270&lt;/span&gt; by the big &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; in the living
room, though it was running Freevo (and now has a dead tuner and no &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt;,
or something like that). So, I decided that I might do things right -
drop a 5- or 8-port GigE switch in the apartment, put GigE NICs in the
two boxes with tuners (putting MythTV on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GX270&lt;/span&gt; also), and setting up
a centralized system. The problem is that the ideal solution would be a
single dedicated back-end system for storage and control, with the two
tuner/video out boxes just providing A/V I/O. Unfortunately, the two
boxes with tuners are both high-spec&amp;#8217;ed P4&amp;#8217;s, and I&amp;#8217;m not sure what I
can come up with in terms of a server for the&amp;nbsp;backend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, &lt;em&gt;the question for anyone who may be
reading&lt;/em&gt; - I&amp;#8217;d like to setup a good amount (1-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;2TB&lt;/span&gt;) of storage for
this. My roommate wants a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAID&lt;/span&gt; configuration, but I don&amp;#8217;t see the need
for videos - if I lose my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; recordings, I set MythTV to record it again
the next time it&amp;#8217;s on. Anyway, I have an 8-bay external &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCAI&lt;/span&gt; enclosure
and cards in all of the servers, but &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCSI&lt;/span&gt; disks are expensive. I was
thinking of going to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SATA&lt;/span&gt; 3.0. Most likely, I&amp;#8217;d get some sort of 4-8
disk enclosure, start with 1-3 disks in the 400-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;750GB&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the question - what type of system specs would be needed to stream
audio and video, uncompressed, perhaps even &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDTV&lt;/span&gt; (we have the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; and
cable box, would just need an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HD&lt;/span&gt; tuner) to remote storage over the
network? I was thinking of doing either a Linux master MythTV backend
with eSATA cards, or letting each &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; computer be its&amp;#8217; own backend, and
then doing Solaris/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ZFS&lt;/span&gt; with iSCSI or ATAoE. Any suggestions? I&amp;#8217;m pretty
much thinking of using a PowerEdge 2550 for&amp;nbsp;this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&amp;#8217;m also filling up my backup disks at home, and don&amp;#8217;t want to
shorten my expiration cycle. My nightly backup runs put quite a strain
on my main Fast Ethernet &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;, so I&amp;#8217;ve been planning for a while on
moving to GigE. My thought at home is to setup a second, separate GigE
switch/lan, with GigE NICs in all of the servers. Not exactly cheap, but
I can pickup a Linux-/Solaris-compatible Negear &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GA311&lt;/span&gt; for around $40, in
addition to the Intel Pro/1000 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XT&lt;/span&gt; and Asante GigaNIC that I already
have. The problem here is finding a good GigE switch - I&amp;#8217;d really like
something with Telnet, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SNMP&lt;/span&gt;, VLANs, the&amp;nbsp;works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, I highly recommend reading the &lt;a href="http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20080221184924826"&gt;Groklaw story on
Microsoft&amp;#8217;s latest pledge for
interoperability&lt;/a&gt;.
I especially liked the one quote from the &lt;a href="http://www.ecis.eu/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ECIS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years now, Microsoft has either failed to implement or has
actively corrupted a range of truly open standards adopted and
implemented by the rest of the industry. Unless and until that
behaviour stops, today&amp;#8217;s words mean&amp;nbsp;nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More fundamentally, today&amp;#8217;s announcement is still all about the rest
of the world interoperating with Microsoft on Microsoft&amp;#8217;s own terms,
not the other way&amp;nbsp;around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s even links to &lt;em&gt;ten&lt;/em&gt; previous Microsoft statements promising&amp;nbsp;interoperability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, this is a promise to interoperate with old-fashioned
competitors. It doesn&amp;#8217;t enable interoperability with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;, which is
not compatible with patent licenses, and that is Microsoft&amp;#8217;s true&amp;nbsp;competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Michael Cunningham, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VP&lt;/span&gt; and General Counsel of Red&amp;nbsp;Hat:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eight years ago the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;U.S.&lt;/span&gt; regulatory authorities, and four years ago
the European regulators made clear to Microsoft that its refusal to
disclose interface information for its monopoly software products
violates the law. So, it is hardly surprising to see even Microsoft
state today that “interoperability across systems is an important
requirement” and announce a “change in [its] approach to
interoperability.” Of course, we’ve heard similar announcements
before, almost always strategically timed for other effect. Red Hat
regards this most recent announcement with a healthy dose of
skepticism. Three commitments by Microsoft would show that it really
means what it is announcing&amp;nbsp;today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit to open standards: Rather than pushing forward its
    proprietary, Windows-based formats for document processing, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt;,
    Microsoft should embrace the existing &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt;-approved, cross-platform
    industry standard for document processing, Open Document Format
    (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ODF&lt;/span&gt;) at the International Standards Organization’s meeting next
    week in Geneva. Microsoft, please demonstrate implementation of an
    existing international open standard now rather than make press
    announcements about intentions of future standards&amp;nbsp;support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit to interoperability with open source: Instead of offering a
    patent license for its protocol information on the basis of
    licensing arrangements it knows are incompatible with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt; –
    the world’s most widely used open source software license –
    Microsoft should extend its Open Specification Promise to all of
    the interoperability information that it is announcing today will
    be made available. The Open Specification Promise already covers
    many Microsoft products that do not have monopoly market
    positions. If Microsoft were truly committed to fostering openness
    and preventing customer lock-in, it would extend this promise to
    the protocol and interface information it intends to disclose
    today. There is no explanation for refusing to extend the Open
    Specification Promise to “high-volume” products, other than a
    continued intention on Microsoft’s part to lock customers into its
    monopoly products, and lock out competitors through patent&amp;nbsp;threats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit to competition on a level playing field: Microsoft’s
    announcement today appears carefully crafted to foreclose
    competition from the open source community. How else can you
    explain a “promise not to sue open source developers” as long as
    they develop and distribute only*/ “non-commercial”
    implementations of interoperable products? This is simply
    disingenuous. The only hope for reintroducing competition to the
    monopoly markets Microsoft now controls – Windows, Office, etc. –
    is through commercial distributions of competitive open source
    software&amp;nbsp;products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amen!!!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 11:32:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-02-26:2008/02/february-26-2008/</guid><category>GigE</category><category>microsoft</category><category>mythtv</category><category>sata</category><category>storage</category></item><item><title>Update</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/07/update/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#8217;t been too active on here lately, mainly due to spending my
summer as a paid transport &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMT&lt;/span&gt;, working 50 hours a week or so, and still
trying to keep up on&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;life&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a few things planned for the next month or so of summer, so stay
tuned. Some of them&amp;nbsp;include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redesign of my site including lots of information that&amp;#8217;s been stored
    away in text files, and a new wiki for technical&amp;nbsp;information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some embedded development work, and notes on&amp;nbsp;that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Converting some sort of low-cost handheld computer, tablet, or eBook
    reader for use as a Linux-based &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; reader (updated over &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt; nightly
    and cached locally), hopefully including an image of my software as
    well as some conduit to an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; reader program, and ability to email
    a list of &amp;#8220;flagged&amp;#8221; articles on sync (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; update over&amp;nbsp;network).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A vast update of my &lt;a href="http://repo.jasonantman.com"&gt;Code Repo&lt;/a&gt; with
    most of my home-grown F/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt; programs, including my (very basic)
    web-based budget/finance&amp;nbsp;program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An update to &lt;a href="http://php-ems-tools.com"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes on my experience with MythTV, an integrating it with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IR&lt;/span&gt;
    controls, Cablevision &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SA&lt;/span&gt; set-top box, and ultimately a &amp;#8220;smart&amp;nbsp;room&amp;#8221;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My never-ending quest to find a way to interface a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CDMA&lt;/span&gt; handset to a
    computer for purposes of sending &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt; from the command line (Nagios
    out-of-band alerts on a&amp;nbsp;budget).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A trial run of Asterisk and VoIP from the house to the&amp;nbsp;dorm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some more projects including:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finding and implementing a hardware/software trouble- and
    change-tracking system, which will also integrate with my&amp;nbsp;Wiki.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choosing bug tracking software for my internal&amp;nbsp;projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choosing and implementing a network-wide backup system to handle
    *nix, Windows, and my remote *nix&amp;nbsp;machines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenSolaris.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figuring out a system to handle automated nightly/weekly tasks
    on my diverse machines including log analysis, backups, software
    updates, and the usual stuff (SpamAssassin updates and training
    and other routine&amp;nbsp;tasks).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A status tracker/to-do list of my numerous&amp;nbsp;projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Releasing most of my web-based kludges under &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt; for anyone who
    may be&amp;nbsp;interested.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2007 01:14:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-07-14:2007/07/update/</guid><category>emergency medical</category><category>linux</category><category>mythtv</category><category>php ems tools</category><category>tablet</category><category>update</category></item></channel></rss>