<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/net-neutrality.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 09:07:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>Net Neutrality - What is it, and what will the recent FCC decision do?</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2010/12/net-neutrality-what-is-it-and-what-will-the-recent-fcc-decision-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_neutrality"&gt;Net Neutrality&lt;/a&gt; is a
&lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt; issue these days, and one that&amp;#8217;s exploded out of the geek
circles into mainstream media. I&amp;#8217;ll admit that it seems like there are
endless variations on exactly what people consider Net Neutrality to be
(or what it &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be). The general goal of Net Neutrality is to
ensure that Internet Service Providers (ISPs) provide (relatively)
unfiltered access to the Internet to their customers. Specifically, that
if a given customer pays for a level of service - i.e. 10 Mbps
downstream speed and 2.5 Mbps upstream speed - they receive that speed
no matter what they are accessing. The goal of Net Neutrality is to
require ISPs to treat their connections as a &amp;#8220;common carrier&amp;#8221;, much like
telephone companies or freight trucks. Within reason (excepting
explosives and other hazardous materials), &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt; will ship a package for a
given rate based only on what it weighs and how far it&amp;#8217;s going (since
the Internet is run by many companies, and data passes from one to
another, the distance portion of this analogy is constant). They don&amp;#8217;t
charge more based on what&amp;#8217;s in the box, and they don&amp;#8217;t ship come boxes
faster than others based simply on who sent it or what&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, over the past century, many laws have been created that
regulate the telephone industry. While there was a time when customers
had to rent their telephones from the phone company, long-standing
legislation states that a customer can hook any properly functioning
device into the phone network, and a customer can say whatever they want
over the phone and receive the same call quality, at the same&amp;nbsp;rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To try and summarize, the goal of Net Neutrality is to ensure that you,
the customer of an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; (whether cable, FiOS, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DSL&lt;/span&gt;, etc.), is entitled to
certain rights. Generally (the exact interpretation of this concept
varies) this&amp;nbsp;includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to connect any device you want to your Internet
    connection - any computer, game console, or other device, running
    any operating system or other&amp;nbsp;software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your ability to connect to any service (web site, protocol, etc.)
    that you want without it being intentionally degraded or slowed
    down, even if it&amp;#8217;s a service viewed to be a competitor of your&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your ability to transfer data to and from any other user of the
    Internet, regardless of who they&amp;nbsp;are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What could happen if Net Neutrality isn&amp;#8217;t&amp;nbsp;enforced?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me first say that most of the following is pure speculation. These
are things that &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; happen, but most have not yet actually been
done. Some have. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; industry seems to say that Net Neutrality is &amp;#8220;a
solution without a problem&amp;#8221;, but my personal view is that those are
generally good things. Preventing a problem from occurring is generally
better than fixing it after it&amp;#8217;s a problem. So here are a few scenarios
of what could happen if Net Neutrality isn&amp;#8217;t properly legislated and&amp;nbsp;enforced:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies like Cablevision, Comcast, Verizon, and other major ISPs
    also offer &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; services (Optimum, FiOS &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;, etc.) that include Video
    On Demand (VoD) as a separate paid service. Websites like Hulu and
    Netflix offer the same service, for free or a much cheaper rate.
    Without Net Neutrality, your &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; could intentionally slow down or
    block sites like Hulu or Netflix to force you to buy their more
    expensive service. Comcast has &lt;a href="http://www.computerworld.com/s/article/9198498/Comcast_demands_fees_for_Web_movie_viewing_Level_3_says"&gt;already
    tried&lt;/a&gt;
    to do something like this, asking Netflix&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; for a substantial
    fee to allow Comcast customers to access Netfix (that&amp;#8217;s a bit of an
    oversimplification, but gets the point). If this happens, it&amp;#8217;s most
    likely that Netfix will have to increase their fees substantially.
    Net Neutrality legislation would require ISPs like Comcast to treat
    all Internet traffic the same, whether it&amp;#8217;s from Netflix, Facebook,
    or my humble little&amp;nbsp;blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few ISPs (mainly Comcast) have already tried all-out blocking Peer
    to Peer (p2p) file sharing traffic such as bitTorrent, Kazaa, etc.
    While they cite copyright infringement as the reason, there are many
    people who use p2p file sharing to distribute legal files, such as
    the Linux operating system and other free software. Blocking all p2p
    traffic because some people use it for illegal purposes is based on
    a presumption of guilt, no different from outlawing steak knives
    because some people stab other people with&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Throughout the history of the Internet, some of the most popular and
    innovative technologies, including Google, Facebook, etc. have
    started out as small projects run by a few geeks and programmers. If
    ISPs were allowed to charge content providers (i.e. websites) to be
    viewed by the ISPs customers, it would limit innovation and new
    technologies to only the big businesses with enough money to pay
    these artificial&amp;nbsp;tolls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most ISPs also offer a phone service. It would be trivial for them
    to flat-out prevent their customers from using Vonage, Skype, iChat,
    etc. and force you to subscribe to their service. It&amp;#8217;s also possible
    for them to do this in a covert way - when Comcast blocked
    bitTorrent users, they did it in a way so clever that it took weeks
    for experts to figure&amp;nbsp;out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Without a mandate that any suitable device can connect to the
    network, your &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; could partner with, for example, Dell and
    Microsoft, and say that you could only get Internet access on a Dell
    computer running the latest version of Windows (yes, this is a bit
    of a stretch, but possible in an unregulated &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;market).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important fact to note here is that most people in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; don&amp;#8217;t have
much choice in terms of broadband ISPs - generally the only &amp;#8220;choice&amp;#8221; is
between the cable and phone companies, who provide more or less the same
service. With such limited choice, Internet users are effectively held
hostage by the policies of a handful of companies that control Internet&amp;nbsp;access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A short note on the History of the&amp;nbsp;Internet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to the ISPs &amp;#8220;solution without a problem&amp;#8221; view, I think this is
a solution that should have been implemented long ago. The network that
evolved into what we now know as the Internet, in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;, was first
developed in the 1970s. The project, ARPAnet, was developed by the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;
government for research purposes, and funded by taxpayer money. It
wasn&amp;#8217;t opened to commercial use until the early 1990s, when it was
privatized. While the development into what is now the Internet could
never have been foreseen at that time, Net Neutrality rules should have
been built in from the start when the project was handed over from the
federal government to the private sector. Regardless, it must be
remembered that the Internet is a technology that was originally
developed with taxpayer funds, for the country as a&amp;nbsp;whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;doing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, in short, not much. It appears that the Net Neutrality rules
delivered by the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt; earlier this week are, more than anything, a
compromise effort to make the issue just &amp;#8220;go away&amp;#8221;. The ISPs feel that
the rules aren&amp;#8217;t needed (and argue that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt; doesn&amp;#8217;t have the power
to make them), and most Net Neutrality proponents feel that the rules
pay only lip service to the goals of Net Neutrality. The main failings
already apparent in the rules&amp;nbsp;are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two of three major parts of the rules ignore wireless ISPs (cellular
    carriers). With the explosion of smartphones, it seems that wireless
    is not only the new frontier of the Internet, but the way that more
    and more people get Internet access. If Net Neutrality is
    legislated, it should be about the Internet - regardless of how a
    customer is connected to the&amp;nbsp;network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a provision for ISPs to be able to block or slow down
    traffic as is &amp;#8220;reasonable&amp;#8221; to operate their network, but there are
    no guidelines on what &amp;#8220;reasonable&amp;#8221; means, and it seems that the
    burden of proof would be on the customer to fight their &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; in court
    and show that something was&amp;nbsp;unreasonable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until very recently, ISPs generally didn&amp;#8217;t engage in the kind of
conduct that Net Neutrality rules would prohibit. The Internet as we
know it today is a product of a world with unwritten Net Neutrality
rules. Amazing sites and services like Facebook, Google, Twitter, and
many others started as experiments by a few dedicated people with little
to no budget. The fact that you can easily view web pages created by
anyone - like my blog - would be ended if website publishers had to pay
ISPs to be allowed through. The choice that you have in using your &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; or phone service, or something like Netflix or Vonage, is central to
the Internet as we know it, but is under attack. I know that many people
look at this as a &amp;#8220;problem for the geeks&amp;#8221;. We take the Internet for
granted. Over the next few days, every time you visit a web site or use
an Internet-based service, ask yourself: Would I be happy if I had to
pay for this? Would this even exist if the people who designed it had to
pay from day one? Make no mistake, if websites have to pay every &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; in
the country to be viewed, the days of wonderful free services sustained
by advertising revenue only will be long&amp;nbsp;gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In closing, I highly recommend reading an &lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2010/12/steve-wozniak-to-the-fcc-keep-the-internet-free/68294/"&gt;open letter on Net Neutrality
by Steve
Wozniak&lt;/a&gt;,
co-founder of Apple, genius, and guy who helped change the world as we
know&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other interesting&amp;nbsp;links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/timothy-karr/obama-fcc-caves-on-net-ne_b_799435.html"&gt;Obama &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt; Caves on Net Neutrality &amp;#8212; Tuesday Betrayal
    Assured&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huffington&amp;nbsp;Post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2010/12/21/fcc-we-didnt-impose-stricter-net-neutrality-regulations-on-wir/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt;: We didn&amp;#8217;t impose stricter net neutrality regulations on
    wireless because Android is
    open&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engadget&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://act.boldprogressives.org/sign/sign_netneutrality_3things/?akid=3050.937978.xH20je&amp;amp;rd=1&amp;amp;source=e1-netflix-fin&amp;amp;t=3"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt; breaks Obama&amp;#8217;s promise on Net Neutrality: 3 things you need to
    know&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BoldProgressives.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 09:07:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2010-12-23:2010/12/net-neutrality-what-is-it-and-what-will-the-recent-fcc-decision-do/</guid><category>free speech</category><category>freedom</category><category>internet</category><category>net neutrality</category></item></channel></rss>