<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/open-source.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://newblog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2010-03-02T21:45:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>The Newest Generation of Hackers</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2010/03/the-newest-generation-of-hackers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-02T21:45:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2010-03-02:2010/03/the-newest-generation-of-hackers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note for non-technical readers (not that I expect there to be many).
The title of this post includes the word &amp;#8220;hacker&amp;#8221;. If you think that has
anything to do with illegal acts or unethical behavior, you&amp;#8217;ve fallen
victim to what happens when the mainstream media latches on to a term
they don&amp;#8217;t understand. The
&lt;a href="http://www.catb.org/jargon/html/H/hacker.html"&gt;definition&lt;/a&gt; of
this word is far from negative. Within the geek community, the title
&amp;#8220;hacker&amp;#8221; is the utmost compliment - something like Grand Master in the
martial arts, or perhaps whatever title is given to an eminent artist.
It both describes someone who is an expert in their field. Or, more
generally, someone who enjoys seeking knowledge simply for the sake of
knowledge - figuring out how things work, how to make them, and how to
make them better. If you&amp;#8217;re looking for a term that describes a
criminal, &amp;#8220;attacker&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;malicious user&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;computer criminal&amp;#8221; work fine.
While I wouldn&amp;#8217;t by any extent consider myself a hacker in the
super-genius-wizard sense of the term, I do definitely subscribe to the
hacker ethic - the burning need to figure out how things work and make
them&amp;nbsp;better.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the snow at the end of last week, and a long weekend, I
actually got to do some reading that didn&amp;#8217;t involve man pages or books
strictly about software. I finally finished &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Daemon-Gnu-Penguin-Peter-Salus/dp/097903423X"&gt;The Daemon, the Gnu, and
the
Penguin&lt;/a&gt;
by Peter H. Salus, a wonderful book (with a great foreword by maddog
Hall). I also &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; got a chance to start reading &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Cathedral-Bazaar-Musings-Accidental-Revolutionary/dp/0596001088/"&gt;The Cathedral &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;
the Bazaar: Musings on Linux and Open Source by an Accidental
Revolutionary&lt;/a&gt;
by Eric S. Raymond (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ESR&lt;/span&gt;). I&amp;#8217;m only up to page 50 or so, but it&amp;#8217;s an
equally good book, and I&amp;#8217;ve been looking forward to reading it for&amp;nbsp;years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve always been very interested in history (heck, I have a minor in
it), and specifically the history of my other interests. When
photography took up most of my time, I read every photo history book I
could get my hands on (including many primary sources on now-archaic
techniques). In the past few years, I&amp;#8217;ve been amassing books on
computing history (specifically &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ARPANET&lt;/span&gt;/the Internet and Unix/Linux/Free
software) at a near-alarming&amp;nbsp;rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through all of my reading, two main things have struck me: the utterly
amazing feats accomplished by previous generations, and how my own
generation takes them for granted. I was born in 1987 which, I feel,
makes me part of a very small group who were lucky enough to grow up
during the real rise of the Internet. I remember playing simple games on
my grandmother&amp;#8217;s (business) &lt;span class="caps"&gt;386DX&lt;/span&gt; long before I could read most of the
words on the screen. But I also remember my father dialing in to an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;
(I honestly don&amp;#8217;t remember which one) on a 9600 baud serial modem, and
how unique that was at the time (at least among kids my age). By 13 or
so, I had a 10BaseT network in my house, sharing a 56k dial-up
connection between two computers. I feel that I&amp;#8217;m part of a short
historical period of kids who &amp;#8220;grew up&amp;#8221; with computers, used them in
middle school, are perfectly at home with them, but still remember
dial-up, the launch of Windows 98, and ordering Linux on CDs because you
just couldn&amp;#8217;t get it any other way (too young to have access to the
resources of a college, only&amp;nbsp;dial-up).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, on to my&amp;nbsp;point&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I read about those who stepped before me (and my generation), those
who thought up such amazing ideas as Unix, the Internet, networking and
most of the software and protocols we have today, I realize how big
their shoes are, and how difficult it will be for the next generation to
fill them. Sure, we have Facebook, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; feeds, Web 2.0 and smartphones,
but will we be able to innovate on the level that those who came before
us did? And then it strikes me how much we young aspiring hackers take
for granted. How many aspects of technology today would be seemed
impossible 20 years ago, but we use without a second&amp;nbsp;thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last generation of hackers and programmers were raised on software
distribution tapes. Their idea of &amp;#8220;open&amp;#8221; was formed by what they were
used to - a Cathedral development model, with regular releases
(production, perhaps beta, perhaps even less) and accompanying source
code. However, in the pre-Internet days, they were still bound by
physical media. They were still bound to the Cathedral development
model, to a small and tight-knit group of sages determining when the
world was ready to see the fruits of their&amp;nbsp;labor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current generation - those of us just out of college or grad school,
or even younger - think of Linux as the quintessential open source
project. For those of us who came into computing when Linux was already
around (I first ran Linux in 2001 when, at 14, I bought the
newly-released &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt; set of SuSE 7.3), Linux sets the bar. It&amp;#8217;s what we
were raised on (at least in terms of open source). Fixed releases - even
with source - seem antiquated, pre-Internet, our fathers&amp;#8217; open source.
To us, open means nightly builds, world-readable ticket/bug trackers,
anonymous Git or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SVN&lt;/span&gt; access, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; feeds of every commit. It means
being able to see every line of code at every moment in time, even if
we&amp;#8217;ve never e-mailed one of the&amp;nbsp;developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even just a few years ago, the word &amp;#8220;open&amp;#8221; was used by vendors to mean
almost anything - everything from software based on Linux, to software
that included source (regardless of the license) to software that just
used (patent encumbered) documented protocols or formats. For the next
generation, even the generation entering the workforce now, open means
much more. It means transparency in development, in code, in
documentation, in&amp;nbsp;management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many times, I&amp;#8217;ve found an &amp;#8220;open&amp;#8221; software project, and searched their
web site endlessly looking for links to Git or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SVN&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt;. Or looked
endlessly for the (internal) bug tracker. Every time, I had to remind
myself that the world, even many of the open source projects, are still
far behind my expectations. Even Google&amp;#8217;s Android Open Source project
only has code merged in periodically from the production (closed) tree,
and maintains a separate bug tracker. Far from my expectation of just
having some parts of the tree unavailable on the Internet, and some
classes of bugs filtered out from public&amp;nbsp;view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody - not even Microsoft - can deny that the world is moving more and
more to open source. It&amp;#8217;s already the de-facto standard on the Internet,
but it&amp;#8217;s moving more and more to the desktop every day. And, as this
happens, the expectations of what open means (increasingly more
transparent than just &amp;#8220;open&amp;#8221;) are also increasing. The software world -
both proprietary and open source - will have to keep up. And, hopefully,
as the generation raised on the Internet begins to fill the ranks of
geeks in the workforce, we&amp;#8217;ll see more and more open source&amp;nbsp;usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a side note, I&amp;#8217;d be very interested to see how open source use
compares to demographics. I know that Linux use (on student-owned
computers) at most colleges is way above the global average, and the
same goes for&amp;nbsp;Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="free"></category><category term="hacker"></category><category term="linux"></category><category term="open source"></category><category term="svn"></category></entry><entry><title>F/OSS Monitoring Comparison - Hyperic Part I</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2008/02/foss-monitoring-comparison-hyperic-part-i/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-02-08T16:54:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2008-02-08:2008/02/foss-monitoring-comparison-hyperic-part-i/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;#8217;ve made some headway on the comparison. I have Hyperic installed
and partly configured, albeit without email alerts yet. I&amp;#8217;ve found some
serious features that I need missing, but I&amp;#8217;m going to give it a full
run before I move on to&amp;nbsp;another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full text, updated a few times a day, is available on &lt;a href="http://www.jasonantman.com/wiki/index.php/Network_Monitoring_Comparison"&gt;my
wiki&lt;/a&gt;.
Here&amp;#8217;s a bit of an&amp;nbsp;excerpt:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="part-i-installation"&gt;Part I -&amp;nbsp;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;setup Xen virtual machine running OpenSuSE 10.3 base packages. (3
    hours, some server problems, some Xen problems, and some time
    learning Xen administration from the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download &lt;code&gt;hyperic-hq-installer-3.2.0-607-x86-linux.tgz&lt;/code&gt; from
    &lt;a href="http://www.hyperic.com/downloads/dl-hq-oss.html" title="http://www.hyperic.com/downloads/dl-hq-oss.html"&gt;Hyperic&lt;/a&gt;
    and&amp;nbsp;extract.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browse to
    &lt;a href="http://support.hyperic.com/confluence/display/DOC/Full+Installation+Guide" title="http://support.hyperic.com/confluence/display/DOC/Full+Installation+Guide"&gt;http://support.hyperic.com/confluence/display/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DOC&lt;/span&gt;/Full+Installation+Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; into &lt;code&gt;hyperic-hq-installer&lt;/code&gt; and run &lt;code&gt;./setup.sh -full&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The installation can&amp;#8217;t be run as root (though I assumed it would
    need root&amp;nbsp;privileges).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I selected to install all 3 components - Server, Shell, and&amp;nbsp;Agent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well, whoops! Sorta stupid to not allow installation as root,
    when the default location to install to is &lt;code&gt;/home/hyperic&lt;/code&gt;. How
    do they expect an arbitrary user to install there? Even worse,
    it appears that the default OpenSuSE 10.3 installation doesn&amp;#8217;t
    come with &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; (!!!!) so I can&amp;#8217;t try&amp;nbsp;that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As root, create &lt;code&gt;/home/hyperic&lt;/code&gt; and chown to my&amp;nbsp;user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repear the above steps (well, hopefully not all of&amp;nbsp;them).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default ports for everything - web &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; on 7080, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTPS&lt;/span&gt; web &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; on
    7443, jnp service on 2099, mbean server on&amp;nbsp;9093,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change domain names in default URLs to logical ones for my test
    environment (no real &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt;, just IPcop hosts, so
    devel-hyperic1.localdomian). I hope that I can change these
    later, or even better that absolute paths aren&amp;#8217;t used too much,
    as this will screw with my idea of using &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; port forwarding for
    remote&amp;nbsp;access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leave the default &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMTP&lt;/span&gt; server alone and change it later - I
    odn&amp;#8217;t even have mail running here at the&amp;nbsp;apartment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the built-in PostgreSQL database with default port of&amp;nbsp;9432.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go with the defaults for everything after&amp;nbsp;this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything runs nicely, and then it tells you to login to
    another terminal as root and run a script. I&amp;#8217;m not sure I like
    this method, but I guess it works. Login and do&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How will it start the builtin database? As my user???? Yup.
    postgres is running as my user. Wonderful. Nothing in the
    &lt;a href="http://support.hyperic.com/confluence/display/DOC/Full+Installation+Guide" title="http://support.hyperic.com/confluence/display/DOC/Full+Installation+Guide"&gt;install
    document&lt;/a&gt;
    mentioned user creation. Was this just assumed? Because in the
    naive world I live in, most installer scripts (think Nagios)
    create a user for you, or tell you&amp;nbsp;to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup script complete. A few instructions&amp;nbsp;follow&amp;#8230;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;/home/hyperic/server-3.2.0/bin/hq-server.sh start&lt;/code&gt;&amp;#8230; as my
    user. &lt;em&gt;Note to self:&lt;/em&gt; setup a user for Postgres and Hyperic. Believe
    it or not, but it booted - but followed with the message, &amp;#8220;Login to
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HQ&lt;/span&gt; at:
    &lt;a href="http://127.0.0.1:7080/" title="http://127.0.0.1:7080/"&gt;http://127.0.0.1:7080/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browsed to
    &lt;a href="http://devel-hyperic1:7080/" title="http://devel-hyperic1:7080"&gt;http://devel-hyperic1:7080&lt;/a&gt;
    and was greeted by a startup page, saying that the server was 18%
    finished booting. My, I yearn for little C binaries and a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;frontend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Page turns blank and stops there. I refresh, and get a login page. I
    enter my username and password, and get a little message box where
    the &amp;#8220;invalid password&amp;#8221; box usually is - says &amp;#8220;Server is still
    booting&amp;#8221;. This is over a minute later. I&amp;#8217;m happy to see
    Apache/Coyote1.1, but would like to be able to get into Hyperic in
    less time than it takes the machine to boot to a graphical login
    screen (ok, granted, I&amp;#8217;m running &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XFCE&lt;/span&gt;). In SuSE&amp;#8217;s YaST Xen Monitor,
    I see that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VM&lt;/span&gt; is at 45% of its&amp;#8217; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;464MB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt;, and 90% &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CPU&lt;/span&gt; - with
    8.5% consumed by&amp;nbsp;dom0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CPU&lt;/span&gt; usage for the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VM&lt;/span&gt; drops to 1% and I login again. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BAM&lt;/span&gt;! Hyperic &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HQ&lt;/span&gt;.
    Aside from the fact that it shows &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NO&lt;/span&gt; resources&amp;#8230; oh&amp;#8230; start the&amp;nbsp;Agent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start the Agent on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VM&lt;/span&gt; running Hyperic. It asks me for the server
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; address. What, no &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt;? I enter the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; as it is&amp;#8230; for now. I keep
    everything at defaults, including using the hqadmin username and
    password. Successfully&amp;nbsp;started.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;BAM&lt;/span&gt;! In Dashboard, I see the auto-discovered host with the right
    hostname, as well as Tomcat, Agent, JBoss, and PostgreSQL. Amazing!
    Click &amp;#8220;Add to&amp;nbsp;Inventory&amp;#8221;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out the &amp;#8220;Resources&amp;#8221; -&gt; &amp;#8220;Browse&amp;#8221; screen. It knows this machine
    is OpenSuSE 10.3, and I see my four services (listed above). Of
    course, no metrics yet, but I see the correct &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt;, gateway, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt;,
    vendor (SuSE), kernel version, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt;, architecture, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CPU&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking through the &amp;#8220;Inventory&amp;#8221; screen, I see everything - NICs and
    MACs, running servers and one service (a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CPU&lt;/span&gt; resource). What more
    could a man want in&amp;#8230;let&amp;#8217;s see.. just over an&amp;nbsp;hour!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really *love* the &amp;#8220;Views&amp;#8221; screen which, even out-of-the-box,
    allows &amp;#8220;Live Exec&amp;#8221; information from cpuinfo, df, ifconfig, netstat,
    top, who, and&amp;nbsp;more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well, it&amp;#8217;s 03:35, and I have work and class tomorrow. I think it&amp;#8217;s
    time to give Part I a rest. But&amp;nbsp;first&amp;#8230;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the &amp;#8220;Platform&amp;#8221; page for my one machine and&amp;#8230; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;YES&lt;/span&gt;! Graphs are
    starting to&amp;nbsp;appear!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Following the suggestion
    &lt;a href="http://support.hyperic.com/confluence/display/DOC/HQ+Quick+Start#HQQuickStart-enableTracking" title="http://support.hyperic.com/confluence/display/DOC/HQ+Quick+Start#HQQuickStart-enableTracking"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;,
    I enable log and config tracking on the platform for &lt;code&gt;/var/log/warn&lt;/code&gt;
    and &lt;code&gt;/etc/hosts&lt;/code&gt;,&amp;nbsp;respecitvely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before I call it a night (now 03:42), I stop back at the &lt;a href="http://www.hyperic.com/downloads/dl-hq-oss.html" title="http://www.hyperic.com/downloads/dl-hq-oss.html"&gt;downloads
    page&lt;/a&gt;
    and grab the Linux x86 Agent for the dom0 machine, hoping to get
    some physical information as well. While I&amp;#8217;m at it, I grab the Linux
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AMD64&lt;/span&gt; Agent to try on my laptop. I create &amp;#8220;hyperic&amp;#8221; users on each
    system. On the base Xen server, I give it a shot and get &amp;#8220;Unable to
    register agent: Error communicating with agent: Unauthorized&amp;#8221;. Same
    thing on the&amp;nbsp;laptop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did a little reading
    &lt;a href="http://support.hyperic.com/confluence/display/DOC/Installation+Non-Windows#InstallationNon-Windows-install" title="http://support.hyperic.com/confluence/display/DOC/Installation+Non-Windows#InstallationNon-Windows-install"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
    As to keeping all of the defaults, it turns out that both clients
    had firewalls blocking &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TCP&lt;/span&gt; port 2144. I opened it up on both, and
    also set the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; address (that the server uses to contact the client)
    to the correct ones. Viola! Now I have 3 clients connected, and
    gatheirng data for the next \~16 hours until I have time to check it
    out&amp;nbsp;agian.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More to come in Part &lt;span class="caps"&gt;II&lt;/span&gt; tomorrow - actually doing something with
Hyperic. For&lt;br /&gt;
now (04:08), time to&amp;nbsp;sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="part-ii-configuration"&gt;Part &lt;span class="caps"&gt;II&lt;/span&gt; -&amp;nbsp;Configuration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I haven&amp;#8217;t had much time to play with Hyperic in the two
days&lt;br /&gt;
since installation. The most I&amp;#8217;ve really done is setup Agents on my
laptop,&lt;br /&gt;
desktop, and the host machine (both dom0 and domU for Hyperic), so that
they&lt;br /&gt;
start to collect&amp;nbsp;data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I found a lot of upsetting stuff in the features list (see below),
I&lt;br /&gt;
decided to go ahead and add some other devices. On the network at the&lt;br /&gt;
apartment, I have two manageable switches (a Linksys and a 3Com) - which
pretty&lt;br /&gt;
much make up the sum of non-host equipment. I also have an IPcop box,
though I&lt;br /&gt;
assume the standard Linux Agent will handle that. The one item missing
that I&lt;br /&gt;
have at home is my set of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;APC&lt;/span&gt; SmartUPS UPSs with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SNMP&lt;/span&gt; cards, but I guess
I&amp;#8217;ll&lt;br /&gt;
just have to skip them for this&amp;nbsp;review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I went in and added a platform (Resources-&gt;Browse, Tools
Menu-&gt;Add&lt;br /&gt;
Platform) for the 3Com switch (a SuperStack &lt;span class="caps"&gt;II&lt;/span&gt; Switch 3300). It showed&lt;br /&gt;
successful creation - but nothing else. I went in and entered the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SNMP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
community string, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt;, and version (1). In about a minute or so, I
started to&lt;br /&gt;
see metrics - Availability, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; Forwards, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; In Receives, an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; In
Received per&lt;br /&gt;
Second. While it&amp;#8217;s quite basic, that&amp;#8217;s good for a starting point. While
the&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;a href="http://support.hyperic.com/confluence/display/DOCSHQ30/Network+Device+platform" title="http://support.hyperic.com/confluence/display/DOCSHQ30/Network+Device+platform"&gt;http://support.hyperic.com/confluence/display/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DOCSHQ30&lt;/span&gt;/Network+Device+platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Network Device Platform] documentation lists lots of metrics that can
be&lt;br /&gt;
enabled, I&amp;#8217;d also like telnet availability and - my big one since I use
a&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8220;cute&amp;#8221; (crappy) IPcop installation for local &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt;, a dig on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; to make
sure&lt;br /&gt;
the entry is there. In the Monitor screen, I was able to enable a bunch
of&lt;br /&gt;
additional metrics (by clicking on the &amp;#8220;Show All Metrics&amp;#8221; link), though&lt;br /&gt;
there&amp;#8217;s also no way (that I can find) to monitor the status of
individual&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;ports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I browsed through the &amp;#8220;Administration&amp;#8221; pages, setup a few users,
and&lt;br /&gt;
started setting *way* more default metrics for various platforms,
services,&lt;br /&gt;
and servers. While I don&amp;#8217;t have mail running yet, that will come this&lt;br /&gt;
weekend. While I added a lot of things as &amp;#8220;Default On&amp;#8221;, I still need to
go&lt;br /&gt;
back and add more things in the templates as&amp;nbsp;Indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also added some escalations, though they&amp;#8217;re quite simple - you can
notify &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HQ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
users or &amp;#8220;other users&amp;#8221; by email or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;, write to SysLog, or suppress
alerts&lt;br /&gt;
for 0 minutes to 24 hours. Hopefully I&amp;#8217;ll also find a plugin for
Asterisk&lt;br /&gt;
integration. One striking omission is user groups. Also, the concept of&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8220;Roles&amp;#8221; (maybe their idea of groups?) is only available in the
Enterprise&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, I also notice one other majoe issue, though perhaps I&amp;#8217;ll
find a&lt;br /&gt;
solution in my experimentation - there doesn&amp;#8217;t be a way to setup
default&lt;br /&gt;
alerts for metrics. If they have all of this platform, server, and
service&lt;br /&gt;
information defined as default templates, why not just have a way to
assign&lt;br /&gt;
default users (and groups) to these objects, and have default alerts&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;generated?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of Apache 2.2 monitoring, out-of-the-box, nothing worked. No
metrics&lt;br /&gt;
at all. Firstly, Hyperic requires the mod_status module. Persoanlly,
I&amp;#8217;d&lt;br /&gt;
rather handle all of that through a backend, like Nagios. Secondly, it
got the&lt;br /&gt;
pidfile and apache2ctl paths wrong. Furthermore, it has no &amp;#8220;smart&amp;#8221;
checking for resources - while my Apache 2.2 resource config was clearly
wrong (wrong &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PID&lt;/span&gt; file path, no mod_status), Hyperic didn&amp;#8217;t detect this
and was showing the resource as&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;Down&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, I setup a bunch of alerts for things that I thought would be
off-kilter a lot (like &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WARN&lt;/span&gt; log entries on my laptop, high memory usage
on some stressed machines, etc.) as well as log and config file
monitoring and alerts for them. While I didn&amp;#8217;t have mail working yet, I
figured I might as well get that stuff&amp;nbsp;running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Xen dom0 host that runs the Hyperic vm (box called xenmaster1), I
wasn&amp;#8217;t able to add config file tracking for any of the /etc/xen/ files.
At this point I notice some serious shortcomings - not only is it not
possible to define a template of alerts for a given
platform/server/service, it&amp;#8217;s also impossible to define a template for
alerts. I also noticed that it&amp;#8217;s not possible to define groups of
contacts. This wasn&amp;#8217;t much of a problem for my test installation - the
alerts are only going to my roommate and I - but it would surely be an
issue in any larger&amp;nbsp;setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point in configuration, I come to a make-or-break point. With
some of these shortcomings, I really need a way to call a script with
alert information when an alert is generated - whether it&amp;#8217;s to dial out
through Asterisk or just automatically create a ticket for the&amp;nbsp;problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding alerts is a cumbersome process. You have to browse to a page for
a specific metric - which means going to the page for a specific
platform, server, or service - and then opening the page for that
metric. The actual alert creation takes up two pages - one for the
metric, threshold, and time-based criteria, and a second for who to
alert. This means that to add alerts for a machine, you need to view the
platform page as well as the services and servers pages, and each metric&amp;nbsp;therein.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll be posting some more in the days to come. From a &lt;a href="http://forums.hyperic.com/jiveforums/thread.jspa?messageID=14561&amp;amp;#14561"&gt;post at the
Hyperic
Forums&lt;/a&gt;,
I was able to find out that a Xen plugin is in the works, but for the
Open Source version, the only way to trigger a script is to send an
email and have it handled by a filter such as&amp;nbsp;Procmail.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="hyperic"></category><category term="monitoring"></category><category term="open source"></category></entry><entry><title>openEPCR</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2007/12/openepcr/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-12-27T01:46:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2007-12-27:2007/12/openepcr/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been toying around for a while with the idea of creating a software
package for handling Electronic Patient Care Reports for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMS&lt;/span&gt; (Emergency
Medical Services) agencies. There are a few popular packages around, but
most of them are web-based. In the event of a disaster - or even bad
storm - when Internet connectivity is minimal to non-existent, frankly,
you&amp;#8217;re up the creek without a paddle. There are also, to my knowledge,
no Free/Open-Source (or free of cost) packages available. This isn&amp;#8217;t
good, especially with many states and regions moving to standardized
PCRs with electronic submission. This is even worse for the thousands
(or more) of purely volunteer &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMS&lt;/span&gt; organizations out there, who have
little to no&amp;nbsp;budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;#8217;ve started a project - &lt;a href="www.openepcr.org"&gt;openEPCR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that, for me, this is a *big* undertaking. I figured that Java
is the best option, since it&amp;#8217;s available on almost all platforms,
robust, and frankly is very well accepted. The idea is that such a
system should be able to cost *nothing* - so the target audience is
people using Linux (or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BSD&lt;/span&gt; or Solaris) or an existing Windows
installation, along with a simple server - MySQL, PostgreSQL, or another
database, along with some web server running &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;. I&amp;#8217;ll admit that my
Java isn&amp;#8217;t what it used to be - but more to the point, frankly, if I&amp;#8217;m
the only person working on this, it&amp;#8217;ll take years to finish. So,
hopefully, when I get a more concrete plan, I&amp;#8217;ll be able to enlist some
other developers - especially someone more knowledgeable than me about
how best to deal with data caching (in the event - or certainty, as in
wireless or vehicular applications - of a loss of connectivity), mobile
devices, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HIPPA&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall idea is to design a platform that is a base for an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EPCR&lt;/span&gt; -
something that can handle data collection, printing a hard copy,
analysis, administration, security, etc. - and all the while be
organization-independent. In essence, a framework. Firstly, after having
this problem with &lt;a href="http://www.php-ems-tools.com"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMS&lt;/span&gt; Tools&lt;/a&gt;, it
should all be designed with i18n/L10n in mind from the beginning,
providing good and easy support for translations. More importantly, all
settings should be configurable. To top off the problem, anything that&amp;#8217;s
obviously organization-specific - like the data set, layout of input
forms on the screen, reports on the data, printed copy (both blank and
filled-in), user access rights/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RBAC&lt;/span&gt;, authentication methods, etc. -
should all be designed as pluggable modules. The end result would be a
system where a single organization or group of organizations can develop
- or pay to have developed - a &amp;#8220;module&amp;#8221; that includes all of this. The
license would have additional terms stating that any changes to the
code, modules, or updates to modules *must* be given back to the
openEPCR community. The general idea is something like this scenario:
the state of New Jersey decides to adopt a standardized &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PCR&lt;/span&gt; and data
set. Many volunteer ambulance squads don&amp;#8217;t have the funds for a
commercial solution. A bunch of them pool their resources or funds and
develop a &amp;#8220;module&amp;#8221; for openEPCR that provides everything required to
implement a printed and electronic version of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NJ&lt;/span&gt; state &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PCR&lt;/span&gt;. If a
single organization wishes to deviate, they can simply &amp;#8220;extend&amp;#8221; that
module as they see fit, building off of the main code. OpenEPCR itself
remains neutral, but provides a repository of modules to use or&amp;nbsp;modify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I see it, there are three main&amp;nbsp;difficulties:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designing something that&amp;#8217;s abstracted to such a great&amp;nbsp;degree.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dealing with data when we don&amp;#8217;t know the environment - we might be
    stand-alone, always connected to a single master database server,
    intermittently connected, or even connecting to a different server
    every&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We want centralized administration - optimally, all custom data,
    settings, and organization-specific information (as well as updates
    to this) will be pushed out from a central server to all clients.
    But we need to assure security in an environment that is untrusted
    and may even be hostile - perhaps even hostile users - and balance
    the fact that some instances of the software may be actively
    collecting and recording data before they have been notified of a
    certain change or&amp;nbsp;update.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you think this sounds interesting, or have any suggestions - from
either the technical or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMS&lt;/span&gt; standpoint - please check out the &lt;a href="http://www.openepcr.org"&gt;project
homepage&lt;/a&gt; or drop me an
&lt;a href="mailto:jason@jasonantman.com"&gt;E-Mail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excerpted from the homepage is a bit of information on my&amp;nbsp;goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Mission:&lt;/strong&gt;
OpenEPCR aims to provide the Emergency Medical Services sector with a
Free (as in Freedom, a.k.a. Open-Source) Electronic Patient Care Report
(&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EPCR&lt;/span&gt;) software solution. Licensed under the &lt;a href="http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html" title="http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GNU&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
it will be easily extendable by users&amp;#8217; organizations. Such a solution
does not currently exist. Furthermore, many states and regions are
moving to electronic data aggregation for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMS&lt;/span&gt;. OpenEPCR aims to provide
an easy way for organizations to adopt a standardized data set and
submit their data - and only the data that they choose - to a trusted
third party. The software will attempt to do all of this while paying
heed to applicable standards on privacy and security, as well as being
fully&amp;nbsp;platform-independent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project&amp;nbsp;Goals:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; code licensed under the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GNU&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;, and make code as
    easy as possible to modify and&amp;nbsp;extend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be fully platform-independent and database-independent, running in a
    platform-independent&amp;nbsp;language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NO&lt;/span&gt; reliance whatsoever on outside services i.e. be able to run
    in a disaster situation with a full communications&amp;nbsp;breakdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be designed with internationalization (i18n) and localization in
    mind, specifically with easy support for&amp;nbsp;translations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have all data set, user information, rights/access management,
    authentication, and authorization abstracted, allowing
    organization-specified rules as well as various authentication means
    (central server, local file, passwords, hardware tokens, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OTP&lt;/span&gt;,&amp;nbsp;etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attempt to conform to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HIPPA&lt;/span&gt; and other applicable standards governing
    security and&amp;nbsp;privacy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow all organizational data such as &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PCR&lt;/span&gt; forms, data sets,
    printable versions, etc. to operate as pluggable modules; changing
    the entire &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PCR&lt;/span&gt; structure should be as easy as adding a few new files
    and running a&amp;nbsp;script.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be designed with both the small, volunteer, virtually budget-less
    squad and the large paid organization in&amp;nbsp;mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run on a variety of devices including desktops, laptops, and mobile
    devices of all&amp;nbsp;flavors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operate in environments including standalone, central server, ad-hoc
    network, and a network of distributed master&amp;nbsp;servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have the utmost regard to integrity of data - data loss or
    corruption is &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NOT&lt;/span&gt; an&amp;nbsp;option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support virtually unlimited customization for an end-user&amp;nbsp;organization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be designed with ease of extension in mind - it should be easy for
    end-user organizations to design custom add-ons that integrate
    fully, while conforming to the Access Control&amp;nbsp;model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eventually, include support for administrative functions such as
    equipment/vehicle checks, scheduling, roster functionality,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eventually, consider creation of an integrated incident management
    system for patient, resource, and personnel&amp;nbsp;tracking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be designed with as much space for custom software hooks as&amp;nbsp;possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attempt to pull together developers from various disciplines and
    gather suggestions from a vast sampling of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><category term="emergency medical"></category><category term="EMS"></category><category term="free"></category><category term="healthcare"></category><category term="medical"></category><category term="open source"></category><category term="openepcr"></category><category term="patient care report"></category><category term="pcr"></category><category term="prehospital"></category></entry><entry><title>Short Commentary</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2007/11/short-commentary/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-11-30T14:09:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2007-11-30:2007/11/short-commentary/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just a short note today - it&amp;#8217;s an insanely busy week. I&amp;#8217;ve been
finishing up the web &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; for my print accounting system (previously
mentioned) and had to dive into &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CUPS&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IPP&lt;/span&gt; to pull out information on
whether or not a print job is printed in duplex. I&amp;#8217;ve also been going
crazy with raw &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PJL&lt;/span&gt; queries to get some information that doesn&amp;#8217;t appear
to be found in &lt;a href="http://www.faqs.org/rfcs/rfc1759.html"&gt;Printer-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MIB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. In
other news, I have an exam Monday moring in a class (Religions of the
Eastern World - my non-western requirement) that I&amp;#8217;m getting a D in.
Then I have an essay for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; History &lt;span class="caps"&gt;II&lt;/span&gt; due Thursday - I haven&amp;#8217;t even
read the books&amp;nbsp;yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Tuesday night, I have my first tech demo as a Sun Campus Ambassador,
a short OpenSolaris overview for &lt;a href="http://ruslug.rutgers.edu/w/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RUSLUG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
that should touch on the coll facets of DTrace, Zones, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ZFS&lt;/span&gt;, etc. as well
as the new installer. So it&amp;#8217;s going to be a pretty busy weekend. And I&amp;#8217;m
hard set on doing a kick-ass demo, despite some of the &lt;a href="http://directorymanager.wordpress.com/2007/11/28/an-open-letter-to-the-opends-community-and-to-sun-microsystems/"&gt;disturbing
things&lt;/a&gt;
I&amp;#8217;ve been hearing about Sun lately. If I can get OpenSolaris to boot on
my laptop by then, I&amp;#8217;ll use that. If not, I guess I&amp;#8217;ll be dragging the
PowerEdge 2550 over&amp;nbsp;there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, I was looking through Google Reader this morining (my
only source for news) and came by a LinuxInsider article on the
&lt;a href="http://www.linuxinsider.com/rsstory/60447.html"&gt;upcoming &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KDE&lt;/span&gt; release&lt;/a&gt;.
Being a user of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KDE&lt;/span&gt; since 2000, this interested me. However, what struck
me was a comment about the new&amp;nbsp;KOffice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was speaking with a supervisor at the Rutgers University student
computer labs the other day, and was pretty astonished to realize that
&lt;a href="http://www.openoffice.org/"&gt;OpenOffice&lt;/a&gt; isn&amp;#8217;t loaded on the lab
computers. Why? Because 99% of their &amp;#8220;patrons&amp;#8221; wouldn&amp;#8217;t know what it is,
and can&amp;#8217;t handle choices. &lt;strong&gt;Can&amp;#8217;t handle choices&lt;/strong&gt;. Or, at least, don&amp;#8217;t want them. It&amp;#8217;s attitudes like this
that lead to a world where you have &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONE&lt;/span&gt; cable company, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONE&lt;/span&gt; phone
company, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONE&lt;/span&gt; high-bandwidth &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;, and can only use &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONE&lt;/span&gt; cellular
provider&amp;#8217;s equipment on a network. I wonder how those same &amp;#8220;patrons&amp;#8221;
would feel if they went to a car dealer and were offered the option to
buy a Honda Accord, a Honda Accord, or maybe a Honda&amp;nbsp;Accord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I&amp;#8217;m concerned, the biggest issue is publicity. The users don&amp;#8217;t
want choices because they don&amp;#8217;t know about them. And I thought that a
University was supposed to educate people? How naive of&amp;nbsp;me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hanging out at the &lt;a href="http://www.midlandparkambulance.com/"&gt;ambulance
corps&lt;/a&gt; that I volunteer with (I
have nothing to do with the front-end web site) the other weekend, and
one of the women asked whether I had Microsoft Office, since she needed
Word for a project. She said she didn&amp;#8217;t want to pay $250. I asked her
why she couldn&amp;#8217;t use OpenOffice. She asked what it was. It&amp;#8217;s absolutely
wonderful to hear the astonishment in someone&amp;#8217;s voice when you tell them
that they can download something at no cost that does everything that
Word&amp;nbsp;does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, my question is how many of these &amp;#8220;patrons&amp;#8221;, mostly students, would
use OpenOffice if they knew about it? More importantly, how many of them
would use it if someone told them they don&amp;#8217;t *have* to pay $150 to put
Word and Excel on their computers? I know the functionality isn&amp;#8217;t
perfect, but I routinely open, edit, and then save back Word and Excel
files in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OO&lt;/span&gt; without a&amp;nbsp;problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, back to the point of this rant. Choices are good. Fragmentation is
not. We have OpenOffice, StarOffice, KOffice, and probably a bunch more.
I understand they&amp;#8217;re all separate projects with separate goals. But,
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IMHO&lt;/span&gt;, one of the biggest problems with open-source (and no-cost)
alternatives to proprietary software is getting the word out there. And
fragmentation makes that so much harder. If you ask a Windows or Mac
user what office package is most prominent, they&amp;#8217;ll probably say &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt;
Office. If you ask three Linux users, you&amp;#8217;ll likely get three different&amp;nbsp;answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;#8217;t about the moral battle of Free/Open Source vs. closed or
proprietary. This is about user experience. If there&amp;#8217;s a no-cost (and
even better, Free) package out there that does almost everything a
$150-300 package does, users should have the right to try it and see if
it works for them. And I can think of few places where that&amp;#8217;s more
important than cash-starved college&amp;nbsp;kids.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="open source"></category><category term="openoffice"></category></entry></feed>