<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/openoffice.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 10:56:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>OpenOffice Calc formula for IP addresses</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/05/openoffice-calc-formula-for-ip-addresses/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been a while since I&amp;#8217;ve posted. Things are quite busy, with work 4
days a week (9-5) and classes 6-9:30 at night 4 days a week (though
classes are Mon-Thurs and work is&amp;nbsp;Tues-Fri).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m plodding along on with &lt;a href="http://www.tuxtruck.org/"&gt;TuxTruc&lt;/a&gt;k - we now
have a domain name
(&lt;a href="http://www.tuxtruck.org/"&gt;http://www.tuxtruck.org/&lt;/a&gt;) and playlist
generation is finished. This weekend should yield playlist parsing. Once
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MP3&lt;/span&gt; playing is working, I&amp;#8217;ll begin the hardcore development - &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OBD&lt;/span&gt;,
and Bluetooth. Also, I&amp;#8217;m working on a hardware budget for the prototype,
but it&amp;#8217;s ending up much higher than originally imagined. If I end up
going with the &lt;a href="http://www.xenarc.com/product/MDT-X7000.html"&gt;Xenarc
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDT&lt;/span&gt;-X7000&lt;/a&gt; display (which
includes a head unit with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt; playing, amplifier, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt; playing, and radio
- though those are features I&amp;#8217;d rather to in software on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt;, and
just use the amplifier) which runs $800 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USD&lt;/span&gt;, the total is looking more
like $2000 than the $1000 I had planned. More to the point, the X7000
currently has poor reviews, and is backordered everywhere pending a
firmware revision. I may end up going the route of a separate head unit,
or a dedicated amplifier (though volume control is still an issue) and
getting a better daylight-readable touchscreen (though I still have a
strong preference for a motorized in-dash type, given the theft rate
around&amp;nbsp;school).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another item of news - my mother is considering moving from Verizon FiOS
to the Cablevision/Optimum Triple Play - iO digital &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;, cable, and
voice. Given that jasonantman.com - and all of my other machines - live
on shelves in her basement, this will have quite an impact on me. And a
good one! Optimum offers Business-grade service at 30 Mbps down/5 Mbps
up &lt;strong&gt;with 5 static IPs&lt;/strong&gt; at a rate
that I can afford. So, there may be an end to DynDNS, and my sites might
finally live on port 80, like they should! On the down side, this would
mean (for digital &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;) a major coax rewiring of mom&amp;#8217;s house - and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RG&lt;/span&gt;-6/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;UQ&lt;/span&gt;
isn&amp;#8217;t&amp;nbsp;cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the tip of the day - OpenOffice Calc formula to increase the
last quad of an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; address by&amp;nbsp;one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;=CONCATENATE(LEFT(A1;SEARCH(".[0-9]+$";A1));VALUE(RIGHT(A1;LEN(A1)-SEARCH(".[0-9]+$";A1)))+1)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was doing up a little spreadsheet of IPs in the office, and like a
good &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SA&lt;/span&gt; (with nothing else to do), came up with a formula to increase
the last octet by one. Just enter a dotted-quad &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; in A1 (or whatever
other cell, correcting the formula), paste this below it, and copy down
the page to your heart&amp;#8217;s content. (Granted, it only changes the last
octet, and expects a properly formatted&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 10:56:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-05-30:2008/05/openoffice-calc-formula-for-ip-addresses/</guid><category>ip address</category><category>openoffice</category><category>spreadsheet</category><category>tuxtruck</category></item><item><title>Short Commentary</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/11/short-commentary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Just a short note today - it&amp;#8217;s an insanely busy week. I&amp;#8217;ve been
finishing up the web &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; for my print accounting system (previously
mentioned) and had to dive into &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CUPS&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IPP&lt;/span&gt; to pull out information on
whether or not a print job is printed in duplex. I&amp;#8217;ve also been going
crazy with raw &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PJL&lt;/span&gt; queries to get some information that doesn&amp;#8217;t appear
to be found in &lt;a href="http://www.faqs.org/rfcs/rfc1759.html"&gt;Printer-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MIB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. In
other news, I have an exam Monday moring in a class (Religions of the
Eastern World - my non-western requirement) that I&amp;#8217;m getting a D in.
Then I have an essay for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; History &lt;span class="caps"&gt;II&lt;/span&gt; due Thursday - I haven&amp;#8217;t even
read the books&amp;nbsp;yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Tuesday night, I have my first tech demo as a Sun Campus Ambassador,
a short OpenSolaris overview for &lt;a href="http://ruslug.rutgers.edu/w/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RUSLUG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
that should touch on the coll facets of DTrace, Zones, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ZFS&lt;/span&gt;, etc. as well
as the new installer. So it&amp;#8217;s going to be a pretty busy weekend. And I&amp;#8217;m
hard set on doing a kick-ass demo, despite some of the &lt;a href="http://directorymanager.wordpress.com/2007/11/28/an-open-letter-to-the-opends-community-and-to-sun-microsystems/"&gt;disturbing
things&lt;/a&gt;
I&amp;#8217;ve been hearing about Sun lately. If I can get OpenSolaris to boot on
my laptop by then, I&amp;#8217;ll use that. If not, I guess I&amp;#8217;ll be dragging the
PowerEdge 2550 over&amp;nbsp;there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, I was looking through Google Reader this morining (my
only source for news) and came by a LinuxInsider article on the
&lt;a href="http://www.linuxinsider.com/rsstory/60447.html"&gt;upcoming &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KDE&lt;/span&gt; release&lt;/a&gt;.
Being a user of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KDE&lt;/span&gt; since 2000, this interested me. However, what struck
me was a comment about the new&amp;nbsp;KOffice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was speaking with a supervisor at the Rutgers University student
computer labs the other day, and was pretty astonished to realize that
&lt;a href="http://www.openoffice.org/"&gt;OpenOffice&lt;/a&gt; isn&amp;#8217;t loaded on the lab
computers. Why? Because 99% of their &amp;#8220;patrons&amp;#8221; wouldn&amp;#8217;t know what it is,
and can&amp;#8217;t handle choices. &lt;strong&gt;Can&amp;#8217;t handle choices&lt;/strong&gt;. Or, at least, don&amp;#8217;t want them. It&amp;#8217;s attitudes like this
that lead to a world where you have &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONE&lt;/span&gt; cable company, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONE&lt;/span&gt; phone
company, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONE&lt;/span&gt; high-bandwidth &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt;, and can only use &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ONE&lt;/span&gt; cellular
provider&amp;#8217;s equipment on a network. I wonder how those same &amp;#8220;patrons&amp;#8221;
would feel if they went to a car dealer and were offered the option to
buy a Honda Accord, a Honda Accord, or maybe a Honda&amp;nbsp;Accord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I&amp;#8217;m concerned, the biggest issue is publicity. The users don&amp;#8217;t
want choices because they don&amp;#8217;t know about them. And I thought that a
University was supposed to educate people? How naive of&amp;nbsp;me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hanging out at the &lt;a href="http://www.midlandparkambulance.com/"&gt;ambulance
corps&lt;/a&gt; that I volunteer with (I
have nothing to do with the front-end web site) the other weekend, and
one of the women asked whether I had Microsoft Office, since she needed
Word for a project. She said she didn&amp;#8217;t want to pay $250. I asked her
why she couldn&amp;#8217;t use OpenOffice. She asked what it was. It&amp;#8217;s absolutely
wonderful to hear the astonishment in someone&amp;#8217;s voice when you tell them
that they can download something at no cost that does everything that
Word&amp;nbsp;does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, my question is how many of these &amp;#8220;patrons&amp;#8221;, mostly students, would
use OpenOffice if they knew about it? More importantly, how many of them
would use it if someone told them they don&amp;#8217;t *have* to pay $150 to put
Word and Excel on their computers? I know the functionality isn&amp;#8217;t
perfect, but I routinely open, edit, and then save back Word and Excel
files in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OO&lt;/span&gt; without a&amp;nbsp;problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, back to the point of this rant. Choices are good. Fragmentation is
not. We have OpenOffice, StarOffice, KOffice, and probably a bunch more.
I understand they&amp;#8217;re all separate projects with separate goals. But,
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IMHO&lt;/span&gt;, one of the biggest problems with open-source (and no-cost)
alternatives to proprietary software is getting the word out there. And
fragmentation makes that so much harder. If you ask a Windows or Mac
user what office package is most prominent, they&amp;#8217;ll probably say &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt;
Office. If you ask three Linux users, you&amp;#8217;ll likely get three different&amp;nbsp;answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;#8217;t about the moral battle of Free/Open Source vs. closed or
proprietary. This is about user experience. If there&amp;#8217;s a no-cost (and
even better, Free) package out there that does almost everything a
$150-300 package does, users should have the right to try it and see if
it works for them. And I can think of few places where that&amp;#8217;s more
important than cash-starved college&amp;nbsp;kids.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2007 14:09:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-11-30:2007/11/short-commentary/</guid><category>open source</category><category>openoffice</category></item></channel></rss>