<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog - partaker</title><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/partaker.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2018-06-14T16:28:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>New Home Router - Partaker I5</title><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/2018/06/new-home-router---partaker-i5/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-14T16:28:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-14T16:28:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Jason Antman</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2018-06-14:/2018/06/new-home-router---partaker-i5/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quick overview of the Partaker I5 network appliance that I bought for my new home&amp;nbsp;router.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The work I&amp;#8217;ve been doing lately with my &lt;a href="/2018/05/linux-surveillance-camera-software-evaluation/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; security cameras&lt;/a&gt; was unexpectedly put on hold this past Monday evening when an extremely close lightning strike fried my router, switch, and the wired (motherboard on-board) Ethernet port in my desktop computer. The best I can tell the surge must have come in over the coax to my cable modem, as the only devices effected were in close physical and Ethernet proximity to it (and the electrical service comes in to the opposite corner of the house from the cable, and everything else was fine). I&amp;#8217;d been thinking of replacing my aged &lt;a href="https://www.pcengines.ch/alix2c1.htm"&gt;PCEngines Alix.2c1&lt;/a&gt; router running &lt;a href="https://vyos.io/"&gt;VyOS&lt;/a&gt; for a while, but it was still working (despite running constantly for eight years) and I wasn&amp;#8217;t quite sure what Linux router hardware exists these&amp;nbsp;days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily (and somewhat amazingly) both the cable modem and all of my desktop except for the onboard ethernet were fine. But that left me in need of a new system for my router &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ASAP&lt;/span&gt;. After about an hour of looking around on Amazon, I settled on &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B073F9GHKL/"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.inctel.com.cn/product/detail/338.html"&gt;Partaker I5&lt;/a&gt; system. For &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USD&lt;/span&gt; $230 I got a small (approximately 5x5x1.5 inches) box with a 2.42GHz Celeron J1900 processor, four Intel gigabit NICs, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VGA&lt;/span&gt;, serial, dual &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; 2.0, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;4GB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt; and a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;32GB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSD&lt;/span&gt; - about four times my old router in every measure. Despite having no reviews on Amazon, I decided to give it a try half because I could get it next day (which wasn&amp;#8217;t possible with the newer PCEngines &lt;span class="caps"&gt;APU&lt;/span&gt; boards, though they&amp;#8217;re half the cost) and half because the description listed it as compatible with RouterOS, Mikrotik, m0n0wall, IPCop, etc. It also appears visually to be very similar to the &lt;a href="https://protectli.com/product/fw1/"&gt;Protectli &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FW1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which is both listed in the &lt;a href="https://wiki.vyos.net/wiki/Network_appliances"&gt;VyOS wiki&lt;/a&gt; and has &lt;a href="https://protectli.com/kb/how-to-install-vyos-on-the-vault/"&gt;their own page on installing VyOS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="stock photo of Partaker I5 appliance" src="/GFX/partaker_i5.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few minor hiccups in the installation process, I&amp;#8217;m happy to say that this little network device is working amazingly well. I&amp;#8217;ve only had it running for about 24 hours so I can&amp;#8217;t speak to longevity, but it worked fine out-of-the-box (it shipped with pfSense installed) and seems to be doing the job exceedingly&amp;nbsp;well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The installation was straightforward using VyOS x86_64 on a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; flash drive, though I did find out some interesting bits of information about this device - which shipped with zero documentation whatsoever - that may be of use to&amp;nbsp;others:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are two small tactile buttons on the front labeled &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SW&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RST&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221;. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RST&lt;/span&gt; is, as I figured, a reset button. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SW&lt;/span&gt; is actually the power button. Press it once and the system turns on. Press this scarily easy-to-hit button again, and it sends a shutdown signal to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The board runs &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AMI&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BIOS&lt;/span&gt;, and the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BIOS&lt;/span&gt; prompt is very short. It took me a few cycles of resetting the machine and pressing Delete on my keyboard, as fast as I could over and over, to get into the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;BIOS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I first booted the VyOS install flash drive, it failed to load with a slew of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; errors. I was able to fix this in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BIOS&lt;/span&gt; by navigating to Chipset -&amp;gt; South Bridge -&amp;gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; Configuration, disabling &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XHCI&lt;/span&gt; and enabling &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; 2&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EHCI&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By default, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BIOS&lt;/span&gt; is set to stay powered down when power is restored, which is definitely not what I want in a network device. Chipset -&amp;gt; South Bridge -&amp;gt; Restore &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AC&lt;/span&gt; Power Loss is the setting to fix&amp;nbsp;this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After some intense worry that my brand-new router was defective, I found that the Ethernet port labeling on the device is the opposite of how Linux sees the interfaces; the leftmost interface labeled &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN4&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221; is actually eth0, and the rightmost interface labeled &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN1&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221; is&amp;nbsp;eth3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll update this post if I have any issues with it, but as far as I can tell this is a very nice, if not terribly cheap, device to use as a network&amp;nbsp;appliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that my move is done and my network is mostly back in operation, I plan on writing another post sometime soon on the progress I&amp;#8217;ve made with my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; camera&amp;nbsp;system.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="router"></category><category term="firewall"></category><category term="vyos"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="partaker"></category><category term="embedded"></category><category term="appliance"></category></entry></feed>