<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://newblog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/passwords.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2007 15:54:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tech - Updates</title><link>http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2007/12/tech-updates/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;First of all, until I decide on either splitting my blog, or setting up
separate &amp;#8216;channels&amp;#8217; for personal and technical stuff, I&amp;#8217;ll annotate the
difference in post&amp;nbsp;titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I have a few days of sanity - the last week of classes - before exam
time. Hopefully I&amp;#8217;ll wrap some things up, and even finish my Christmas
shopping (&lt;a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com"&gt;ThinkGeek&lt;/a&gt; will be happy&amp;#8230;). I
don&amp;#8217;t have a whole lot of real value to say, but a few notes on upcoming&amp;nbsp;projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#8217;m going to be buying a few SunBlade 100s and 150s as surplus from
    Rutgers. I&amp;#8217;m probably going to have one or two running at home
    replacing my ancient mail server. I might also bring my PowerEdge
    2550 home to virtualize a few of my machines - though, arguably, my
    two backup machines are the best candidates, though I don&amp;#8217;t like the
    idea of virtualizing&amp;nbsp;backups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think the new mail server will run Solaris, though I haven&amp;#8217;t
    looked into the technicalities of
    Procmail/Postfix/SpamAssassin/some-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IMAP&lt;/span&gt;-server on&amp;nbsp;Solaris.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/2007/11/print-accounting.html"&gt;Print
    Accounting&lt;/a&gt;
    is finished, though the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; isn&amp;#8217;t completely done. I&amp;#8217;ll have it in
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt; sometime this&amp;nbsp;week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m thinking about password managers. I posted a comment to the
&lt;a href="http://www.sage.org/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SAGE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; mailing list, but didn&amp;#8217;t get many helpful
replies. I&amp;#8217;m looking for a solution that can keep track of all of my
usernames and passwords. It needs to be secure. Very secure. I&amp;#8217;d like to
set separate passwords for almost every machine/account that I have.
More importantly, I want something easily portable. Unfortunately, I
find things like the
&lt;a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com/gadgets/security/91a2/"&gt;Mandylion&lt;/a&gt; a bit
limiting - not only does the device generate passwords for you, so you
can&amp;#8217;t really store many notes (I might want to keep track of a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;, name
for the entry, username, member number, etc.) but it&amp;#8217;s also a single
hardware device - no way to back it up, and easy to lose. I also saw the
&lt;a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com/gadgets/security/99f1/"&gt;IronKey&lt;/a&gt; which sounds
damn good - especially the Mission Impossible-esque self-destructing
encryption chip. But that means that some @$$ just has to type in 10
incorrect passwords and it&amp;#8217;s useless. Moreover, it needs to be plugged
into a system, so if I don&amp;#8217;t have a laptop and I&amp;#8217;m not at a trusted
terminal, there&amp;#8217;s ample security&amp;nbsp;risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I talked to my roommate (an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EE&lt;/span&gt; major) about hardware solutions, but they
seem to be a bit expensive and way too much R&amp;amp;D time. So, it seems like
the only real solution is software. At the moment, what I have to work
with includes a &lt;a href="http://maemo.org/community/wiki/nokia_770_hardware_specification/"&gt;Nokia 770 Internet
Tablet&lt;/a&gt;,
a Blackberry 7250 (hopefully being replaced by a Treo 650p or 700p
soon), an array of Linux desktops, and my laptop (right now a Linux box
that stays on my desk, but maybe a MacBook, iBook, or &lt;a href="http://eeepc.asus.com/"&gt;Asus
eeePC&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;soon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall idea is to create a set (or trio, or quartet) of
applications to act as a password manager. They would store passwords
and related information (initial acitvation date, reset date, scheduled
reset date, username, system/site name, notes) in a flat file or a
simple database like
&lt;a href="http://www.oracle.com/technology/products/berkeley-db/index.html"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;BDB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
That file would then be encrypted using GNUpg and strong encryption.
Another possibility is separate files per &amp;#8220;class&amp;#8221; of password, such as
one for root accounts, one for user accounts, one for web sites, etc.
with different encryption strength for each class (speed may be an issue
for en/decrypting large files on small devices like&amp;nbsp;phones).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of the program, ideally I&amp;#8217;d have a graphical client for my
phone (Treo or Blackberry) probably written in Java, a graphical client
for the Nokia 770 (maybe Java, maybe something using Python and native
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GTK&lt;/span&gt;), a graphical client for my laptop, and a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; client for the 770 and
laptop. Databases would have to be sync&amp;#8217;ed across machines - the 770 is
easy enough to just find the newest file and copy it, or manually
decrypt, diff, and then encrypt. I don&amp;#8217;t know how I&amp;#8217;d do it on the
phones, the only thing I can think of right now is to pay for data
usage, and then manually copy over to the phone (either via &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SFTP&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCP&lt;/span&gt;,
or a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTPS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;connection).&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2007 15:54:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2007-12-11:2007/12/tech-updates/</guid><category>passwords</category></item></channel></rss>