<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/preparedness.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://newblog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2010-01-20T21:25:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Federal Government: Ignoring what we learned 5,000 years ago</title><link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2010/01/federal-government-ignoring-what-we-learned-5000-years-ago/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-20T21:25:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2010-01-20:2010/01/federal-government-ignoring-what-we-learned-5000-years-ago/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Being a volunteer
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emergency_medical_technician"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and at
times an outdoorsy-type person, I occasionally get emails from friends
about disaster-related topics. Especially in the post-9/11 days.
Recently, I got an email asking me if I&amp;#8217;d seen the Department of
Homeland Security&amp;#8217;s disaster preparedness site,
&lt;a href="http://www.ready.gov"&gt;ready.gov&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;d heard a bit about it, but hadn&amp;#8217;t
really looked around. The site&amp;#8217;s main premise is to educate people about
how to prepare for a disaster - &amp;#8220;get a kit&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;make a plan&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;be&amp;nbsp;informed&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site&amp;#8217;s own &lt;a href="http://www.ready.gov/america/about/index.html"&gt;About
page&lt;/a&gt; states that it is
&amp;#8220;designed to educate and empower Americans to prepare for and respond to
emergencies including natural and man-made disasters. The goal of the
campaign is to get the public involved and ultimately to increase the
level of basic preparedness across the&amp;nbsp;nation.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step on the site, &lt;a href="http://www.ready.gov/america/getakit/index.html"&gt;&amp;#8220;Get a
Kit&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;, includes a list
of supplies to have on hand as a basic disaster kit. The introduction to
the page&amp;nbsp;reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may need to survive on your own after an emergency. This means
having your own food, water, and other supplies in sufficient quantity
to last for at least three days. Local officials and relief workers
will be on the scene after a disaster, but they cannot reach everyone
immediately. You could get help in hours, or it might take days. In
addition, basic services such as electricity, gas, water, sewage
treatment, and telephones may be cut off for days, or even a week or&amp;nbsp;longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will admit, I assumed this would be geared more towards urbanites, not
those of us in the suburbs or rural America (the latter generally being
more accustomed to self-sufficiency), so I adjusted my expectations
accordingly. At first glance, it seems to include most of the things
that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMT&lt;/span&gt; in me would want it&amp;nbsp;to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food and&amp;nbsp;water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First aid&amp;nbsp;kit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrench or pliers to turn off gas&amp;nbsp;line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prescription&amp;nbsp;medications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bleach (as a disinfectant and for water&amp;nbsp;purification)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fire&amp;nbsp;extinguisher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I found a number of things obviously missing. Sure, some are
minor - matches but no mention of fuel, bleach but not even coffee
filters to remove particulate matter from water. I also find it comical
that so many years after the Cold War &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Duck_and_cover"&gt;&amp;#8220;Duck and
Cover&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; approach to nuclear
safety, the government is now telling people to
&lt;a href="http://www.ready.gov/america/makeaplan/shelter_in_place.html"&gt;Shelter-In-Place&lt;/a&gt;
in the event of a biological attack - by covering their doors and
windows with plastic&amp;nbsp;sheeting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But by far the most egregious omission from the list - something learned
by man at least 5,000 years ago, and taught to every Boy Scout - is the
simplest tool: a knife. Yup, that&amp;#8217;s right, the Disaster Kit list doesn&amp;#8217;t
include &lt;strong&gt;any variety of cutting implement&lt;/strong&gt;. I don&amp;#8217;t know if whoever
wrote up the list is just scared of getting sued when little Bobby finds
the knife and kills himself, or whether they&amp;#8217;re really that stupid. But
I, for one, never leave my house without some variety of the oldest real
tool devised by man, and can&amp;#8217;t imagine anyone thrown into any sort of
&amp;#8220;survival&amp;#8221; situation without at least a rudimentary way to cut, scrape,
pry, etc. I&amp;#8217;d say that if I were without utilities or organized public
safety for &amp;#8220;at least three days&amp;#8221;, I&amp;#8217;d sure want to be able to make
simple repairs, fashion simple tools, or perhaps cut&amp;nbsp;something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On another (albeit less important) note, there are still &lt;em&gt;many, many&lt;/em&gt;
Americans, not just in rural areas, who have a fireplace or wood stove.
What about a few days&amp;#8217; worth of&amp;nbsp;wood?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="disaster"></category><category term="EMS"></category><category term="government"></category><category term="preparedness"></category></entry></feed>