<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog - review</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/review.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2011-07-03T22:03:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>A Quick Review of Mint.com - from both a user and programmer perspective</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2011/07/a-quick-review-of-mint-com-from-both-a-user-and-programmer-perspective/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-03T22:03:00-04:00</published><updated>2011-07-03T22:03:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2011-07-03:/2011/07/a-quick-review-of-mint-com-from-both-a-user-and-programmer-perspective/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those of you who are unfamiliar with
&lt;a href="http://www.mint.com"&gt;Mint.com&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;#8217;s a free online personal finance
site that allows you to track spending across all of your bank accounts
and manage budgets and financial goals. Once upon a time it was a nice
little Web 2.0 startup, now …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those of you who are unfamiliar with
&lt;a href="http://www.mint.com"&gt;Mint.com&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;#8217;s a free online personal finance
site that allows you to track spending across all of your bank accounts
and manage budgets and financial goals. Once upon a time it was a nice
little Web 2.0 startup, now it&amp;#8217;s owned by Intuit. The service is free,
but it&amp;#8217;s ad supported, albeit in an unintrusive way - &amp;#8220;partner&amp;#8221; services
(credit cards, savings accounts, etc.) are recommended. I&amp;#8217;ve been using
it for about two weeks now, with a goal of tracking my spending,
developing a budget and getting a better handle on my present and future
finances. So here are some of my impressions, considering that the
service is still growing but has been around for a&amp;nbsp;while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&amp;nbsp;Good:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Account Sync&lt;/strong&gt; - Some things I&amp;#8217;ve read online suggest that Mint
    now uses the &lt;a href="http://yodlee.com"&gt;Yodlee&lt;/a&gt; service to sync
    transactions from your financial institutions. Whatever they use,
    they seem to be able to sync transactions and account balances from
    all of my accounts, even ones at a few small investment companies.
    The sync is fast, and they do push notifications (low balance, large
    deposits, etc.) very well. They even seem to support many more
    institutions than Quicken last time I used it (2010 I&amp;nbsp;think).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Budgets&lt;/strong&gt; - Mint has a very nice, clean, simple monthly budget
    implementation. You tell it how much you want to spend in a given
    category in a month, and it shows a nice horizontal bar graph of how
    far through your allotment you are. It even makes some suggestions,
    and sets baseline budgets by category based on previous spending.
    About the only problem is when my bi-weely pay checks fall on odd
    weeks in the month. Most of my bills are due near the end of the
    month, and if my pay check happens to be around the same time my
    bills are due, I&amp;#8217;ll have quite a bit less cash on hand at the
    beginning of the next month than the budgets&amp;nbsp;reflect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Categorization&lt;/strong&gt; - they do it very well. One of their big selling
    points is their categorization engine, and it seemed to get about
    80% of my purchases right, from day one. That&amp;#8217;s much better than
    anything else I&amp;#8217;ve seen. The only down side is that they only look
    at the Vendor name, not the description - so when I use my debit
    card and the vendor name is &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NYCE&lt;/span&gt; Transaction&amp;#8221; but the store
    name/address is in the description, Mint is hopelessly lost. They
    offer rules to put transactions in category, but only exact matching
    on the vendor name, so there&amp;#8217;s no way to tell it to look at a
    description that includes &amp;#8220;123 Main St&amp;#8221;. From a programmer&amp;#8217;s
    perspective, they should allow rules based on either vendor name
    &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; description, and maybe they should let the user highlight or
    specify the part that matches (or a&amp;nbsp;RegEx?).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apps&lt;/strong&gt; - I haven&amp;#8217;t tried the iOS ones, but the Android app is
    pretty nice. It gives a nice quick picture of your spending and
    account balances, how you&amp;#8217;re doing with your monthly budget, and any
    alerts/messages. Transaction history isn&amp;#8217;t easily accessible and is
    per-account only, so it&amp;#8217;s hard to answer &amp;#8220;hmmm, how much did it cost
    last time I was here?&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;where did I get lunch last Tuesday?&amp;#8221;, but
    it&amp;#8217;s still handy enough to tell me how much I have left in my
    Entertainment budget, or whether I should put this big purchase on
    my credit or debit&amp;nbsp;card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals&lt;/strong&gt; - Mint has a good idea with goals - it includes a number
    of pre-configured financial goals like paying off credit card debt,
    saving for retirement, or stashing away some emergency cash. But in
    order to function correctly, you must have a specific, dedicated
    account for each goal. I guess this is where Mint makes money - they
    suggest accounts with specific attributes (high interest, high
    liquidity, whatever) from their partners. But there doesn&amp;#8217;t appear
    to be a way to set up a Goal without associating it with a dedicated
    account, and (as per some forum posts I read, I haven&amp;#8217;t tried this)
    you can&amp;#8217;t associate a cash asset account with a goal, so there&amp;#8217;s no
    way to track my progress on building the Depression fund I keep
    under my&amp;nbsp;mattress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Bad/Room for&amp;nbsp;Improvement:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer Service&lt;/strong&gt; - I don&amp;#8217;t know when Mint was bought up by
    Intuit, but to me, they have the feel of an agile Web 2.0 property
    that was bought up by a slow-moving bureaucratic company unable to
    keep up with customer demands or the amount of support requests.
    They use &lt;a href="http://getsatisfaction.com/"&gt;GetSatisfaction&lt;/a&gt;, a new-age
    forum-based customer &amp;#8220;community&amp;#8221; provider, for customer service. But
    their forums are filled with feature request threads that have
    &amp;#8220;we&amp;#8217;ll bring it up to Product Development and get back to you&amp;#8221;
    responses over half a year old. There appears to be very little
    follow-through or feedback on feature requests, and poor
    announcement/communication surrounding the one feature that was
    recently brought in to an invitation-only beta. Unfortunately, I get
    the general feeling (and I&amp;#8217;ve found this far too many times lately)
    that they were originally a cutting-edge, agile, fast-paced, &amp;#8220;cool&amp;#8221;
    service, developed by a team that probably stayed up all night
    coding a cool feature their users were asking for, that&amp;#8217;s now been
    swallowed up by a behemoth that wants a 6-month-long risk assessment
    before writing a line of&amp;nbsp;code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cash Tracking&lt;/strong&gt; - I understand that Mint makes money from
    recommending the services of lenders, banks, etc. But if you want to
    monetize every single feature, you&amp;#8217;re bound to fail. In this
    respect, Mint&amp;#8217;s total lack of cash accounting is a serious failure
    for many of their users (and the forums are filled with threads to
    this effect). The site allows users to manually input cash
    transactions, but that&amp;#8217;s about it. You can deduct the amount from an
    automatically-synced &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ATM&lt;/span&gt; withdrawal (just your last &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ATM&lt;/span&gt; withdrawal,
    no choice if you have multiple &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ATM&lt;/span&gt; accounts, or you and your
    partner/spouse both use the same Mint account), but that just
    complicates things further. There&amp;#8217;s also no logic of tracking cash
    on hand - you can create a &amp;#8220;Asset&amp;#8221; (cash) account, but you have to
    manually update the balance. If you&amp;#8217;re like me and use cash for
    small purchases, or often get meals at local places that only accept
    cash, this becomes quite a bit of a hassle. Even more so if, like
    me, you&amp;#8217;ve ever lost an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ATM&lt;/span&gt; card on a holiday weekend, and now keep
    some actual cash in the house. Honestly, I think this is my biggest
    complaint about Mint, and the one that&amp;#8217;s most likely to keep me
    looking for alternatives. More importantly, this has been requested
    and voted for over and over on their support forums for over a year,
    with no informational response. For a company whose developers
    aggregate and analyze data from thousands of banks, I&amp;#8217;d think that
    letting users type in a series of dollar amounts and then totaling
    it up would be pretty&amp;nbsp;easy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheduled Transactions&lt;/strong&gt; - On the plus side, Mint parses the &amp;#8220;next
    payment due&amp;#8221; date out of credit card and loan account information,
    so it gives you nice (email, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;, and web) alerts a configurable
    number of days before. However, it doesn&amp;#8217;t even have a feature to
    set calendar reminders for when bills are due, so I&amp;#8217;m still stuck
    opening Mint and Google Calendar if I need to figure out whether I
    can make that big purchase today or if I should wait until my next
    pay check. This was also a very commonly requested feature on their
    forums, and apparently they have an invitation-only beta running.
    But I responded to the thread a few days late, so I wasn&amp;#8217;t given an
    invitation. As far as I can tell, there was never an announcement of
    the beta, and I never got a chance to check a &amp;#8220;please let me beta
    test&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forecasting&lt;/strong&gt; - This is my #2 biggest issue with Mint, after the
    lack of cash tracking. And the other one most likely to drive me
    either to another service, to write my own software (again), or to
    go back to a spreadsheet. Mint is great at tracking your transaction
    history, your account balances and net worth, and your current
    monthly budget. But it has absolutely no concept of financial
    forecasting or balance predictions. If you&amp;#8217;re on a tight budget,
    this can be a problem. At the moment, I have a spreadsheet were I
    keep a list of all of my regularly recurring expenses (in date order
    over the month), my pay dates, and the combined balance of my
    checking/savings accounts. I can easily see what (within reason, not
    counting discretionary expenses) my cash on hand will be at any time
    in the month. This seems like a no-brainer necessary feature for a
    site like Mint, and combined with its great budgeting features,
    could provide a wonderful picture of what to expect in the next
    month or two, and when I should plan on making that unusually large&amp;nbsp;purchase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Couples/Families&lt;/strong&gt; - My girlfriend and I both use Mint, and have
    somewhat combined finances (but not accounts). It doesn&amp;#8217;t make sense
    for us to have two Mint accounts, since it would be a real pain to
    keep track of. But, on the other hand, having all of our accounts in
    one Mint isn&amp;#8217;t an ideal solution either. I can categorize
    transactions, but there&amp;#8217;s no easy way to track &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; the purchase
    was for, short of duplicating (or triplicating - Me, Her, Both) all
    of the categories. I&amp;#8217;m trying something with tags, but it&amp;#8217;s a real
    kludge in Mint&amp;#8217;s search interface to get a list of transactions
    filtered by category &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; tag. Also, the account name doesn&amp;#8217;t show
    up in the transactions list unless you pull down the Detail box for
    a transaction, so it&amp;#8217;s troublesome to look through a list and sort
    out whose cards everything was&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miscellaneous:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passwords.&lt;/strong&gt; In order to sync data from my banks, I have to supply
    mint.com with all of my login credentials. I understand that, until
    banks enter the 21st century (and be smart about it - even a less
    likely possibility) this is just the way it is, and I can&amp;#8217;t blame
    Mint for a system imposed by the banks. But still, I&amp;#8217;m not too happy
    about the idea of Mint storing in plain text (I assume, since they
    need to pass them on to the bank) my username and password for all
    of my banking sites. I got some comfort knowing that the site is
    owned by Intuit - a company that, if not totally security-minded, is
    at least big enough not to fold overnight after a breach. Maybe one
    day, banks and credit card companies will let me specify separate
    credentials specific to third-party software and websites, which I
    could then revoke with my &amp;#8220;master&amp;#8221; password. Until then, I guess
    this is just a risk I have to live&amp;nbsp;with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importing Transactions&lt;/strong&gt; - Mint only supports importing up to 3
    months of transaction data per account. Some institutions provide
    less than that. Obviously Intuit doesn&amp;#8217;t want people switching from
    their paid software, so the two &lt;span class="caps"&gt;YEARS&lt;/span&gt; of transactions I meticulously
    categorized in Quicken are now useless to me in Mint. However, I
    guess I can&amp;#8217;t really fault them too much on this one. Firstly, that
    would be a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LOT&lt;/span&gt; of data for them to store. It would also be much more
    of a headache to try and ensure that the export formats of whatever
    software packages they support are properly&amp;nbsp;parsed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mint does a lot of things well. And it&amp;#8217;s a nice clean interface. But
there are also some key features missing, which I feel like I really
need. So, for the time being, I&amp;#8217;m going to keep using mint, but also
explore what other options are available, and look into anyone who
offers an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; for pulling transaction data that might actually be
powerful enough for me to use to write my own web-based app (since my
attempts at pulling &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OFX"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OFX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feeds only
worked for about half my accounts). If you don&amp;#8217;t care as much about
tracking cash spending/cash on hand, and are financially stable enough
that you don&amp;#8217;t need to forecast the next month or two, Mint is&amp;nbsp;wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="finance"></category><category term="mint"></category><category term="review"></category></entry><entry><title>Acer X233Hbid Review</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/05/acer-x233hbid-review/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-05-18T17:27:00-04:00</published><updated>2009-05-18T17:27:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-05-18:/2009/05/acer-x233hbid-review/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just bought myself a new monitor for my
&lt;a href="http://www.mythtv.org"&gt;MythTV&lt;/a&gt; box, as I&amp;#8217;ve moved my beautiful Acer
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AL2416W&lt;/span&gt; 24&amp;#8221;er to my new desktop. The chosen monitor, based on price,
reviews and features, is the Acer X233Hbid. It&amp;#8217;s a 23&amp;#8221; 16:9 (not 16:10)
monitor that runs …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just bought myself a new monitor for my
&lt;a href="http://www.mythtv.org"&gt;MythTV&lt;/a&gt; box, as I&amp;#8217;ve moved my beautiful Acer
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AL2416W&lt;/span&gt; 24&amp;#8221;er to my new desktop. The chosen monitor, based on price,
reviews and features, is the Acer X233Hbid. It&amp;#8217;s a 23&amp;#8221; 16:9 (not 16:10)
monitor that runs at 1920x1080, provides true 1080p, and has an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDMI&lt;/span&gt;
input (not that I&amp;#8217;d ever use a
&lt;a href="http://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2007/01/hdcp-screwing-fans-more-ways-ever"&gt;restricted&lt;/a&gt;
connection). After a few minutes of having it turned on and running, the
picture quality is quite nice, even with quite a bit of&amp;nbsp;glare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I have two major complaints within the first ten minutes of
unboxing&amp;nbsp;it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No real manual, nor an online copy&lt;/strong&gt;. The monitor comes only with
    a Quick Start Guide. There&amp;#8217;s no printed full manual. More
    distressingly, it isn&amp;#8217;t even listed in their list of monitor models
    on their Support site. There&amp;#8217;s no manual copy online either. There
    was a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt; provided with the user&amp;#8217;s manual on it. However, for a
    company that sells netbooks with no &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt; drive, this seems like quite
    a bad decision. But why, you ask, would I need a manual for my&amp;nbsp;monitor?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VESA&lt;/span&gt; mounting instructions&lt;/strong&gt; One of my main criteria in
    choosing a monitor was that it allow
    &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/VESA_mount"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;VESA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; mounting, as I have
    my MythTV monitor on a monitor arm (easily adjustable angle so
    others in the room can see). The Acer X233Hbid has a 100x100mm &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VESA&lt;/span&gt;
    mounting space on the back. However, in a rare design mistake
    (unlike my 24&amp;#8221; Acer &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AL2416W&lt;/span&gt;), the monitor stand is two parts - one
    rectangular column about 4&amp;#8221; long attached to the back of the
    monitor, and a base with a column which mates with the one on the
    back of the monitor. Unfortunately, the column part on the back of
    the monitor came pre-attached, and there was no mention in the
    manual of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VESA&lt;/span&gt; mounting or how to remove the&amp;nbsp;column.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Column removal:&lt;/strong&gt; The part of the monitor base which ships attached to
the monitor is a fairly easy removal. Though I was originally worried
about breaking something on my beautiful new screen, I found two plastic
pieces on either side of the pre-attached part of the base which
appeared to be snap-in trim pieces. Prying them off with a screwdriver
revealed four screws which hold this piece to the monitor. Not only was
removal easy, but the trim pieces snapped back into place for a nice
clean&amp;nbsp;look.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="acer"></category><category term="cant fix stupid"></category><category term="monitor"></category><category term="review"></category></entry><entry><title>Brother HL-2170W - great features from a personal laser printer</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/03/brother-hl-2170w-great-features-from-a-personal-laser-printer/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-03-18T21:29:00-04:00</published><updated>2009-03-18T21:29:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-03-18:/2009/03/brother-hl-2170w-great-features-from-a-personal-laser-printer/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve posted an &lt;a href="/2009/04/brother-hl2170w-dhcp-problems/"&gt;update about serious &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt; problems with this
unit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week my mother&amp;#8217;s printer died, and she asked me to find a new one
for her. After a quick look on &lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com"&gt;NewEgg&lt;/a&gt; (sort by
ratings is a wonderful thing) I found the &lt;a href="http://www.brother-usa.com/Printer/ModelDetail.aspx?ProductID=hl2170W"&gt;Brother
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HL&lt;/span&gt;-2170W&lt;/a&gt;.
Aside …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve posted an &lt;a href="/2009/04/brother-hl2170w-dhcp-problems/"&gt;update about serious &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt; problems with this
unit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week my mother&amp;#8217;s printer died, and she asked me to find a new one
for her. After a quick look on &lt;a href="http://www.newegg.com"&gt;NewEgg&lt;/a&gt; (sort by
ratings is a wonderful thing) I found the &lt;a href="http://www.brother-usa.com/Printer/ModelDetail.aspx?ProductID=hl2170W"&gt;Brother
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HL&lt;/span&gt;-2170W&lt;/a&gt;.
Aside from having a wireless interface (only a security hole, as far as
I&amp;#8217;m concerned) it seemed pretty cool - tiny B&amp;amp;W laser, Ethernet, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PCL6&lt;/span&gt;,
23ppm, 32 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt;, 250 sheet capacity and 2400x600 dpi. So, for a mere
$99 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USD&lt;/span&gt;, I bought it for&amp;nbsp;her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the printer showed up, I was a bit let down to find no sticker
bearing the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MAC&lt;/span&gt; address on either the box or the printer itself - and
given the one-button hard control, there wasn&amp;#8217;t a way to manually print
a config sheet. So, after plugging it into the network and using the
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt; logs to give it a static assignment, a quick reboot of the printer
had everything working. As usual, I skipped to the last few pages in the
installation manual, and found the ½ page section on the web interface.
Configuration was pretty simple - change the admin password, disable a
bunch of unneeded services, etc. And then, when playing around with the
admin interface, I found a bit of a holy grail - there in the
enable/disable services screen were two options that I found unusual for
a &amp;#8220;personal&amp;#8221; printer; &lt;strong&gt;Telnet&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SNMP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. I immediately tried both.
An snmpwalk revealed the usual (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RFC1213&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HOST&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RESOURCES&lt;/span&gt;, and
Printer-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MIB&lt;/span&gt;) including information on status and consumables. Though the
Telnet login process wasn&amp;#8217;t terribly intuitive, &amp;#8220;help&amp;#8221; revealed familiar
set/show/clear functionality as well as an option to zero out counters.
While I was a bit let down to see that there wasn&amp;#8217;t a way to view
consumable status or printer status, it did allow access to every
conceivable configuration parameter, including a few that weren&amp;#8217;t
mentioned on the web&amp;nbsp;interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, while I can&amp;#8217;t comment about reliability or quality yet, this
cute little printer seems to have quite a feature set, especially when
it comes to manageability and remote troubleshooting (a good thing for
any printer that&amp;#8217;s used by a family member who you support). And best of
all, it supports &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IPP&lt;/span&gt; and&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LPR&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="printer"></category><category term="review"></category></entry><entry><title>Bug/Issue Tracking - Update / Review of Eventum</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/09/bugissue-tracking-update-review-of-eventum/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-09-17T14:47:00-04:00</published><updated>2007-09-17T14:47:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-09-17:/2007/09/bugissue-tracking-update-review-of-eventum/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, after many hours of investigating potential bug/issue tracking
packages, I have chosen one. And gone live with it, all in one weekend.
After much evaluation, my final choice was
&lt;a href="http://eventum.mysql.com/"&gt;Eventum&lt;/a&gt; from MySQL (I&amp;#8217;m using the current
version, 2.0.1). I will admit that it is not …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, after many hours of investigating potential bug/issue tracking
packages, I have chosen one. And gone live with it, all in one weekend.
After much evaluation, my final choice was
&lt;a href="http://eventum.mysql.com/"&gt;Eventum&lt;/a&gt; from MySQL (I&amp;#8217;m using the current
version, 2.0.1). I will admit that it is not perfect. There are some
features I wanted that weren&amp;#8217;t there, and the documentation is awful.
But it&amp;#8217;s written in&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, it is very much a community-driven project. The support
on the mailing list, both from other community members and from Bryan
Alsdorf, has been wonderful. I had some issues viewing the help
documents, specifically those in pop-ups, but I&amp;#8217;ve been told that most
new documentation has been moved to the wiki at the link&amp;nbsp;above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project provides for advanced bug- and issue-tracking including time
tracking, file attachments, and customizable statuses, priorities, and
categories. It also provides email integration, both in terms of sending
email alerts and opening issues (as well as updating and tracking) by
parsing incoming emails. The email alerts worked out-of-the-box, but I
did not configure parsing of&amp;nbsp;emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my main requirements which was met perfectly by Eventum is its&amp;#8217;
ability to easily handle multiple projects. It also has a built-in
capability to allow anonymous issue submission (enabled on a
project-by-project basis). You can define custom fields for issues on a
project-by-project basis, and set them as required fields for either
registered users, anonymous users, or&amp;nbsp;both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One feature that I found lacking was the possibility for a user to view
all of the open issues assigned to them. Currently, all user interface
is on a project-by-project basis. Therefore, listing of open issues is
only available for the currently selected project. To cope with this, I
hacked together a little &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; script that just queries the database for
issues by user and displays it in a simple little&amp;nbsp;page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the major features about Eventum that caught my eye was
integration with a version control system (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCM&lt;/span&gt;, as far as the Eventum
docs are concerned). The feature list stated integration with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt; and
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SVN&lt;/span&gt;. When I actually looked into integrating it with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt;, however, the
problems began. Firstly, the javascript-based help popup would not
display anything, let alone the proper page. Installation was otherwise
perfect under Apache2. I was forced to browse to the included &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; file
manually and check it out. The overview seemed simple enough - throw a
script in your &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVSROOT&lt;/span&gt; loginfo file, update a few variables in the
web-based Eventum configuration, and you&amp;#8217;re off to the races. Reading
on, I found that the installation page was a confusing jumble of
references to a deprecated perl script and the current &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; script to
call from loginfo. Furthermore, database access is provided by having
the script called from loginfo parse the logging information and then
&lt;em&gt;run a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GET&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; on a local script served in the Eventum web
directory. This added level of abstraction not only confuses me to no
end, but also introduces the possibility for malicious users to insert
data in the Eventum &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCM&lt;/span&gt; database simply by visiting a well-known&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, the script provided to be called by loginfo seems to
expect the old &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt; logging format, not the new one being provided by my
installation of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt; 1.12.12. While annoying, this ended up being a minor
fix in the provided &amp;#8220;process_cvs_commits.php&amp;#8221; - I simply had to
rewrite the argument parsing code so that it no longer expects the file,
old version, and new version (%{sVv}) information to be space-separated
on the command line in the form of s,V,v tuples, but expects everything
to be space-separated. I should be cleaning up my fix a bit and
submitting it for inclusion in the next&amp;nbsp;release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once patched, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt; integration works perfectly. Simply append an
identifier to the end of your commit log message, such as &amp;#8220;(issue: 21)&amp;#8221;
or &amp;#8220;(bug: 21)&amp;#8221; and the commit will be automatically associated with the
issue of that number. When viewing an issue, a list of associated &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt;
commits can be&amp;nbsp;viewed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It must be remembered that, as I have read, Eventum is used internally
by MySQL. It is, therefor, a mature project that is well tested in one
circumstance. I believe that it is mature and generally well-working
(though I&amp;#8217;ve heard reports that the 2.x tree isn&amp;#8217;t as stable as the
older versions, which are most likely still in use at MySQL). It must
also be noted that the issue with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt; integration is most likely only
with the newer &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt; versions using the new logging format (I don&amp;#8217;t know
when the switch was made) and will probably not be noticed in older
projects which have established &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, for the opinion section. Eventum has thousands of features. I have
detailed every issue that I have, which total about five. I found it to
be a stable system, ready-to-run out of the box. Overall, I think it has
the best feature set of the open-source bug tracking systems that I
surveyed, which are probably most of the ones out there. It&amp;#8217;s a great
project which I&amp;#8217;d recommend to anyone, though if you want more advanced
features (like integration with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt;, or things not offered such as
anonymous issue viewing) you should be comfortable with coding in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;
until someone makes patches&amp;nbsp;available.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="bug tracking"></category><category term="eventum"></category><category term="PHP"></category><category term="review"></category><category term="ticketing"></category></entry></feed>