<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://newblog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/rutgers-school-iti-it-microsoft-comparison-sun-solaris-java.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 00:38:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Microsoft, Sun, School News</title><link>http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2007/10/microsoft-sun-school-news/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I&amp;#8217;m currently applying to the &lt;a href="http://www.scils.rutgers.edu/information-technology-and-informatics-major/program-information.html"&gt;Information Technology and
Informatics
(&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ITI&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;
major at Rutgers. I&amp;#8217;m in my third year of college (transferred in from
&lt;a href="http://www.rit.edu"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; after a trimester there freshman year. This
will also be my fourth prospective major - hopefully this one will
stick. If you&amp;#8217;re interested in the list, it was a trimester (10 weeks)
at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIT&lt;/span&gt; for Fine Art Photography (probably the most fun I ever had in
&amp;#8220;school&amp;#8221;), followed by the Rutgers list - a semester of general ed
requirements while thinking about Biological Sciences/Pre-Med, then a
realization and a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CS&lt;/span&gt; major, a year of that and here I am at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ITI&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CS&lt;/span&gt; was
interesting, but it quickly became apparent that the curriculum was far
too low-level to hold my interest - my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CS&lt;/span&gt; 102 (Intro to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOP&lt;/span&gt; / Java) and
103 (Data Structures) classes were interesting, but I kept wanting to
ask my profs why they wanted to fail me for saying that not every
program needs &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOP&lt;/span&gt; (What? A 20-line shell script is bad because it&amp;#8217;s a
procedural language?), and couldn&amp;#8217;t cope with spending weeks on coding a
class to do X when I know that it;s already been done, been &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPL&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;d, and I
could study the code in a night and move on to a program that does
something. The list of higher-level courses didn&amp;#8217;t look much better.
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ITI&lt;/span&gt;, on the other hand, has courses in Linux, e-Commerce, and
Information Security, not to mention management-related courses covering
legal aspects, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HR&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More to the point, we were given an assignment for a research project -
a paper that&amp;#8217;s supposed to convince the management of an organization
whether or not to adopt a &amp;#8220;new&amp;#8221; technology. Having a last name between
A-G (I love how professors randomly pick criteria) my assignment is
supposed to be directed towards an online university. We were given a
list of topics to choose from, including social networking sites such as
Second Life, My Space, etc., PIMs, search results visualization (i.e.
Grokker), and a few others. While I guess these are new technologies,
the topic that I chose (obviously not on the list) was &amp;#8220;The use of
self-healing technologies in service-oriented organizations&amp;#8221;. (Yes, I
was hoping that she grades by buzzword count, or at least number of
hyphenated words). I still have almost a week to write the paper, but
I&amp;#8217;m hoping to come up with some interesting stuff, including a whole
list of good research references, and lots of talk about &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LCFG&lt;/span&gt; and
cfengine. Stay tuned, maybe I&amp;#8217;ll end up finding something interesting.
The plus to this whole project is that I realized that as a Rutgers
student, I have access to the entire &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACM&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IEEE&lt;/span&gt; online archives, among
other cool&amp;nbsp;resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sun Campus Ambassador year is starting to kick into gear. There&amp;#8217;s a
lot of hype about the new Sun developments such as the unification of
the Storage and Systems groups, the Microsoft deal (grimace), the
upcoming NetBeans 6.0 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IDE&lt;/span&gt; release, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;J2EE&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;J2ME&lt;/span&gt; programming
languages, etc. There&amp;#8217;s also a lot of boring administrative details,
like remembering to use the names of Sun technologies as adjectives not
nouns (something to do with trademarks that makes no sense to me). This
weekend will be full of organization and Sun training&amp;#8230; and hopefully,
plans to take Sun up on the employee discount for Solaris operating
system certification (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCSA&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCNA&lt;/span&gt;). Also of interest, I was asked to
complete a survey on the use of Sun technology on campus. I know that a
lot of the programming courses are Java-based, and I&amp;#8217;m sure that
NetBeans has a strong following. However, I&amp;#8217;m very interested in finding
out how well Solaris has penetrated the University environment (beyond
the fact that every student uses it for Email, Web, Portal, etc. without
knowing&amp;nbsp;it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now, something I wrote yesterday at&amp;nbsp;work:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having a Microsoft discussion with someone, I wanted to clear up
a few things related to my views on Microsoft. Mainly, that I don&amp;#8217;t have
an issue with Microsoft per se. I have issues with Microsoft&amp;#8217;s
policies, and Microsoft happens to be the most publicly visible company with such
policies. Some of these&amp;nbsp;Include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lack of software openness. Both the ethical implications of
   software that isn&amp;#8217;t &lt;a href="http://www.fsf.org"&gt;Free Software&lt;/a&gt;, and
   functional issues with software that I can&amp;#8217;t modify to do what I
    want, distribute to others, or (if I were a large corporation) have an
   independent company audit the source of for security risks. I want
   control of my software. Microsoft doesn&amp;#8217;t allow that. Moreover, I
    think
   that non-technical end users should have the option of having
    control
   over their software as&amp;nbsp;well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software that is designed to a specific intended user, and can&amp;#8217;t be
   modified otherwise. Specifically, I&amp;#8217;m a technical person. I want
   software that&amp;#8217;s designed to be run on a network and an operating
    system
   that&amp;#8217;s designed to be administered from a graphical terminal in the
    next
   room, or over a text-based &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; session from hundreds of miles away.
    If I
   want to use the command line, I want to have that option. Basically,
    I
   want options. I don&amp;#8217;t want someone deciding that I&amp;#8217;m too stupid to
    use
   those options. Other users don&amp;#8217;t even need to know that a
    command-line
   is there, but I want to. And, more importantly, I don&amp;#8217;t believe
    that
   these options (such as *good* remote administration) should
    require
   expensive server&amp;nbsp;versions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want an operating system that recognizes &lt;a href="http://www.fsf.org"&gt;Free
    Software&lt;/a&gt; and doesn&amp;#8217;t attempt to
   cripple&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#8217;m a programmer. I like standards. Things work because of
    standards.
   We can send e-mail and view web sites because of standards. I think
    that
   standards are good. And I like *one* set of standards which are
    accepted
   as best. All web browsers let you view web pages via &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt;. I think
    that
   document formats should have one standard. I think that standard
    should
   include, for anyone to use however they wish, all of the
    information
   needed to implement it. I don&amp;#8217;t want software that goes beyond a
   standard in undocumented ways. Almost all non-Microsoft browsers
    render
   &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; in pretty much the same way. Web designers that I know have
    two
   test systems - &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IE&lt;/span&gt; and not &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IE&lt;/span&gt;. They test their web page under Windows
    in
   &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IE&lt;/span&gt; to find out how it looks on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IE&lt;/span&gt;. They test it on anything else to
    see
   how it looks in everything&amp;nbsp;else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t want a vendor telling me that I have to use their software.
    I
   don&amp;#8217;t want someone to tell me that their browser is *part* of my
   operating system. I want to be able to add and remove whatever
    software
   I want. And I want to be able to make it work. If need be, I want to
    be
   able to replace software with my own, or with something that I think
    is
   better. I want to be able to choose what gets installed on my
    computer,
   in a fine-grained level of accuracy, if I&amp;nbsp;want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want proven security. And more importantly, I want to have
    control
   over the security. I want to be able to add third-party patches
    from
   organizations like the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSA&lt;/span&gt; to harden my security. And I want them
    to
   pervade every level of the system, not just userspace. I want to be
    able
   to add security fixes from anyone I want, and have anyone I want
    audit
   the&amp;nbsp;code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want an operating system that&amp;#8217;s time-tested. I like seeing
   copyright notices that go back to the 1980s. The fact that an
    operating
   system has had multiple major redesigns in the past 10 years does
    not
   speak well for your code. Furthermore, I don&amp;#8217;t want to buy a
    product
   that comes in five versions, or however many there are of Windows
    now.
   I&amp;#8217;d be happy with Desktop and Server versions. Maybe even a third
   Development version. Anything more than that sends me the message
    that
   you&amp;#8217;re just trying to tax features and keep them out of the hands of&amp;nbsp;users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t want to be locked in to a vendor. Yes, this is a direct
   reference towards Free/Open Source Software. If your company goes
   bottom-up, or just decides that you don&amp;#8217;t care about what I want, I
   should be able to hire an independent programmer to maintain what
    you
   gave me, or make the changes that I want. More importantly, if you
   decide to stop supporting a product that I like, I want to be able
    to
   have someone else support it, possibly better than you&amp;nbsp;did.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t want to buy from a company that actively engages in
    campaigns
   of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FUD&lt;/span&gt; (fear, uncertainty, doubt). I want to buy from a company
    that
   respects their customers/users and their choices. I don&amp;#8217;t want a
    vendor
   that engages in scare tactics or buying up competitors and killing
    them
   off. I want a company that is nice to people. I don&amp;#8217;t want a
    company
   that threatens the the customers of their competitors with&amp;nbsp;lawsuits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to buy from a company that understands compatibility and
   strives for it. I don&amp;#8217;t want a company that tries to bury all
    mention of
   competing products. I want a vendor that can honestly admit that in
   certain cases their product X isn&amp;#8217;t as good as a competitor&amp;#8217;s
    product Y,
   but in many other cases it&amp;#8217;s better. I want a vendor that
    understands
   that I want to run operating systems W, X, Y, and Z and have them
    all
   work together, even if this vendor only sells&amp;nbsp;X.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A vendor that I buy from will &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NOT&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EVER&lt;/span&gt;, tell me tell me that I
    need
   a state-of-the-art system to run a desktop computer or a server.
    There
   is no reason at all why my mail server needs to run a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt;. More
   importantly, in 2007, there is absolutely no reason why my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;
   development web server should have 1 Gb of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt; just to run the
    operating
   system. I&amp;#8217;m only coding some &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; form-based apps for a personal
    web
   site - there&amp;#8217;s no reason why I need more than 512 Mb to run a simple
    web
   server. Finally, and this is just a personal thing, but I like a
    vendor
   that understands students. I&amp;#8217;m in college. I want an operating
    system
   that will install, if not out-of-the-box then with some simple
   customization, on the type of computer that I&amp;#8217;d find at the&amp;nbsp;curb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 00:38:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2007-10-10:2007/10/microsoft-sun-school-news/</guid><category>rutgers school iti it microsoft comparison sun solaris java</category></item></channel></rss>