<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://newblog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/school.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 23:24:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Internet Security, Microsoft Lies</title><link>http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2008/09/internet-security-microsoft-lies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet&amp;nbsp;Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this semester I&amp;#8217;m taking a class on Internet Security. Our textbook
is &lt;a href="http://search.barnesandnoble.com/booksearch/isbninquiry.asp?ean=1423901304"&gt;Management of Internet Security, 2nd
Edition&lt;/a&gt;
by Michael E. Whitman and Herbert J. Mattord. It seems pretty basic, and
very much focused on the management side of things (as opposed to
technical). The table of contents is as&amp;nbsp;follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to the Management of Information&amp;nbsp;Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning for&amp;nbsp;Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning for&amp;nbsp;Contingencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Security&amp;nbsp;Policy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing the Security&amp;nbsp;Program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security Management Models and&amp;nbsp;Practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk Management: Identifying and Assessing&amp;nbsp;Risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk Management: Assessing and Controlling&amp;nbsp;Risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protection&amp;nbsp;Mechanisms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personnel and&amp;nbsp;Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Law and&amp;nbsp;Ethics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Security Project&amp;nbsp;Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, given that it&amp;#8217;s really a &amp;#8220;management&amp;#8221; book, I can&amp;#8217;t say I&amp;#8217;m
surprised that it reads like an essay that was graded on a scale of
buzzwords-per-sentence. However, it seems to be missing the one chapter
that&amp;#8217;s the most important - actually, the only chapter that would be in
the book if I wrote it - &amp;#8220;How to get management to allocate the money
you need for proper security.&amp;#8221; In fact, skimming over the book, I found
a lot of content on general management planning, job descriptions,
sample policies, and a lot of other pie-in-the-sky stuff, but not one
concrete section dedicated to the most difficult part of security -
getting the &amp;#8220;resources&amp;#8221; to do it&amp;nbsp;right!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft&amp;nbsp;Lies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why we would spend time analyzing corporate mission statements in an
Internet Security class, I have no idea. That seems, to me, too much
like what we covered in &amp;#8220;Management of Technological Organizations.&amp;#8221;
But, we do, and one of the examples used is &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/About/default.mspx"&gt;Microsoft&amp;#8217;s Mission and
Values statement&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps,
being the F/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt; advocate that I am, my reading of it was a bit cynical.
Let&amp;#8217;s take a look at&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;At Microsoft, our mission and values are to help people and business
throughout the world realize their full potential.&amp;#8221; Well, we&amp;#8217;re off to a
good start. Aside from the fact that they want you to realize that
potential using &lt;strong&gt;only their software&lt;/strong&gt;, and use their power and money
to actively monopolize (or attempt to) most industries that they enter,
this seems pretty&amp;nbsp;run-of-the-mill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corporate Citizenship:&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8220;Every successful corporation has &lt;em&gt;a
responsibility to use its resources and influence to make a positive
impact on the world and its people&lt;/em&gt;. Microsoft’s Global Citizenship
Initiative is focused on mobilizing our resources across the company and
around the world, to create opportunities in the communities where we do
business, and to &lt;em&gt;fulfill our commitment to serving the public good
through innovative technologies and partnerships&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#8221; Well. Now we&amp;#8217;re
getting somewhere. Apparently &amp;#8220;a positive impact on the world and its
people&amp;#8221; is defined as trying to monopolize every sector that Microsoft
touches, whether attempting to crush and then buy-out the competition,
or through flat-out
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fear,_uncertainty_and_doubt"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FUD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and
billion-dollar marketing campaigns. Hmm&amp;#8230; innovative partnerships&amp;#8230; as
in&amp;nbsp;Novell?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Legal and Corporate Affairs:&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8220;Microsoft’s Legal and Corporate Affairs
Group works on the cutting edge of business and regulatory issues around
the world.&amp;#8221; Well, I can&amp;#8217;t argue with that, they sure are on the cutting
edge. What started with Bill Gates mailing out whiny letters about
pirated Altair &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BASIC&lt;/span&gt; has now turned into a global juggernaut, capable of
forcing the creation of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; standards at their whim, and successfully
quashing any dissent about obviously flawed and under-reviewed
&amp;#8220;standards&amp;#8221; (which, in fact, simply describe current software, rather
than setting any real&amp;nbsp;standard).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Values:&lt;/em&gt;As a company, and as individuals, we value &lt;strong&gt;integrity&lt;/strong&gt;,
&lt;strong&gt;honesty&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;openness&lt;/strong&gt;, personal excellence, &lt;strong&gt;constructive
self-criticism&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;continual self-improvement&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;mutual
respect&lt;/strong&gt;. We are committed to our customers and partners and have a
passion for technology. We take on big challenges, and pride ourselves
on seeing them through. &lt;strong&gt;We hold ourselves accountable to our
customers&lt;/strong&gt;, shareholders, partners, and employees by honoring our
commitments, providing results, and &lt;strong&gt;striving for the highest
quality&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;integrity&lt;/strong&gt; - i.e. not creating a draft &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; standard and then
    &lt;a href="http://www.networkworld.com/news/2007/083007-microsoft-employee-offered-incentives-for.html"&gt;offering monetary incentives for
    acceptance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;honesty&lt;/strong&gt; - when it works. Intentionally making Vista-Capable
    labeling so ambiguous that it even &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/09/business/09digi.html?_r=1&amp;amp;oref=slogin"&gt;confuses Microsoft
    executives&lt;/a&gt;?&amp;nbsp;Fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;openness&lt;/strong&gt; um&amp;#8230; did they seriously say that? Openness like&amp;#8230;
    protocol interoperability? Standards that can be implemented without
    patent violations? An &amp;#8220;Open Specification Promise&amp;#8221; that doesn&amp;#8217;t come
    with a &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/interop/osp/default.mspx"&gt;three page
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FAQ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;? Nope. Not&amp;nbsp;Microsoft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;constructive self-criticism&lt;/strong&gt; - Ok, I&amp;#8217;ll give them this one. They
    do, rarely, criticize themselves. Though &amp;#8220;constructive&amp;#8221; usually
    means making comments about the poor design of a previous product,
    and suggesting that everyone upgrade to the new&amp;nbsp;version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;continual self-improvement&lt;/strong&gt; - I&amp;#8217;ll give them this one too. In
    fact, they&amp;#8217;re so crazy about it that they&amp;#8217;ve been improving the same
    codebase for&amp;nbsp;decades!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mutual respect&lt;/strong&gt; - See&amp;nbsp;above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We hold ourselves accountable to our customers&lt;/strong&gt; - Ok. They &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt;
    offering to allow users to &lt;a href="http://download.microsoft.com/download/5/f/4/5f4c83d3-833e-4f11-8cbd-699b0c164182/royaltyoemreferencesheet.pdf"&gt;downgrade from Vista to
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;striving for the highest quality&lt;/strong&gt; - I don&amp;#8217;t think so. They&amp;#8217;re
    striving for products that have the highest &lt;em&gt;market share&lt;/em&gt;. As long
    as the quality is acceptable to the majority of users, and the
    products do what the majority of users need, that&amp;#8217;s fine. But
    wait&amp;#8230; apparently they even missed &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; goal with&amp;nbsp;Vista.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just the opinion of one person. My motivations may be diverse,
and surely there&amp;#8217;s a bit of zealotry in there. After all, if Ford told
me I couldn&amp;#8217;t put fog lights on my car myself, I had to bring it to the
dealer and pay $400, I&amp;#8217;d stop buying their cars - and make sure everyone
else knew what they did. But there&amp;#8217;s also my ever-present desire to make
sure people know both sides of the story, and all the facts. The
mainstream media (specifically dumbed-down television) rarely reports on
the less cheerful side of Microsoft, like the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#8220;standard&amp;#8221;
&lt;a href="http://www.networkworld.com/news/2007/083007-microsoft-employee-offered-incentives-for.html"&gt;scandal&lt;/a&gt;,
or the &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/03/09/business/09digi.html?_r=1&amp;amp;oref=slogin"&gt;Vista
letters&lt;/a&gt;,
or the
&lt;a href="http://yro.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=08/04/22/2032232&amp;amp;from=rss"&gt;Vista-Capable&lt;/a&gt;
fiasco. And I find this to be horribly disturbing. Many people don&amp;#8217;t
realize that there &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; alternatives to Microsoft products, even ones
that are provided by such big names as &lt;a href="http://www.sun.com"&gt;Sun
Microsystems&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.ibm.com"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IBM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But,
most striking, is Microsoft&amp;#8217;s overwhelming monopoly. Windows&amp;#8217; market
share is currently
&lt;a href="http://marketshare.hitslink.com/report.aspx?qprid=8"&gt;90.66%&lt;/a&gt; or higher.
I ask you, what other industries which affect not only consumers, but
nearly every aspect of our daily lives (as computing does) would be
allowed to have such a monopoly? It has happened in many other American
industries - oil, steel, the railroads, telephone service. Where is the
government&amp;nbsp;now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened to the America that made massive monopolies illegal? Have
we forgotten a supremely part of our history that began in 1980 with the
Sherman Act? Or even the recent events with Bell? In order to truly
stimulate competition in the software industry, and provide for not only
choice but the improved quality, reliability, and security that comes
with true software competition, something needs to be done. For
starters, how about breaking Microsoft into separate entities - browser,
Office, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;, server, etc. And - the important part - preventing any
package sales, discounts, or bundling between the separate types of
software (and separate&amp;nbsp;companies).&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 23:24:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2008-09-16:2008/09/internet-security-microsoft-lies/</guid><category>microsoft</category><category>rutgers</category><category>school</category><category>security</category></item></channel></rss>