<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/servers.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 19:35:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>New server, and looking for work</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2011/09/new-server-and-looking-for-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;First off, I&amp;#8217;ve moved this blog from a server in my basement to
&lt;a href="http://www.linode.com"&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt; virtual hosting, in preparation for my
move from New Jersey to an apartment in Georgia. This will mark the
first time since 2001 (when I was 14) that I didn&amp;#8217;t have at least a
publicly-accessible Linux server in my home. It also means that, as sad
as it is, the rack will probably all be either going in Ebay or to scrap
(after a good &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gutmann_method"&gt;Guttmann
wipe&lt;/a&gt;, of&amp;nbsp;course).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="server rack" src="/GFX/rack_2011-09-27_small.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m a bit sad to give up hosting &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; myself and having my beautiful
per-zone, per-domain, hourly &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; statistics, but that was my first move,
and Linode&amp;#8217;s web-based &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; manager is much nicer than my collection of
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; scripts, MySQL backend, and rndc reload wrapper (and I no longer
need &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BIND&lt;/span&gt; split-horizon since the hosting is remote). Mail was next, and
I&amp;#8217;ve got one web server moved and the other on the way. The biggest
disappointment is losing my testbed for all the fun stuff I can&amp;#8217;t do (or
doesn&amp;#8217;t make sense) with a virtualized hosting provider -
&lt;a href="http://puppetlabs.com/"&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt;, real &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISC&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BIND9&lt;/span&gt;, Cisco CatOS and
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IOS&lt;/span&gt; devices, &lt;a href="http://www.bacula.org"&gt;Bacula&lt;/a&gt;, running my own edge
router, etc. There&amp;#8217;s at least a handful of current production Rutgers
services and tools that got their start here as projects in my spare
time. But I&amp;#8217;m sure I&amp;#8217;ll make up somehow, and I&amp;#8217;m planning on putting
aside some money for a massive new desktop to run a slew of&amp;nbsp;VMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a second note, the one thing holding back my move to Georgia is,
well, my lack of a job there. I&amp;#8217;m really just starting to look around,
and am very much hoping to find something comparable to my current
position at Rutgers - a group supporting diverse services, doing mainly
architecture and implementation of new services, a good dose of
automation and custom tool development, and hopefully also some work
with performance and availability monitoring (think
&lt;a href="http://www.nagios.org"&gt;Nagios&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.cacti.net/"&gt;Cacti&lt;/a&gt;),
logging, etc. And, of course, something that&amp;#8217;s network-focused, whether
wireless or wired. Maintaining some data center space/physical
infrastructure and occasionally working with my hands is fun too. So, if
you know anyone who&amp;#8217;s hiring a Linux/open source dude in the general
vicinity of Athens, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GA&lt;/span&gt; (including Atlanta and the surrounding area),
please give me a heads-up, or pass them along to
&lt;a href="http://resume.jasonantman.com"&gt;resume.jasonantman.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 19:35:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2011-09-27:2011/09/new-server-and-looking-for-work/</guid><category>linode</category><category>move</category><category>rack</category><category>servers</category></item></channel></rss>