<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/slide.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 09:34:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Remotely-controlled deck.js slide presentations</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2014/05/remotely-controlled-deckjs-slide-presentations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been struggling to find a good, cross-platform remote meeting solution. We&amp;#8217;re using &lt;a href="http://www.imeet.com"&gt;iMeet&lt;/a&gt;
at work at the moment, but there&amp;#8217;s no way to present or screen share from a Linux machine. For most of our ops and
automation team daily and weekly meetings, we use &lt;a href="http://www.teamspeak.com/"&gt;TeamSpeak&lt;/a&gt; - sure it&amp;#8217;s not open source,
but it&amp;#8217;s simple, supports all OSes that matter to us (Mac, Linux, Windows, Android and iOS), can be self-hosted,
and has the holy grail, functional push-to-talk. But it&amp;#8217;s audio&amp;nbsp;only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Friday I was running two short elaboration meetings, and had quick little slide decks done up in &lt;a href="http://imakewebthings.com/deck.js/"&gt;deck.js&lt;/a&gt;
to keep us on track. I couldn&amp;#8217;t help but think, gee, it sure would be nice if instead of switching to Mac or a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VM&lt;/span&gt; and sharing my screen,
we could just use the audio communication mediums that we already do, and I could simply control the slides in a&amp;nbsp;browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well this morning I stumbled on &lt;a href="http://cleverchris.com/"&gt;Chris Jaure&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;s &lt;a href="https://github.com/chrisjaure/deckjs-remote"&gt;deckjs-remote&lt;/a&gt;
project that does exactly that. It&amp;#8217;s a nodejs npm module that runs a websocket server, and allows people to join a session and follow
along as the presenter changes&amp;nbsp;slides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did have a few hiccups getting it working - mainly some issues with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CORS&lt;/span&gt;. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;README&lt;/span&gt;.md has a large block of markup to be added to
the slide deck html to support &amp;#8220;older browsers that don&amp;#8217;t support &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CORS&lt;/span&gt;.&amp;#8221; I&amp;#8217;m running Firefox 28.0 (Firefox has supported &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CORS&lt;/span&gt; since
3.0, quite a few years back) and still needed to add this to get everything working. I also needed to manually add a script tag
for socket.io coming from the nodejs server in order to get everything&amp;nbsp;working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a bit of a delay for the socket connection to come up after initially loading the page, but once that&amp;#8217;s done, the presenter
(&amp;#8220;master&amp;#8221; session) should get the password prompt, and any guests should get a prompt asking if they want to join the current
session. Perhaps the best part is that the nodejs server interally stores each deck by &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;, so it seems to work perfectly fine
when running one instance for N presenters (i.e. a single instance running persistently on a shared&amp;nbsp;server).&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Antman</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 09:34:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2014-05-12:2014/05/remotely-controlled-deckjs-slide-presentations/</guid><category>slide</category><category>presentation</category><category>deck.js</category><category>deckjs</category><category>javascript</category></item></channel></rss>