<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/solaris.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 15:27:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>My biggest problem with Linux</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/10/my-biggest-problem-with-linux/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For one of my wonderful classes, Internet Security, I&amp;#8217;m doing a
presentation on &amp;#8220;patch management&amp;#8221;. While I&amp;#8217;m obligated to cover Windows
- and, of course, will talk about MacOS - I&amp;#8217;ll obviously be spending a
good deal of time on the Unix/Linux side of things. This has gotten me
thinking about one of my biggest problems with Linux (and specifically
&lt;a href="http://www.opensuse.org"&gt;OpenSuSE&lt;/a&gt;, my usual default distro. Patch
management is utterly&amp;nbsp;awful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s the problem: I have about a dozen machines under my control. I
need to keep them all up-to-date. Currently, I manually do patches and
upgrades via YaST or zypper. I thought about scripting this through
zypper, but that doesn&amp;#8217;t make any sense - the packages on the machines
are far from homogenous, so there&amp;#8217;s no clear way to make one script that
updates them all. I considered using Puppet or CFengine or something of
that sort, but that&amp;#8217;s too heavy-weight for me - for only a dozen
machines, many of which are personal or development only, that&amp;#8217;s a lot
to keep track of by hand, and a lot of work defining which patches
should be applied, and which machines shouldn&amp;#8217;t be&amp;nbsp;changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My other peeve is distribution upgrades. About three of my machines are
still running OpenSuSE 10.0 or 10.1, both of which are unsupported, and
no longer even have downloads available. Why? Becuase I&amp;#8217;ve done major
OpenSuSE upgrades before, broken a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LOT&lt;/span&gt; of stuff, and I simply can&amp;#8217;t risk
that on machines that can&amp;#8217;t stand extended downtime. This process
*needs* to be made easier. Bottom line - it should be made no more
difficult or unreliable than a kernel upgrade. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IMHO&lt;/span&gt;, the biggest selling
point for Solaris is its&amp;#8217; ability to do a total upgrade to a second
partition, and switch-over at runtime. Why doesn&amp;#8217;t Linux (or SuSE) have
this&amp;nbsp;yet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What&amp;#8217;s my ideal solution?&lt;/em&gt; A curses application that uses text-file
backends (curses so I can run it over &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; even if I have a slow link or
high latency, like from a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; session on my cell phone, if need be). The
app would allow me to list all of the machines I want managed. It would
connect to the machines over standard &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt;, and would leave an extensive
audit trail of what&amp;#8217;s done, both on the management console and on the
machines (as well as running as a dedicated user). The application would
maintain an inventory of all of the packages on every machine. It would
check daily for new patches/updates to any of those packages, and e-mail
me a daily summary of what&amp;#8217;s new, including all dependency changes, and
which machines need the update. It would also allow me to define, on a
per-machine (or per-group-of-machines) basis, rules for packages that
must stay at their current version - i.e. I have a bunch of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP4&lt;/span&gt; apps,
so machine X needs to stay at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP4&lt;/span&gt;. The e-mail summary would include any
packages that aren&amp;#8217;t going to be updated for a specific machine because
of dependency/version rules, as well as warnings about any new packages
that have a dependency that has a rule set. I could then run the main
curses app on my admin machine and, starting from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NO&lt;/span&gt; selections, select
which updates I want to apply and whether I want to ignore or create new
rules to keep something at its current version, on a per-machine or
per-group basis. This curses app would generate a file (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt;?) of what to
do (which would also be generated or edited by hand, easily). The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt;
file would then be fed into a script that downloads all of the needed
packages to a central (local) mirror (or, optionally, for remote
machines, has them download locally on the machine), checksums them, and
then installs them (running commands over &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt;) on all applicable
machines. It would then keep a log of all changes, both on each machine
changed (in a master changelog file) and on the central administrative
machine. &lt;strong&gt;Most importantly&lt;/strong&gt;, the curses interface would have a simple,
quick way to back out any specific update or group of updates for all
machines, a group of machines, or one machine. All data needed to back
out a change would be kept on each machine (say, cleaned up at the next
update of that package and all of its&amp;#8217; dependencies) with
machine-readable instructions kept in a central file, allowing local
rollbacks - i.e. a machine goes down, I realize that it was because of
an update to package X, and on the local machine I can check the
changelog, see an entry like &amp;#8220;Package X updated 1.0.0 to 1.0.1 on
yyyy-mm-dd, Change &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ID&lt;/span&gt; 1234&amp;#8221; and then, to rollback, simply issue a
command like &amp;#8220;patchmgt rollback 1234&amp;#8221; on the effected&amp;nbsp;machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just some ideas, and a little&amp;nbsp;rant.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 15:27:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-10-27:2008/10/my-biggest-problem-with-linux/</guid><category>linux</category><category>patch management</category><category>solaris</category><category>updates</category><category>upgrades</category></item><item><title>Rutgers Student Linux Group and Sun</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/03/rutgers-student-linux-group-and-sun/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The next week will be quite busy. For one, I&amp;#8217;m going to attempt an
&lt;a href="http://www.opensolaris.org/os/"&gt;OpenSolaris&lt;/a&gt; operating system
installation on my &lt;a href="http://event.asus.com/eeepc/microsites/en/index.htm"&gt;Asus
eeePC&lt;/a&gt;. Last I
heard, there were some compatibility issues - though this was my first
attempt at running the Solaris operating system on a laptop, and it took
quite an effort to get my favorite mainstream Linux distro installed on
the eeePC, though I&amp;#8217;ve been running that on laptops for 6+&amp;nbsp;years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Sunday, March 30&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, the &lt;a href="http://ruslug.rutgers.edu/w/"&gt;Rutgers University Student Linux Users&amp;#8217;
Group&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RUSLUG&lt;/span&gt;) will be hosting our annual
Installfest in the &lt;a href="http://ruslug.rutgers.edu/w/EitDirections"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EIT&lt;/span&gt; Lab&lt;/a&gt;
from 10 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt; until 6 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt;. While the event is generally marketed towards
Linux newbies, it&amp;#8217;s usually attended by a diverse range of students (and
staff) from first-timers to Solaris sysadmins. I&amp;#8217;ll be attendance, as
always, and will also be conducting some demos of new Sun technology
(mainly OpenSolaris and NetBeans). For anyone in the New
Brunswick/Pisctaway area, I&amp;#8217;ll also be armed with some door prizes and a
whole plethora of CDs and DVDs. For anyone interested, I&amp;#8217;ll be providing
information and pointers on NetBeans and Solaris, as well as
installation assistance (and maybe some prizes) for anyone looking to
give OpenSolaris a whirl on their&amp;nbsp;system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following up the Installfest, on Tuesday, April 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; at 9 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt; (also in
the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EIT&lt;/span&gt; lab) will be the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RUSLUG&lt;/span&gt; Newbie Night. It&amp;#8217;s generally a
fun-filled evening with &lt;a href="http://www.ubuntu.com/"&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; LiveCDs and a
general Q&amp;amp;A session about Linux. Generally this includes one-on-one
assistance for new Linux users. In an effort to raise the level of
content (and provide a diversion for more experienced users if there
aren&amp;#8217;t many new faces), I&amp;#8217;ll be once again demo&amp;#8217;ing some Sun technology,
and specifically providing an overview of my recently completed personal
mailserver migration from SuSE Linux to OpenSolaris. Once again,
visitors can expect some door prizes and lots of fun CDs to take&amp;nbsp;home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RUSLUG&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;news:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It looks like I&amp;#8217;ll be running to become an officer next year. Anyone
    else at Rutgers can feel free to contact me with ideas,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RUSLUG&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s current box,
    &lt;a href="http://ruslug.rutgers.edu/"&gt;ruslug.rutgers.edu&lt;/a&gt;, is a Dell desktop
    thrown on a shelf in a closet. I&amp;#8217;d like to find someone willing to
    help out with procuring a new box. It doesn&amp;#8217;t need to be anything
    fancy - just pretty simple, though I&amp;#8217;d like to look into high
    capacity storage for mirroring distros. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FYI&lt;/span&gt;, the current box is a
    Dell desktop with a 1.7GHz P-4 (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;256KB&lt;/span&gt; cache), 512 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt;, and about
    &lt;span class="caps"&gt;250GB&lt;/span&gt; of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IDE&lt;/span&gt; storage (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;150GB&lt;/span&gt; + &lt;span class="caps"&gt;100GB&lt;/span&gt;, no &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAID&lt;/span&gt;). We don&amp;#8217;t need a big
    upgrade in processor power, but more &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAID&lt;/span&gt; for the system and
    user disks would be nice (distro mirrors can be a big &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IDE&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SATA&lt;/span&gt; or an
    external&amp;nbsp;disk).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2008 23:46:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-03-26:2008/03/rutgers-student-linux-group-and-sun/</guid><category>ruslug</category><category>solaris</category><category>sun</category></item><item><title>Sun Blade 150 working!</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/12/sun-blade-150-working/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Yes, it&amp;#8217;s 3 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt; here, and I&amp;#8217;ve been working since about 6 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt; on this. But
I finally got one of my two surplus (and fully locked down in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NVRAM&lt;/span&gt;) Sun
Blade 150 workstations up and running. I encountered a few problems
along the way, but managed to solve them - more or&amp;nbsp;less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="problem-1-nvram-password-set-impossible-to-install-an-os"&gt;Problem 1 - &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NVRAM&lt;/span&gt; password set, impossible to install an&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of googling, and asking for advice. Eventually, I came
by a forum post expressing success with a procedure of pulling out and
then re-inserting the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NVRAM&lt;/span&gt; *while* the system is powered on. This
left my system un-bootable. I pulled the chip again, and found two pins
bent. I straightened them, re-inserted, and rebooted using the Stop+N
Equivalent Functionality (after powering on the system, once you hear
the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;POST&lt;/span&gt; beep, click the power button twice quickly). This temporarily
resets the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NVRAM&lt;/span&gt; to default settings. I found that the password was
gone, and was able to issue the &amp;#8220;set-defaults&amp;#8221; command at the &amp;#8220;ok&gt;&amp;#8221;
prompt. I then popped in the Solaris 10 install &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt;, issued the
&amp;#8220;reset-all&amp;#8221; command to reboot, and used Stop+A at boot to bring up a
boot menu, and told it to boot from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CDROM&lt;/span&gt; (&amp;#8220;boot cdrom&amp;#8221;). Installation
then&amp;nbsp;started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="problem-2-invalid-nvram"&gt;Problem 2 - Invalid&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NVRAM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the above procedure, when booting, I got a message following the
Sun banner stating that there was a problem with the IDprom checksum.
When the install &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt; booted, I also got messages stating &amp;#8220;Invalid format
code in IDprom&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;Warning: IDprom checksum error&amp;#8221;, and &amp;#8220;os-io Invalid
format code in IDprom&amp;#8221;. After another five hours of work, I found that
it&amp;#8217;s essentially something I have to live with. While OpenBoot previous
to version 4 allowed use of the &amp;#8220;mkp&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;mkpl&amp;#8221; commands to directly
write the IDprom, version 4 and above allows no access to this. The
IDprom was reporting an ethernet (mac) address of all zeros.
Unfortunately, there seems to be no way to correct this as far as I&amp;#8217;ve
found. However, it didn&amp;#8217;t effect my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; installation&amp;#8230;&amp;nbsp;much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*There may be a way to access the IDprom through OpenBoot 4.x, but I
couldn&amp;#8217;t find any reference to it online, and couldn&amp;#8217;t figure out the
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FORTH&lt;/span&gt; commands from the reference&amp;nbsp;docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some helpful links for the above problems include the OpenBoot 4.x
Command Reference Manual, currently found
&lt;a href="http://dlc.sun.com/pdf/816-1177-10/816-1177-10.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, as well as
the Sun Blade 150 Service Manual (from
&lt;a href="http://docs.sun.com/"&gt;docs.sun.com&lt;/a&gt;), document 816-4379-10, currently
indexed with the Sun Blade 150 docs
&lt;a href="http://docs.sun.com/app/docs/coll/sb150"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It was also
interesting, in my search for help, to look at the OpenBoot 3.x Command
Manual, and see how easy it was to re-write the IDprom on older Sun
Blade&amp;nbsp;workstations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pleaese note that the advice given in the &lt;a href="http://040.digital-bless.com/texts/Unofficial_Sun_Blade_100_FAQ.htm"&gt;Unofficial SunBlade 100
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FAQ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
and the &lt;a href="http://www.squirrel.com/sun-nvram-hostid.faq.html"&gt;squirrel.com Sun &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NVRAM&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FAQ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to
work on the 150 with OpenBoot 4.x. From what I can tell, all of that
advice applies only to OpenBoot&amp;nbsp;3.x!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other helpful links included an ITworld.com article on &lt;a href="http://open.itworld.com/5040/nlsunixfirmware070111/page_1.html"&gt;Sun &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NVRAM&lt;/span&gt;
passwords&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://forum.java.sun.com/thread.jspa?threadID=5093819&amp;amp;messageID=9329080"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;
Sun Developer Forum post, and
&lt;a href="http://forum.java.sun.com/thread.jspa?threadID=5093819&amp;amp;messageID=9329080"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;
post on password&amp;nbsp;recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="problem-3-mac-ethernet-address-is-000000000000"&gt;Problem 3 - &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MAC&lt;/span&gt; / Ethernet address is&amp;nbsp;00:00:00:00:00:00&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When booting Solaris, I found that I couldn&amp;#8217;t get &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt;. When I finally
got the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; running and logged in as root, I realized something
interesting - I couldn&amp;#8217;t access or ping anything past the one switch I
was connected to. But everything on that switch was fine, pinging both
from and to the Solaris box. I ping&amp;#8217;ed from my laptop, and then thought
to run &amp;#8220;arp -a&amp;#8221;. It showed a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MAC&lt;/span&gt; address of 00:00:00:00:00:00! Running
&amp;#8220;ifconfig -a&amp;#8221; on the Solaris box confirmed this. Luckily, the first time
I booted this box, I wrote down the ethernet address and hostID as shown
on the banner. I ran a quick ifconfig to setup the correct &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MAC&lt;/span&gt;, like
&amp;#8220;ifconfig eri0 ether xx:xx:xx:xx:xx:xx&amp;#8221;. Networking now worked
perfectly, and I could get to everything on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt; as well as browse
the web. It would be good to somehow reset this in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NVRAM&lt;/span&gt;, but for now
I&amp;#8217;m just going to add it to the startup scripts somewhere. One forum
post that I found suggested adding the previous ifconfig command to the
top of /etc/rc.c/init.d/network, which I&amp;#8217;ve done and will see how it
works at the next&amp;nbsp;boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="problem-4-cant-login-to-smc-solaris-management-console"&gt;Problem 4 - Can&amp;#8217;t login to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMC&lt;/span&gt; (Solaris Management&amp;nbsp;Console)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next task after getting the system up and running, and getting
networking working, as to give myself a user account. I was logged in
using the Java Desktop System, so I opened a terminal and ran &amp;#8220;smc &amp;amp;&amp;#8221;.
After the usual initialization wait, I loaded the toolboxes for the
local machine, and connected. When I clicked on the &amp;#8220;users&amp;#8221; module and
entered my root password, I got an invalid password / login failed
message. I tried again and again, even checking against the post-it that
I wrote the password on until I memorize it. Nothing. Searching the
forums, I came by this
&lt;a href="http://forum.java.sun.com/thread.jspa?threadID=5104081&amp;amp;messageID=9354742"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;,
but the value in /etc/security/policy.conf was correctly set to &amp;#8221;
CRYPT_DEFAULT=__unix__&amp;#8221;. So, on a wild hunch, I used &amp;#8220;passwd&amp;#8221; to
reset my password to a shorter one, which I use on a few other
(unimportant) workstations.&amp;nbsp;Magic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now have, after two days of work, a working Solaris box. Now that I
have a good &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; install, in order to get the other box working, I
*should* just be able to swap HDDs, boot, login as root, and use the
&amp;#8220;eeprom&amp;#8221; command to set &amp;#8220;security-mode&amp;#8221; to &amp;#8220;none&amp;#8221;, bypassing all of this&amp;nbsp;bull****.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2007 02:44:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-12-14:2007/12/sun-blade-150-working/</guid><category>nvram</category><category>openboot</category><category>password</category><category>smc</category><category>solaris</category><category>sun</category><category>sunblade</category></item><item><title>*nix</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/09/nix/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;First off, my Sun blog should be coming sometime this weekend/early next
week. If I post anything interesting there, I&amp;#8217;ll be sure to cross-post&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning at work, while reading &lt;a href="http://digg.com"&gt;Digg&lt;/a&gt;, I came by
two interesting links that got me thinking:
&lt;a href="http://www.foogazi.com/2007/09/27/5-reasons-your-parents-should-use-linux/"&gt;5 Reasons Your Parents Should Use
Linux&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href="http://warpedvisions.org/2006/12/30/ten-things-linux-distros-get-right-that-ms-doesnt/"&gt;Ten Things Linux Distros Get Right (That &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt;
Doesn&amp;#8217;t)&lt;/a&gt;.
Now, I&amp;#8217;ll admit, my *nix experience is pretty much limited to Linux.
I&amp;#8217;ve used &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BSD&lt;/span&gt; a few times, but only as pre-built images for embedded
systems like my &lt;a href="http://www.soekris.com"&gt;Soekris&lt;/a&gt; boxen. I&amp;#8217;ve used
Solaris mainly just as a user/web developer in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; at work. And while I
now have a work computer running Solaris 10 and a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SXDE&lt;/span&gt; image on my
laptop, I&amp;#8217;m still relatively new - and, given that I&amp;#8217;m now doing
hardware support and wireless work, I don&amp;#8217;t even know what I need
another machine in the office&amp;nbsp;for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, the second link got me thinking. Specifically, about
something I read in &lt;a href="http://www.catb.org/~esr/writings/taoup/"&gt;The Art of Unix
Programming&lt;/a&gt; [Wikipedia] by
Eric S. Raymond (available online
&lt;a href="http://www.catb.org/~esr/writings/taoup/html/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) with regards to
interface design. One quote that I was able to find in the online
version, comes from Chapter 11, under the subtitle &amp;#8220;Tradeoffs between
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; and Visual Interfaces&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;Resistance to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; interfaces tends to
decrease as users become more expert. In many problem domains, users
(especially frequent
users) reach a crossover point at which the concision and expressiveness
of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; becomes more valuable than avoiding its mnemonic load. Thus, for
example, computing novices prefer the ease of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; desktops, but
experienced users often gradually discover that they prefer typing
commands to a&amp;nbsp;shell.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is another similar
quote in the book, mentioning how resistance to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; drops as
&lt;em&gt;typing speed&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;increases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, in some areas I&amp;#8217;m still bound to Windows. Though my only
personal use for it is to control an ancient Umax Mirage IIse &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCSI&lt;/span&gt;
scanner (with only Windows and Mac drivers), I ultimately need to touch
it now and then - whether on my mother&amp;#8217;s box (she claims she has to have
Windows and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MS&lt;/span&gt; Office because &amp;#8220;that&amp;#8217;s what businesses use&amp;#8221;) or as admin
of the four boxes at the &lt;a href="http://www.midlandparkambulance.com"&gt;Ambulance
Corps&lt;/a&gt; where I&amp;nbsp;volunteer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, whenever I am (unfortunately) pushed into the task of working
on a Windows box, I always feel something lacking. To be blunt, I don&amp;#8217;t
see how experienced users can deal with it. And this isn&amp;#8217;t just an issue
of multiple desktops, or reliability (I expect my desktop to have months
of uptime, and my servers to have years). This isn&amp;#8217;t just pro-Linux,
it&amp;#8217;s anti-Windows. Linux is great. Solaris seems wonderful, and I can&amp;#8217;t
want to move my servers over. And, believe it or not, due to playing
around with the Solaris Management Console, for the first time in 5
years, I plan on running X on my servers.
What this is, is a talk about total workflow. Years ago, I reached the
point where I am more comfortable at the command line, or in an
Ncurses-style &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt;, than in&amp;nbsp;X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I an attribute this to two factors - verbosity and speed. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; is as
verbose as anything can get. I remember setting a static &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; on a Windows
box. I had to navigate the Start menu, open up the control panel, the
network thingy, click on the network card, and work through a series of
dialogs. In Linux, I clicked on the terminal icon, typed &amp;#8220;sudo ifconfig
eth0 up 192.168.0.211&amp;#8221; and then a password. Done. Likewise, refreshing a
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHCP&lt;/span&gt; lease on Windows requires a whole bunch of &amp;#8220;repair connection&amp;#8221;
nonsense, whereas in Linux all it requires is &amp;#8220;dhclient eth0&amp;#8221;. The
bottom line I know what I&amp;#8217;m doing. Windows should have an option to let
me quickly do&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speed is a related issue. Click, click-click, drag, click, click&amp;#8230;.
what about just typing? Even for people who aren&amp;#8217;t &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt;-friendly, there&amp;#8217;s
Ncurses. YaST2, the SuSE/openSuSE administration tool, has both &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; and
Ncurses interfaces. I always use the Ncurses interface. Why? Because
I&amp;#8217;ve been using it for years. I know that if I want to add a user
through YaST, I hit the down arrow 7 times, tab once, down 5, enter. Tab
once more to bring up the add user dialog. I can do this in well under a
second. What&amp;#8217;s the bottom line? Well, first of all, my hands are already
on the keyboard. That&amp;#8217;s where they like to stay. That&amp;#8217;s where they&amp;#8217;re
comfortable. My fingers need to move a *lot* less to navigate with the
arrow keys, tab, and enter than they do to use a mouse. If you know what
you&amp;#8217;re doing, if you already know what you&amp;#8217;re looking for, then a mouse
is slower than the speed of thought (or&amp;nbsp;reaction).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where&amp;#8217;s the Windows bashing? Simple. How do people at Microsoft deal
with this? How does the guy who *wrote* that network settings dialog
deal with navigating the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; every time, even though he already knows
exactly what he wants to do - and probably the system calls to do&amp;nbsp;it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that every time I sit down at a Windows machine, I
wonder how the most popular &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; is one that doesn&amp;#8217;t give any thought to
advanced users. I know that I can type faster than I can move a mouse,
why don&amp;#8217;t you let me use that? More importantly, why didn&amp;#8217;t Microsoft
ever think that people would use computers on a network? When I
installed Solaris, I wanted to edit a config file. I hadn&amp;#8217;t customized
&lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; yet, hadn&amp;#8217;t installed any other software, nothing. Yet, I
was able to open up a terminal and grab my .emacs file from my laptop in
one line&amp;nbsp;(scp).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be totally honest, the question running through my mind is something
like &amp;#8220;everything is so much quicker on Linux. How do experts deal with&amp;nbsp;Windows?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2007 13:22:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-09-28:2007/09/nix/</guid><category>Digg</category><category>Eric S Raymond</category><category>linux</category><category>solaris</category><category>sun</category><category>Unix</category></item><item><title>Sun, Solaris, other fun stuff</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/09/sun-solaris-other-fun-stuff/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A few bits of news, none of them too&amp;nbsp;important:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve just been hired as the Sun Microsystems Campus Ambassador for
Rutgers University. Essentially, my job is to tell students, faculty,
staff, and researchers about Sun&amp;#8217;s open source technologies and what
they can do. This involves giving some tech demos and talks, some
networking, and completing a lot of training on my part. Hopefully also
getting to hand out some neat Sun swag around campus. I have to admit,
I&amp;#8217;ve never been a real fan of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; IDEs - I do pretty much all of my
development (admittedly, very little in Java, most of my work is simple
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; stuff) on Emacs. That being said, I&amp;#8217;m really pyched about trying
some new stuff like &lt;span class="caps"&gt;J2EE&lt;/span&gt; and maybe some Ruby. However, I also looked
over some of our training materials on the upcoming
&lt;a href="http://www.netbeans.org/"&gt;NetBean&lt;/a&gt;s 6.0, and truthfully, I&amp;#8217;m damn
interested. I haven&amp;#8217;t used a Java &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IDE&lt;/span&gt; since three years ago in high
school, and it looks as though they&amp;#8217;ve come a very long&amp;nbsp;way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m also really getting into Solaris. The new
&lt;a href="http://www.opensolaris.org"&gt;openSolaris&lt;/a&gt; / Solaris Express releases
have a lot of great features - and I can&amp;#8217;t want to get my hands on a
machine running Zones, Containers, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ZFS&lt;/span&gt;, just to mention a few
technologies. I setup Solaris 10 on one of my work computers, and I&amp;#8217;m
hooked. It&amp;#8217;s fine for a desktop, but I can honestly say that after a few
minutes playing around with the Solaris Management Console, I&amp;#8217;m
seriously considering ditching SuSE (now OpenSuSE) which I&amp;#8217;ve been using
as a server &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; for some 7 years, and switching over to&amp;nbsp;Solaris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Solaris is really an enterprise &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;. That means it has
loads of wonderful features that are also rock-solid, and was designed
with the idea of centrally-administered servers in mind - something that
SuSE only caught onto recently. However, that also means that it is
intended to run on what I would call &amp;#8220;new&amp;#8221; hardware. In other words,
don&amp;#8217;t look to put Solaris 10 or Solaris Express (openSolaris / Solaris
11) on your 386. And if you&amp;#8217;re like me and running something along the
lines of a Generation 1 Compaq Proliant &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ML370&lt;/span&gt; with a 2nd-generation
SmartArray &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAID&lt;/span&gt; controller (a system that was made about 10 years ago),
you might have some issues. It appears that the &amp;#8216;smartii&amp;#8217; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAID&lt;/span&gt; driver
(and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EISA&lt;/span&gt; support) was removed from Solaris 10 in 6/06. The solution?
I&amp;#8217;m going to be looking into buying a bunch of new systems, possibly
Dell PowerEdge servers and, if I can get the cash, a few Sun&amp;nbsp;systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, within the week, I&amp;#8217;ll be setting up a blog at
&lt;a href="http://blogs.sun.com"&gt;blogs.sun.com&lt;/a&gt;. This will probably contain a lot
of Rutgers-specific information, but will also most definitely include
my notes on Sun products, and a healthy amount of Solaris-related&amp;nbsp;information.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2007 14:36:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-09-26:2007/09/sun-solaris-other-fun-stuff/</guid><category>solaris</category><category>sun</category></item></channel></rss>