<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/spectrum.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2008 12:13:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Where are we going and what’s with the handbasket?</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/04/where-are-we-going-and-whats-with-the-handbasket/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;#8217;s it. Not only did Verizon and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AT&lt;/span&gt;&amp;amp;T come out on top in the
&lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2008/03/20/fcc-releases-700mhz-auction-details-verizon-atandt-big-winners/"&gt;700MHz spectrum
auction&lt;/a&gt;
- promising an end to hopes of Google&amp;#8217;s utopian ideals of a truly open
network - but I just heard that &amp;#8220;Office Open &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221; &lt;a href="http://www.iso.org/iso/pressrelease.htm?refid=Ref1123"&gt;was approved as an
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; standard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think it even merits comment on my part. The world is run by
corporations. Corporations with more money than brains, hopes, or balls.
The 700MHz spectrum will become another copy of what American has now -
a resource (frequencies) that are &amp;#8220;owned by the people&amp;#8221;, yet controlled
by major corporations, and horribly biased
&lt;em&gt;against&lt;/em&gt; the interests of the&amp;nbsp;consumer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt; is now a standard. Is it any less flawed? No. Is it any
safer for me to implement? No. Does it even contain enough information
for me to implement? No. But it&amp;#8217;s a specification, and it&amp;#8217;s here. While
Jason Matusow may have stated that &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/jasonmatusow/archive/2008/02/26/open-xml-brm-day-2-thoughts.aspx"&gt;the patents related to the
technology are not a barrier to use - for anyone, in any country, for
all
time&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;,
I&amp;#8217;m still a bit worried about the issues that will crop up with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOXML&lt;/span&gt; -
not to mention the fact that it&amp;#8217;s a standard squarely aimed at
eliminating choice (we all know Microsoft will push hard for
organizations not to use &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ODF&lt;/span&gt;) and preventing competition in a sector
already overwhelmingly dominated by &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, what happened in the past few weeks? A confirmation that the
governments and organizations of the world care little about the
individual, and fear change. They&amp;#8217;re owned by big business, and the
700MHz spectrum will end up being, at best, a marginal improvement over
the current restrictive cellular system. And big business doesn&amp;#8217;t even
have the balls to fight for itself. Or, even worse, doesn&amp;#8217;t worry about
vendor lock-in or proprietary software because, as long as they keep
bending over backwards to follow Microsoft&amp;#8217;s every whim, Microsoft will
always be there to help&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m surprised that even multinational corporations, who have a data
center filled with redundant systems, and fiber running in every
direction in case this or that &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CO&lt;/span&gt; goes up in flames, doesn&amp;#8217;t consider
closed standards, proprietary (possibly patent-encumbered) software, or
closed-source software to be as obvious a single point of failure as a
critical service running on a single desktop computer. Sure, your vendor
might tell you their software will achieve five-nines. But if they
discontinue support, or have a few bad quarters, and they won&amp;#8217;t fix it
for you, what&amp;nbsp;then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m just thankful that there are &lt;a href="http://blogs.sun.com/jonathan/"&gt;some
people&lt;/a&gt;, few and far between, that don&amp;#8217;t
fall into the&amp;nbsp;trap.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2008 12:13:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-04-02:2008/04/where-are-we-going-and-whats-with-the-handbasket/</guid><category>700mhz</category><category>microsoft</category><category>ooxml</category><category>spectrum</category></item></channel></rss>