<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog - standards</title><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/standards.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2009-06-22T23:48:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Please Don’t resize my browser</title><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/06/please-dont-resize-my-browser/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-06-22T23:48:00-04:00</published><updated>2009-06-22T23:48:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-06-22:/2009/06/please-dont-resize-my-browser/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It always amazes me to see how much &amp;#8220;old school&amp;#8221; web design practice is
still out there. I&amp;#8217;m talking about commercial sites (not MySpace pages)
that blatantly ignore web standards about both content and user
experience. This isn&amp;#8217;t just a Linux thing, though some aspect of it
certainly …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It always amazes me to see how much &amp;#8220;old school&amp;#8221; web design practice is
still out there. I&amp;#8217;m talking about commercial sites (not MySpace pages)
that blatantly ignore web standards about both content and user
experience. This isn&amp;#8217;t just a Linux thing, though some aspect of it
certainly is. The web site of my home town,
&lt;a href="http://www.mpnj.com"&gt;mpnj.com&lt;/a&gt; uses a Flash-based navigation menu that
even the official, proprietary Flash player for Linux won&amp;#8217;t support -
the transparency renders as white, obscuring the text beneath the fully
extended size of the menu. I emailed the developer about this on the
launch day, and was told in no uncertain terms that - despite the fact
that he had a fully-functional alternate version - Linux wasn&amp;#8217;t
important enough to fix the site. Ironically for a town government web
page, it also doesn&amp;#8217;t incorporate any accessibility features, which
seems to be standard for most of these poor&amp;nbsp;designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still countless large news sites whose Flash-based video
players won&amp;#8217;t run under Linux, and even CitiBank&amp;#8217;s credit card site has
a flash ad that plays incorrectly under&amp;nbsp;Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real pain that I happened to see today was a company who uses
coupons.com to allow customers to print out retail coupons. My first
surprise was that to print the coupons, you have to download Windows or
Mac software. I&amp;#8217;m not quite sure how many people will do this, but it&amp;#8217;s
probably how viruses spread so quickly (people who will download
anything that claims to get them half a dollar off of a roll of toilet
paper, or whatever the coupons are for). So, that&amp;#8217;s not cool - most
coupons I&amp;#8217;ve gotten were just &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; emails or PDFs. If their thinking is
to control the distribution (they make some comment about a &amp;#8220;paper-based
printer, not a fax or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt; creator&amp;#8221;), they&amp;#8217;ve obviously forgotten about
photocopy machines and scanners, let alone capturing the spool file on&amp;nbsp;Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More striking, however, was the shock of opening their help page. My
primary monitor is a 24&amp;#8221; widescreen, and I generally keep a browser
window occupying half the screen width and a terminal next to it. Once I
opened their &amp;#8220;help&amp;#8221; site, it promptly resized my browser window to a
tiny&amp;nbsp;640x480!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This problem, unfortunately, isn&amp;#8217;t as rare as it should be. There are
still sites that force browser size, disable right clicks (I hadn&amp;#8217;t seen
that since about 2004 until a few weeks ago&amp;#8230; obviously someone who&amp;#8217;s
never used `wget`) or have a page that doesn&amp;#8217;t fully work in FireFox
on any platform. Even worse, my personal pet peeve (as at the time of
writing this I have about 50+ tabs open in Firefox, and it&amp;#8217;s only using
a small sliver of my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;2GB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt;) is sites that don&amp;#8217;t play well with tabbed
browsing - either using only JavaScript for &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; navigation links, or
opening all links (site-wide) in the same tab/window. I don&amp;#8217;t know how
many web sites have lost my business because of this. Or the one I know
of that starts a new shopping cart for every tab opened (so if I open
each product I want to buy in a new tab, when I add them all to the
cart, it ends up with only&amp;nbsp;one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know how there can be anyone out there who&amp;#8217;s still not using
valid &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XHTML&lt;/span&gt; with all of the accessibility features for anything new,
especially a commercial site. But even more so, how can there still be
people designing web sites who disregard the golden rule of web design:
&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t mess with someone&amp;#8217;s browser.&lt;/strong&gt; Leave things like where to open
the link and how big to make the browser to the user. If they&amp;#8217;re not
technically literate, changing what &amp;#8220;usually happens&amp;#8221; will just confuse
them. If they&amp;#8217;re well-versed in how to use a web browser, like me,
they&amp;#8217;ll just get aggravated by having someone else change their workflow
(I doubt the guys who designed those sites would like it if I told them
they had to design the whole thing in Emacs). If they&amp;#8217;re somewhere in
the middle (just found Ctrl+click in Firefox), you&amp;#8217;ll confuse them. And
God forbid they&amp;#8217;re blind and using a page reader&amp;#8230; good luck with
JavaScript or Flash&amp;nbsp;navigation.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="design"></category><category term="standards"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>Finally - CSS for Printing</title><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/2008/10/finally-css-for-printing/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-10-27T17:55:00-04:00</published><updated>2008-10-27T17:55:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2008-10-27:/2008/10/finally-css-for-printing/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It seems like it&amp;#8217;s taken forever. I don&amp;#8217;t know how many times I&amp;#8217;ve
struggled with web apps that I wrote for the &lt;a href="http://www.midlandparkambulance.com"&gt;ambulance
corps&lt;/a&gt; to try and get printed
output correct. I&amp;#8217;ve done everything from generating PDFs, doing screen
captures of a browser and printing as …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It seems like it&amp;#8217;s taken forever. I don&amp;#8217;t know how many times I&amp;#8217;ve
struggled with web apps that I wrote for the &lt;a href="http://www.midlandparkambulance.com"&gt;ambulance
corps&lt;/a&gt; to try and get printed
output correct. I&amp;#8217;ve done everything from generating PDFs, doing screen
captures of a browser and printing as a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;, to things as crazy as
trying to print schedules directly from the server, where they&amp;#8217;re setup
as&amp;nbsp;postscript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just happened to be going through my news in &lt;a href="http://reader.google.com"&gt;Google
Reader&lt;/a&gt; and found some interesting &lt;span class="caps"&gt;W3C&lt;/span&gt; draft
standards for &lt;a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/css-print/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt; Print Profiles&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-page/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS3&lt;/span&gt; Paged Media Module&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Finally&lt;/em&gt;,
after waiting for literally years, there will (from the way it looks) be
a way for me to specify, in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;, the page size - and more importantly,
orientation - and have something print&amp;nbsp;correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the end of me having to manually print ambulance corps rosters,
and then set the print settings back to landscape and 73% scaling for
the schedule, are finally going to be&amp;nbsp;over!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C&amp;#8217;mon, Mozilla, I&amp;#8217;m counting on a quick implementation once they&amp;#8217;re&amp;nbsp;finalized.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="css"></category><category term="printing"></category><category term="standards"></category><category term="w3c"></category></entry><entry><title>PCpro UK: Boycott ad-blocking Firefox, urges furious web designer</title><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/2007/09/pcpro-uk-boycott-ad-blocking-firefox-urges-furious-web-designer/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-09-17T14:04:00-04:00</published><updated>2007-09-17T14:04:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2007-09-17:/2007/09/pcpro-uk-boycott-ad-blocking-firefox-urges-furious-web-designer/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When browsing through &lt;a href="http://digg.com/"&gt;Digg&lt;/a&gt; this morning, I came by a
story at PCpro &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt; entitled &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://www.pcpro.co.uk/news/news/124719/"&gt;Boycott ad-blocking Firefox, urges furious
web designer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;. This gentleman
stated that, &amp;#8220;Software that
blocks all advertisement is an infringement of the rights of website
owners and&amp;nbsp;developers.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I don&amp;#8217;t like giving press to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When browsing through &lt;a href="http://digg.com/"&gt;Digg&lt;/a&gt; this morning, I came by a
story at PCpro &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt; entitled &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://www.pcpro.co.uk/news/news/124719/"&gt;Boycott ad-blocking Firefox, urges furious
web designer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;. This gentleman
stated that, &amp;#8220;Software that
blocks all advertisement is an infringement of the rights of website
owners and&amp;nbsp;developers.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I don&amp;#8217;t like giving press to such a story, I found it alarming on
many&amp;nbsp;levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I&amp;#8217;ve never heard of rights of website owners and developers.
Being a &amp;#8220;website owner and developer&amp;#8221; myself, I understand that the web
is a dynamic medium. Moreover, I think of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; as what it is - a markup
language. It just tells a program (browser) how to display something in
a user-friendly style. I test my pages with Lynx, and expect them to
conform to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;/1.1. In other words, I believe that the Internet is an
information distribution tool. I expect, I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt;, my content to be
viewable by as many people as possible. I try to use simple markup and
make use of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ALT&lt;/span&gt; tags so that as many people as possible will be able to
view the content. I want it to make sense on as many platforms as
possible. I want people who need accessibility aids to be able to
understand it. In short, I want my content to reach as many people as&amp;nbsp;possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only is this developer trying to do something which is ignorant and
a case of being a flat-out bad citizen of the &amp;#8216;net, but he is trying to
fight against the progress which has so painstakingly been made in the
field of web standardization. I well remember when, not long ago at all,
I was handicapped by my choice of using Firefox. I still come by the odd
site which chose to use a component which is tied to Internet Explorer,
thereby alienating 35% of web&amp;nbsp;users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will admit that I am by no means the typical Internet user. The fact
that all of my some dozen or so machines (excepting one which I need to
use a legacy &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCSI&lt;/span&gt; flatbed scanner) run 100% Free/Open Source software. I
use Linux. OpenSolaris. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BSD&lt;/span&gt;. I believe that I have a right to examine
and modify the source code of the programs that I use. When choosing a
bug tracking system, I spent hours customizing an open-source
alternative because I was unwilling to use the closed-source option
which seemed to fit best. Therefore, I guess it is easy to understand
that I refuse to buy from, or even visit, a web site that doesn&amp;#8217;t
support&amp;nbsp;Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a browser war. This is not me simply deciding to flame
someone who isn&amp;#8217;t a F/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt; zealot. This boils down to a deeper issue that
can be seen all around us - including in the recent news surrounding the
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FCC&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s auction of a portion of the 700MHz spectrum. The issue at hand
is the complacency of technology users, and the feeling by technology
providers that they can push anything they want on users. The concept
that providers are sending data to me, and that I can use that data
however I want (within the extent of the law) is getting&amp;nbsp;lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I watch &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;, I used to leave the room or pick up a book when a
commercial comes on. Now that I have a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PVR&lt;/span&gt; (specifically, MythTV), I can
record the shows I want, and then have commercials flagged for automatic
skipping before I watch them. When I decide to watch them, I have no
commercials. When I use the web, I select the content that I want. If I
don&amp;#8217;t want it, I don&amp;#8217;t get&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, another large issue at hand is the simple nature of digital
media. This applies to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; recording, music and movie sharing, software
piracy, etc. Digital media is not the same as analog media. An &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MP3&lt;/span&gt; (or,
for that matter, a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt;) is not the same as a tape. In product litigation,
there is a term known as &amp;#8220;perceived use&amp;#8221;. If you make a glass coffee
table that is exactly at knee height, it is perceived that eventually,
someone will try to sit on it. That&amp;#8217;s common sense. If it shatters and
kills them, it was your responsibility to foresee such an obvious
eventuality. It&amp;#8217;s only common sense that if something is flat and at
normal sitting level, someone will try to sit on&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, I would argue that when any content is distributed digitally,
you must foresee that it will be copied or altered. It is simply the
nature of the medium. If the recording industry didn&amp;#8217;t want people
ripping music from CDs, they should have kept releasing things on tape.
Even more so with DVDs - I&amp;#8217;m sure we all remember the push. Five years
ago, I was hard pressed to find a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt; in a local rental store. Today, I
haven&amp;#8217;t seen a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHS&lt;/span&gt; tape in years. The industry *pushed* the format on
us, and is now complaining when we use it in a brutally obvious way. If
I had to liken it to any legal phenomenon, I would pick entrapment. It&amp;#8217;s
not a far stretch to compare the recording industry&amp;#8217;s actions to those
of a police officer who leaves a car running, with the keys in the
ignition, and a sign on the windshield that says &amp;#8220;Take me for a spin
around the parking lot&amp;#8221; and then arrests someone for auto theft when
they leave the lot. If they industry is worried about piracy, it should
have been their obligation to look into exactly how easy piracy would
be, before they chose a distribution&amp;nbsp;medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In closing my rant, I will ask a few simple&amp;nbsp;questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it that the law, being as biased to corporate interests (and
against the individual) as it is, doesn&amp;#8217;t recognize the rights of the
individual to use what they legally purchased in a way that they see
fit? (i.e. if I buy a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt;, I should be able to make a backup copy on my
computer - even the &lt;em&gt;copyright law&lt;/em&gt; states&amp;nbsp;that).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How long will it be before someone turns up an internal &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RIAA&lt;/span&gt; memo
from ten years ago stating that the industry could increase its&amp;#8217; profits
by releasing music on a medium (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt;) that is prone to piracy, and then
fining the people who exploit that common&amp;nbsp;sense?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When they came out with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VHS&lt;/span&gt; recorders, the industry was up in arms
about piracy. So, they got together and added a small amount on the
price of every blank tape, intended to reimburse the
labels/artists/networks for the copy that it would be used to make. Why
can&amp;#8217;t they just tack $3 onto every blank &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CD&lt;/span&gt;, $20 on every blank
hard drive, and stop suing college&amp;nbsp;kids?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="ad blocker"></category><category term="firefox"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="standards"></category></entry></feed>