<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog - stats</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/stats.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2012-03-17T11:48:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Some Thoughts on Choosing a New Wordpress Theme</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/03/some-thoughts-on-choosing-a-new-wordpress-theme/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-03-17T11:48:00-04:00</published><updated>2012-03-17T11:48:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-03-17:/2012/03/some-thoughts-on-choosing-a-new-wordpress-theme/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;#8217;m going to choose a new theme for my blog. The current theme
is &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/themes/inove"&gt;iNove&lt;/a&gt; (albeit an older
version with some custom modifications), and I feel like it looks a bit
messy and has gotten a bit cluttered, so it&amp;#8217;s time to find something
new. I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;#8217;m going to choose a new theme for my blog. The current theme
is &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/themes/inove"&gt;iNove&lt;/a&gt; (albeit an older
version with some custom modifications), and I feel like it looks a bit
messy and has gotten a bit cluttered, so it&amp;#8217;s time to find something
new. I like the 2-column layout, and have a few other things I&amp;#8217;m looking
for - specifically, aside from something with advanced features like
lots of widget support and hooks, something that has good visual
separation between different posts and widgets. I also really want
something, if possible, with relative column widths. My current home and
work desktops both have dual monitors, and the minimum resolution I have
on one screen is 1920x1080. When I look at my blog in a maximized
window, about half the screen width is wasted with empty space. So,
ideally, I&amp;#8217;d like a theme that&amp;#8217;s based on relative widths, probably with
a &amp;#8220;min-width&amp;#8221; property so it wouldn&amp;#8217;t get compressed to an absurdly
narrow width on small&amp;nbsp;screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/"&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt; (as noted in
the &lt;a href="/privacy-policy/"&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;) for visitor statistics on this
blog (more about that in a moment). So, I took a peek at the breakdown
of visitors by screen resolution, and saw that for the past year, 94% of
the 27,500 visits had a screen width of 1024px or more (and the majority
of the others looked like mobile device resolutions, so they&amp;#8217;d probably
zoom the page correctly). So, my first gut reaction was to assume that I
could use a theme approximately 1000px wide. Unfortunately, there&amp;#8217;s two
main problems with that: first, as mentioned by &lt;a href="http://css-tricks.com/screen-resolution-notequalto-browser-window/"&gt;Chris Coyier on
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;-Tricks.com&lt;/a&gt;,
just because someone has a given screen resolution doesn&amp;#8217;t mean their
browser window (let alone the viewport) is that size. As a matter of
fact, I usually have my main browser window set at about 80% of the
width of one of my monitors, with my instant messaging client
&lt;a href="http://pidgin.im/"&gt;Pidgin&lt;/a&gt; taking up the rest of the space. So there&amp;#8217;s
one inaccuracy. There&amp;#8217;s a potentially much greater inaccuracy in my
stats as well, which I&amp;#8217;m going to discuss in a &lt;a href="/2012/03/inaccuracies-in-google-analytics-for-website-stats/"&gt;separate
post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="analysis"></category><category term="analytics"></category><category term="blog"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="logging"></category><category term="stats"></category><category term="theme"></category><category term="wordpress"></category></entry><entry><title>Inaccuracies in Google Analytics for Website Stats</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/03/inaccuracies-in-google-analytics-for-website-stats/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-03-17T11:46:00-04:00</published><updated>2012-03-17T11:46:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-03-17:/2012/03/inaccuracies-in-google-analytics-for-website-stats/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I use Google Analytics for visitor stats on this blog. Not because I&amp;#8217;m
trying to direct-market to my readers or become Big Brother, but for a
number of simple&amp;nbsp;reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#8217;s simple - no software for me to update, and nothing that needs
    to run on my server and …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I use Google Analytics for visitor stats on this blog. Not because I&amp;#8217;m
trying to direct-market to my readers or become Big Brother, but for a
number of simple&amp;nbsp;reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#8217;s simple - no software for me to update, and nothing that needs
    to run on my server and read through giant log files every night.
    Google does it all for&amp;nbsp;me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gives a lot more information than I can get from just web server&amp;nbsp;logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because of Google&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;big brother&amp;#8221; tracking, and the vast number of
    sites that they track people on, I can tell things I&amp;#8217;d have no other
    way of knowing, like how long someone stayed on my&amp;nbsp;page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They tell me &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt; stats like which search keywords brought the
    most people to my site and which posts are the most popular, which I
    keep in mind when writing new stuff and updating older&amp;nbsp;posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They tell me information about client operating system and browser
    version, which I think tells quite a bit about my&amp;nbsp;audience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As far as I know, they&amp;#8217;re pretty good at filtering out anything
    other than an actual human&amp;nbsp;visitor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They tell me stats that have no real use to me, but are just cook -
    like what countries my visitors are from, what type of Internet
    connection they&amp;#8217;re on, their screen resolution,&amp;nbsp;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously not for google, but for me, all of these stats are totally
anonymous - I just get percentages or numbers of visits, it&amp;#8217;s not like I
can see all of the details per-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; address. The most important aspect to
me is just the ease of use - I sign up and put a little snippet of code
on my pages, and I get an amazing dashboard interface with all of this
information. Nothing to install and update on my server, and (most
importantly, since I&amp;#8217;m now running everything of mine on one virtualized
server) no massive program to run as a cron job that has to read all my
server log&amp;nbsp;files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I was talking with a couple of my co-workers, specifically
about the stats that I get from Google Analytics. While I know it&amp;#8217;s not
uncommon to run &lt;a href="http://noscript.net/"&gt;NoScript&lt;/a&gt; especially among the
more security- and privacy-conscious groups of people, I was a bit
disturbed to hear that they all block Google&amp;#8217;s tracking code in their
browsers via NoScript. I assume there&amp;#8217;s also a percentage of people who
still just turn off JavaScript alltogether (although I can&amp;#8217;t imagine how
they use the modern Web), and many who use the &lt;a href="http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en"&gt;Google Analytics
Opt-Out&lt;/a&gt; feature. So,
especially with as technical an audience as I have, I guess that means
I&amp;#8217;m likely missing a large number of visitors in my stats. On one hand,
I want to respect the privacy of my visitors, and respect their desire
to opt-out of advanced tracking. On the other hand, since I no longer
parse web server logs for statistics, these privacy-conscious visitors
aren&amp;#8217;t even showing up in what I think of as my monthly visit count, or
in my information on what posts and search keywords are most popular,
which I only use for &amp;#8220;good&amp;#8221; purposes - to make my blog more useful. So
that&amp;#8217;s a bit of a&amp;nbsp;conundrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll admit that I do run &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/adsense/"&gt;Google AdSense
Ads&lt;/a&gt; on my blog, and I&amp;#8217;m sure there are
some people who block the ads. On one hand, that upsets me a bit; I run
this blog to try and share information that I find or learn with others,
and the hosting costs aren&amp;#8217;t insignificant. If I can get paid to just
show some ads, to try and help offset the cost of running the site, I
think that&amp;#8217;s good. And if other people can help support the site by just
letting the ads stay on the page, why not? On the other hand, my hosting
costs $50/month (granted the server also handles all of my email, and a
&lt;em&gt;whole bunch&lt;/em&gt; of other sites). I&amp;#8217;ve been participating in Google AdSense
since March 5, 2010 (two years and two weeks), and my &amp;#8220;estimated
earnings&amp;#8221; are currently $80. The payout is in $100 increments. So, I
haven&amp;#8217;t seen a cent from it in two years, so I&amp;#8217;ve given up being
concerned with it. If you want to be nice, and find my posts
interesting, click on one of the ads. Unfortunately, unless I get
famous, the ads aren&amp;#8217;t going to come close to offsetting even part of
the cost of running the&amp;nbsp;site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google itself
&lt;a href="http://support.google.com/googleanalytics/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=55610"&gt;says&lt;/a&gt;,
&amp;#8220;In order for Google Analytics to record a visit, the visitor must have
JavaScript, images, and cookies enabled for your website.&amp;#8221; There seems
to be some buzz about this on the &amp;#8216;net, and I&amp;#8217;ve seen
&lt;a href="http://garmahis.com/tips/google-analytics/#use-Google-Analytics-without-JavaScript"&gt;a&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://djangosnippets.org/snippets/2338/"&gt;number&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://translate.google.com/translate?hl=en&amp;amp;sl=nl&amp;amp;u=http://andrescholten.nl/google-analytics-zonder-javascript/"&gt;of&lt;/a&gt;
(translated; &lt;a href="http://andrescholten.nl/google-analytics-zonder-javascript/"&gt;original post in
Dutch&lt;/a&gt;)
posts advocating building a request to a Google Analytics &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GIF&lt;/span&gt; manually
on the server side, and then including it as an image element inside a
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;noscript&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag in the page. While this is probably one of the nicer
solutions (and much more likely to reduce double-counting), it doesn&amp;#8217;t
capture any of the advanced data (screen resolution, etc.) that
JavaScript-based Analytics does, and more importantly, I imagine that
many of the Ad blocking extensions also block traffic to
google-analytics.com, so this is an incremental improvement at best.
There are also
&lt;a href="http://www.vdgraaf.info/google-analytics-without-javascript.html"&gt;quite&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://blog.datalicious.com/google-analytics-without-javascript-rss-xml-e"&gt;a&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://blogs.walkerart.org/newmedia/2009/11/12/building-walkers-mobile-site-google-analytics-without-javascript-pt2/"&gt;few&lt;/a&gt;
posts about how to make a request to Analytics purely server-side. This
has a few disadvantages as well; it bypasses the google domain
blacklisting problem that the client-side image has, but it also means
you lose the client &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; address (and therefore geolocation), and that you
double-track any user who allows javascript (so you need a separate
profile, and then need to average out the results). It also means that
you track every search engine and bot that crawls your site, and
possibly every person who clicks a link and then hits &amp;#8220;back&amp;#8221; before the
page finishes loading. I found another blogger who &lt;a href="http://www.realityburst.com/battle-of-the-inaccuracies-how-accurate-is-google-analyticsawstatsstatpress"&gt;commented
about&lt;/a&gt;
the wide disparity he saw between Google Analytics, the
&lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/statpress/"&gt;StatsPress&lt;/a&gt; WordPress
plugin, and &lt;a href="http://awstats.sourceforge.net/"&gt;AWstats&lt;/a&gt; (a server-side
log file&amp;nbsp;analyzer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what&amp;#8217;s the&amp;nbsp;solution?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the options have a down side, but I&amp;#8217;m looking for something
that&amp;#8217;s the best I can reasonably do. As much as I&amp;#8217;d rather not, I&amp;#8217;m
going to look into self-hosted alternatives to Google Analytics (a
self-hosted JavaScript-based stats provider), in the hopes that NoScript
users will be more friendly to scripts coming from my own domain, and
sending requests to my own domain, than ones from Google or other major
trackers. I don&amp;#8217;t think I want to try anything that parses web server
logs as a primary approach, as I don&amp;#8217;t think I could ever get a
meaningful comparison to Google Analytics or something else&amp;nbsp;JavaScript-based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did have one other idea which I think is interesting, though a bit of
an overhead. I could have Apache (or, more likely, a Perl script called
in the Apache configuration) generate a random string for each request,
and save it in an Apache environment variable. The environment variable
would then be added to a field in the server logs, and also added (via
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; or whatever else generates the pages server-side) as a custom
parameter for the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JS&lt;/span&gt; tracking code, enabling page hits to be correlated
between the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JS&lt;/span&gt; tracking and the server logs. Assuming the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JS&lt;/span&gt; tacking
backend stores its data in a sane format (and as raw data, not just
aggregated), and at the cost of a serious performance penalty, a
server-side statistics program like
&lt;a href="http://awstats.sourceforge.net/"&gt;AWstats&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href="http://www.webalizer.org/"&gt;Webalizer&lt;/a&gt; could be patched to lookup the
unique identifier in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JS&lt;/span&gt; stats data store, and ignore all hits which
were tracked that&amp;nbsp;way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m going to start by looking into self-hosted open source alternatives
to Google Analytics, which I&amp;#8217;ll post about sometime hopefully&amp;nbsp;soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="analytics"></category><category term="google"></category><category term="logging"></category><category term="statistics"></category><category term="stats"></category></entry></feed>