<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/support.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2009-02-25T11:07:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>ROUThost DNS problems; GoDaddy and Security through Obscurity</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/02/routhost-dns-problems-godaddy-and-security-through-obscurity/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-02-25T11:07:00-05:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-02-25:2009/02/routhost-dns-problems-godaddy-and-security-through-obscurity/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The external-facing web site and (internal use) mailing list for the
&lt;a href="http://www.midlandparkambulance.com"&gt;ambulance corps&lt;/a&gt; is hosted by
&lt;a href="http://www.routhost.com"&gt;ROUThost&lt;/a&gt;. Not my choice, it was inherited.
ROUThost, first off, appears to be a fly-by-night hosting provider that
just buys a few boxes in a colo facility. I should have known to raise a
stink when they say you need to fax a copy of your driver&amp;#8217;s license to
get &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; turned on, and that you have to agree - in legalese - not to
mess with anyone else&amp;#8217;s configs. Well, last night, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt; for the site went
down. As in nothing, wouldn&amp;#8217;t resolve at all. I submitted a ticket
online for ROUThost&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;24x7&amp;#8221; support - by the way, they don&amp;#8217;t have a
phone number, only an online ticket form. After 2h 34m 40s of downtime,
the issue resolved itself and I downgraded the ticket from &amp;#8220;critical&amp;#8221; to
medium. Now, 11 hours later, it still hasn&amp;#8217;t been replied to. And my
emails to support and management - 2 hours ago - are&amp;nbsp;unanswered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the problem started, I knew the yearly contract with ROUThost was a
bad idea - even at $35/year &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USD&lt;/span&gt;. So, given the great experience I&amp;#8217;ve had
with them as registrar for my myriad domains, I took a look at
&lt;a href="http://www.godaddy.com"&gt;GoDaddy&amp;#8217;s Site&lt;/a&gt;. They offer shared
hosting at around $4/month (for shared on a Linux box) and are currently
offering some deals, so I figured it would be a good idea. I know and
trust GoDaddy&amp;#8217;s support, and have had an account with them for &lt;em&gt;quite
some time&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ambulance corp&amp;#8217;s web site, hosted through ROUThost, does essentially
three things; provide a minimal web presence (the whole web root is
probably &amp;lt; 1Mb minus the photo albums), five e-mail forwarders for the
officers and a &lt;a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/mailman/index.html"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GNU&lt;/span&gt;
MailMan&lt;/a&gt; mailing list
for internal business. Unfortunately, I couldn&amp;#8217;t find anything in their
&amp;#8220;features&amp;#8221; list mentioning MialMan or any other listserv, or even what
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MTA&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDA&lt;/span&gt; they&amp;nbsp;run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put a call in to GoDaddy &amp;#8220;Sales/Support&amp;#8221;. The poor guy had never heard
of MailMan, but asked &amp;#8220;one of the hosting guys&amp;#8221; and was told it would
only be supported on dedicate hosting accounts. Not exactly financially
feasible for a mailing list with 30 subscribers, maybe 2 messages a day,
and a monthly &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt; transfer of under 20Mb. I was told their shared
hosting packages don&amp;#8217;t include any mailing list/listserv software,
though they include every &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CMS&lt;/span&gt; and language known to man. Hell-bent to
get away from ROUThost, I then asked if they ran an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDA&lt;/span&gt; that supported
piping mail to a command, as can be done with .procmailrc. After a brief
hold (not to sound cynical, but I&amp;#8217;m sure the gentleman was looking up
&amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDA&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221;) he came back on the line and told me they didn&amp;#8217;t. I then switched
to problem-solving mode and asked what &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MTA&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDA&lt;/span&gt; they were running.
Another brief hold, and I was told &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;I can&amp;#8217;t tell you that&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;. Speechless
for a moment, I asked what that meant; &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;we don&amp;#8217;t give out that
information&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;. Just about ready to begin explaining &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMTP&lt;/span&gt; headers, I gave
up and thanked him for his&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, so Sales probably doesn&amp;#8217;t understand &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMTP&lt;/span&gt; headers. I&amp;#8217;d considered
trying to find mail from a GoDaddy Linux hosted box and check the
headers, but I figured I couldn&amp;#8217;t do that before the call ended. So, now
I&amp;#8217;m left with a dilemma. ROUThost is not, in my opinion, reliable, and
their support is flat-out nonexistent. 11 hours is far too long to wait
for a reply to a &amp;#8220;critical&amp;#8221; ticket when someone claims 24x7 support.
However, by previous experience, GoDaddy would be my next choice - but
not only do they ot support mailing lists - arguably the most used
feature of our current hosted account - but they won&amp;#8217;t even tell a
customer what &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MTA&lt;/span&gt; they&amp;#8217;re running. I&amp;#8217;m too let down by this to telnet 25
on one of their boxes and see what&amp;nbsp;happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;#8217;s left? I guess waiting until (hopefully some time within the
next few weeks) I upgrade to Optimum static &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; at home, and consider
running it all there (and hope mains power never goes out for more than
30&amp;nbsp;minutes?)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="dns"></category><category term="godaddy"></category><category term="hosting"></category><category term="routhost"></category><category term="security through obscurity"></category><category term="support"></category></entry></feed>