<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog - survey</title><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/survey.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2018-11-01T18:07:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Open Source WiFi Site Survey Heatmap Tool</title><link href="https://blog.jasonantman.com/2018/11/open-source-wifi-site-survey-tool/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-01T18:07:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-11-01T18:07:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Jason Antman</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2018-11-01:/2018/11/open-source-wifi-site-survey-tool/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A bit about a Python project I wrote to plot floorplan heatmaps of wireless site&amp;nbsp;surveys.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I finally bought myself a new wireless access point (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AP&lt;/span&gt;) to replace my current ones, a pair of older Ubiquiti models that have been continually in service without issue for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/j_antman/status/1029135879695228929"&gt;nine years&lt;/a&gt; and five years, respectively. I bought another Ubiquiti, of course, but wanted to be a bit more methodical and scientific in figuring out the best placement of it in my&amp;nbsp;house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years ago when part of my job was supporting an extremely large wireless network, we used some expensive proprietary Windows software (I&amp;#8217;m pretty sure it was &lt;a href="https://www.ekahau.com/products/ekahau-site-survey/overview/"&gt;Ekahau Site Survey&lt;/a&gt;) for performing site surveys to
determine &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AP&lt;/span&gt; location. Essentially you temporarily rig up a running &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AP&lt;/span&gt; where you propose locating one, load a floorplan of the building into the site survey software, and then walk around the area tapping on the floorplan at your current location. At each tap, the software performs some measurements through the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AP&lt;/span&gt; (I don&amp;#8217;t remember what the specific software we used did, but generally it&amp;#8217;s some bandwidth measurement like &lt;a href="https://software.es.net/iperf/"&gt;iperf&lt;/a&gt;) and ends up plotting a (predictive, interpolated) heatmap of signal strength or data transfer speeds over the&amp;nbsp;floorplan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to do something similar for my new &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AP&lt;/span&gt;, but was rather surprised that I couldn&amp;#8217;t find any existing F/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSS&lt;/span&gt; solution; only a handful of proprietary options costing anywhere from &amp;#8220;more than I&amp;#8217;d pay for a one-time thing&amp;#8221; to astronomical prices, and none of them clearly with Linux support. The closest I was able to find - and I&amp;#8217;m very thankful that I found it - was a &lt;a href="https://github.com/beaugunderson/wifi-heatmap"&gt;GitHub repository from Beau Gunderson&lt;/a&gt; that plots a heatmap superimposed on a floorplan using a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSV&lt;/span&gt; file of WiFi signal strength measurements. This was enough to get me started on a similar project to automate the&amp;nbsp;process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over a couple of afternoons I came up with a really rough tool, &lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/python-wifi-survey-heatmap"&gt;python-wifi-survey-heatmap&lt;/a&gt; to handle this. The full documentation is in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/python-wifi-survey-heatmap/blob/master/README.rst"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;README&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but the gist is that it&amp;#8217;s a Python &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; (wxPython) and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; application that automates the process. It&amp;#8217;s currently Linux-only because it uses &lt;code&gt;iwlib&lt;/code&gt; (wireless_tools) to pull wireless information and perform scans, but that could be fixed by adding collector classes for other OSes. In short you run an iperf3 server somewhere on your &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAN&lt;/span&gt;, connect to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSID&lt;/span&gt; you want to test, fire up the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; passing it the path to an image to use as the floorplan background and the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; or hostname of the iperf3 server, and then walk around clicking the floorplan at your current location. For each click the application will draw a yellow circle and then change it to green when measurement is complete, about a minute&amp;nbsp;later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each measurement point (location on the floorplan), the application&amp;nbsp;captures:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current wireless statistics including quality, signal strength, and noise level (like &lt;code&gt;iwconfig&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A current scan (like &lt;code&gt;iwlist scan&lt;/code&gt;) of all visible networks and their signal&amp;nbsp;strength/quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three 10-second iperf3 measurements to the iperf&amp;nbsp;server:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;TCP&lt;/span&gt; upload (client/application to&amp;nbsp;server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;TCP&lt;/span&gt; download (server to&amp;nbsp;client)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;UDP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;upload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After each measurement is complete all data is saved to a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt; file in the current directory, and the gui application can optionally load an existing &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt; output file to continue a previous survey. None of this uses any sort of shell/subprocess/exec hackery; we interface with iwconfig and iwlist information via the python &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/iwlib/"&gt;iwlib&lt;/a&gt; package, a cffi Python wrapper around wireless_tools&amp;#8217; iwlib, and with iperf3 via the &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/iperf3/"&gt;iperf3&lt;/a&gt; package, a cdll wrapper around&amp;nbsp;libiperf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#8217;ve completed capturing data for your site survey, the &lt;code&gt;wifi-heatmap&lt;/code&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; entrypoint processes the data and generates some heatmaps as well as channel utilization graphs like&amp;nbsp;these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/channels24_WAP1.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="example 2.4 GHz channel usage" src="/GFX/channels24_WAP1_sm.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/channels5_WAP1.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="example 5 GHz channel usage" src="/GFX/channels5_WAP1_sm.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/jitter_WAP1.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="example jitter heatmap" src="/GFX/jitter_WAP1_sm.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/quality_WAP1.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="example quality heatmap" src="/GFX/quality_WAP1_sm.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/rssi_WAP1.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="example rssi heatmap" src="/GFX/rssi_WAP1_sm.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/tcp_download_Mbps_WAP1.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="example tcp download heatmap" src="/GFX/tcp_download_Mbps_WAP1_sm.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/tcp_upload_Mbps_WAP1.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="example tcp upload heatmap" src="/GFX/tcp_upload_Mbps_WAP1_sm.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/udp_Mbps_WAP1.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="example udp upload heatmap" src="/GFX/udp_Mbps_WAP1_sm.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the code and some initial documentation is available at &lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/python-wifi-survey-heatmap"&gt;https://github.com/jantman/python-wifi-survey-heatmap&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s very alpha and rough around the edges, and I doubt I&amp;#8217;ll be actively developing or supporting it once I&amp;#8217;m done installing my new &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AP&lt;/span&gt;, but I very much hope that it might be of use to someone else and maybe someone will even improve it a&amp;nbsp;bit.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="wifi"></category><category term="survey"></category><category term="wireless"></category><category term="heatmap"></category><category term="python"></category></entry></feed>