<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog - tasker</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/tasker.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2012-04-04T20:40:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Rsync on an Android phone</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2012/04/rsync-on-an-android-phone/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-04-04T20:40:00-04:00</published><updated>2012-04-04T20:40:00-04:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2012-04-04:/2012/04/rsync-on-an-android-phone/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while, there are some files that I want kept in sync
between my Android-based phone and one of my Linux (or Mac, or any Unix,
or maybe Windows too, but I use Linux&amp;#8230;) boxes. Yeah, I can copy them
over manually via &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; or even something …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while, there are some files that I want kept in sync
between my Android-based phone and one of my Linux (or Mac, or any Unix,
or maybe Windows too, but I use Linux&amp;#8230;) boxes. Yeah, I can copy them
over manually via &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; or even something a bit simpler like
&lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=lysesoft.andftp"&gt;AndFTP&lt;/a&gt;
(assuming you can &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SCP&lt;/span&gt; to the target machine). But that&amp;#8217;s a real pain for
anything like my &lt;a href="http://keepass.info/"&gt;KeePass&lt;/a&gt; (well, actually
&lt;a href="http://www.keepassx.org/"&gt;KeePassX&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.android.keepass"&gt;KeePassDroid&lt;/a&gt;)
password database, that I might add something to at any time and forget
to sync. I also try to occasionally (waiting in line?) backup &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;, call
logs, etc. on my phone, and like to have those synced back to the
desktop&amp;nbsp;automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the solution: &lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=eu.kowalczuk.rsync4android"&gt;rsync backup for
Android&lt;/a&gt;,
a &lt;a href="http://rsync.samba.org/"&gt;rsync&lt;/a&gt; client for Android that includes
Tasker plugins (there are a few things about the app that I don&amp;#8217;t like,
but it seems to be the only option at the moment), and
&lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=net.dinglisch.android.taskerm"&gt;Tasker&lt;/a&gt;,
an automation framework for Android.Tasker is one of the few Android
apps that I&amp;#8217;ve actually bought (i.e. not free/no-cost), and is currently
selling for $6.49. It&amp;#8217;s an incredibly capable task automator, very much
akin to &lt;a href="http://www.twofortyfouram.com/"&gt;Locale&lt;/a&gt; on steroids. On the
down side, Tasker can eat up battery life if you don&amp;#8217;t configure it
intelligently, and it&amp;#8217;s not &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; 100% reliable when interacting with
the system. On the positive side, Tasker can identify practically any
combination of states in the android system (from hardware and software
events to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; location, time, signal status, etc.) and perform almost
any task on the system based on this information. Sure, this specific
problem could be solved with a cron replacement (which Android lacks, of
course), but Tasker can do things like play specific audio files when
you get an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt; from a specific number, mute audio at certain &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;
locations, or turn WiFi on when I get home and off when I leave the
house. It also has a plugin architecture, and rsync backup for Android
happens to have a plugin that works with&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, our goal is to have a daily, bi-directional, newest-file-wins sync
between a directory on our Android phone and a directory on a computer.
I&amp;#8217;m not going to go into a lot of the computer-side stuff, mainly
because that varies quite a bit between operating systems, and also
because my personal setup is a bit paranoid in terms of security. For
the computer side, we&amp;#8217;ll need a machine that can be SSHed to from the
Internet (either a static &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; or a known hostname/dynamic &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNS&lt;/span&gt;), a user
that can run rsync over &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt;, and a directory that&amp;#8217;s writable&amp;nbsp;(obviously).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy and install the
    &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.dinglisch.android.taskerm"&gt;Tasker&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=eu.kowalczuk.rsync4android"&gt;rsync backup for
    Android&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure the rsync stuff on the computer. In the simplest form,
    we&amp;#8217;ll just need a user that can login and run rsync, and a directory
    to sync from/to &lt;em&gt;(note: this should be a directory used only for
    syncing the&amp;nbsp;phone&amp;#8230;).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the rsync backup for Android app. Use Menu -&gt; Generate Keys to
    generate a new pair of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; keys, and then get the public key setup
    on the target computer. See &lt;a href="http://android.kowalczuk.eu/rsync4android/"&gt;the developer&amp;#8217;s web
    site&lt;/a&gt; for&amp;nbsp;instructions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once keys are setup, create a new profile called &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt;-droid&amp;#8221;. Set the
    local directory to a new empty directory (I used &lt;code&gt;/sdcard/sync&lt;/code&gt;),
    enter the remote host address, port, username, and remote directory,
    and select the private &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; key that you created. Check off &amp;#8220;rsync on
    reverse direction&amp;#8221;. As this program is just a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; wrapper around
    normal rsync binaries, you can specify additional options to the
    rsync command; my string ended up being
    &lt;code&gt;-vHrltDuO --chmod=Du+rwx,go-rwx,Fu+rw,go-rw --no-perms&lt;/code&gt;. If it
    helps, at the bottom of the screen you can see the actual rsync
    command line that will be run. Save when&amp;nbsp;done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save the profile, then long-press it and select &amp;#8220;Duplicate&amp;#8221;. Change
    the name to &amp;#8220;droid-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221;, uncheck &amp;#8220;rsync in reverse direction&amp;#8221;, and
    change your additional options as needed (mine became
    &lt;code&gt;-vHrltDu --chmod=Dug+rwx,o-rwx,Fug+rw,o-rw --no-perms&lt;/code&gt;). Save when&amp;nbsp;done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a test file in the sync directory on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt;, and a different
    one in the sync directory on the&amp;nbsp;droid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One at a time, in the rsync backup app, tap on the profile names. If
    all goes well, the syncs should run, and both files will now be in
    both places. If there are any problems, the output should help; the
    most likely issues are probably permissions, rsync command options,
    or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;keys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long-press each profile, select &amp;#8220;Edit&amp;#8221;, and check off &amp;#8220;Close log
    window after job is done&amp;#8221;. Save&amp;nbsp;profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now fire up Tasker. Click the &amp;#8220;+&amp;#8221; at the bottom of the screen to
    create a new profile, call it &amp;#8220;sync&amp;#8221;, and click the check&amp;nbsp;mark.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the First Context panel, tap Time, and select when you want the
    jobs to run; I chose 03:01. Tap the check&amp;nbsp;mark.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the Task Selection panel, tap New Task. Give it a name, like&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;sync2&amp;#8221;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the Task Edit panel, tap the &amp;#8220;+&amp;#8221; button at the bottom left, tap
    Plugin, tap &amp;#8220;rsync backup for Android&amp;#8221;, click the &amp;#8220;Edit&amp;#8221; button on
    the Configuration line, and select the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt;-droid rsync profile. Tap
    the check mark in the lower left to&amp;nbsp;save.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat the last step for the droid-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt; rsync&amp;nbsp;profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap the check box in the lower left. This saves the&amp;nbsp;profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the main Tasker screen, make sure there&amp;#8217;s a green check to the
    right of the profile you just added, and that the button at the
    bottom right of the screen is set to&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;On&amp;#8221;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming this all went well, the next time the time you specified rolls
around, your sync should run. If you gave the task a name in step 12,
you can setup additional profiles to run it at other times (or use the
repeat logic&amp;nbsp;builtin).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="android"></category><category term="rsync"></category><category term="tasker"></category></entry></feed>