<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://newblog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://newblog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/tether.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2010 10:29:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>WiFi tether for Droid</title><link>http://newblog.jasonantman.com/2010/08/wifi-tether-for-droid/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;My Motorola Droid (purchased on &lt;a href="/2009/11/droid/"&gt;November 10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;,
2009&lt;/a&gt;, 4 days after the release) is still running
Android 2.0.1. I guess this is somewhat out of laziness - I love the
Incredible and its new (and more refined) Android version and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UI&lt;/span&gt;, but my
phone is rooted. I&amp;#8217;m not willing to give up root, or any of my apps, and
I have yet to find a tutorial for the upgrade to 2.1 (or 2.2??) without
losing root or my apps or&amp;nbsp;data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&amp;#8217;m in North Carolina for the weekend and though the hotel
advertised free wifi, much as I feared, nobody bothered to do a site
survey or a real installation, and the signal level in my room is
useless (despite a pretty low noise floor). So after a little googling,
I managed to find the &lt;a href="http://szym.net/projects/barnacle/"&gt;Barnacle Wifi
Tether&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="market://search?q=pname:net.szym.barnacle"&gt;Market
link&lt;/a&gt;) app. Sure enough, it
allows any Droid users with a rooted phone to setup an ad-hoc wireless
network for tethering without a custom kernel. In fact, I&amp;#8217;m writing this
right now on my MacBook Pro tethered to my phone over WiFi. I&amp;#8217;m seeing
764Kbps down and 234Kbps up. Not enough for serious work (forget my
girlfriend&amp;#8217;s hope of playing Warcraft), but definitely enough for email,
web browsing and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSH&lt;/span&gt; on a much larger&amp;nbsp;screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only real complaints are that it&amp;#8217;s an ad-hoc network (which
apparently is a limitation of the Android WiFi driver for the phone), it
doesn&amp;#8217;t support anything better than &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WEP&lt;/span&gt; (so no online banking, and the
usual security concerns with what I&amp;#8217;d equate to public open WiFi), and I
can&amp;#8217;t seem to figure out how to get the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MAC&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACL&lt;/span&gt; to&amp;nbsp;work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But given how little I travel, it&amp;#8217;s definitely a good app, a quick
install and setup, and a lot less complex than trying to get &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt;
tethering working when I eventually get Linux on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MBP&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2010 10:29:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:newblog.jasonantman.com,2010-08-15:2010/08/wifi-tether-for-droid/</guid><category>android</category><category>droid</category><category>tether</category><category>wifi</category></item></channel></rss>