<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/usage.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2017-04-17T16:11:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Python script to check xfinity data usage</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2017/04/python-script-to-check-xfinity-data-usage/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2017-04-17T16:11:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Jason Antman</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2017-04-17:2017/04/python-script-to-check-xfinity-data-usage/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I got one of those invasive, abusive, utterly awful (and idiotic) &lt;a href="https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20161123/10554936126/comcast-takes-heat-injecting-messages-into-internet-traffic.shtml"&gt;injected popups from Xfinity&lt;/a&gt; that I&amp;#8217;m at 75% of my monthly bandwidth allocation. Nevermind the fact that I have a bunch of automated scripts running on my computer and injected &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; might never be seen by a human, or that I work from home and every once in a while I&amp;#8217;ll find myself pulling and pushing multi-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GB&lt;/span&gt; Docker images, which completely kills my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;1TB&lt;/span&gt; bandwidth limit. But it&amp;#8217;s only half way through the month and, frankly, I&amp;#8217;m pretty mystified how I could have used so much data this quickly. I went to Xfinity&amp;#8217;s site to check my usage meter - after rummaging around in my password manager to find my credentials - and realized that while it shows a graph of the past three months and a progress bar for the current month, it doesn&amp;#8217;t show me any detailed (i.e. daily or hourly) data that would help me figure out the&amp;nbsp;cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I wrote a little &lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/xfinity-usage"&gt;script&lt;/a&gt; using Python and Selenium to log in to their My Account site and screen-scrape the &lt;a href="http://www.xfinity.com/usagemeter"&gt;usage meter&lt;/a&gt;. Why Comcast would require me to log in to view my usage when I&amp;#8217;m accessing their site from the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IP&lt;/span&gt; address &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; gave me, on &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; network, I have no idea&amp;#8230; unless it&amp;#8217;s to provide a disincentive for customers to be aware of their usage. But I wrote the script, and it seems to be working. For the time being, I&amp;#8217;m both pushing the results into Graphite so I can see usage over time, and sending myself a daily email so I can keep on top of&amp;nbsp;usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently Comcast used to have &lt;a href="http://usmapp-qa.comcast.net/"&gt;a desktop app&lt;/a&gt; to track usage but it&amp;#8217;s since been completely shut down, along with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;API&lt;/span&gt; that backed it (which an enterprising fellow reverse-engineered in &lt;a href="https://github.com/WTFox/comcastUsage"&gt;this script&lt;/a&gt;). I can only assume this is another indication that, though the bandwidth cap was introduced citing &amp;#8220;network performance&amp;#8221;, they really don&amp;#8217;t want people lowering network load (and avoiding&amp;nbsp;fees).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t remember anything about screen-scraping in the Xfinity terms of service - and if they&amp;#8217;re f-ing injecting elements into &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; web traffic, I sure as hell hope they don&amp;#8217;t complain about me checking my own usage - but use this at your own risk. Also be aware that it&amp;#8217;s screen-scraping, so it may well break with a site redesign or element &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ID&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone would find this useful, please see &lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/xfinity-usage"&gt;https://github.com/jantman/xfinity-usage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="comcast"></category><category term="xfinity"></category><category term="data"></category><category term="usage"></category><category term="bandwidth"></category><category term="cap"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="selenium"></category></entry></feed>