<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/versions.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 23:31:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>How Yum and RPM Compare Versions</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2014/07/how-yum-and-rpm-compare-versions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently tripped up by a bug in Puppet, &lt;a href="https://tickets.puppetlabs.com/browse/PUP-1244"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PUP&lt;/span&gt;-1244&lt;/a&gt;,
dealing with how it compares package versions. All of Puppet&amp;#8217;s Package types assumed
&lt;a href="http://semver.org/"&gt;semantic versioning&lt;/a&gt;, and that&amp;#8217;s far from the case for RPMs and therefore Yum. This
manifested itself in how Puppet validates package installations - if a version was explicitly specified
and Yum/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt; could install it, puppet would shell out to them and install the package, but then report
a failure in its post-install validation, as the &lt;em&gt;exact&lt;/em&gt; version string specified isn&amp;#8217;t present.
For example, many RedHat/CentOS packages (such as those from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EPEL&lt;/span&gt;) include a release string with the major
version of the distribution they were packged for - i.e. &amp;#8220;.el5&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;.el6&amp;#8221;. If Puppet was instructed to
install package &amp;#8220;foo&amp;#8221; version &amp;#8220;1.2.3&amp;#8221;, but the actual package in the repositories was &amp;#8220;foo-1.2.3-el5&amp;#8221;,
Puppet would cause the package to be installed, but then report&amp;nbsp;failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cut a &lt;a href="https://github.com/puppetlabs/puppet/pull/2866"&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt; against the Puppet4 branch to
fix these issues, essentially re-implementing yum and rpm&amp;#8217;s version comparison logic in Ruby. It took
me a few days of research and sorting through source code (and in the process I found that &lt;code&gt;yum&lt;/code&gt;, despite
its use in so many distributions, has no unit tests at all) but I finally got it finished. In the process,
I found out exactly how&amp;#8230; weird&amp;#8230; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s version comparison rules&amp;nbsp;are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="package-naming-and-parsing"&gt;Package Naming and&amp;nbsp;Parsing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt; package names are made up of five parts; the package name, epoch, version, release, and architecture.
This format is commonly referred to as the acronym &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEVRA&lt;/span&gt;. The epoch is not always included; it is assumed
to be zero (0) on any packages that lack it explicitly. The format for the whole string is &lt;code&gt;n-e:v-r.a&lt;/code&gt;.
For my purposes, I was only really concerned with comparing the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EVR&lt;/span&gt; portion; Puppet knows about package names
and the bug herein was with what Puppet calls the &amp;#8220;version&amp;#8221; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EVR&lt;/span&gt; in yum/rpm parlance). Parsing is pretty&amp;nbsp;simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is a &lt;code&gt;:&lt;/code&gt; in the string, everything before it is the epoch. If not, the epoch is&amp;nbsp;zero.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is a &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;remaining&lt;/em&gt; string, everything before the first &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; is the version,
  and everything after it is the release. If there isn&amp;#8217;t one, the release is considered&amp;nbsp;null/nill/None/whatever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="how-yum-compares-evr"&gt;How Yum Compares&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EVR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the package string is parsed into its &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EVR&lt;/span&gt; components, yum calls &lt;code&gt;rpmUtils.miscutils.compareEVR()&lt;/code&gt;,
which does some data type massaging for the inputs, and then calls out to &lt;code&gt;rpm.labelCompare()&lt;/code&gt;
(found in &lt;code&gt;rpm.git/python/header-py.c&lt;/code&gt;). &lt;code&gt;labelCompare()&lt;/code&gt; sets each epoch
to &amp;#8220;0&amp;#8221; if it was null/Nonem, and then uses &lt;code&gt;compare_values()&lt;/code&gt; to compare each &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EVR&lt;/span&gt; portion, which in turn falls through
to a function called &lt;code&gt;rpmvercmp()&lt;/code&gt; (see below). The algorithm for &lt;code&gt;labelCompare()&lt;/code&gt; is as&amp;nbsp;follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set each epoch value to 0 if it&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;null/None.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare the epoch values using &lt;code&gt;compare_values()&lt;/code&gt;. If they&amp;#8217;re not equal, return that result, else
   move on to the next portion (version). The logic within &lt;code&gt;compare_values()&lt;/code&gt; is that if one is empty/null
   and the other is not, the non-empty one is greater, and that ends the comparison. If neither of
   them is empty/not present, compare them using &lt;code&gt;rpmvercmp()&lt;/code&gt; and follow the same logic; if one
   is &amp;#8220;greater&amp;#8221; (newer) than the other, that&amp;#8217;s the end result of the comparison. Otherwise, move
   on to the next component&amp;nbsp;(version).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare the versions using the same&amp;nbsp;logic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare the releases using the same&amp;nbsp;logic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If all of the components are &amp;#8220;equal&amp;#8221;, the packages are the&amp;nbsp;same.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real magic, obviously, happens in &lt;code&gt;rpmvercmp()&lt;/code&gt;, the rpm library function to compare two
versions (or epochs, or releases). That&amp;#8217;s also where the madness&amp;nbsp;happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="how-rpm-compares-version-parts"&gt;How &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt; Compares Version&amp;nbsp;Parts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt; is written in C. Converting all of the buffer and pointer processing for these strings
over to Ruby was quite a pain. That being said, I didn&amp;#8217;t make this up, this is actually the
algorithm that &lt;code&gt;rpmvercmp()&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;lib/rpmvercmp.c&lt;/code&gt;) uses to compare version &amp;#8220;parts&amp;#8221;
(epoch, version, release). This function returns 0 if the strings are equal, 1 if &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; (the
first string argument) is newer than &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; (the second string argument), or -1 if
&lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is older than &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt;. Also keep in mind that this uses pointers in C, so it works by removing
a sequence of 0 or more characters from the front of each string, comparing them, and then repeating
for the remaining characters in each string until something is unequal, or a string reaches its&amp;nbsp;end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the strings are binary equal (&lt;code&gt;a == b&lt;/code&gt;), they&amp;#8217;re equal, return&amp;nbsp;0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loop over the strings, left-to-right.&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trim anything that&amp;#8217;s not &lt;code&gt;[A-Za-z0-9]&lt;/code&gt; or tilde (&lt;code&gt;~&lt;/code&gt;) from the front of both&amp;nbsp;strings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If both strings start with a tilde, discard it and move on to the next&amp;nbsp;character.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If string &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; starts with a tilde and string &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; does not, return -1 (string &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is older);
   and the inverse if string &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; starts with a tilde and string &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; does&amp;nbsp;not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;End the loop if either string has reached zero&amp;nbsp;length.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the first character of &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is a digit, pop the leading chunk of continuous digits from
   each string (which may be &amp;#8221; for &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; if only one &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; starts with digits). If &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; begins
   with a letter, do the same for leading&amp;nbsp;letters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the segement from &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; had 0 length, return 1 if the segment from &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; was numeric, or
   -1 if it was alphabetic. The logical result of this is that if &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; begins with numbers
   and &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; does not, &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is newer (return 1). If &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; begins with letters and &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; does not,
   then &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is older (return -1). If the leading character(s) from &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; were both
   numbers or both letters, continue&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the leading segments were both numeric, discard any leading zeros and &lt;em&gt;whichever one is longer
   wins&lt;/em&gt;. If &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is longer than &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; (without leading zeroes), return 1, and vice-versa. If
   they&amp;#8217;re of the same length, continue&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare the leading segments with &lt;code&gt;strcmp()&lt;/code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; in Ruby). If that returns a non-zero
   value, then return that value. Else continue to the next iteration of the&amp;nbsp;loop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the loop ended (nothing has been returned yet, either both strings are totally the same or they&amp;#8217;re
   the same up to the end of one of them, like with &amp;#8220;1.2.3&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;1.2.3b&amp;#8221;), then the longest wins -
   if what&amp;#8217;s left of &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is longer than what&amp;#8217;s left of &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt;, return 1. Vice-versa for if what&amp;#8217;s
   left of &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; is longer than what&amp;#8217;s left of &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt;. And finally, if what&amp;#8217;s left of them is the same
   length, return&amp;nbsp;0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well there you have it. Quite convoluted. And full of things like the &amp;#8220;~&amp;#8221; magic character (&amp;#8220;~1&amp;#8221; is always
older than&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;9999zzzz&amp;#8221;).&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Antman</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 23:31:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2014-07-11:2014/07/how-yum-and-rpm-compare-versions/</guid><category>rpm</category><category>yum</category><category>puppet</category><category>versions</category></item></channel></rss>