<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jason Antman's Blog - work from home</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/work-from-home.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</id><updated>2016-08-26T15:10:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>The Psychological Side of Remote Work</title><link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/2016/08/the-psychological-side-of-remote-work/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-26T15:10:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-08-26T15:10:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Jason Antman</name></author><id>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2016-08-26:/2016/08/the-psychological-side-of-remote-work/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some thoughts on the psychological aspects of remote&amp;nbsp;work&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For most of my professional career, I&amp;#8217;ve worked from home a few days a week - and a few times, for
stretches of a few weeks - and that&amp;#8217;s been the norm on most of my teams, not counting full-time
remote workers. But for all the talk about remote work, much of it seems to focus on tools,
collaboration and productivity - and relatively little on the human side, and tips to help
balance work and life when the work happens in your home (or wherever else you&amp;nbsp;are).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These certainly aren&amp;#8217;t for everyone, but here are some of the tricks I&amp;#8217;ve accumulated so
far that help me be happier, more productive and more sane when working from home, whether
it&amp;#8217;s a day or few a week or a few weeks straight. I know these aren&amp;#8217;t applicable to everyone,
and they also assume a culture that already values work-life balance, but might not spend
a lot of time talking about the little hacks to make remote work better. Not all of these
will work for every person, and there are plenty I&amp;#8217;m surely forgetting or not aware&amp;nbsp;of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-dress-for-the-job"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#1-dress-for-the-job"&gt;1. Dress for the&amp;nbsp;Job&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve made the &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m working from home so I&amp;#8217;m not wearing pants&amp;#8221; joke plenty of times
myself. But it&amp;#8217;s never true. When I&amp;#8217;m working from home, the first thing I do is
go through the same morning routine I do when going in to the office - most importantly,
making coffee and getting dressed. Lately I&amp;#8217;ve taken to wearing &amp;#8220;nicer&amp;#8221; (read: having
buttons somewhere on them) shirts to the office, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt;, I&amp;#8217;ll wear a t-shirt when I&amp;#8217;m
home. But I still put on long pants and&amp;nbsp;shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this is a big part of the psychological side of work/life separation. I have
&amp;#8220;work clothes&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;hanging around the house&amp;#8221; clothes. When I&amp;#8217;m going to be working,
I wear work clothes. When I&amp;#8217;m done for the day, a (psychologically) big part of my
end-of-the-work-day routine is changing from work clothes to &amp;#8220;hanging around&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;clothes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoever I heard this from - and I&amp;#8217;m sad to say I don&amp;#8217;t even remember who it was - probably
sounded crazy to me. But it really goes a long way to psychologically separate work time
from personal time - especially on the days when I finish up work and get right back to
the keyboard working on personal projects or&amp;nbsp;gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2-separate-profiles"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#2-separate-profiles"&gt;2. Separate&amp;nbsp;Profiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep separate profiles in your browser, one for work and one for personal.
&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/2364824?hl=en"&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="https://www.chromium.org/user-experience/multi-profiles"&gt;Chromium&lt;/a&gt; have support
for separate users; Firefox recently added built-in
&lt;a href="https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/profile-manager-create-and-remove-firefox-profiles"&gt;support for switching profiles&lt;/a&gt;,
which is quite nice for those of us who had been using &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Mozilla/Profile_Manager"&gt;Profile Manager&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;#8217;m sure there are some people who do this simply to keep history/bookmarks/etc. separate,
I do it as an incentive to focus on work when I&amp;#8217;m at work and focus on not work when I&amp;#8217;m not.
At the end of my work day I close my &amp;#8220;work&amp;#8221; browser session and open my &amp;#8220;personal&amp;#8221; one back
up. Thanks to session restore, all of my tabs are right where I left them&amp;#8230; and I don&amp;#8217;t have
a reason to leave distracting personal tabs open during the work day, or work tabs open
when I&amp;#8217;m on my own&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I know this doesn&amp;#8217;t work for everyone, especially if you&amp;#8217;re on-call and it&amp;#8217;s busy. In those
cases, I usually keep tabs in separate windows, one for work and one for personal; it&amp;#8217;s all
there when I need it, but out of the way when I&amp;nbsp;don&amp;#8217;t).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3-take-breaks"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#3-take-breaks"&gt;3. Take&amp;nbsp;Breaks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#8217;m physically in the office, my day is usually broken up by moments away from my computer
work with colleagues - whether it&amp;#8217;s walking to a meeting or lunch, whatever conversations pop up
in the room, or even just whiteboarding a problem. Sure, there&amp;#8217;s plenty of conversation on HipChat
when we&amp;#8217;re remote, but I&amp;#8217;m not &lt;em&gt;getting away from the keyboard&lt;/em&gt; like I do in the&amp;nbsp;office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take breaks. Take the dogs out, take five minutes to play with your kids or pets, go make coffee
or lunch, whatever. Just be sure to break up your day and not fall into the trap of sitting in
the same spot for however many hours staring at a monitor. Our bodies need &amp;#8220;get up and walk around&amp;#8221;
time, but our minds need a change of scenery too. Five minutes away from the same monitor is helpful.
Sure, if I&amp;#8217;m deep in the middle of something, I&amp;#8217;ll keep at it. But I usually find that stepping
away for a few minutes now and then at logical context switch points helps a lot. And if it&amp;#8217;s
a day of mostly writing code, it also provides a good time to think about what I&amp;#8217;m working on
without the burning urge to immediately start&amp;nbsp;implementing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t fall into the trap of feeling that work from home time demands that
you&amp;#8217;re glued to the keyboard every second without pause - nobody in the office is doing that.
And don&amp;#8217;t fall into the trap of feeling like you have to prove you&amp;#8217;re being productive while
remote by never taking a break - if you&amp;#8217;re like many people I know, you&amp;#8217;re probably already
more productive when you&amp;#8217;re in an environment that feels more comfortable (you can always
point people to Psychology Today&amp;#8217;s
&lt;a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/mind-the-manager/201605/remote-workers-are-happier-and-more-productive"&gt;Remote Workers Are Happier and More Productive&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, don&amp;#8217;t give up opportunities to change your surroundings. If you have a webinar or
online meeting, grab the laptop and take it from the couch (assuming the setting is acceptable
for the attendees). Need to read a lengthy article or documentation? Bring the laptop
outside. Anything to get a mental and visual change of&amp;nbsp;pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="4-lunch-is-holy"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#4-lunch-is-holy"&gt;4. Lunch is&amp;nbsp;Holy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#8217;m in the office, if my team doesn&amp;#8217;t have lunch plans (which is the rule rather
than the exception), I tend to eat at my desk, and only take as much time as I need
to eat. Sometimes I&amp;#8217;m good to myself and read something, other times I just work while
I&amp;nbsp;eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#8217;m at home, I take the 45 minutes we&amp;#8217;re given for lunch, every day. If my wife is
home, we watch something on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; and eat together. If she isn&amp;#8217;t, I catch up on an episode
of something on Netflix. But no matter what I do, I set aside the full &amp;#8220;official&amp;#8221;
45 minutes to decompress, step away from the keyboard, and breathe a bit. Sure, sometimes
my mind is still churning away on whatever I&amp;#8217;m working on, and I usually only break
for food at a logical stopping point. But it&amp;#8217;s still an important part of staying
focused through the day, and not hitting the end of the day feeling exhausted and&amp;nbsp;glassy-eyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5-disconnect"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#5-disconnect"&gt;5.&amp;nbsp;Disconnect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On-call or similar exceptions aside, when they day&amp;#8217;s over, the day&amp;#8217;s over. Disconnect.
I have HipChat and various other communication tools on my phone if I absolutely have
to be reached after hours. But aside from that, when my work day is over, I close my
work browser session and switch to personal, close any editors/windows/etc. I have open,
and ensure all of my changes are committed and pushed. As much as I occasionally rue
the fact that my current job has almost everything on our private network, it means
I can disconnect my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VPN&lt;/span&gt; client and be unable to access anything work-related. I&amp;#8217;ll
admit that I usually leave my work-related &lt;code&gt;screen&lt;/code&gt; windows open overnight, just
for ease of picking back up, but I always close them over a weekend or&amp;nbsp;vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you&amp;#8217;re being paid for a 168-hour work week, you deserve to have some time
away from work. I&amp;#8217;ll admit I&amp;#8217;ve had some jobs where on-call was&amp;#8230; quite busy&amp;#8230;
but it doesn&amp;#8217;t take that long to connect and start up what you need, when needed.
You owe it to yourself: when you&amp;#8217;re done, make the work stuff disappear from your
field of view. If you spend much time at your computer outside of work, you need
to keep the two separate&amp;#8230; or else &amp;#8220;work time&amp;#8221; becomes &amp;#8220;awake&amp;nbsp;time.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6-end-of-day-routine"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#6-end-of-day-routine"&gt;6. End-of-day&amp;nbsp;Routine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Develop a daily end-of-work routine or ritual. Do something to psychologically say
to yourself &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m done with work for today, I&amp;#8217;m switching gears to my personal life.&amp;#8221;
If your office is also your home, you miss out on the decompression and context switch
provided by a commute (even a short one). Put something in its place. This is
especially important if your after-work time, even occasionally, involves going back
to the same chair, keyboard and monitor(s) - whatever the&amp;nbsp;reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change your clothes, catch up with family, spend some time with your pets, watch a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;
show or read a book, cook dinner, go for a walk - whatever. Just do something to signal
to yourself that the work day is over, and you can leave all of those thoughts, anxieties,
problems, ideas and tasks until tomorrow. As much as you may intellectually know that
you&amp;#8217;re &amp;#8220;done&amp;#8221; for the day (even if your pager might go off), do something to &lt;em&gt;show&lt;/em&gt;
yourself, and tell your subconscious, that you&amp;#8217;re &amp;#8220;going&amp;nbsp;home.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7-get-outside"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#7-get-outside"&gt;7. Get&amp;nbsp;Outside&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m an introvert, and have occasionally suffered from mild depression. Neither of those
is unusual in our industry; the former is just much more accepted and discussed
than the latter&amp;nbsp;(unfortunately).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can, &lt;strong&gt;get outside&lt;/strong&gt;. Even if it&amp;#8217;s just to run an errand, take a short walk,
or drive around the block, get out of the house. This is especially important if
you usually don&amp;#8217;t (but can), or if you&amp;#8217;re working long hours. At a previous job
we had an &amp;#8220;incident&amp;#8221; that resulted in the engineering team working round-the-clock
for the better part of two weeks; we ended up scheduling a 24x7 rotation, but until
that two-week-ish mark, we were all more-or-less working whenever we were awake.
It was awful for all of us - both our personal well-being and our productivity
and focus. Even just running to the store or to pick up dinner was an immense
relief from the wake-work-sleep-repeat&amp;nbsp;cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you&amp;#8217;re not working insane hours (and I certainly hope you&amp;#8217;re not), be aware
of how much time you&amp;#8217;re spending at home indoors. If you&amp;#8217;re not terribly social by
nature, make sure you get outside, and do it on a regular basis. Even if you don&amp;#8217;t
&lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to go somewhere, do it anyway for a change of scenery and a chance to clear
your&amp;nbsp;mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8-talk-about-burnout-and-frustrations"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#8-talk-about-burnout-and-frustrations"&gt;8. Talk About Burnout and&amp;nbsp;Frustrations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This goes for everyone, but more so for people who are remote full-time or for
long stretches, on a team that&amp;#8217;s at least partially in-office. It&amp;#8217;s really easy
to feel disconnected from what&amp;#8217;s happening, and it&amp;#8217;s also really difficult -
especially if you do most of your communication via text - for your manager and
co-workers to know when you&amp;#8217;re feeling stressed or overworked. Talk about&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burnout - even to the point of suicide - in technology has been talked about
more recently, including John Willis&amp;#8217;
&lt;a href="http://itrevolution.com/karojisatsu/"&gt;Karōjisatsu&lt;/a&gt;, Gene Kim&amp;#8217;s recent work,
and &lt;a href="https://victorops.com/blog/burnout-in-tech/"&gt;Jason Hand&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s certainly
something that our industry needs to be &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; more aware of, and something we
all need to work to fix, both personally and with our colleagues. If you&amp;#8217;re a
manager of remotes, make sure you check in with them often - not just on how
their work is going, but on how they&amp;#8217;re doing emotionally, especially related
to work. Find out what&amp;#8217;s frustrating them, what&amp;#8217;s draining their energy and
how their work-life balance is. If you&amp;#8217;re not a manager, check in with your
coworkers about the same things, and make sure someone knows how you&amp;#8217;re doing.
It might feel awkward when you&amp;#8217;re having a great time or starting a new job,
but it&amp;#8217;s a habit that&amp;#8217;s much easier to get into when things are going well
than when you really need&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="wfh"></category><category term="remote"></category><category term="work"></category><category term="balance"></category><category term="work from home"></category><category term="culture"></category></entry></feed>