<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jason Antman's Blog</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://blog.jasonantman.com/feeds/tags/work.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 15:10:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Psychological Side of Remote Work</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2016/08/the-psychological-side-of-remote-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For most of my professional career, I&amp;#8217;ve worked from home a few days a week - and a few times, for
stretches of a few weeks - and that&amp;#8217;s been the norm on most of my teams, not counting full-time
remote workers. But for all the talk about remote work, much of it seems to focus on tools,
collaboration and productivity - and relatively little on the human side, and tips to help
balance work and life when the work happens in your home (or wherever else you&amp;nbsp;are).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These certainly aren&amp;#8217;t for everyone, but here are some of the tricks I&amp;#8217;ve accumulated so
far that help me be happier, more productive and more sane when working from home, whether
it&amp;#8217;s a day or few a week or a few weeks straight. I know these aren&amp;#8217;t applicable to everyone,
and they also assume a culture that already values work-life balance, but might not spend
a lot of time talking about the little hacks to make remote work better. Not all of these
will work for every person, and there are plenty I&amp;#8217;m surely forgetting or not aware&amp;nbsp;of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-dress-for-the-job"&gt;1. Dress for the&amp;nbsp;Job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve made the &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m working from home so I&amp;#8217;m not wearing pants&amp;#8221; joke plenty of times
myself. But it&amp;#8217;s never true. When I&amp;#8217;m working from home, the first thing I do is
go through the same morning routine I do when going in to the office - most importantly,
making coffee and getting dressed. Lately I&amp;#8217;ve taken to wearing &amp;#8220;nicer&amp;#8221; (read: having
buttons somewhere on them) shirts to the office, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt;, I&amp;#8217;ll wear a t-shirt when I&amp;#8217;m
home. But I still put on long pants and&amp;nbsp;shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this is a big part of the psychological side of work/life separation. I have
&amp;#8220;work clothes&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;hanging around the house&amp;#8221; clothes. When I&amp;#8217;m going to be working,
I wear work clothes. When I&amp;#8217;m done for the day, a (psychologically) big part of my
end-of-the-work-day routine is changing from work clothes to &amp;#8220;hanging around&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;clothes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoever I heard this from - and I&amp;#8217;m sad to say I don&amp;#8217;t even remember who it was - probably
sounded crazy to me. But it really goes a long way to psychologically separate work time
from personal time - especially on the days when I finish up work and get right back to
the keyboard working on personal projects or&amp;nbsp;gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2-separate-profiles"&gt;2. Separate&amp;nbsp;Profiles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep separate profiles in your browser, one for work and one for personal.
&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/2364824?hl=en"&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="https://www.chromium.org/user-experience/multi-profiles"&gt;Chromium&lt;/a&gt; have support
for separate users; Firefox recently added built-in
&lt;a href="https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/profile-manager-create-and-remove-firefox-profiles"&gt;support for switching profiles&lt;/a&gt;,
which is quite nice for those of us who had been using &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Mozilla/Profile_Manager"&gt;Profile Manager&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;#8217;m sure there are some people who do this simply to keep history/bookmarks/etc. separate,
I do it as an incentive to focus on work when I&amp;#8217;m at work and focus on not work when I&amp;#8217;m not.
At the end of my work day I close my &amp;#8220;work&amp;#8221; browser session and open my &amp;#8220;personal&amp;#8221; one back
up. Thanks to session restore, all of my tabs are right where I left them&amp;#8230; and I don&amp;#8217;t have
a reason to leave distracting personal tabs open during the work day, or work tabs open
when I&amp;#8217;m on my own&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I know this doesn&amp;#8217;t work for everyone, especially if you&amp;#8217;re on-call and it&amp;#8217;s busy. In those
cases, I usually keep tabs in separate windows, one for work and one for personal; it&amp;#8217;s all
there when I need it, but out of the way when I&amp;nbsp;don&amp;#8217;t).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3-take-breaks"&gt;3. Take&amp;nbsp;Breaks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#8217;m physically in the office, my day is usually broken up by moments away from my computer
work with colleagues - whether it&amp;#8217;s walking to a meeting or lunch, whatever conversations pop up
in the room, or even just whiteboarding a problem. Sure, there&amp;#8217;s plenty of conversation on HipChat
when we&amp;#8217;re remote, but I&amp;#8217;m not &lt;em&gt;getting away from the keyboard&lt;/em&gt; like I do in the&amp;nbsp;office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take breaks. Take the dogs out, take five minutes to play with your kids or pets, go make coffee
or lunch, whatever. Just be sure to break up your day and not fall into the trap of sitting in
the same spot for however many hours staring at a monitor. Our bodies need &amp;#8220;get up and walk around&amp;#8221;
time, but our minds need a change of scenery too. Five minutes away from the same monitor is helpful.
Sure, if I&amp;#8217;m deep in the middle of something, I&amp;#8217;ll keep at it. But I usually find that stepping
away for a few minutes now and then at logical context switch points helps a lot. And if it&amp;#8217;s
a day of mostly writing code, it also provides a good time to think about what I&amp;#8217;m working on
without the burning urge to immediately start&amp;nbsp;implementing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t fall into the trap of feeling that work from home time demands that
you&amp;#8217;re glued to the keyboard every second without pause - nobody in the office is doing that.
And don&amp;#8217;t fall into the trap of feeling like you have to prove you&amp;#8217;re being productive while
remote by never taking a break - if you&amp;#8217;re like many people I know, you&amp;#8217;re probably already
more productive when you&amp;#8217;re in an environment that feels more comfortable (you can always
point people to Psychology Today&amp;#8217;s
&lt;a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/mind-the-manager/201605/remote-workers-are-happier-and-more-productive"&gt;Remote Workers Are Happier and More Productive&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, don&amp;#8217;t give up opportunities to change your surroundings. If you have a webinar or
online meeting, grab the laptop and take it from the couch (assuming the setting is acceptable
for the attendees). Need to read a lengthy article or documentation? Bring the laptop
outside. Anything to get a mental and visual change of&amp;nbsp;pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="4-lunch-is-holy"&gt;4. Lunch is&amp;nbsp;Holy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#8217;m in the office, if my team doesn&amp;#8217;t have lunch plans (which is the rule rather
than the exception), I tend to eat at my desk, and only take as much time as I need
to eat. Sometimes I&amp;#8217;m good to myself and read something, other times I just work while
I&amp;nbsp;eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#8217;m at home, I take the 45 minutes we&amp;#8217;re given for lunch, every day. If my wife is
home, we watch something on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; and eat together. If she isn&amp;#8217;t, I catch up on an episode
of something on Netflix. But no matter what I do, I set aside the full &amp;#8220;official&amp;#8221;
45 minutes to decompress, step away from the keyboard, and breathe a bit. Sure, sometimes
my mind is still churning away on whatever I&amp;#8217;m working on, and I usually only break
for food at a logical stopping point. But it&amp;#8217;s still an important part of staying
focused through the day, and not hitting the end of the day feeling exhausted and&amp;nbsp;glassy-eyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5-disconnect"&gt;5.&amp;nbsp;Disconnect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On-call or similar exceptions aside, when they day&amp;#8217;s over, the day&amp;#8217;s over. Disconnect.
I have HipChat and various other communication tools on my phone if I absolutely have
to be reached after hours. But aside from that, when my work day is over, I close my
work browser session and switch to personal, close any editors/windows/etc. I have open,
and ensure all of my changes are committed and pushed. As much as I occasionally rue
the fact that my current job has almost everything on our private network, it means
I can disconnect my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VPN&lt;/span&gt; client and be unable to access anything work-related. I&amp;#8217;ll
admit that I usually leave my work-related &lt;code&gt;screen&lt;/code&gt; windows open overnight, just
for ease of picking back up, but I always close them over a weekend or&amp;nbsp;vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you&amp;#8217;re being paid for a 168-hour work week, you deserve to have some time
away from work. I&amp;#8217;ll admit I&amp;#8217;ve had some jobs where on-call was&amp;#8230; quite busy&amp;#8230;
but it doesn&amp;#8217;t take that long to connect and start up what you need, when needed.
You owe it to yourself: when you&amp;#8217;re done, make the work stuff disappear from your
field of view. If you spend much time at your computer outside of work, you need
to keep the two separate&amp;#8230; or else &amp;#8220;work time&amp;#8221; becomes &amp;#8220;awake&amp;nbsp;time.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6-end-of-day-routine"&gt;6. End-of-day&amp;nbsp;Routine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Develop a daily end-of-work routine or ritual. Do something to psychologically say
to yourself &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m done with work for today, I&amp;#8217;m switching gears to my personal life.&amp;#8221;
If your office is also your home, you miss out on the decompression and context switch
provided by a commute (even a short one). Put something in its place. This is
especially important if your after-work time, even occasionally, involves going back
to the same chair, keyboard and monitor(s) - whatever the&amp;nbsp;reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change your clothes, catch up with family, spend some time with your pets, watch a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;
show or read a book, cook dinner, go for a walk - whatever. Just do something to signal
to yourself that the work day is over, and you can leave all of those thoughts, anxieties,
problems, ideas and tasks until tomorrow. As much as you may intellectually know that
you&amp;#8217;re &amp;#8220;done&amp;#8221; for the day (even if your pager might go off), do something to &lt;em&gt;show&lt;/em&gt;
yourself, and tell your subconscious, that you&amp;#8217;re &amp;#8220;going&amp;nbsp;home.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7-get-outside"&gt;7. Get&amp;nbsp;Outside&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m an introvert, and have occasionally suffered from mild depression. Neither of those
is unusual in our industry; the former is just much more accepted and discussed
than the latter&amp;nbsp;(unfortunately).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can, &lt;strong&gt;get outside&lt;/strong&gt;. Even if it&amp;#8217;s just to run an errand, take a short walk,
or drive around the block, get out of the house. This is especially important if
you usually don&amp;#8217;t (but can), or if you&amp;#8217;re working long hours. At a previous job
we had an &amp;#8220;incident&amp;#8221; that resulted in the engineering team working round-the-clock
for the better part of two weeks; we ended up scheduling a 24x7 rotation, but until
that two-week-ish mark, we were all more-or-less working whenever we were awake.
It was awful for all of us - both our personal well-being and our productivity
and focus. Even just running to the store or to pick up dinner was an immense
relief from the wake-work-sleep-repeat&amp;nbsp;cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you&amp;#8217;re not working insane hours (and I certainly hope you&amp;#8217;re not), be aware
of how much time you&amp;#8217;re spending at home indoors. If you&amp;#8217;re not terribly social by
nature, make sure you get outside, and do it on a regular basis. Even if you don&amp;#8217;t
&lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to go somewhere, do it anyway for a change of scenery and a chance to clear
your&amp;nbsp;mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8-talk-about-burnout-and-frustrations"&gt;8. Talk About Burnout and&amp;nbsp;Frustrations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This goes for everyone, but more so for people who are remote full-time or for
long stretches, on a team that&amp;#8217;s at least partially in-office. It&amp;#8217;s really easy
to feel disconnected from what&amp;#8217;s happening, and it&amp;#8217;s also really difficult -
especially if you do most of your communication via text - for your manager and
co-workers to know when you&amp;#8217;re feeling stressed or overworked. Talk about&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burnout - even to the point of suicide - in technology has been talked about
more recently, including John Willis&amp;#8217;
&lt;a href="http://itrevolution.com/karojisatsu/"&gt;Karōjisatsu&lt;/a&gt;, Gene Kim&amp;#8217;s recent work,
and &lt;a href="https://victorops.com/blog/burnout-in-tech/"&gt;Jason Hand&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s certainly
something that our industry needs to be &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; more aware of, and something we
all need to work to fix, both personally and with our colleagues. If you&amp;#8217;re a
manager of remotes, make sure you check in with them often - not just on how
their work is going, but on how they&amp;#8217;re doing emotionally, especially related
to work. Find out what&amp;#8217;s frustrating them, what&amp;#8217;s draining their energy and
how their work-life balance is. If you&amp;#8217;re not a manager, check in with your
coworkers about the same things, and make sure someone knows how you&amp;#8217;re doing.
It might feel awkward when you&amp;#8217;re having a great time or starting a new job,
but it&amp;#8217;s a habit that&amp;#8217;s much easier to get into when things are going well
than when you really need&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Antman</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 15:10:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2016-08-26:2016/08/the-psychological-side-of-remote-work/</guid><category>wfh</category><category>remote</category><category>work</category><category>balance</category><category>work from home</category><category>culture</category></item><item><title>My New-found Love of Trello and a Helpful GreaseMonkey Script</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2015/03/my-new-found-love-of-trello-and-a-helpful-greasemonkey-script/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When I started at my current job two and a half years ago, we were just really getting into &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kanban_%28development%29"&gt;Kanban&lt;/a&gt;.
We used a web-based Kanban board (&lt;a href="https://github.com/cmheisel/kardboard"&gt;Kardboard&lt;/a&gt;, written by our director of development at the time), and each team had
their daily stand-up status meetings in the middle of the office in front of a projector screen, with their board filling the entire wall (and remotes on Skype). It took me a while
to get used to it, having always worked in very ticket-and-emergency-driven ops roles. But once it clicked, it was like an epiphany. Suddenly I could see all
of the (non-breakfix or unforeseen) work headed to our team, its priority and due dates, and what everyone (including myself) was working on at a given moment.
Even though work-in-progress (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;WIP&lt;/span&gt;) limits never made it to the ops team, it reduced my stress level amazingly. Instead of dealing with a massive queue of tickets
assigned to me - some of which were such low priority I&amp;#8217;d probably never get around to them - suddenly all I had to concern myself with was my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WIP&lt;/span&gt; and what was
next up for&amp;nbsp;me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past year we&amp;#8217;ve had a major (almost complete) changeover of management, and many of the old ways have disappeared. Some might even say that, as a technical
company, we&amp;#8217;ve regressed quite a bit. Either way, we haven&amp;#8217;t been using Kanban for over six months. Our development teams are moving to &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrum_%28software_development%29"&gt;Scrum&lt;/a&gt;,
and our more ops-y teams (I&amp;#8217;m now on our Automation and Tooling team, straddling the awkward line between the two) are trying to figure out what&amp;#8217;s right for us.
And I haven&amp;#8217;t been this stressed since I started work here; my team is both busier than ever and understaffed by almost 50%. We stopped using the Kanban board in our
stand-ups, our new manager stopped referring to it, so (even with mostly-working synchronization with Jira) it stopped being useful, and I stopped using it. Without thinking,
I went back to my old &amp;#8220;page showing &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; assigned to me&amp;#8221; view in our ticketing system, and grew increasingly frustrated by managing my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WIP&lt;/span&gt; and deciding what
needed to be worked&amp;nbsp;next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, after discussing this with the rest of my team, last week two of us came to the same conclusion, independently, on the same day: use &lt;a href="https://trello.com/"&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; to
run our own personal Kanban boards. I&amp;#8217;ve been doing so for about a week now, and all I&amp;#8217;m horribly embarrassed that I didn&amp;#8217;t think of this sooner. It&amp;#8217;s absolutely wonderful -
I can keep managing my own work in a Kanban-like form (albeit without formal &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WIP&lt;/span&gt; limits) without needing management endorsement. Sure, it only works for things that I know
are coming and takes some manual curation time, but so far, it&amp;#8217;s been amazingly refreshing and calming. The best part is being able to (once again) visually see
both my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WIP&lt;/span&gt;, and my recently-complete&amp;nbsp;work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone else on my team mentioned that they use Trello for their personal tasks; I created two more boards, one for my personal development work, and another for my general
around-the-house tasks and to-do&amp;#8217;s (my wife connected with her inner manager once I shared my board with her and she figured out that she could re-order by backlog&amp;#8230;).
It&amp;#8217;s 8 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt; on Sunday night, and I can confidently say that I&amp;#8217;ve had one of the most productive weekends in ages. And one of the most relaxing. Instead of spending
lots of time trying to figure out what I have to do this weekend and what the priorities are, I just used the same Kanban method that I loved from work. And it
paid&amp;nbsp;off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-greasemonkey-script"&gt;The GreaseMonkey&amp;nbsp;Script&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one thing that initially bothered me about Trello was the time it took to add cards. At work every task I have is in either our ticketing system or
a GitHub Issue. Our previous official tool, &lt;a href="https://github.com/cmheisel/kardboard"&gt;Kardboard&lt;/a&gt;, synchronized with Jira so everything was always
up-to-date and on the right board. At first I was adding cards manually, but I figured there had to be a better way. A quick Google search turned up
a &lt;a href="https://github.com/danlec/Trello-Bookmarklet"&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://github.com/danlec"&gt;Daniel LeCheminant&lt;/a&gt; of Trello, to add a Trello card for the current
page. It does some really cool stuff, like parsing Jira and GitHub issues and setting the card title nicely for them, as well as some other ticketing
systems. I also found a &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/aggieben/5811685"&gt;GreaseMonkey script&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://github.com/aggieben"&gt;Benjamin Collins&lt;/a&gt; of StackExchange
that adds a link to create Trello cards from StackExchange meta&amp;nbsp;posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I took things a bit further and whipped up a GreaseMonkey script, &lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/userscripts#trellocontextmenu"&gt;TrelloContextMenu&lt;/a&gt;. It
uses Daniel&amp;#8217;s card naming code (plus fixing the GitHub format a bit and adding support for &lt;a href="https://www.reviewboard.org/"&gt;ReviewBoard&lt;/a&gt; code reviews) and
the GreaseMonkey/Trello logic from Benjamin&amp;#8217;s script. Once installed and authenticated with Trello, the script retrieves a list of all of your boards
and cards, and adds an &amp;#8220;Add to Trello&amp;#8221; right-click context menu in Firefox, allowing you to add the current page to any list on any of your&amp;nbsp;boards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/GFX/TrelloContextMenu_large.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="screenshot of TrelloContextMenu context menu popup in Firefox" src="/GFX/TrelloContextMenu_sm.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The script is &lt;a href="https://github.com/jantman/userscripts#trellocontextmenu"&gt;available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; (the link in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;README&lt;/span&gt; will go to an installable raw
version of the script), and uses GreaseMonkey&amp;#8217;s versioning capabilities. At the moment I&amp;#8217;ve only tested it with GreaseMonkey in Firefox, and I don&amp;#8217;t
expect it to work elsewhere as it uses a few GreaseMonkey-specific features, such as &lt;code&gt;GM_xmlhttpRequest&lt;/code&gt; and GreaseMoneky&amp;#8217;s browser-wide SQLite
persistent storage (to store your boards and lists, and authentication credentials, until you manually refresh). I&amp;#8217;d be happy to accept pull requests
from anyone who can get it working in other&amp;nbsp;browsers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Antman</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 19:36:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2015-03-22:2015/03/my-new-found-love-of-trello-and-a-helpful-greasemonkey-script/</guid><category>Trello</category><category>kanban</category><category>tickets</category><category>organization</category><category>work</category></item><item><title>Building a Rebuild-able Site</title><link>http://blog.jasonantman.com/2009/05/building-a-rebuild-able-site/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At $&lt;span class="caps"&gt;WORK&lt;/span&gt;, my group runs about two dozen servers that provide services
for over 60,000 users. They&amp;#8217;re a mix of Windows and Linux, with some old
Solaris stuff thrown in there. The one thing they have in common is
they&amp;#8217;re all hand-built, hand-configured, and old. They&amp;#8217;ve been around
for a while. At the moment, we don&amp;#8217;t even have an adequate backup&amp;nbsp;system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, being the closest thing to a SysAdmin we have (my official title is
still Student Systems Programmer), it&amp;#8217;s my job to build a new
installation, configuration and backup infrastructure. We&amp;#8217;ve already
standardized on &lt;a href="http://www.centos.org"&gt;CentOS&lt;/a&gt; as a University-wide
distro, and have a local full mirror, so I don&amp;#8217;t need to choose a
distro. I do, however, have to plan the installation and backup
architecture. The main requirements&amp;nbsp;are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lowest overall time for bare-metal recovery to a working&amp;nbsp;system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ease of use, as people other than myself will need to administer it
    (so they should be able to do so from a cheat sheet in the&amp;nbsp;wiki).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeatability - it should be easy and intuitive to make an
    almost-exact-copy of a&amp;nbsp;machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started a thread a few days ago on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SAGE&lt;/span&gt; mailing list, which you
can find
&lt;a href="http://mailman.sage.org/pipermail/sage-members/2009/msg00447.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, it looks like the general idea that I&amp;#8217;m going with is to
use &lt;a href="http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Anaconda/Kickstart"&gt;Kickstart&lt;/a&gt; to
install the systems, using a basic and minimal Kickstart file. Basic
package selection (minimalist) with just what&amp;#8217;s needed to configure the
system with a hostname and network settings for the management &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VLAN&lt;/span&gt;.
I&amp;#8217;ll then have Kickstart install and configure a configuration
management package - I&amp;#8217;m leaning towards
&lt;a href="http://reductivelabs.com/products/puppet/"&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt; over
&lt;a href="http://www.cfengine.org/"&gt;Cfengine&lt;/a&gt; and am starting testing. The config
management software will handle all of the customization for the system
(everything different from the base generic Kickstart install) so it&amp;#8217;s
all kept under the control of config management from step&amp;nbsp;1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final part is a backup system, mainly for whatever eventually -
whether out of human error or simple laziness - ends up out of the
config management system&amp;#8217;s control. Our previous &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SA&lt;/span&gt; had settled on
&lt;a href="http://www.zmanda.com/"&gt;Zmanda&lt;/a&gt;, the paid version of
&lt;a href="http://www.amanda.org/"&gt;Amanda&lt;/a&gt;, which comes with specific plugins for
MySQL and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MSSQL&lt;/span&gt;. I&amp;#8217;m also looking at &lt;a href="http://www.bacula.org"&gt;Bacula&lt;/a&gt;,
mainly because of its&amp;#8217; advanced features, scheduling (especially the new
scheduling in Bacula 3) and&amp;nbsp;scalability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beauty that I see in having Kickstart do something minimal and then
letting Puppet handle the rest is that (especially since we&amp;#8217;ve
standardized on SunFire X4100&amp;#8217;s with identical configurations) I can
kickstart and rack up a few spare machines, and to get them up and
running all I need to do is power them up (iLOM) and tell Puppet what to
make&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m currently starting testing of both Puppet itself and getting
Kickstart to start the puppet install and daemon (instructions from
&lt;a href="http://watzmann.net/blog/index.php?cat=21"&gt;David Lutterkort&amp;#8217;s blog (Red Hat software
engineer)&lt;/a&gt;). We&amp;#8217;ll see how
everything&amp;nbsp;goes&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">admin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2009 08:42:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.jasonantman.com,2009-05-06:2009/05/building-a-rebuild-able-site/</guid><category>backup</category><category>configuration</category><category>kickstart</category><category>linux</category><category>puppet</category><category>recovery</category><category>work</category></item></channel></rss>